- [Instructor] My name is Chris Anatalio
and I'm a senior software engineer.
I have over a decade of experience
crafting scalable
modular web applications.
Modern application development
is more demanding than ever.
You need to support mobile and tablet apps
as well as web applications.
A well built rest API can provide the data
to power all three.
In this course, we're
going to build a rest API
with Java and Spring Boot.
We will also build a
responsive modern front end
using Angular JS 2.
We will walk through how to
design and model your resources.
Finally we will go over how
to test and document your API.
After completing this course,
you will have a solid foundation
for creating a modern, scalable API.
You will also have a foundation
for building a fast, responsive front end.
Now, let's get started.