- [Instructor] If you have
access to the exercise files
for this course, you could
download it to your desktop.
Included you will find
a begin and end state
of the project for each video.
If you're following along,
coding with each video,
navigate to the exercise files directory.
Find the directory for the
video you're currently on.
Then review the project at that state.
You can also import the
project at that state
into your IDE.
In Eclipse, click on file then import.
Select existing cradle project.
Click next and next.
Then go into browse, find the location
where you downloaded the
exercise files folder.
Navigate to the directory of
the video you're currently on,
select your desired state,
then select the project route,
and click open.
Then click finish.
If you're viewing this
course on a mobile device,
a set top device where your membership
does not provide access to the
exercise files that's okay.
I encourage you to still follow along
as we go through the course.
Now, let's get started.