- [Instructor] Now let's set up
your development environment.
You will need to install
node JS and Gradle
to work with the exercise files.
You will also need to install
Eclipse and Post Mane.
First let's install Brew.
Brew is a package manager for Mac OS.
Let's navigate to the
Homebrew site, brew.sh.
Let's open up a terminal
and execute the following command here.
Now that we have Brew installed,
let's make sure it is up to date.
Okay now let's verify it
is configured correctly
by running Brew Doctor.
Okay it looks like we have
Brew installed correctly.
Now, let's add it to the path.
Type in export path /usr/local/bin path.
Okay now that we have brew set up
let's install node JS using Brew.
Type in brew install node.
Okay so now we have node installed.
Next let's install get
and then finally let's install Gradle.
Okay you should now be
all set and ready to build
and run the application locally.