- [Instructor] In this course,
we will be building a mobile,
responsive website for the
fictional Landon Hotel.
We will design and build a rest API
using Java and Spring Boot.
Then, we will build a responsive front-end
using Angularjs 2.0 and Twitter Bootstrap.
Finally, we will test each end point
using a tool called Postman.
The website will be
mobile, responsive, and
be able to scale to a tablet
or mobile device view port.
A user will be able to
check for available rooms
based on a check-in and check-out date.
The results of your search
will be populated by
our back-end rest API.
You will also be able to reserve a room.
As you can see here,
after clicking reserve,
we executed a post request
to the back-end rest API
and got back a 201, in response.
We will also use Postman
to check each end point
on our rest API.
Here, we are executing a get
command to get available rooms
based on a check-in and check-out date.
After executing that get command,
we get back a response of 200 OK.
Looking at the request
body in the content field
we have an array of available rooms.
Each room has a self-referential link
that allows you to look up
more information on that entry.
The results will also be paginated,
so that you are able to
page through results.
You will be able to create
a new room reservation
by executing a post command passing in
a JSON raw body
including the room you want to reserve,
the check-in date, and the check-out date.
Let's try to execute that post command.
After executing that command,
we get a 201 created,
and information about the
reservation we just created.
You can also update a
existing room reservation
using a put command.
Finally, you should be able
to delete a room reservation
passing in a reservation ID.