- [Instructor] Now let's
create our Spring Boot project
using Spring Initializer.
We will navigate to start.spring.io.
Select Gradle Project with
the latest stable release.
Gradle is a build and
dependency management tool
similar to Maven.
Gradle uses a Groovy DSL instead of XML.
This makes Gradle files less verbose,
more readable, and more scriptable.
For the Group field,
enter in communication.linkedin.learning.
Note that the names and
folder structure I chose
are arbitrary.
You can choose your own
names and folder structure,
and this will not impact the
functionality of the project.
For the artifact name, enter in
linked-in-learning-full-stack-app-angular-spring-boot.
This artifact name will
define the name of the
self executable JAR.
Next you want to click on
Switch to the full version.
For their description, enter
in Building a Full-stack App
with AngularJS 2 and Spring Boot.
Next we will add the
following dependencies.
Web, JPA, and H2.
Web will allow us to define our end points
using a annotation-based system.
JPA will allow us to implement
JPA-based repositories
to interact with the data.
H2 is a really fast embedded database
that will start up when
you start your application.
Next let's click Generate Project.
This will generate a Zip file that will
automatically be downloaded.
Extract the Zip folder into
your projects directory.
Let's grab the file we just downloaded.
Let's copy the file, navigate
to our home directory,
create a new folder, rename
it to EclipseProjects.
Let's go into that directory
and paste in our Zip file
and then extract it.