- [Instructor] Now that we've
extracted the project files,
let's get the project
imported into our IDE.
First, let's install Spring Tool Suite.
Let's navigate to Spring.io/tools.
Click download STS.
Next, let's open the downloaded file.
Double click to extract,
open the extracted files,
click on STS, and copy.
Then, let's navigate to
applications, and paste.
Now, let's open STS using
the default workspace.
Next, we'll need to install
the Gradle plugin for Eclipse,
called Buildship.
Let's navigate to
projects.eclipse.org/projects/tools.buildship.
Click on the current version,
then copy the link to
the update site.
Next, let's open up Spring Tool Suite,
click on the help tab, then
install the new software.
Next, let's click Add, then
paste the update site link
into the location and
name field, then click OK.
Check the box next to the box
next to the Buildship plug-in,
then click next, and next again.
Accept the terms, and click finish.
Then click yes to restart STS.
Next, let's import our project into STS.
Click on the File tab, select Import,
expand the Gradle item in
the import wizard tree.
Select Existing Gradle Project,
then click Next, and Next.
Click Browse, and navigate to
your projects root directory,
and click Open, then click Finish.
The project will now
begin importing, building,
and downloading dependencies.
Next, let's build and run the application.
Right click on the
project's root directory,
click Run As, then select Spring Boot App.
The application should begin starting up.
The final log statement in your
console should indicate your
Spring Boot Application has started.
Next, let's stop the application,
and look into an alternative
way of writing your app.
Open up a terminal and cd into your
project's root directory.
Next, let's run the application
using the Gradle wrapper,
and the bootrun task.
We're able to run a Spring
Boot Application without first
deploying it to a servlet
container, such as Tomcat,
because the servlet container is embedded
in the jar file itself.