- [Narrator] Now let's
dive into some code.
First, we need to
configure our application.
We will use annotative Java
classes for our configuration.
Let's create a package named config.
Let's right click on the root package,
mouse over new, and select package.
And then we're going to name it config.
Next, click finish.
Let's right click on the config package,
mouse over new, and create a new class.
Let's name the class ApiConfig.
Then, click finish.
First, let's add a
configuration annotation
so that Spring knows to use
this class for configuration.
Let's left click on the error
and import the Spring framework
configuration annotation.
Next, we will add two beans to this class,
an ObjectMapper and an ObjectWriter.
The ObjectMapper will
define how JSON strings
in the request body are
deserialized from requests
in POJOs or Plain Old Java Objects,
which we use to model our data.
The ObjectWriter will
define how we serialize
our Java objects into a JSON
string in the response body.
Let's create a new public method,
ObjectMapper, that returns
a ObjectMapper object.
Next, left click on the error and import
the Jackson ObjectMapper.
Then let's add a bean
annotation to that method.
Click on the error, and
import the Spring framework
bean annotation.
Next, let's create another public method
that takes in that ObjectMapper bean
as a parameter.
This method will return a ObjectWriter.
It will use the ObjectMapper to create
a Default PrettyPrinter,
which will output a JSON
in Human Readable Format.
Let's click on the error, and import
the Jackson ObjectWriter.
Next, let's add another bean annotation.
Next, let's jump to our
Spring Boot Application Class.
We are going to add two annotations,
enable auto configuration
and component scan.
The annotation, enable auto configuration
will intelligently configure beans
that you are likely to need in your
Spring application context.
The annotation, component scan,
will enable automatic scanning
for configuration classes to wire up
in your Spring application context.
Left click on the error and import
the enable auto configuration annotation.
Now let's add the
component scan annotation.
Click on the error,
and import the component scan annotation.
Let's save our changes.
Right click on the project root,
go to run as Spring Boot App.
Okay, great.
So our application started up correctly.