- [Instructor] We will
be building a application
for the fictional Landon Hotel.
An example resource will allow users
to view available rooms,
create, update, and delete a reservation.
Let's go over resource modeling.
A RESTful system is composed of resources.
A resource is anything that has a URI.
Examples of resources in the room domain
are reservation, amenity,
and service requests.
You can create, update,
retrieve or delete a resource.
These actions are mapped to the HTTP verbs
POST, PUT, GET, and DELETE.
Resources are grouped into domains.
A domain is a cohesive set of resources.
An example of a domain is a room.
In the room domain, you
will have resources such as
Room Reservation, Amenities,
and Service Request.
We will want to identify the
proper domain and resource
to be used in a URI for our endpoints.
An API endpoint will be in the format
slash, domain, slash,
resource, slash, version.
For example, at the Landon Hotel
we will have a domain called room.
You can check for available rooms
and create a reservation for a room.
Getting a list of available rooms
would return a collection.
Getting a single resource by ID
would retun a singleton.
Versioning allows you to handle
different versions of a resource.
When booking a reservation,
the complete URI
would be POST, slash, room,
slash, reservations, slash, v1.
You will also need to include
the required headers and request body.
The POST will be in JSON format.
You will need to include the ID
of the resource being reserved,
in this case, the room.
You will also need to include
the check-in date and the check-out date.