- [Instructor] Let's take
a look at the code needed
to implement a get endpoint in our API.
Let's right click on base package,
go to New and create a
new package called rest.
Next, let's right click
on the rest package
and create a new class.
Let's name it, ReservationResource.
The ReservationResource
class will represent
the resource remodeled in the last video.
We will create a method
that will let you view
available rooms for reservation.
First, let's annotate this class
with a RestController annotation,
then let's import that annotation.
RestController is a convenience annotation
that combines the controller annotation
with the RequestBody annotation.
The controller annotation
is a specialization
of the component annotation
that marks a candidate
for auto-detection through
classpath scanning.
HTTP requests are intercepted
by the DispatcherServlet
which looks for handler
mappings and it's type,
then routes request to the
correct RestController method.
A response body annotation
indicates a method return value
should be bound to the web response body.
Next, let's add a
request mapping endpoint.
Let's import that annotation
and then let's set the value
to /room/reservation/v1.
Next, let's create a public
method called getAvailableRooms.
This will return a ResponseEntity
containing a ReservationResponse.
This method will take in two parameters,
a local date object, an iso
date format called checkin,
and a local date object in iso
date format called checkout.
Local date is a Java 8 date class.
Okay, let's add the checkin
and checkout parameters.
Let's import the ResponseEntity object.
Next, let's import the local date class.
Okay, now, let's add a
RequestParameter annotation
to checkin.
Let's import that annotation,
then let's add the field value
and set that value to checkin.
Next, let's add a
DateTimeFormat annotation.
Let's import that annotation,
then let's add a a field called iso
and set iso to DateTimeFormat.ISO.DATE.
Next, let's add those two annotations
to the parameter checkout.
Next, let's return a ResponseEntity
containing a empty ReservationResponse
and the HTTP status code of 200 OK.
Next, let's at a request mapping
annotation to this method.
Let's add three fields,
path, method, and produces.
Path will be set the empty,
method will be set to get,
produces will be set
to MediaType.APPLICATION.JSON.UTF8 value.
Next, let's create the
ReservationResponse class.
Right click on the base package
and create a new package called model.
Within model, let's create
another package called response.
Within response, let's create a class
called ReservationResponse.
Within ReservationResponse,
let's create four variables.
First, let's create a private
class member called ID
which is of the type long.
Next, let's create a private
integer called roomNumber,
then, let's create another
private integer called price.
Then finally,
let's create another
class member called links.
Use the keyboard shortcut,
Command + Alt + S
to bring up your source menu.
Let's create getters and setters
for each of our variables.
Click on Select All then OK.
Next, let's create a constructor.
Open up the source menu
again using Command + Alt + S
and click on Generate Constructor.
The first constructor will take in
room number and price as parameters.
Next, let's create a
parameter list constructor.
Click Deselect All and OK.
Then, let's clean up
the formatting and save.
Next, let's create the links
object in the model package.
Let's add a private
class member called self.
Let's open up the source menu
and add a getter and setter,
click on self and OK, then save.
Next, let's create a self object.
Within self, let's create a
private string called ref,
bring up the source menu
and then generate a getter and setter.
Click on ref and OK, then save.
Let's go back to our ReservationResponse
and import the links object
we just created, then save.
Next, let's go back to
the ReservationResource
and import the ReservationResponse.
Now, let's open up a browser
and search for
com.fasterxml.jackson.datatype
jsr310 maven,
click on the link to Maven Repository,
click on the latest table of release,
click on the Gradle tab,
copy the import statement,
navigate to build.gradle in
your root project directory,
scroll down to the dependency sections,
then paste in the dependency we copied
from the Maven Repository,
save your bill.gradle file,
click on the Gradle Task
window, expand build,
and double-click on the
build gradle task, okay?
Our build was successful,
let's close that gradle task window,
and then open up application.properties.
Let's add a new property,
spring.jackson.serialization.write-dates-as-timestamps.
Then, set that to false and save.
Next, in the rest package,
let's create a new class
called ResourceConstants.
Let's pull the request
mapping into a constant.
So, let's go back to the
ReservationResource class,
copy the request mapping, go
back to ResourceConstance,
and add a public static final String
called ROOM in all caps
_RESERVATION_V1
and set it equal to your request mapping.
Copy that constant.
Let's go back to the ReservationResource
and add in the constant into
the request mapping, then save.
Let's right click on the
root project directory,
go to Run As, Spring Boot App.
Now, that our application has started up,
let's go to a browser, and
let's test the endpoint.
Type in localhost:8080/room/reservation/v1
and add the parameter
checkin and checkout,
both of which are iso formatted dates.
Iso format is a four-character year,
a two-character month,
and a two-character day.
After submitting the request,
we get back a response containing
a empty ReservationResponse.