- [Instructor] Next, let's download
an application called Postman.
Postman is a GUI tool
to make API development
faster and easier.
It can help you test, document,
and share your API endpoints.
In a browser, let's
navigate to getpostman.com
Click on the MacOS button,
to download the app for macOS.
Let's navigate to the Downloaded file,
Extract the application,
and let's Add it to our
Applications Directory.
Then, let's Double click
on the Application.
The first time you install Postman,
you may be prompted to create an account.
On the left-hand side,
you will see a section called collections.
Let's click into the Collections tab,
and then click on the
Add Collection button.
Let's name it Reservation.
Then, click Create.
Navigate to the field
called Enter Request URL.
Enter in
http://localhost8080/room/reservation/v1,
and then add the parameter
checkin, and let's set it to
2017-03-18, then Add a
second parameter, Checkout,
and let's set it to 2017-03-20.
On the right-hand side, let's
navigate to the Save button,
and click on the Dropdown,
and click Save As.
Let's clear out the Request Name field.
Let's name the request Get
available room reservations.
Then, let's Save it to the
existing collection Reservation.
And click Save.
Next, let's make sure our
application is running.
So let's go back to clips.
Click on the Root Project directory,
click Run As, Spring Boot App.
Okay, so now that our
application is started,
let's head back to Postman.
Let's click on the Get
available room reservations
request, and click Send.
You should notice the status
code is equal to 200OK,
and in the request body,
we have a empty reservation response.