- [Instructor] Okay, now let's build out
the remaining endpoints.
First, let's add a post endpoint.
Post is a HTTP verb that is used
to create a new resource.
Let's open the class
called reservation resource
and add a method which will allow us
to reserve a room.
Let's add a public method
called create reservation
that returns a response entity
that contains an empty
reservation response
and a 201-created status quote.
Create reservation will
take in a parameter
called reservation request,
which is a request body.
Next, let's add a request body annotation
to that parameter.
Let's import that annotation.
Next, let's add a request
mapping annotation to the method.
Let's add in four fields,
path, method, produces, and consumes.
Let's set path to an empty string.
Next, let's set method to post.
Let's set produces to
application JSON UTF8 value.
Finally, let's set consumes
to application JSON UTF8 value.
Next, let's make sure the
method returns a response entity
containing that empty reservation response
and the status code created.
Next, we need to create
the reservation request.
Reservation request is a class
which will represent the request body
which is sent during a post.
First, let's create a new
package called request in model.
Let's right click on the model package
and add a new package called request.
Within request, let's create a class
called reservation request.
Let's add three class
members to this request,
id, date start, and date end.
Id is a private long.
Check in is a private local date.
Check out is also private local date.
Let's import local date,
then let's add a date time
format annotation to check in.
Let's import that annotation,
and then pass in a field called iso,
with a value iso date.
Now let's add that same
date time annotation format
to check out.
Next, let's use a keyboard shortcut,
Command + Alt + S to
open up the source menu.
Let's click Generate Getters and Setters,
click on Select All, and OK.
Next, let's create a constructor.
Open up the source menu,
and click Generate Constructor.
Select all the fields, and click OK.
Next, let's also create a
parameter list constructor.
Open up source, generate a constructor,
click Deselect All, and OK.
Let's clean up the spacing,
and save our changes.
Next, let's go back into
reservation resource.
Let's import the reservation request class
we just created.
Now, let's save our changes.
Now, let's jump back in
to the api config class,
and update the object mapper
so that is able to parse
iso-formatted dates.
First, let's create a new object mapper.
Next, let's register a module
with that object mapper
called JavaTimeModule.
Then, let's import JavaTimeModule.
Okay, let's save our changes.
Now, we should be all
set to test the endpoint.
Let's go back to Postman,
and add our post endpoint.
Click on your existing
get available room reservations endpoint,
click on the dropdown
by Save, click Save As,
then rename the request,
create room reservation.
Click on the endpoint
create room reservation,
and then let's change the method to post.
Next, let's remove the check
in and check out parameter.
Then, click on the Body tab.
Click raw, then click JSON.
We want to create a JSON string
that will represent a reservation request.
Let's add a field id,
and then we can set it
to an arbitrary value.
Next, let's add a check in field,
and set it to an iso-formatted date.
Next, let's add a check out field,
and also set it to an iso-formatted date.
Okay, let's Save the request,
and then let's go back to Eclipse.
Let's right-click on
the project directory,
click Run As, Spring Boot App.
Okay, after it starts up,
let's head back to Postman,
and submit that post request.
We can see, we get a 201-created response
and a empty reservation response.
Let's head back to Eclipse,
then open up reservation resource.
Next up, let's add a put endpoint.
Put is a HTTP verb that is used
to update a existing resource.
Our put endpoint will be
exactly like our post endpoint,
except with a different request method.
Let's add a new public method
called update reservation
that returns a response entity
that contains a empty reservation response
in a 200-okay status code.
Let's copy the method create reservation.
Let's update the method
name to update reservation.
Then, update the method to put.
Next, let's change the status code
from 201-created to 200-okay.
Let's save, and then restart the server.
Okay, once it's back up,
let's go back to Postman.
Click on your post, click
on the dropdown by Save,
click Save As, then
update the request name
to Update room reservation, and Save.
Click on the request you just created,
update the method to put,
save it, and then send.
We should get back a 200-okay status
and an empty reservation object.
Finally, let's add a delete endpoint.
Coming back to reservation
resource one more time,
let's go ahead and add a new public method
called delete reservation
that returns a response entity
that contains no body in a
204 no content status code.
Next, let's add a reservation id
of the type long, as a parameter.
Let's add the type
annotation path variable.
Let's import the annotation,
then let's add a request mapping
annotation to the method.
Let's add two fields, path and method.
Let's set path to the reservation id,
then let's set method to delete.
Next, let's return a empty response entity
with the status no content.
Let's save our changes,
and restart the server one more time.
Okay, once we start back up,
let's head back to Postman.
Alright, let's click on our get,
click on the dropdown by Save, Save As,
then let's update the request name
to Delete room reservation.
Let's click on Delete room reservation
and change the method to delete.
Let's remove the check in
and check out parameters,
and add a path variable.
This variable will be
the id of the reservation
which you want to delete.
Okay, now let's test it out.
Okay, we got a 204 no content
and a empty body as a response.