- [Instructor] Okay, now
that we've a working REST API
on the back end, let's start
working on the front end.
Let's open up a terminal,
and do a global install
of the AngularJS 2 command
line interface or CLI,
using the Node Package Manager or NPM.
Next, let's set up the front
end, using the Angular CLI.
Let's go ahead and navigate
to our project directory.
CD into source, CD into main.
Then, let's create a new
directory called Webapp.
Next up, we will generate
the base project,
using the Angular CLI command ng new.
Ng new will generate a project scaffold,
with everything you
need to run AngularJS 2.
By default, ng new will
initialize your project
as a Git Repository.
Since we want our Java
Spring re: project directory
to be a Git Repo, instead of
the AngularJS 2 project route,
we will be passing in the flag skip-git.
Let's CD into the Webapp directory.
Next, let's run the ng new command,
passing in the name Angular2,
and the flag skip-git.
Okay, now that we created
the Angular2 application,
let's CD into the folder we just created.
Next, let's install Twitter
Bootstrap three, using NPM.
Twitter Bootstap is a grid
based UI component framework.
It will provide us with some good looking,
out of the box, UI components to use.
Don't worry, prior
knowledge of this framework,
is not necessary, since we are just using
the basic pre-build components.
Finally, let's install Fuel UX.
Fuel UX extends Twitter Bootstrap,
and adds some additional UI
components such as a datepicker.
Okay, now that we're all set up,
let's insure it starts up correctly,
using the Angular CLI command ng serve.
By default, ng serve will run the app
on local host on port 4200.
Okay, now that we're started up,
let's try to hit that
endpoint in a browser.
If you see that message, it
means your app is running.
Next up, let's work on customizing our UI.