- [Instructor] First off, let's add
the typescript plugin for Eclipse
so that we have proper syntax highlighting
on our .ts files.
Let's navigate to
github.com/palantir/eclipse-typescript.
Next, let's copy the update site link.
Okay, let's head back to Eclipse,
click on Help, Install New Software.
Let's click on Add,
and then let's copy the update site link
into the location and name field.
Click on the typescript plugin, then Next,
and Next again, then Accept, and Finish.
Then, let's restart.
Okay, now let's click on the
project root, and refresh.
Let's take a look
at the angular JST project
files we generated.
Let's navigate into source,
main, webapp, angular2,
source, and then app.
We're going to go ahead
and reuse some static HTML
and styles from an existing
LinkedIn learning brand,
landonhotel.com.
Having an actual branded front-end
will add context and meaning
to what we're building.
First, get the exercise file
labeled Landon-Hotel.zip.
Double-click to extract,
and then open up the files.
First, let's open up the
file labeled home.html.
Let's right-click, Open With, Other,
and then STS, or Eclipse.
Next, let's open up the file
labeled app.component.html.
Let's go ahead and copy
the content from home.html
into our component, then save.
Next, let's copy the image directory
and then copy the images
into our app directory.
Finally, let's grab the styles
from the landon-hotel.css file.
Let's right-click, Open With, Other,
and double-click on STS or Eclipse.
Let's copy all the content
from landon-hotel.css
and then paste it into
app.component.css, and Save.
Next, let's head to a terminal.
Let's start up our application
using the command ng serve.
Let's head to a browser,
and let's navigate to localhost:4200.
We can now see our new homepage.
If you scroll down,
we can see the message app works.
This has been populated
dynamically from angular JS2.