- [Male Voice] Next, let's update our
AngularJS component and create a form
to allow a user to search
for available rooms
by passing in a desired
check-in and check-out date.
Just to clarify, we will
be using the CSS components
from Twitter Bootstrap and
not the jQuery aspects.
Generally, best practice dictates
that you should not use
jQuery and AngularJS 2
since they represent different
programming paradigms.
There are several libraries out there
that are attempting to
combine Twitter Bootstrap
with AngularJS 2 but many are in alpha
and not currently stable.
Twitter Bootstrap uses a 12
column grid-based layout.
This allows you to organize your content
in a flexible and mobile
responsive manner.
Let's open up app.component.html.
Let's add a row and a 12 column div.
Next, let's grab the header and drop it
in our 12 column div.
Let's update the header to Book a Room.
Next, let's create a form.
Let's use the Twitter Bootstrap
class form dash horizontal.
Next, let's create form group
that contains a label and an input field.
Let's set the label to column dash 4
which will give the label one-third
of the available space.
Let's name the label Check-In.
Let's create a input of a type date
in a div with eight columns.
Next, let's name that input Check-In
then let's associate the
label with that input.
Let's add the class form
dash control to our input.
Now, let's add another
form group for check out.
Let's copy that form group, paste
and then update the label to Check-Out.
Let's update the ID on the input
to Check-Out as well.
Finally, let's add one final form group
with a Submit button.
Let's create a div with
a offset of two columns
and a width of 10.
This will offset this section
two columns from the left.
Let's create a button of the type Submit
and use the classes BTN, BTN dash primary,
and BTN large from Twitter Bootstrap.
Then, let's update the label
on the button to Submit.
Okay, let's save our changes.
If you have your AngularJS
2 server running,
it will automatically update your changes
into the live site.
So let's take a look.
As you could see we have
a form with two fields
Check-In and Check-Out
and a submit button.
But they are not styled correctly.
Let's go ahead and
update our Bootstrap CSS
which we installed using MPM.
And then save.
And we can see that
AngularJS 2 and Wetpack
have automatically updated our changes.
Now our form is formatted correctly.
Next, let's build the
functionality behind our form
by updating the typescript.
Let's open up the file app.module.ts.
Let's import the module
Reactive Forms Module
from Angular Forms.
Then, let's update the imports.
When updating the app.module.ts file
you may see errors pop up.
Just give Eclipse a
couple moments to catch up
and recompile and revalidate your code.
Now, let's go into app.component.ts.
Let's import component, OnInit,
Form Control and Form Group.
Let's implement OnInit
in our app component.
Then let's add a Form
Group called room search.
We could delete this title field
which was generated by
the AngularJS 2 command
just to test our application.
Let's create a NG OnInit
method to initialize
our form group.
Let's add two form controls
to that form group,
check-in and check-out.
Then, let's add another
parameter called submitted
on the type boolean to track
if our form was submitted.
Let's set it to public visibility.
Then let's create a method
on submit to trigger
when our form is submitted.
Let's create a interface, room search
that has two fields,
check-in and check-out.
Let's update our on submit method
to take in two fields,
a room search object
and a boolean indicating
whether a form was submitted.
In a later video, we will
create a rest service
to make a call to our backend rest API.
But for now, let's just use console log
to log the value.
Let's make sure our interface is declared
outside our app component.
Okay, then let's save.
Next, let's head back
into app.component.html.
Let's update our form to hook into
our AngularJS 2 logic.
First, let's add a form group
to our form of room search.
Let's set the NG submit
to the method on submit
passing in the room search object.
Next, let's update the input check-in
with a form control name
also called check-in.
Okay, let's add the
form control name field
to check-out.
Then let's save.
Looks like we got some errors importing
the reactive forms module.
It looks like I tried to import
the reactive forms module
from http when I should've
imported it from forms.
Let's save our changes and it looks like
that fixed the issue.
Okay, it looks like our
changes were updated.
Let's test out the form.
Let's open up the inspect
window by right-clicking
on the background and clicking on inspect.
Then, let's click on the console tab.
Let's test out our form
by clicking on submit.
As you could see, we submitted the object
containing the fields
check-in and check-out.
Which was logged out of app.component.ts.
So it looks like our
form's working correctly.
So in this case, we used a reactive form.
In AngularJS 2 you have an option to use
a template driven form or reactive forms.
Template driven forms
are generally simpler
and require less Javascript.
Reactive forms are much
easier to unit test
because they are model driven.
You could test a reactive form
using a unit testing
framework such as Karma.
Testing a template
driven form would require
a end-to-end testing
framework such as Selenium.