- Next, let's create a dynamic table
to display search results from
our available room search.
We are going to use prebuilt
Twitter Bootstrap classes
to create a mobile,
responsive, dynamic table
that displays the room number, price,
a placeholder picture, and also a button
to create a reservation for that room.
We will use a ngFor directive
to iterate through a list
of room objects populated
from a JSON array.
Let's open up app.component.html.
First, let's create a
row in a 12-column div.
Next, let's create a responsive table.
Then, let's add a tbody element.
Within that tbody, let's add a table row.
Within that table row, let's
add three table columns.
In the first row, let's
add a placeholder picture
of the room.
Let's copy and paste a sample
picture into that column.
This image will serve as a placeholder.
In the next column, we will display
the room number and the price.
In the final column, let's add
a button of the type submit.
Then, let's add the class
btn and btn-primary.
Let's update the button label to Reserve.
Okay, let's save and take a
look at what we've got so far.
Looks like we need to add
a header to that section.
Let's copy and paste
the Book a Room header
and add it to the top of our table.
Let's rename it Available Rooms.
Also, let's add a line break
between Room # and Price.
Next, let's jump into app.component.ts.
Let's create an interface called
Room that has four fields:
id, roomNumber, price, and links.
Let's copy the Roomsearch interface,
paste it right below,
and rename it to Room.
Let's rename checkin to id.
Let's rename checkout to roomNumber.
Let's add a string called price
and another string called links.
Now, let's define a array
of rooms called rooms.
Next, let's create a hardcoded JSON
containing a array of rooms.
This JSON string is similar
to what we would get back
from a call to the backend REST API.
Let's add a id element.
Let's add a random string of
numbers to represent the id.
Then, let's add a room number.
Next, let's add a price.
And then, let's add a
empty string for the links.
Now, let's copy that JSON element
and make two more copies.
On the second element, let's update
the id to a random string.
Let's increment the room
number and change the price.
Then, same thing on the third element.
We are using this array to
simulate a response from our API.
Okay, next, in the ngOnInit method,
let's set the rooms array to
this hardcoded JSON response
we created below.
Next, let's head back
into app.component.html.
In the table row element,
let's add a ngFor directive.
This ngFor directive comes from Component.
Component is a module in angular/core.
Let's set our ngFor directive to iterate
through the array of rooms.
room will keep track of the
current room being iterated on.
For each iteration, let's display
the room number and the room price.
Let's add a literal string $
to indicate the price in US dollars.
Okay, it looks like we may have a typo.
Let's look at app.component.ts.
It looks like we are
trying to create an array
of the object Rooms.
However, we defined
interface as Room, singular.
Let's go ahead and fix that.
Let's save our changes,
and it looks like webpack
compiled our changes now.
So now, it looks like we are
populating the data correctly.
Next, let's add a on-click
action to the Reserve button
to reserve that room by id.
Let's define the click event
to trigger the method reserveRoom.
reserveRoom will pass in the room id.
This id is populated
dynamically for each iteration.
In the app component, let's
create that reserveRoom method.
reserveRoom will accept
a string parameter.
For now, let's go ahead and
console.log the id passed in.
Later, we will create an API
call to reserve that room.
Let's open up the Inspect
window by right clicking
on the background and clicking Inspect.
Click on the Console tab and
then click a Reserve button.
It looks like I need to save my changes
to see them reflected.
You may notice errors sometimes in Eclipse
when in a TypeScript file.
It looks like the tooling
is not fully up to date
or caught up with all
TypeScript ES6 features.
Let's double check that
webpack compiled our changes,
and then go back to our homepage.
Now, let's click on Reserve.
It looks like we might have
a typo in the function name.
Let's make sure the function
defined in the click event
in the button matches up
with the function defined
in the app component.
Then, let's try out the button again.
It looks like we are
logging the id for each room
from app.component.ts as intended.
Later, we will create
a AngularJS 2 service
so that our table can be
populated from a JSON response
returned from a backend REST API.