- [Instructor] Okay now let's finish up
coding the back end rest API
by implementing a persistence layer
to interact with our
in memory, H2 database.
We added the runtime
dependency, com.h2database:h2
during booth trapping our project.
This dependency which you could find
in the build.gradle file
will spin up an in memory H2 database
when we start up our Spring
Boot app using the gradle task
boot run.
Let's create a new class
in our config package
called database config.
Let's add two annotations
the first being enable JPA repositories.
The enable JPA repositories
annotation enables scanning
for spring data repositories.
A JPA repository is an interface uni find
that extends CRUD repository.
A CRUD repository provides
create, read, update,
and delete functions for a defined entity.
An entity is an annotated Java class
which has an object relational
mapping to a database table.
The enable transaction
management annotation
sets up annotation driven
transaction management
such as the transaction interceptor
or aspect J based advice.
Now, let's create the
database config class.
Right click on config, new, class.
Let's name it database config.
Let's add the enable JPA
repository's annotation
then let's import that annotation.
Let's pass in the location
of our repository.
Next let's add the enable
transaction management annotation.
Then let's import that annotation.
Okay then let's save.
Next let's create a new
class, conversion config,
in our config package.
Conversion config will register converters
that will allow us to convert
request or response objects
into entities and vice versa.
Okay now let's create the
conversion config class.
Let's right click on config,
new, and then new class.
And create.
Let's go to API config, copy
the configuration annotation,
and then add it to
conversion config, then save.
Let's create a method, get converters,
that will return a set
of converter objects.
Let's create a new hash set of converters.
Okay let's import set.
Next, let's import hash set.
Next, let's import
org.springframework.core.converter.
Next, let's return that set.
Next, let's add a public method
called conversion service.
Let's create a new conversion
service factory bean.
Then let's import conversion
Next, let's set the convertors
by calling get converters.
Next, let's call after
property set on that bean.
Finally, let's return bean.get object.
Finally, let's import the
spring conversion service
and save.
Let's open up our application
properties in resources.
Let's add the property
spring.h2.console.enabled
equals true.
Next let's set the
console path to /console.
Let's set the platform to h2,
our in memory h2 database.
Finally, let's set our JDBC URL
to our h2 in memory database.
Then let's save.
Next, let's click on the root package
and create a new package
called repository.
Within repository, let's create
a new interface room repository.
Room repository will
extend a CRUD repository.
This CRUD repository will
take in a room entity
and a long variable.
Room entity is an entity we will create
to define a room object in our table.
Next let's crate a method find by ID.
This will return a list of
rooms from our database.
Then let's pass in a
long ID as a parameter.
Next up let's define that room entity.
First, let's create a new
package called entity.
Entity will be a new
package in the base package.
Within entity, let's right
click on that package
and create a new class.
Let's name it room entity.
Let's add the annotation entity.
We want to import the
Javax.persistence annotation.
Next let's add a table annotation,
passing in the name of
our table which is room.
Then let's import that table annotation
from Java X persistence.
Now let's add some fields.
First let's create an auto generated ID.
This ID will be auto generated
anytime you insert a new record.
Let's add an ID annotation.
Let's import it.
Then let's add a
generated value annotation
where the strategy is auto.
Let's import the Java X
generated value annotation.
Then let's also import that
generated type annotation.
Okay we've set the
generation type to auto.
Next let's add a field called room number
of the type integer.
Let's add a not null
annotation to room number.
This will ensure that
room number is populated
anytime you add a new
room record to this table.
Okay let's import not null.
Then let's add another field called price
of the type string.
Let's also add that not
null annotation here.
Let's use the keyboard
shortcut command alt s
to bring up the source menu
and let's generate some
getters and setters.
Select price and room number then okay.
Now let's add a constructor.
Open up that source menu and
click on generate constructor.
Let's pass in room number and price.
Okay and then one more thing.
Let's add a parameter list constructor.
Click on deselect all, and okay.
Now let's go back to room repository
and import that room
entity we just created.
Looks like we have a typo.
We left off an s on extends.
Lets import that CRUD
repository from spring.
Let's ensure we don't have a typo here.
Okay let's import that room
entity that we just created
and finally let's import java.util.list.
Okay let's save all those changes.
Next we're going to create a
class called h2 boot strap.
This class will pre-populate
some data in the room table
so that we have data to work with.
Let's right click on the base
package, go to new, new class.
For the name enter in h2 boot strap.
Let's implement command line runner.
Let's go ahead and import
command line runner.
Now since we implemented that interface
we need to implement
the method run though.
Let's click on that error
and select add unimplemented method.
Okay Eclipse generated the stub for us.
Now let's add in some code.
First let's auto wire
a room repository bean.
Let's go ahead and import
that room repository
and then add an auto
wired annotation to it.
Then let's import that
auto wired annotation.
Now let's create some data.
Using that auto wired room repository,
let's call the save method.
Let's create a room entity
and pass in a room number and a price.
Then let's import that room entity.
Okay let's add a couple more rows of data.
I'm going to copy that save statement
and paste it two more times.
Then I'm going to update that room number
and update the price.
Now we want to verify all
that data got saved correctly.
Let's use that room repository
to select all the data
currently in that table.
Let's use auto complete
to select room repository.
Then let's use the find all method.
If you hold down command
and click on find all
you could find out that it
returns an iterable object.
So let's right click and
copy on that iterable object,
head back to h2 boot strap,
pass in the generic room entity
and then let's name it ITR.
next let's loop through
that interval object
and print out all the rooms.
Let's create a for loop
of room entities from ITR.
For each iteration, let's call
a system.out.printline statement
and then let's call the
get room number method.
So we should print out the
room number for each entry
in the table.
Let's save all our changes.
Let's head to a terminal and
run the gradle task boot run
using the gradle wrapper.
Let's head back to h2 boot strap.
Let's add a diagnostic print
so that we know when these
items are being saved.
Okay we're going to print out
the message boot strapping data
when we begin saving data.
Let's go ahead and save
then let's copy that printline statement
and paste it right above our for loop
and then update the message
to printing out data.
Then let's save.
This time let's do a clean and build
to clean out our cache
using the gradle wrapper.
Okay now let's run a boot run gradle task.
Let's search for this diagnostic
message that we print out.
Using the keyboard shortcut control F
let's paste in that
message and search for it.
It looks like our command line
runner is not being executed
on start up.
Let's make sure all our changes are saved.
Let's try running our application
within Eclipse itself.
Right click on the project
route, run as spring boot app.
It looks like we left off
a component annotation
on our h2 boot strap.
A component annotation
makes a class a candidate
to be added to the spring
application context.
The component scan annotation will search
for classes that have
that component annotation.
Let's go ahead and add
a component annotation
and then import it, save, and
then let's try running again.
Okay if we scroll up in the console
we can see our diagnostic
print boot strapping data
and then printing out data here.
You could see the for loop
looped through each entry,
saved in the database, and
printed out the room number.
It looks like we're saving data
and retrieving data correctly now.