- [Instructor] Okay, now
let's hook our GET endpoint
for listing available
rooms into our data layer.
We are going to change our GET endpoint
to return a Pageable list of rooms
populated from our database.
If you have a lot of data,
you don't want to return
all that data at once to a user.
It's a lot of load on your database,
and it can be difficult to
manage on the front end.
Paging allows an API consumer,
such as your front end,
to iterate through data in
a more manageable fashion.
First off, let's create a room entity
to reservation response converter.
The data model which
represents a database table
will very often be
different than the model
which represents the data which
you will return in your API.
A converter gives you a nice clean way
to perform that conversion.
First, let's create a new
package called converter.
Right-click on the base
package, go to New,
and create a new package called Converter.
Okay, let's create a new class
in that converter package
called room entity to
reservation response converter.
Click on the converter package, go to new,
and let's create a new class.
A spring conversion class should
implement the converter interface,
passing in the source type
and the intended output type.
Let's import the spring
framework converter,
the room entity,
and then let's also import
the reservation response.
Let's right-click on the background,
go to source, and then go to
override or implement methods.
Since we implemented
the converter interface,
it was expecting us to
implement the convert method.
So let's click on that and click okay.
Eclipse will stub out that method for you,
and then you'll go ahead and implement it.
Let's go ahead and create a new
reservation response object.
First, let's set the room number
on the reservation response.
Let's grab that room number
from the passed in room
entity called source.
Next, let's set the price.
You could use the keyboard shortcut,
Ctrl + Space, to auto complete.
Okay, let's get the price from source
and set it in the reservation response.
If you mouse over, it looks
like we're getting an error.
Reservation response is
expecting an integer,
while source has it stored as a string.
So we could perform that conversion
using the value of method in integer.
So if we wrap source.getprice
in a integer.valueof
method call, we can
perform that conversion.
In our reservation response,
we have a section called links.
Within links we will add
a self-referring link
to be able to get that
resource directly by ID.
Let's create a new instance of links.
Then let's import.
Next, let's create a new instance of self.
Okay, and let's import that model.
Next, let's set the ref,
or the self-referring link,
to the room reservation V1 URL
with a link to that resource's ID.
Let's grab that URL from
the resource constants.
Then let's append a forward slash,
and then let's get the ID from the source.
It looks like we may be
missing a getter for ID.
So let's jump into the room entity object.
Let's press Ctrl + Alt + S
and go to generate getter.
Click on ID and click okay.
Let's use Ctrl + Shift + F to auto format
and clean up, then save.
Let's head back to our converter.
Then let's grab the ID from source.
We left off the keyword new,
so let's go ahead and add that and save.
Let's add the ID to the link,
then let's set that link
in reservation response.
Then, let's save.
Using this conversion
service, we keep a lot
of this logic out of the controller.
Next up, let's add this converter
to our conversion config.
Okay, we added a new
instance of room entity
to reservation response converter
to our set of converters.
Any class that auto wires
the conversion service bean
will be able to use that converter.
When you call the convert method,
you pass in the object in
a expected output type.
The conversion service will infer
what converter to use
based on those types.
Let's also be sure to add
a bean to this method.
This bean annotation will make the
conversion service
available for auto wiring.
Next, let's create a
Pageable room repository.
Right-click on your repository package,
go to new, and create a new class.
We are going to extend a
paging and sorting repository.
A paging and sorting repository is similar
to a CrudRepository except
it lets you page the results.
Let's pass in a room entity type and long.
Long is a type of the ID.
It looks like we declared this as a class
when it should be an interface.
Let's create a method, find by ID,
that takes in a long ID and a
Pageable page as parameters.
It will return a page object
containing room entities.
Let's import Pageable from Spring.
Let's use the keyboard
shortcut, Cmd + Shift + O
and organize our imports.
Let's add the extends
keyword so that we extend
the paging and sorting
repository correctly.
Using Cmd + Shift + O, let's optimize
our imports again, then save.
This is because we are returning a list
of room entities from
Pageable room repository.
Now, let's update our endpoint.
Let's go into reservation resource.
First, let's auto wire the
Pageable room repository.
Let's add a auto wired annotation.
Now we have access to the
Pageable room repository bean.
Okay, so let's use that repository.
Let's call the find all method
and pass in a Pageable object.
We don't currently have a
Pageable object in scope,
so let's add it as a parameter.
Let's import that Pageable class.
Then, let's capture the
return value of find all.
Let's import room entity, and let's also
import a page from Spring framework.
Let's update the return value to page
so that we return a paged
list of reservation responses.
Next, let's get the list of
results from a repository,
call the map method, and pass
in the converter we created.
Let's auto complete using Ctrl + space.
This map function will take
a list of room entities
and convert it to a list
of reservation responses.
Let's go ahead and save.
Then let's start up our application,
clicking on the project root
and going to run as Spring Boot.
Be sure to save.
Okay, so we started out,
we boot strapped our data.
Let's head to postman
and call or get endpoint.
So we are returning your paging envelope,
but we are getting no results.
It looks like in our convert method,
we are returning a null value.
So let's go ahead and create
the reservation response.
Okay, let's restart and let's
try out that GET endpoint.
Okay, great.
So, we are returning the three
rooms which we bootstrapped,
along with a paging envelope.
The way you would use that paging envelope
is by adding additional parameters.
You could add a page parameter
and then also a size
parameter for the number
of results you want on each page.
This would give you
page two of 10 results.
Let's check why our self-referencing
link is not currently set up.
Okay, let's go back to our
converter and fix our link setup.
Okay, let's save and restart.
Let's try out that GET endpoint again.
It looks like we're
getting back the results
with the self-referencing link populated.
However, if we try that
link, we get an error.
So let's head back to our resource
and let's add a GET endpoint
to get a room by room ID.
Let' create a method
called get room by ID.
It will return a response
entity containing a room entity,
Ctrl + Shift + O, to import.
We will take in a long room ID,
and then let's annotate
that as a path variable.
Okay, let's add a request
mapping annotation.
Let's set the path to flash room ID.
We are going to use ID
Spring expression language
to pull that ID off the URI.
Let's set the method to
get, and the return value
will be of the type JSON UT58.
Let's auto wire our room repository
since we are jut getting a single result.
Let's be sure to add a
auto wired annotation.
Then, let's use that room
repository to find a room by ID.
Then let's save and restart.
Trying out our GET endpoint again.
Let's check one of these
self-referencing URLs.
It looks like we are
not returning the value
correctly from the repository.
Let's create a new
response entity passing in
that room entity and also
the status code okay.
Okay, let's save and restart.
Okay, jumping back to postman.
Let's call our endpoint,
click on the link,
and now we can get a room
entity by ID as well.