- [Narrator] Next up let's implement
the reservation JPA repository.
Reservations will be another
table in our database.
There will be a one to many relationship
between room and reservation.
One room can potentially have
many different reservations.
First off, let's rename
reservation response
to reservable room response.
This will more accurately
reflect the purpose.
Let's right click on reservation response,
go to refactor, rename.
Make sure update references
is checked, and click finish.
Let's also take a look at the room entity
to reservation response converter.
We can see the type was updated,
but not the base class name.
So let's right click on the name,
go to refactor, and rename.
Okay, let's double check
in our conversion config,
and we can see the name
was properly updated.
Next up, let's add a reservation entity
to model the reservation table.
Let's create a new class in
entity called reservation entity
and click finish.
Okay, first up let's
add a entity annotation.
Be sure to import the entity
annotation from Java X persistence.
Next up, add a table annotation,
and then let's import it.
Let's pass in the table name
to that table annotation.
Let's set the name equal to reservation.
First let's add a ID of the type long.
Let's add the annotation ID.
Let's import it.
Then let's make sure this ID gets
automatically generated upon creation.
Let's add that generated value annotation,
make sure it gets imported,
and then let's pass
in the field strategy
equals generation type auto.
Next up let's add a private
local date field called check in.
Let's add a not null
annotation to make sure
it gets populated upon creation.
Let's import that local date class.
Let's create another field
local date check out.
Now let's be sure to add that
not null annotation, all right?
As a reminder, the keyboard
shortcut to generate getters
and setters is command alt S.
Go to generate getters and setters
and click on select all then OK.
Let's add our constructors.
First one takes in check in and check out.
Next one is parameter
list, deselect all, and OK.
Then command shift F to
autoformat and then save.
Now let's open up the room entity.
Let's add a list of reservations entities
called reservation entity list.
Command shift O, view our
imports, then let's add
an annotation one to many.
Command shift O, this
one to many annotation
indicates that there is a relationship
between room entity
and reservation entity.
A room may have multiple reservations.
That's why this room has a list.
Let's add fetch type set to eager,
and let's say cascade to persist.
Then when we save this
entity, any reservation entity
children connected to this room entity
will also be persisted.
Then let's add a getter and setter
for the field we just added.
Command alt S, generate,
select reservation entity list,
and OK.
Let's also add a method
called add reservation entity.
If reservation entity
list is currently null,
let's create a new one.
Control space to autopopulate.
And let's set it to a
new array list if null.
Control shift O to import, then let's add
the new reservation entity to the list.
Control space, add and
then let's make sure
we're operating on the list, all right?
And then save.
Next, let's open up reservation request.
Let's add in a field private long room ID.
Room ID is the ID of the room that
you want to attach your reservation to.
Let's delete the
constructor, control alt S,
and create a new one with
every field except ID.
Then let's add a getter and
setter for that room ID field.
Control shift F to
reformat, and then save.
Let's create a new class in response.
New class, and let's name it
reservation response, and finish.
Okay?
Let's add in two fields,
check in and check out,
of the type local date.
Command shift O to import,
and let's not forget
the ID field as well, of
the type long, all right?
Let's throw in the getters and setters,
and then add in the fronter.
And then one more.
Deselect all, command
shift F, format, and save.
Next up, let's add a JPA repository.
Right click on repository, new, class.
Let's name it reservation
repository, and create.
All right, let's make sure it
extends the crud repository.
It'll take in a reservation
entity and a long.
Command shift O, let's make
sure this is a interface.
Command shift O, and save.
All right, let's create some converters.
Right click on converter,
new, class, all right?
This one will be reservation request
to reservation entity converter.
This class will take in a
request body from a rest API
call and convert it to
a reservation entity
so that we can save it.
Let's implement the converter,
passing in a reservation
request and a reservation entity.
Fix that typo.
Command shift O to import
and let's make sure
we grab the spring framework converter.
If you click on this error
and click on add unimplemented
methods, it will stub out the method
that you have to override, all right?
Let's create a reservation entity.
Make sure that gets returned.
Let's set the check in
to the source check in.
Let's set the check out
to the source check out,
and then if the source ID is not null,
let's also set that.
Control space to autopopulate, dot set ID.
Command shift F to format, and save.
Let's create one more converter.
This one going from a reservation
entity to a reservation response.
Make sure it's an interface.
Let's make sure it implements converter
going from reservation entity
to reservation response.
Let's make sure that's class, actually.
Okay, let's import converter,
command shift O to do
our imports, click on the error,
add unimplemented methods.
Create a reservation response.
Make sure that gets returned.
Set the check in and set the check out.
Okay, and save.
Next, let's open up conversion config
and add those two converters.
Let's make sure this is named correctly.
Let's right click, refactor and rename,
and let's append converter
to that name, and save.
Let's open up the reservation
resource, all right?
It's in rest.
First, let's add the
reservation repository.
Get it autowired, head
back to the post end point,
then let's convert the reservation request
into a reservation entity.
Let's autowire the conversion service.
Okay, now we have access to that beam.
Let's pass in the reservation request
and set the expected target type
to reservation entity dot class.
Let's grab the reservation
repository beam,
and then save that entity.
Let's grab the room repository beam.
Let's call a find by ID
and get the room ID from
the reservation request.
Let's grab the response.
Then in that room entity
let's add reservation entity
to the list of linked reservations.
Then using room repository,
let's save that room entity.
We are also going to persist
the linked reservation entity.
Let's actually head back
to the reservation entity
and add a room entity field,
and let's add a many to one annotation,
since we could have many
reservations for one room.
Let's save and add a getter and setter.
Select room entity and OK.
Command shift F to format and save.
Let's set the room entity
to return in the response,
then let's create the
reservation response.
Use the conversion service,
passing in a reservation entity
and expecting a reservation response back.
All right, let's grab
that reservation response,
and make sure that gets
returned in the response entity.
Let's make sure we have
the correct return type,
and then save.
Let's restart.
And let's test our post.
Getting a 404, 'cause I might
be expecting an ID field.
Let's close.
Let's reopen the post.
Okay, after we open up a fresh query,
we submitted the post, and we
got a 201 created in response.
Let's do a get.
Let's click on the self referential link.
We could see that reservation entity
has been linked to the
room with the ID of one.
So we could see that
the reservation entity
was properly cascaded and
linked to this room entity
when save was executed on room repository.