- [Narrator] Now that
we have our end points
hooked into our data layer, let's get our
Angular JS2 hooked up into our API.
We will be using HTTP module to execute
our rest API calls.
We will receive what is called
a observable in response.
An observable is a new type
of asynchronous data stream
in Angular JS2.
We will be using RxJS, a
reactive library for JavaScript.
It is a third party
library that is endorsed
by Angular JS2 as a framework.
An observable is a
asynchronous stream of data
that is emitted over time.
This leads to a better user experience
since you can process
data as it streams in.
First, let's add a cross origin annotation
to our reservation resource.
Since our Angular app is
running on local host 4200
and our API is running on local host 8080,
they are considered different origins.
Normally, for security
reasons, you would want
to maintain a same origin policy,
however during local
development we will want
to open up this restriction so that our
Angular JS2 app can
communicate with our API.
So, let's add a cross origin annotation
which is imported from spring.
Let's save and restart our API.
Okay, we're restarted.
Let's open up app.component.ts.
Let's import the dependencies we need
from the HTTP module and also
from the reactive JS module.
Let's import HTTP and response.
If you look in app.module.ts you can see
that we already have that import in place.
Next, let's import observable.
Let's also import the
operators map and catch.
Map will help us process the
results from a HTTP call.
Catch will help us handle
any exceptions we encounter.
In our app component let's pass in HTTP
to our constructor.
Next, let's create a
function called get all.
Make sure this function
is within the scope
of your app component.
Let's add in a HTTP get call.
Let's define our base URL
at the top of app component.
This base URL will be
how we access our API.
Let's pass in that base
URL to our get call
and add in the rest of our URL.
Passing in our check in
and check out parameters.
Next, let's define a mapping function
to help process the result.
The function will be named map room
and will take in one parameter response
of the type response.
It will return a array of rooms.
Room is a object we defined earlier here.
Let's take that response,
extract the json,
and then grab the element
content from that json.
Looking at the raw json
string you can see here
content will return the
actual data which was
returned from your API call minus
all the information used for paging.
Let's map the response
using that mapping function
we just created.
Let's have our get all function return
a observable containing a room array.
Let's make sure we have a colon
between the function
name and the return type.
Now, in the on submit
function which is triggered
when we click search on our page.
Let's call the get all function.
Get all returns a observable
that we can subscribe to.
When you subscribe to an observable
you are subscribing to the
asynchronous data string.
We will pass in a lamda
which will take the
streaming data and put it
into an array called rooms.
We will also pass in a second
lamda to handle errors.
In this case, we will just log each error.
Okay, let's save.
Next, let's delete the hard coded data
we had previously and
remove this initialization.
Now, rooms will be empty until we submit
our get all rest API call.
Let's head to app.component.html.
Let's navigate to the table
which contains our room data,
then let's add a ng if directive.
This directive will
only display the section
if rooms is populated.
Okay, let's save.
We could see webpack has compiled
our changes successfully.
So, let's go take a look at our site.
If you right click on
the page, go to inspect,
right click on refresh
and click on empty cache
and hard reload that will clear your cache
and give you a fresh
update of your website.
Type in a date, then click submit.
Clicking submit will trigger this method
on submit passing in your
form group, room search.
That method will execute the get all
rest API call and then we will subscribe
to the return observable which will
populate data into the array rooms.
Then, we use a ng 4 directive to iterate
through that data and
display it in the table.
We can see the data displayed here.
We have added formatting to make the price
look more like an actual price.
You can see the three elements displayed
in our table now match up
with the three elements
which we pulled from our data base.
We have prices being
two hundred, two fifteen
and two eighteen.
Also, let's take a look at some of the
client side validation.
If you try to add a invalid
date, such as March 32nd,
it will automatically change
it to the last valid date.
If you leave a field empty
and try to click submit
you'll get a validation error.