- [Narrator] Alright,
let's add the functionality
to your reserve a room from our front end.
Let's open up app.component.ts.
We added getAll previously,
but executed a get request to our API.
Now, we want to execute a post.
First, let's create two
fields to keep track of
the values check in ad
check out from the form.
Let's name it current check in value
and current check out value.
Next in ngOnInit, let's
subscribe to changes
from our form group.
Let's define a field called
roomsearchValueChanges.
First, let's define a constant,
roomsearchValueChanges,
and let's set that equal to roomsearch,
which is our form group,
and we're going to set it to valueChanges.
Now that we have that set,
we can subscribe to these
value change events.
Let's pass in a lamda.
Let's copy currentCheckInVal
and set it equal
to the value in that form field.
Same thing on currentCheckOutValue.
That was any time we omit
a value change event,
we are capturing the current
value in these two strings.
Next, let's create a
function called reserve room.
We'll take in a parameter
called value on the type string.
Let's create a new request body object.
Let's name it ReserveRoomRequest.
Let's add a roomId string, checkin string,
and a checkout string.
Then, let's create a constructor,
and then let's copy these three fields,
and paste them into the
constructor parameters.
Let's take off the semi-colons,
and delimit each parameter with a comma.
Then, within the body of the constructor,
let's set all the fields.
Then shift F to format,
then let's head back to
the reserveroom function.
It actually looks like we
had reserveroom defined,
so let's use that existing function.
Let's create a request body,
passing in the parameter value,
which will be the room ID
that you want to reserve,
the current value in the
field currentCheckInValue,
which is populated from the form element,
and the currectCheckOutValue.
Next, let's create a
createReservation function.
Let's pass in that request body,
let's copy ReserveRoomRequest class name.
Let's serialize that
ReserveRoomRequest object
into a JSON string.
Let's add some headers and
let's create an array in place
and pass in the
single header Content-Type
equals to application JSON.
Then let's set the request options.
Fix the typo in content type,
and let's add these headers.
Let's use the HTTP
module to execute a post
passing in the base URL and
the domain and resource,
the request body, and headers.
Then let's subscribe to the
observable that gets returned.
Let's pass in a lamda, and at this point,
all we're going to do is log
that response to the console.
Let's save and webpack
compiled our changes,
so let's head back to our application.
Let's do a refresh.
Let's search for available rooms,
let's right click and inspect,
and then open up the console.
When you click reserve, we
can see that we made a request
to our API and got back a successful 201.
Let's check on our API,
and let's look at that room
with ID one and room number 405.
Now, it looks like we
have two reservations
attached to that room.
So it looks like we were successfully able
to reserve a room from our front end UI
using AngularJS2, and the HTTP module.
Now that we are tracking
the current value of the CheckIn field,
let's go ahead an update the get URL
so that we're passing in the actual value
of that form field instead
of the hard-coded value.
Let's save our changes, let's refresh,
and let's make sure our get still works.
We are now passing in
the CheckIn and CheckOut
from the form fields dynamically.