- [Instructor] Let's take a
look at the server side data
validation that we have
built in to our API.
When you add in a request
parameter annotation, by default,
the field required is set to true.
That will add the validation
where that field is required
to have a valued API call.
Defining the type of
parameter will also ensure
that the passed in data is valid.
Let's demonstrate this
validation in Postman.
If we remove the parameter checkout,
and then try to execute the
get available rooms get call,
we get a validation message,
checkout is not present.
If we pass in an invalid
date, such as March 41,
we get a type conversion
error and a 400 bad request.
This validation will also
occur in the request body.
If you look in ReservationRequest,
we expect an ID,
a LocalDate checkin and
another LocalDate checkout.
If we attempt to remove a
field, which is required,
we will get a validation error.
If you close that tab, click Don't Save,
and then reopen, click on
Body, and then let's try
passing in an invalid date.
March 48th.
In that case we also
get a validation error.
And a 400 Bad Request.
If you pass in a bad URL,
you just get a 404 Not Found.
Our API returns preview
scripted error messages.
They should give the user
enough info to fix their request
if they get an error.