Let's talk about options
for testing your API.
In post-band we have a
two-wall called Runner.
If you click on Runner, on
the upper left-hand side,
it will open up a
Collection Runner interface.
A Collection Runner will quickly test
all of your API end points.
So, let's click on your
existing reservation collection,
set one iteration,
and zero delay.
You could output a log file, if wanted.
Okay?
We've selected our collection.
Let's click Start Run.
You can see it quickly cycled
through all of our end points.
Please make sure that your
application is running,
at the time that you've
run collection Runner.
As you can see, we got a 200
response for each end point.
It will also capture response time,
payload size and other metrics.
You could export the results as a JSON.
You can also test and
validate a rest service
using a JAVA unit test.
One library is REST-assured.
You can learn more about REST-assured
at rest-assured.io
Let's stop our JAVA API server.
Let's try running a
REST-assured unit test locally.
First, lets grab the great all dependency.
Okay, let's do a search
for io.rest-assured maven.
Let's open up MVNrepository,
click on the newest version,
copy the dependency import,
for cradle.
Let's open up the bill dock cradle,
add in the dependency, then
let's rebuild our application
using the cradle wrapper,
let's execute clean and build.
Let's open up ReservationResource.
Let's right-click on source,
flesh test, flesh JAVA.
Go to new and let's create
a new JUnit test case.
Let's name it, ReservationResource.
Click setup so that we
have a setup method.
Now, click finish.
Let's add a RunWith annotation,
passing in SpringRunner.
Let's import the SpringRunner class,
then let's import that annotation.
Next, let's add a
SpringBootTest annotation.
Okay, let's import it and then
let's pass in our SpringBoot
application class and
also our webEnvironment.
Let's use a RANDOM_PORT
for our webEnvironment,
so that we don't have any port conflicts.
This webEnvironment will select
a random open port to use.
Let's create a private int called port
and add the annotation @LocalServerPort.
Let's import that annotation,
then in our setup method,
let's configure RESTassured.
Okay, we set the port, now
let's set the base path.
Let's grab the room reservation constant,
let's export it from ResourceConstance,
then let's set the baseURI.
Let's set it to localhost.
The port will be randomized and set here.
Now, let's add a test.
Let's do a static import
of import static
io.restassured.RestAssured.given
Using that static important,
let's add the given method call
and then a chained when call
and then a chained get call,
passing in slash, plus an expected ID
of one of the rooms,
which we pre-populate in the database.
Then let's add a chained then call,
and then let's add an
expectation of a status code 200.
Okay.
This statement will
attempt to execute a call
to the baseURI, to this
path, on this port,
trying to get the resource
with the ID 1
and then it will ensure it
has a status code of 200.
Let's right-click on the
background, run as JUnit test.
Because we added the annotation @RunWith,
we're going to run the application
with the full application context.
If you click on the JUnit
window, on the right sidebar,
you can see that our test
completed successfully.