- [Instructor] Let's talk
about documenting your API.
Within Postman, you have the
ability to export a collection.
If you mouse over your collection,
click on the elipses, click on export,
Collection v2, and export,
you can export your
collection in JSON format.
There are many tools online
that allow you to document your API.
One example, is apimatic.io.
If you go to apimatic.io and
sign up for a free account,
go to /transformer, click on convert now,
and upload your collection.
Add a file descriptor.
Let's select API Blueprint Format 1A,
and click convert now.
If you go to a site like apiary.io,
which also requires a free account,
if you open the file you downloaded,
copy the API blueprint,
and then paste it into your apiary,
you will then have a live
documentation of your API,
which will describe each end point,
and also the required parameters.
So, for instance, we see our get,
our post, our put and our delete.
If you click on an end point,
such as get available rooms,
scroll down and click try,
it'll give you an example on
how to call that end point.
Let's add in the check-in
and check-out fields
and click call resource.
We got a 404 in this case,
because we don't have a
hosted URL for our API.
But if we did, that'd be
a good way to test it out.
The 1A format is pretty universal,
so you'll be able to use it on many sites
other than apiary.io.
Swagger.io also provides
hosted documentation.
If you go to apimatic and
convert your Postman export
to a Swagger JSON or YAML,
you could also host it on SwaggerHub.