- [Instructor] Okay, we have
built a fully functional
full stack application together.
To learn more on your own,
you can implement the PUT
and DELETE endpoints.
You can also experiment
with client and server side
filtering in our GET
available rooms endpoint.
For example, you could filter
on fields such as price.
In this course, we only
touched on unit testing.
However, it is very important.
You want to have automated
testing in place for all major
functionality.
You want to be sure to test
your Java code as well as
your AngularJS 2 code.
Back-end testing frameworks
we used include JUnit
and Rest Assured.
Testing frameworks on the
front-end provided by AngularJS 2
are Karma, Jasmine and Selenium.
You have many types of testing.
The most basic type is unit testing.
Examples of unit testing
frameworks are JUnit, Karma
and Jasmine.
Examples of integration testing frameworks
are the spring test runner.
An example of a end-to-end
testing framework is Selenium.
There are lots of great
courses on testing here
on LinkedIn Learning,
so go check them out.
As we have learned, Spring
Boot and AngularJS 2
are powerful and flexible tools.
So I recommend you get out
there and build something.