Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to start typing our read up saga.
Now, typing sagas is going to allow us to start really understanding the nuances of why typing them
is so challenging.
There are ways to make it easier and it starts with including a new library as well as a new plug in.
So in order for us to include the new library, what will say is yarn ad typed redux saga.
So Type Redux Saga is a library that extends upon it.
This extension of typing out generators and typing out generators is typically very challenging.
Other than the Type Redux saga, we also need to include a macro for babble.
Now I mentioned before that we will talk about babble at the very end, but for now all we need to really
do is just include this additional dependency.
So yarn at that dash dev babble dash, plug in.
Dash macros.
Now that we have everything installed going back into our code base, what we want to do is we want
to start migrating over our sagas.
So to begin, I'm going to switch this category saga over to a tortoise file.
The reason why we have typed up Saga is that we no longer need to use Redux Saga effects.
Essentially, typed Redux Saga allows us to leverage a typed version of each of these effect creators.
The way to use them, though, is that instead of calling yield, we will now be calling yield star.
So the difference between yield and yield star is that yield typically yields that generator and you're
still inside of JavaScript generator land that handles the actual execution of those generator functions.
Yield start is similar, but it essentially hands up off to the Redux Saga Library.
So Redux Saga is going to behave the same way, except because its Redux saga, redux saga can coordinate
and identify what these effects are, what their return values are going to be.
Because if you remember with a saga, a saga can have multiple yield steps.
Typically with a generator, it's very difficult to determine what the output of these generators are
because each yield is a output of the next call in the generator.
If you remember from our generator video, if you unfamiliar go back, rewatch that generator video
because a lot of the difference between sagas and generators is extremely minimal.
The main thing is just that you can see sagas as generators that have redux bindings within them.
But the other thing is that Redux saga, the library becomes the thing that actually drives and calls
the generator in order to move it forward.
But along the way, what it does is it's able to now determine the types of the values that come back.
And by doing it like this, now, we can see that we are getting the appropriate type arrows.
Now here, when we look at this type of error, what is it that we see that's wrong?
We notice that this is a very extensive mention inside of the overload matches all of that stuff right
now that's not as important.
The key thing that we see is that up here, it says type saga generator is not an array type or a string
type.
The compiler needs to use this option down level iteration to allow the iterating of iterate hours.
So what we need to do is in order for our to properly parse this well, we need to go into our test
config JSON and inside of our compiler options.
Now what we want to add is down level iteration, except we want to set it to true.
On save here, though this may not work the way that we expect it to.
If we go back to our category saga, sometimes if you hover over, you'll notice that the type errors
have not gone away and you'll still see it.
In our case, it did end up working for me.
But if it does not for you, all you need to do is go into your VTS code and just close it.
Make sure you close all of your voice code, restart it.
And what happens is that the Vasco compiler will rerun and hopefully pick up the correct changes from
your test config json.
It really happens when your computer is a little older and a little slower.
Sometimes the code takes a lot of resources, so as a result, the TypeScript compiler and the listing
might be a little bit behind.
But now we see that everything is working here right away.
We actually see that we have this error.
Now, this error is due to the fact that this function does not receive any actual properties.
But here I'm clearly passing it categories.
So this is actually a mistake on my part in JavaScript in one of their own error, because if you pass
a parameter to the function, the function still gets invoked.
All of our code still works, but in my particular case, I'm passing a property in TypeScript that
does not actually expect in this function.
This function takes no properties.
So that's actually one great thing that we can quickly fix to make our code less confusing.
The next error.
And this is, again, that catch error was mentioning.
In this catch, catch can catch any type of error.
So for us, it does not know what this is.
It's always going to throw unknown, even though we're expecting a parameter of error.
So here we might as well just cast this to error because we know that if this fails, we will be getting
an error.
And that's really all we needed to do in order for our sagas to be type now.
So if you look at the saga now, you'll look inside of this generator definition.
You'll see that what it does is it makes a call effect as the categories array.
So each of these different values in the first part of the generator tells you what the yield values
will be.
One is going to be a call effect that returns back the category at Ray.
Now the category array is the return of this.
Categories and documents call.
So yield.
As you can clearly tell of that.
One will give you a call effect, which I mentioned is an effect generated by Redux saga and that returns
you back the category array.
The next is the yield of the put effect.
It does fetch categories success.
Finally, we have also a poor effect of batch categories failed.
These are the three different possible yields that can come out of such categories async.
So that is essentially what the first parameter of the generator represents.
The next one is the return value.
So this is if inside of our generator function, we return something as a final value, which we rarely
ever do inside of our generators.
So for us, that's going to be void.
And then the third argument of the generator or any values that we pass into the next call in order
for them to get passed into the subsequent yield calls.
So for us, we generally also don't really handle those.
So most of the time we're really just focused on this initial typing right here for the generator.
But as we noticed with the yield star call inside of Type two Redux saga, what will happen is that
this inference gets deferred to the actual Redux Saga Library and type Redux Saga is smart enough to
actually go through it and infer all the required times for any sagas and generators that got called
in order to build out this actual type structure.
So we really don't have to do it ourselves.
So now that we've typed category saga, we have to type user sagas and user sagas are going to be more
complicated because there's a lot more saga code in there and there's actually a couple of adjustments
we need to make in order to make it fit inside of TypeScript.
So join me in the next video.
Let's start typing out user sagas.