Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to host our Web site live using Net Lafite through this great platform
that the why we can actually have our website hosted by the end of this video.
And the reason why is because net fi is a platform that focuses primarily on getting frontend modern
applications up as easy as possible.
They've really taken the world by storm in the last two three years, and they're only continuing to
grow.
So this is a really stable, great service to use for hosting applications, and we get great things
like continuous integration right out of the box.
I'll talk more about that once we start signing in and taking a look at nullify.
So if you have not already got an account here, I want you to sign up and go through the process.
And once you've successfully signed in, join me because what you should see is a page like.
This one, once this loads, so now that we're back, hopefully you've signed in and you are seeing
this similar page as I am.
There's a lot of different options here, but the primary thing we want to look at is the CITES section.
So down here in CITES, one I want you to do is just click this import from get.
What this allows us to do is directly choose the GitHub account that we have that we want to host our
application through.
And the great thing about this is because whenever you make a push to GitHub, to the specific branch
that you want to deploy, it will automatically rebuild on that la vie, meaning that your website is
always up to date to a specific branch that you have that you want to be your life website.
So if you haven't already, make sure that your GitHub is currently up to date with all of the code
changes that we've made in the last few videos.
Here, what we're going to do is we're going to choose get as our get provider, but we could have choose
other ones.
What it will ask you to do is authorize GitHub.
So mine, I'm already authorized.
But just go through the steps.
It's very simple.
It's essentially allowing net Lafite to access your repositories inside of GitHub.
Once you've done that, what you want to do now is you want to go and find your specific repository
where you have our project.
Now mine is called.
Crown Clothing v two.
So you can either search for it right here or you can find it, and I'm going to look for mine.
Crown calling me to this is the latest version.
The branch that you want to deploy is the one of your choosing, so mine is going to be main.
Because that is the primary place with my up to date coat.
Now, what we need to do is we need to look at these commands right here.
Nothing I want you to change except for build command.
The build command is the command inside of our package JSON that builds and serves the final packet
of our website after it's been minified and magnified and all that stuff.
Magnification and Uggla ification is the process where we convert our fancy readable code into a less
readable but much more optimized code, and it's handled all by Webpack.
What you need to add is c.i equals and then yarn built.
And the reason why you need sequels equals is because of the continuous integration aspect of our website.
Now let me explain.
So, C.I. continuous integration is the process in which we're allowing this platform to deploy our
website based on very quick code changes that we make to some repository in a get environment get environment
for us right now is GitHub.
Now, typically with deployments, this is actually a manual and arduous process.
If you were to set up the infrastructure and coordinate some of the potential cloud solutions, or maybe
the infrastructure solutions required for a full deployment because you need to allocate resourcing,
you need to figure out where these build files are going to be living in order for you to serve them
to a web site whenever they request them.
Because remember, what's happening with our website is it's getting built into the final version,
but our final version has to live in a resource somewhere, a server somewhere that then needs to be
able to serve that to websites that are asking for it.
And it has to be the latest version of the code or at least the version of the code that we want to
deploy typically in.
Imagine how this process might be complicated and arduous.
But this is what these platforms like Netflix like do is that they've essentially turned all of this
infrastructure into the primary thing that they offer as a service.
So behind the scenes, they're coordinating all these deployments, they're figuring out all of these
build pipelines.
They're figuring out all of the resourcing required in order for you to easily and quickly deploy your
website while listening to some great repository for those changes.
Now we rely on to create React app in order to build our project.
What's happening inside of Nat Lo-Fi is that Nat the fight is essentially going to scaffold up, create
React app and run, create React apps build command.
So that means that you're essentially instead of building on our local terminal while building inside
of a net lo-fi environment.
Nullify, of course, is, as I mentioned, now a CGI environment.
So what happens is that because it's still using create racked up to build up our project, it's rely
on Create React app to look at the CIA environments of Nat Lo-Fi and look for any potential issues.
Now what will happen is that some of these tools, because in a sealed environment, might throw a couple
warnings inside of our build step.
The moment that happens in a CSI environment create React app has decided to be a lot more strict,
meaning that it'll treat warnings as errors.
Which is why if you don't have sequels to overthrow that CIA variable inside of Create React app, then
what happens that create wrapped up will fail inside of nullify?
But that's only because of an overly aggressive treatment towards warnings which will get thrown from
these internal libraries we're relying on inside of nullify.
So by saying, Hey, ignore that, don't worry about it, just build now it all works.
As for the published directory, this is just what directory we want to serve our build files from and
knowing that yarn build would create React app builds into a build folder.
That's exactly the folder we want.
So now I just want you to head deploy site.
Now what should happen is you should land on this page.
Here, you'll notice that we have a random string that's generated for our website and it'll say site
deploy in progress.
If you scroll down, you will see these three steps that nullify is suggesting we go through in order
to have a fully secure and up to date website.
We don't need step two and step three right now.
All we need is to leverage the existing you are all that they're generating for us, which is going
to be based off of this randomly generated string.
And we just need to wait for our site to finish deploying.
If you scroll down, you'll see that these are our production to place.
So generally speaking, this process takes about two to three minutes, but it really depends on how
much code you have, because what's happening behind the scenes right now is that Nullify is running
our Create React app build script in order to build out the final folder that is going to actually use
to host our website.
So let's just quickly wait until this finishes.
And there you should see published.
So now, if we scroll back up, we'll see our website is located at this address.
If you click this, it will open up our web application and you'll see that our entire application works
the way that we had originally designed it to.
In fact, if you click around, you'll see that you have everything working, including all of our features.
And let's check our sign in, so here I'm going to sign in with an email that I know we've already created,
I sign in.
And there we go.
Our users also authenticated up.
It'll get all these different checks and balances.
If you're using Chrome browser, which will tell you whether or not you want to update or store your
passwords.
But either way, our website works.
Authentication works.
Everything is built in.
So there we go.
Our website is live, but there's one last step we need to do.
If you click on jackets or any other deeper nested route, if you hit refresh.
Notice that we get a page not found.
Now, don't worry, this is perfectly normal.
We'll discuss why this is happening, and it'll be a really quick fix for us related to not the.
And we'll do that in the next video to see you there.