Welcome back, everyone.
In this video series, we are going to talk about performance optimization in React.
Now, performance optimization React is a interesting topic because a lot of people want to write code
that is performant.
In fact, that is the main goal for a lot of developers is to make sure that not only is your application
working, but it's very performance and provides a good user experience.
But I do want to talk about a few things.
The first thing being that you do not want to over optimize your code when you start writing it.
This is an incredibly important point that I want you to understand as a React developer.
You only want to start improving the performance of your code or optimizing your code.
Once you see there is a performance bottleneck.
If you do not notice any slowdowns in your code, there is no reason to start optimizing ahead of time.
The reason for this is because these optimizations have a cost.
That is a very important thing to note.
Optimizations are not free.
There are tradeoffs.
When you optimize your code, you are essentially saying, I'm going to spend more time, not just your
time, but the computer's processing and resourcing time to improve the performance of some part of
my code so that later it's more efficient.
A good example of this is when we think about our selectors.
When you think about the fact that we're memorizing these selectors, this create selector call has
a cost on the memory and it has a cost on the rendering time.
When re select as memorizing this selector, it's literally storing the output value in memory somewhere.
And to do that storage, it also takes time.
However, the reason why we think it's optimized is because we're going to make the selector call multiple
times, and every time our component renders, we might actually end up calling the selector every single
time.
So if that's the case, then by memorizing this selector function, yes, the initial step might be
a little bit slower, but in the long run it's way faster because every subsequent call doesn't require
us to read, determine what the value of that selector is.
So there you can see already where the trade off wise.
We trade off in the beginning so that we get more optimized calls later on.
So this is a very important thing I want to talk about.
A lot of the patterns that we've been coding in and learning in throughout this course are designed
already to give you very optimal code.
The React library and the React team is constantly working fervently on figuring out how to make their
application also more performance.
So this is the thing you need to know about React Library.
It's got a ton of stuff under the hood to try and optimize and get around a lot of these issues anyways.
So knowing that, it's very crucial that, you know, moving throughout this video series that you only
optimize when you see a performance problem.
If there is no performance problem, do not optimize.
Now, despite that, there are some tools that React has given us to optimize the code inside of these
components, and we'll discuss that in the next video.
So I'll see that.