Welcome back, everyone.
And the last video we discovered that we seem to have this styling clash.
And what you would notice if you look inside of the category container is you see that we have both
styling coming from our category dot styles that says, but we also have styling coming from our category.
Item dot styles our category item, if you remember, is what we named these components.
So this is actually an unfortunate side effect that does happen very frequently when we write season
sass.
The reason being that if we forget the name ining and the nomenclature of these components, it's very
easy to accidentally write the same class names for specific elements that you might have forgotten
about for some time now.
This is also a very common problem in general.
Web development when you're writing CC and Sass, CSI is present across the entire page.
If you're not super diligent with your strategy, it's very easy to find these clashes.
So for us, this is actually a two fold problem that we can solve.
The first is solving this immediately.
The next is figuring out if we can solve it using something in the React ecosystem.
And I'm going to talk about that later.
First, let's just fix this with the first solution, which is just to resolve this conflict.
So back inside of our component, we have this category item component.
This component is what we use to demonstrate on the main page.
These five different selectable options.
What these are is instead of calling them category item, we can call them directory item because they
are housed in the directory component, if you remember.
So let's start renaming these.
I want to rename this to directory item.
And similarly, the code inside this should be directory item component.
And also directory item dot styles.
For this directory item, of course, we need to update all references to this, so let's focus on our
internal files first.
Directory item like so.
And then instead of category container, this should be directory item container.
And instead of category bottom container, we'll call this directory item body container.
In fact, let's just call it directory item body.
So now let's save this and inside of our directory item styles, let's remember what we change this
to.
This is now directory item container.
And similarly, it's just now body.
If I remember correctly that we just call a body.
Now we call it directory item body, no, let's call it body body is pretty clear because it's housed
under directory item container, so it's the body of the directory item.
And let's see if anywhere else we might have this.
Yes, we do.
Let's fix this here as well.
And now, if we save this, we need to now make sure that we're leveraging the new item in the correct
place, which will be inside of our directory component.
So here now, this is no longer a category item.
This is a directory item which we can now save and now we come back.
Let's see.
Our component is now working.
And now if we navigate to slash shop slash hats.
We also see that our shop page is working.
So what about the other roots?
Well, here if we go to shop jackets.
We see that it also works.
The last thing we need to do that we seem to miss with our collection preview is we did not make these
clickable links to take us to the appropriate place so you can actually leverage the link component
we get from Rotterdam to switch this over.
Let's actually do this quickly together.
Go to the navigation component.
Pause the video and try and figure out how to leverage this link component and use it inside the category
preview component.
I'm going to give you a second to try yourself.
And now let's do it.
So what we need to do is import in link from React Rotterdam and then what we're going to do is we're
going to replace this span with Link and then the two is going to take us to title.
Because we're using title as our roots.
If I save this now, if I click hats, it does take me two hats.
Inside of this page, we can also render the title up here as well, since we haven't done that.
So let's go into our category component and at the very top, before any of this, we can render a H2
where we just show the actual category.
And we can give this a class name of title.
Now, similarly, we are going to want to stall this title, so inside a category styles, we can target
title.
And let's just take the same font that we've been using throughout the other parts of our application.
So inside of our category preview.
Component right here.
Let's take this font size.
And let's just put this inside of here.
In fact, let's increase it to 38, and now if we save this, we come back.
Now we see that our hats is being rendered in the wrong place.
Of course it is because it's a grid.
So now let's go back to our category component and let's move this above, which means that if we're
going to do that, then we want to wrap this in a fragment.
And now we can say fragment.
Fragment.
Let's paste this in like so and then move the div below it.
Save.
Come back to our application.
And now we see hats up here.
So what we can also do is to upper case, we need to call the method like so.
And here we see hats.
So you can further stall this if you want if you want to center this more, if you want to make this
bigger.
All you need to do is because this is no longer inside of the category container.
You can say title like so.
But the problem with this, of course, is that now any of our other titles might inherit this style
if they have this class name of title.
So here we actually need to be more explicit.
We need to call this something like category title.
But again, this is assuming that we can properly remember that this is called category title.
This becomes that same problem where we're getting these styling clashes that keep happening.
So this is actually what's going to bring me towards my next topic.
But before that, let's finish up styling.
What we need to stop.
So category title, I'm also going to add a text align center here, and then I'm going to update the
corresponding component in our category component so that its category title.
And now let's save come back and there we go.
This is pretty much it.
We built our entire application.
There's a couple of things that we're missing, such as the checkout or not the actual checkout, but
the payment step, but we can discuss that in a later video.
It's not the most pressing thing right now because it's just an additional feature.
What I do want to do is take a second and really congratulate you because you've built a rather complicated
React application that utilizes a lot of the modern technology and a lot of the complex base of what
React has to offer in the next video we're going to discuss.
The first thing I mentioned at the beginning of this video, which is that there is this styling clashing
problem that we keep seeing.
The styling clashing issue comes from the fact that we are relying on CIUSSS to style these individual
components and thinking about how we named their classes may not be the most accurate option.
What we're going to do is talk about CIUSSS in J.
S Solutions, so that's what we're going to do.
And we're going to talk about that in the next video.
But until then, take a quick breather.
Appreciate the work that we've done.
You've come a long way and you've really built something great now.
You've learned a lot about React, and that is no easy feat to pat yourself on the back and then join
me in the next video.