Welcome back, everyone.
In this video.
What we're going to do is we are going to introduce in Redux Persist.
Now, Redux Persist is a tool that allows us to persist our reducer values inside of local storage.
So to start all we need to do is we need to add in redux persist as a library.
So once it's inside, there's a lot of nuance, setup and configuration we have to do.
Not a lot, but at least there's some that won't make a lot of sense up right until we actually see
it in action.
So in order to use it, what we need to do is we have to import in two things from redox persist.
We have to import in first the actual persist store method.
From Redux persist like this.
And then the other thing we need is persist reducer.
These are the two methods that will help us actually set up our persistence.
We need a configuration object that tells me to persist what we want.
Now, this config is relatively straightforward and you can find out what other values you can set inside
of the docs that I want for redox persist.
But here in our current config object, we need to say, okay, what's the key?
So the key is the part that we want to start with.
And Root just says, I want you to process the whole thing, which is what we want.
We want to start from the root level.
Then as far as the storage, what do we want to store this into?
So here we need to import this in from redux.
Persist.
Slash lib slash storage.
So by default in any web browser, this will just use local storage, which is what we want.
So this is what will pass as the storage value like so.
Except using this shorthand where we cast the variable as the key name.
And then what we need is we need to think about whether we want a blacklist or white list.
Any of these reduce our values.
So here, this is where you would put in an array of strings of the actual values that you don't want
for which reducer you don't want to persist.
For us, we know that our user value is coming from our author state listener anyways.
So if that's the case, we probably don't want to persist the user because this might conflict and clash
with local storage in a way where we get some weird interactive behavior we may not want.
So I'm just going to blacklist the user.
Now what I'm going to do is I'm going to say I want to create a persisted reducer using this process
config.
So I'm going to call persist reducer like so.
And here I'm going to pass it two things.
First is the persist config.
And then the next thing is the root reducer with these two.
Now I have created a persisted reducer, which is what I want to use for my store.
So now my store is by default, going to be using persistent reducer.
And then what I'm going to do is I'm also going to export out a persistent object which calls persist
store using the store object.
So it's using these new modified, persisted values that we have in Redux that we can now persist the
store.
But to do so, we have to actually go into our index indexes, and we need to import the component that
we're going to pass all this to.
So here what we're going to import in is this thing called a persist gate.
So I'm going to import in persist gate, which is a component specifically from Redux persists that
we can use for React.
So this loss under redux persist, not react slash integration slash react like this.
Now this component we want to wrap inside of our provider.
And we want to wrap all of our application inside of our new Persist gate.
And what we passed of Persist Gate is our sister that we are now exporting from this file.
So I'm going to say persist or is equal to poor sister.
And now if we go back to our application.
If we have looking inside of our car, we have some items.
Let's refresh now.
What we see is that we have retained the same items and looking inside of our code here, we see that
we receive an action of type redux.
Persist or persist.
Slash persist and then persist.
Rehydrate.
So here, this rehydrate, as you can see, is giving us back the actual values that we told that to
persist.
Remember, we said, don't persist the actual user.
And through this, we're now able to actually retain the initial state that the user previously had.
If we remove some values and then we refresh again.
We see that we are persisting the same values.
One additional thing you can also add to this Pacific Gate is you can pass a loading value and here
you just renders something.
You can pass it a component or whatever you want when it's trying to determine how long it takes to
actually rehydrate the store.
So if I say no.
Essentially what happens is that it'll render nothing until Persiste is actually finished.
But there we go.
Now we have in local storage and persistence that you can carry your actual state across multiple sessions.
And this is, again, one of the benefits we get out of Redux is that the ecosystem for Redux has a
lot of these solutions and tools already solved.
You most likely want to use Redux when you're building a large application that has really large state
and really complex state.
If you don't need a lot of these optimizations, then just use context.
API is enough.
But now we've migrated the entire application to Redux, and this is pretty much a lot of what you need
in Redux is just these same patterns over and over again.
A lot of practice will go a long way.
So at this point you can continue to learn redux by either building in new features yourself, or you
can try and convert this application back to context.
By doing so, you'll actually think about these mappings and all of these different logical decisions
that we made in order to architect the application this way.
So there's a lot of different ways that you can learn.
Again, practice always makes perfect.
But now that you're armed with the knowledge, at least you'll know what to do.
Redux is one of those things that naturally, again, has a steep learning curve that will only get
easier the more you practice.
But that's it.
We have in our Redux process, we have Redux.
And now you have seen what it takes in order to set up Redux as your state management service inside
of a React application.