In this video, we are going to cover a very important topic and that is routing so typically with react,
you either are going to use one of two main libraries, at least the majority of React projects, while
you're either going to use React router or you're going to use recruiter.
They both are different libraries that essentially tackle the same topic, which is how do you determine
based off the URL, i.e. the navigation on a website?
What pages to render, remember and react?
Everything is a component.
So you want to think about pages the same way?
So let's look at a visual example.
So at a high level, we understand what these libraries are doing because while these libraries are
different and they'll go through iterations and they'll go through different versions, essentially
they are trying to achieve the same thing.
And as long as you're able to understand the high level topic, what the actual implementation details
are is largely not that important.
So imagine that you had your browser inside your browser.
You have your website, your URL, you're all based.
Navigation is pretty much the standard way that we navigate through a website.
Let's say on this website, when you land on your home page, you have some component, like a navigation
bar.
Those little black lines.
Imagine that those are different lengths that take you to different routes on this website.
Let's say that you selected the first website and it takes you to, let's just say, crown clothing
and then Route one when you navigate here.
We might expect a specific page to render.
What will notice, though, is that that page is an entire component.
I want you to think about it like that.
Imagine that entire page that just got rendered when we navigate to Route one is a brand new component
that we mount onto the page in response to navigating to Route one.
Now what I want you to notice, though, is that the navigation bar component is still there.
I've created out a little so you can see and highlight which link we're currently on.
But if you think about a lot of our applications, we know that in many applications, regardless of
where you navigate onto the page, there are certain components that are always there, particularly
navigation bars, side panels, all of those are always present.
And the libraries that we use, whether it be React router or recruiter, should allow us that functionality.
We should be able to modify and change what lives on the page based on the route.
And what's changing is going to be what components render and don't render.
So in our particular case with the navigation bar, most of the time we probably always want it there.
So there's a composition here that's important to think about because it really extends into how you
would intuitively build applications.
So we know we have a navigation bar.
The content below the navigation bar is the one that typically changes on the route change.
So here we see out route one.
We've rendered in this different component at the bottom that reflects a page.
Now, let's say, instead, we navigate to route to the second link here.
What should happen is that we should render in some new content, as we expect on the side here.
I want you to notice that there is now this sidebar.
This sidebar might be some kind of navigation for the content within this route, meaning that depending
on what you select inside of this side navigation, it may also additionally determine what gets rendered
on the content to the right.
So this you can imagine as a sub route within a main route that we're nesting in.
This is a very common pattern that you see in web applications as well.
Some things, like Facebook Messenger chat is a good example of this.
Depending on what you choose, the continental right will render a different conversation.
So similarly here, let's imagine that we selected the first link.
We might render some specific things inside of here.
If you look at the URL, you'll notice that now we're saying route to slash sub route one, meaning
that we're in the first sub route of Route two, which is indicated by the first link that we've clicked
in our sidebar.
So the right content reflects accordingly because the right content is the components that are being
rendered regarding this route.
Now, let's say, for example, we chose a different route sub route to inside of our sidebar navigation.
Here, of course, we expect the content inside to change again.
So what I'm hoping that these diagrams have shown you is a very common pattern that we see throughout
different web applications.
We know that depending on the routes that we navigate to, certain parts of the page may change.
Certain parts may not, such as navigation bars within the parts of the pages that are changing as we
move throughout the application by routing to different links.
There may be certain routes that have components that stay with deeper subreddits.
So in those sub routes, an even smaller portion of that website is rendering and coming in with new
components and showing new content.
But as we've seen here with our side navigation bar nested in route to that component may also stay
as long as you're nesting in Route two and navigating through these nested sub routes inside of rap
too.
Now, once again, perhaps if we were to change the main route, let's say we went to Route three in
this particular case.
Of course, everything underneath the main navigation bar renders and that is expected behavior based
on what we've been discussing so far.
So again, this is a very common pattern that you see in how websites are built throughout probably
the majority of the web applications you use on your day to day.
We just want to be able to replicate this behavior with routing inside of our own application.
In this particular app, we're going to be using React router.
So in the next video, let's learn how to implement the newest version of React router inside of our
application.
I'll see in the next video.