Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to start building out some of our reliance on the front end with some kind
of database.
So in this course, I'm not actually going to build a database from scratch.
We're going to leverage a great existing tool made by Google called Firebase.
And what Firebase is going to help us do is we are going to be able to build out our sign in page using
authentication so that we can store the users and refer to those users and sign in those users whenever
anyone wants to access our application.
Luckily for us with Firebase, we can also leverage sign in with Google, which is Google sign, in
which we'll talk about after we learn about Firebase first.
So what is Firebase?
Firebase is a Google platform that allows you to spin up a database.
It actually is a pretty comprehensive suite of hosting tools and different things for your website.
But the primary usage is that it helps us leverage some kind of database.
That's the most important thing so that we do not have to set our own up.
So what I want you to do is I want you to go to Firebase Dot Google.com or click the Firebase Link inside
of your resources folder.
Once you're inside a firebase, I want you to click Go to console up in the right corner.
What this will do is this will take you to the list of all of your existing Firebase projects.
I already have one because we've had this application course now out for almost two and a half years
by the time of this recording.
So what you're going to do, though, is let's make a brand new one.
I'll make a new one with you.
I want you to click this ad project and here I want you to name your project whatever you want.
I'm just going to name my crown clothing DB.
So here this will be my project name.
But down here, you'll notice that there's this unique identifier for your project.
So this pretty much just allows Firebase to say that once you instantiate up your instance of Firebase,
this is your Firebase platform's unique ID.
So whatever it generates, you can just keep it or you can name it something else if you want.
But here I'm just going to say Crown Clothing DB and then I'm going to hit continue.
Next up, they're going to ask if you want Google Analytics.
I don't want Google Analytics because this actually makes it a little bit more complicated.
I also don't have a Google Analytics account that I want to tie to this project, but you can do so
if you want to with your firebase.
But honestly, for the purpose of this project and for this course, we're not going to touch it.
So from here, we just create the project.
And now let's just wait for our project to finish building.
OK, so our new project is ready.
And what you're going to do is going to continue, this will now take you into your actual clown clothing
database or whatever you named your Firebase instance.
And there's two main things that I want you to focus on inside of your project.
One is authentication and one is these two database options.
We are going to use Fyre Store Database because this is the newest instance.
Real time database is their old database, so don't worry about that.
Just ignore it.
We're not going to use as much storage or hosting.
We might use some functions, but that'll be later.
We won't use machine learning.
These are all just a different suite of tools that comes with Firebase.
But we really just want to leverage buy our store database and the authentication.
So we have this instance now set up, but before we start using it, there's a couple things we need
to do.
We need to actually allow our reactor application to leverage Firebase and Firestar and authentication.
And to do that, we need to install the Firebase library.
So in order to install Firebase, let's go back to our terminal inside our project.
We are going to type yard.
Add Firebase now at the time of this recording.
The version of Firebase that is going to install is nine point six point six.
Google does like to change up Firebase every once in a while, but generally speaking, they're always
backwards compatible, meaning that whatever you learn here is also going to be largely compatible in
the newer versions.
Maybe the UI that you've seen changes, or maybe the docs change a little bit, but largely speaking,
the high level concepts of Firebase is all going to be the exact same.
And it's really important that I teach you these high level concepts.
It's also important that you learn these high level concepts because unfortunately, especially in React
and with the front end world, things constantly change.
Libraries change.
A couple of years is a lifetime inside of the frontend world, so you need to really be able to understand
these high level concepts so that when the libraries change, you still largely know what's going to
happen.
You might just update the syntax a little bit.
Follow some new patterns and conventions that they believe will leverage and give you greater capability.
But generally speaking, the most important thing to understand is these high level concepts.
So now that we have Firebase installed, what we're going to do is we're just going to go into our application
and just set up a quick route for sign it.
So inside of routes, I'm going to make a new folder called Sign In and inside of this folder.
Let's make a new file called sine and dark component Dutch assets.
And this is just going to be a very simple component.
So I'm going to call it sign-In.
It's a functional component that just returns a div and inside the div is just an H1 that says sign
in page just so that we know that our routing is working.
Remember, it's always important that in order to minimize your errors, just code a bit at a time.
Start with what you know.
Make sure it validates and works and then continue.
So here, let's duplicate our route path and the path should go to sign in.
And the element that we want to render is going to be our silent component.
So here I'm just going to say part sign in from roots, sign in sign in component.
And then instead of rendering shop, I want to render sign in.
So this, of course, is nested inside of our root level route, so it will be slash sign it as we know,
just like we saw with home and just like we see with shop.
And once we have our sign in, what we also need to add is a way to get there.
So inside of your navigation component, I want you to duplicate this second link and inside say that
it goes to sign in.
Actually, let's use the dash, I kind of like the syntax a little better.
So let's go back to our OPG's and switch this route to sign in like this.
And then let's make sure that we say that it's a sign in link.
And now let's verify this works.
So we've added a link that takes us to sign in, and we also included a route that points to the path,
sign in and renders our sign and elements.
So we're just rehashing everything we've done so far and learn so far about navigating and react on.
So let's go back to our application or our browser, and we see that we now have a sign in button inside
of our navy link.
If we click it, we see that we're also rendering our sign in page.
So everything is working as we expect.
sign-In is working.
And now what we need to do is actually bring in Firebase, the library that we downloaded into our application
and write some code to leverage this library.
But primarily leverages libraries so we can actually access this instance that we have of Firebase that
we've also set up.
So in the next video, I'm going to talk about how we do that and also get a better understanding of
a lot of these external tools and how these libraries that we're using actually connect with them and
understanding the better practices on the frontend web.
I'll see you in the next video.