Let's get started with React BASIX now, if you've taken any of my previous courses where Aftar react
or you're not a react beginner and you've built some applications before with react, then you can actually
just skim through these videos or skip this entire section as this section covers their react basis.
We're going to build our first react application from scratch using something called create react up.
And then we're going to deploy to GitHub pages.
Again, if you're completely new to react, then you have to finish this section to move on with the
course.
However, for those with a bit of experience, you might find the section a little bit easy.
Determine for yourself which direction you want to go.
Remember, our goal here is to build these basics so that we can build our giant application, our e-commerce
platform, using react now in this section, we're going to learn a few things.
However, we're going to make a few assumptions here.
First, we're going to assume, you know how to use your terminal or your command prompt.
And you can also use any code editor you want, you can use visual studio code, sublime text or any
other popular JavaScript developer environments.
Now, this section is going to be a code along, so I highly recommend, if you're following along,
to have your terminal or command prompt set up, if you're on Windows Terminal, if you're on Mac or
Linux system and have your code editor.
So you follow along.
Now, over the next couple of videos, we're going to install node if you don't have it already, and
also the Create React app that is going to allow us to.
Right.
React.
I do want to make a few notes, though.
First.
Would this course, as long as you have a version 10 or higher four note, you're going to be fine.
If you don't have a version of note on your system that is 10 or lower, then I recommend updating note
or if not, you can use something called and VM and SVM is a node version manager.
So it's a simple way in the terminal for us to switch node versions.
Now, this is something you can go through on your own.
The easiest way to do things is to just simply download Noad from the Node Jamesburg website.
Now, the second thing we're going to do is we're going to actually install something called create
reactor and if I go to Reactor or here and I go to Dock's.
Under the create a new reactor up, we have this thing called create reactor, which we're going to
talk about in the upcoming video.
Now, the one thing I want to mention is that you'll see this command, NPR and NPR is actually new
and comes with version of NPM five point two.
So if your AMPM version is lower than this, this command won't work.
So you might want to update your NPM version as well.
Now and for those that haven't seen it before, runs a command of a package without installing it explicitly.
So what does that mean?
Well, before we had NPCs, this is what we had to do.
You see here that this is the current version of REACT based on when you're watching the video, you
might have versions that are higher.
But again, this course will work with any versions higher than sixteen point eight.
If I go here and go to an older version of react, let's say fifteen point six, if I click on documentation
and then let's do docs, and then finally we look at the installation.
You'll see that we had to run NPM, install globally, create a reactor, and then we ran the Korea
reactor up command to create our app and allows us to not install this global version of a reactor and
just simply run that one comment to create our app.
All right.
Now, let's go back.
If for some reason during this section you are unable to get this started, there is another option
where you can use this code sandbox daddio, which I'll link to that actually allows you within the
browser to use react online.
Now, one last thing, we're going to get started and go step by step into building our reactor application,
but I also want to point something out to you.
You see, when we study or learn libraries or frameworks or tools like react, the best place to learn
about something is often the documentation.
And most tutorials don't mention this fact that, well, we have the official reac documentation that
explains how we react works inside and out.
Most materials that you see online are taught using this basic template.
So remember, if you ever have questions, this is always the best place to start.
Now we're going to be covering some main concepts and react here, but remember that the way you learn
a library is not like reading a dictionary where you just learn every single thing that this library
gives you.
The thing to understand that will go into later on in this course is how to build bigger and bigger
applications, how to architect your app so that instead of learning something like a dictionary, one
by one, we learn the principles and the concepts that allow us to do advanced things and build real
life applications, something that I'm really excited to do in this course.
So enough talk.
It's time for us to get started.
We're going to start setting up our environment in the next video.
We're going to build our first app and it's going to be a fun one.
I'll see that one by.