Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, I want to talk about Firebase Security roles inside of your Firebase console.
Go into your Firestar database.
Inside of this database, you'll notice that you have a rules tab.
When you click this Rules Tab, your version of your rules may look different from my version.
In fact, you will see inside of your version, most likely this list of original rules where every
single document is readable and readable.
So here, let's discuss how these rules work and the format.
First off, looking at the left hand side, you will notice that the history is being tracked of all
of the changes between how the rules have been modified.
My ruleset is going to be different from your rule set because students may potentially accidentally
download my actual configuration that allows their application to access my version of this Firebase
database.
So as a result, I have to make it very strict.
I essentially only allow users to get users or read and write to them, but I do not allow them to update
it unless that is their own student account.
As for matching, I match every document that I allowed anyone to read.
Just in case, once again, you need to read from my database.
But other than that, I do not allow any users to create or to write to this database.
But let me go through these rules in a very simple way.
Essentially from the top level rules are designed to be a series of match statements.
So here, if you look inside.
We're in Rules Version two.
I don't know the future.
Firebase will update to a newer version of the rules, but right now the rules is version two.
The service is for Cloud Fire Store, which is the database that we're running.
This statement match matches a path to a series of documents.
So of course, it starts with match databases and then the general database.
So these angular brackets designate that any database inside of the database, and then the following
documents are going to abide by the following rules.
Now to begin, we want only users to be able to access their own user profile, and we want users only
to be able to modify their own profile.
So we're going to match to that database, which is our users database.
So let's say slash users and then slash.
And in here you can isolate down to the actual user ID by saying user ID like.
So Firebase knows that when you add this identifier ID, it will cast that variable so that it will
know that if you're trying to access a specific user document by the ID, well now you can only access
it inside based on these rules.
So we can say that will allow anybody to read well, allow anybody to get and will allow people to create.
So creating, reading, getting no problem, but only you're allowed to write to it.
As in you're allowed to update it if.
The request, which has a special keyword inside of these rules, meaning that with every request that
gets sent to Firebase, there's a couple of things on this special keyword that comes with the request.
I'm going to say auth, meaning that this user's authenticated and only if they're authenticated.
So I'm going to say that if this does not equal not only if they're authenticated and the request asks
you ID meaning that their authentication identifier is equal to the user ID only.
If these are true can the user actually write to this user ID.
Now, as far as the categories go, we can make a new line and I can say match slash categories, which
is the name of our categories database in fire store.
And now if I do a wild card, meaning that I access any individual category document.
Remember, you cannot target collections.
You can only target documents.
You have to write this slash.
You're not allowed to just put this.
You have to do either with an ID or with just the base.
Variable, essentially through doing this wild card here, I'm going to allow reading only because I
don't want anybody to be able to add categories, modify categories or anything like that.
I can allow myself to write by saying allow writes if once again request does not equal no, and I can
say request to off uid equals.
And then I can paste in here the uid for my specific user.
If I can find my user that I want to be allowed to actually make write requests, I would just paste
that in there, but I'm not going to put that here in case anybody sees it.
So I can just say allow, read.
Now, one more thing I want to mention.
If in the future I were to add additional properties or additional tables into my database, I may forget
to update the rules here and I want to match everything else that does get added.
So to do that, I'm just going to say match slash and then document equals and then two cards.
This is enough to tell Firebase, Hey, I want to match every other document inside that has not already
had rules defined for it above, as we see.
And then here, I'm just going to allow read for all of those ones.
And this is my updated rules.
I can publish these and now my firebase is more secure.
I'm going to link for you additional documentation to these rules.
You can actually get pretty happy with them.
But for our application, it's pretty simple.
There's not additional that much to learn about it, but if you really want it to get really verbose
with it, you definitely can.
You can even try and implement a cart feature where we store the cart inside a fire store and remember
only the user who owns that cart should be allowed to access it.
If you wanted to access it, how would you do so?
Again, you may have to look through the docs to figure out how to implement that feature, but it would
be an interesting feature to try out.
So that's it for Firebase Rules.
I'll see you in the next video.