Welcome back, everybody.
So in the last few sections, I know we didn't work off of our main application because we were mostly
implementing in different features that can challenge the existing solutions of react redux inside of
our main e-commerce platform by testing out context API and then switching over to graphical and Apollo
client.
So it's actually been a while since we've worked on our main application, but now that we've finished
those tangential sections where we've really deeply explored other alternatives to the React Redux architecture
that we already currently have, it's time we come back and start rounding out our application with
the last 20 percent that gives our application that extra month.
Now, these things might not actually be any features at all.
In fact, in the upcoming sections, we are going to round out your skillset as a web developer so that
you understand that last kind of mysterious part of what it takes to build an application effectively
and have it be performance.
So one of the first things that I want to talk about is actually making our website mobile friendly.
Now, currently, our website is not mobile friendly.
It is a little bit responsive, but it's not fully optimized for the mobile viewing experience.
So what we are going to do is actually modify the case in our files to show that they are more aligned
with how we would want it to look on a mobile browser.
And I'm going to show you that by using media queries now before we actually dive into the code of writing
or media queries.
One of the main things we have to think about is actually how do we make sure that we can view our application
inside of a mobile environment?
If you're rolling chrome, it's actually extremely easy to do so.
The Chrome browser allows us to just open up the dev tools and click this little tablet looking icon
inside at the top of that toolbar, which says Toggle device toolbar.
If you click this, you'll actually see your mobile web view be your main view now where your browser
was before.
You can adjust the size of this and in the top number here, you'll see the actual width and height
of your new view.
So this pretty much simulates a mobile view.
So this is the main way that we are going to use it to see what it is that we are actually going to
have as the mobile version of our Web application.
Now that we have this, we are going to start leveraging these media queries to modify our code to be
more mobile friendly.
So let's go back to our application.
One of the first things that we need to do is actually change this final access file over to start components.
Now, the way that we imported the stylesheet is perfectly fine, right?
It's just one aftertax stylesheet that doesn't necessarily have to change when we moved over to Season
Jass.
But for consistency sake, we might as well do it.
And it's really easy in order to implement global styles.
All we have to do is use this new function called Creates Global Stars, so in order for us to do that,
we're going to make a new folder that will hold the component that represents our global status.
So we'll write this new file and we'll call it global dot styles DOT.
Now, inside of here, we are going to import in from the Style Components Library, this thing called
create global style.
So with this, we can actually create this new concept called global style, which is equal to us using
this crazy global stuff.
And then we pass it, are to build a version of our strength.
Right, because we want strong interpolation.
And now all we do is we just put all the styles that we had inside of our index access inside of here.
If we really wanted to, we could even do it with our index as well, but this is inside of our index
and it's not 100 percent necessary.
Right.
Let's just do it with our access.
So once we place the new stars inside of this global star, we'll make sure to export this out.
And all we need to do in order to bring it into our application is literally load it at the top level
of our app.
So what we'll do is we will go back to our objects, will remove this import that we had before and
in its place we will import in our global sales.
So let's actually move this header up here and say import global style from our new global styles file.
And now it's literally just the component that we can put above the header like so and this will apply
those styles into our application.
So if we go back to our application and we search you back, we'll see that our global style and our
padding is still there.
In fact, if we inspect this, we see we still have our padding and our body still has the padding code
that we had from our global.
So it's really convenient to do it this way because now we are pretty consistent with the way that we're
writing our code.
In fact, now we can get rid of this after successful because we don't need it anymore and we can start
leveraging these media queries.
So the first thing I want to do is I want to reduce the padding on this mobile view of our application.
So how do I do that?
Well, I keep talking about media queries, so I'm going to show you what it actually looks like when
we write them.
You put the media query inside of the CSA selector that you want to modify.
So if we have style components, we just make sure to put this media query inside of that style component
as well.
And the way that a media career looks is it takes the format of this at media.
And here what we'll say is scream and and then inside of here, we put certain properties that tell
it, at what point do we want this style block to be applied?
Now, here you can set things like Menwith and Max with or just one or the other, and all this is saying
is pretty much I only want you to render the block here that will put inside of here.
So wherever here it is, we'll say there's some scissors inside of here.
Right.
We only want this to render based on the rules that we write inside of these brackets.
So in my case, I'm going to say max width is eight hundred pixel.
Meaning that anything below eight hundred and below in terms of the width will get these styles, anything
above eight hundred pixels will not get these styles.
So our body styles will be applied.
But then these media screen max width of eight hundred pixels, this block of access that we're about
to write is going to be applied as long as the windows width does not exceed eight hundred pixels.
So here, I want to set the panning to 10 pixels all around instead of what we had before where our
padding was 20 pixels, top bottom 40 pixels on the left.
And right now, if we save when we go back, we see that our padding has shrunk.
Now we only have a 10 pixel board or padding around the body.
So that is our immediate query now, Ilinka, resource for you guys to see other media queries that
you can write because there's so many, right?
This is literally just the pixel.
Not that I chose to dictate because I find with iPhones there, pixel count based on the new retina's
is a little bit challenging so that sometimes the amount of pixels that you think it might be might
be a little higher.
I find that most browsers do not have a with smaller than just pixels.
And if it's a tablet, it's perfectly fine if it responds the same way as we would see for a mobile
device if it was inside of a portrait view.
So I find a hundred pixels to be one that I'm comfortable with.
Of course, you can dictate and set them to whatever else you want, resources that I've linked for
you have multiple break points that are also always changing as the technology for phones gets better,
screen resolutions get larger.
It's literally just completely dictated by whatever you and your team decide to do.
I personally like this 800 pixel rule for my max with for a project like this where mobile views are
not big is the most important thing to me.
But I do want my screen to be responsive and I want my application to be responsive.
And it's really just that simple.
We have this media query for our mobile view of eight hundred pixels right or below, and then we just
make sure to modify the padding or whatever other properties we want to set differently or also add
now.
Right.
So that our screen responds the right way when it's in this mobile view.
Now, I'm going to go around and modify a couple more components in the next lesson, but then I do
want you guys to try it yourself and tinker around with it, because this is a great chance for you
to kind of see and play around with some of the success so you can have it look a way that you want.
In the end.
It's really just a matter of taste with styling.
But I'm going to show you what I'll do for some of these components that I think we'll end up looking
nice.
So you can either proceed yourself with trying to convert some of these styles yourself first.
You can watch the next video and then do it after that.
It's entirely up to you.
But this section is purely on making our website responsive.
So with that, I will see you in the next lesson.