Now, before we continue, I just want to bring up something very important, so in this course, we
will cover extensively many concepts and react, but also a lot of concepts in JavaScript, because
they will fundamentally play a large role in how we understand the code that we're writing.
Now, the first things I want to focus on are actually Arae methods, particularly these five map filter,
reduce, find and includes.
Now, we may not cover all of them right away because we're not going to use, for example, reduce
until later in the code.
But I want to cover the ones that we will encounter immediately, so even though I'm showing you these
five, don't worry if you feel like you don't know them all right away, I'm definitely going to cover
them just before we have to use them or whenever we do use them.
I'll explain it then.
But this is an important concept, the idea of Arae methods.
The reason for this is because we will use them a lot inside of our record.
Array methods are methods you can call on any array that will perform some kind of action on that array
or with that array.
So I will explore that a little bit later.
But the way that you use these methods is you take any array.
So let's say we make a new array called Meyera, and it's equal to an array of these four numbers.
You're able to call radar map, dot filter, right, dot, reduce, dot, find, dot includes and inside
you would pass it something that it needs in order for it to work.
Now, every Arae method takes something different, which we'll explore, but this is how you use them.
Now, the first one that I definitely want to cover is MAP.
So in order for us to understand map, let's go to our browser.
Now, inside of our browser, we want to access the JavaScript console, so in order to do that, we
have to right click and click inspect.
Now, if you're familiar with the dev tools, you'll know that the console is right here.
But if you're not familiar with the dev tools, this is a great tool that we're going to use to see
how our Web application is either performing or how it ends up being rendered.
But there's lots about this tool that is a very good lens for us to use to see how our application is
doing.
But for this case, we're going to click this console tab up here to go to the JavaScript console.
This allows us to write and run JavaScript code because the browser supports JavaScript.
So what we're going to do is we're going to declare our array again.
So const my array equals an array of one, two, three, four.
What we want to do, for example, to better understand what math does is to understand what we're trying
to get to.
So let's say we have this array.
What if I wanted to increase the value of each element in this array by one so that I get an array of
two, three, four, five?
How do we do this?
Well, one way might be to write a for loop, which you are familiar with, right?
We might write something where we loop over the an array, the array, we get the value right and then
we increase it.
But that's kind of very similar to what MAP does, but in a more efficient way.
Plus, MAP gives us a new array back.
So what we would write is map Meyera dot map.
And then inside, we pass a function that gets called on each element in the array in the order that
they appear, we actually get that element in our function as the first parameter of our function.
So our first parameter being the element.
And then whatever we return from this function will be the value in our new array in the place where
that element was in the original array.
So if we do element plus one, then we'll get two, three, four or five because we're just taking the
element from that place and adding one and returning it in a brand new array.
We don't even have to use the element we could actually, instead of mapping with the element, right,
we could pass nothing through and just return the letter B and what will get.
Don't eat the return.
And what we'll get is be in four places where this function was called on each element in the array,
but this is also a new era.
We know this because Meyera is still one, two, three, four.
So this is what map does, it lets us create new arrays based on our existing arrays and this is really
handy and we'll use it extensively when building our application.