Welcome back, everyone.
I know some of you have been curious about all these things about Web and Bable that we occasionally
mention throughout this course, if you remember from one of the initial lessons that we taught, the
big thing about Create React app is that it hides away all of the babble and all of the web configurations
that you would normally have to figure out.
It's one of the big advantages of great reachout, because Web pack and babble have a lot of possible
configurations that you have to do.
However, if you just wanted to get started with a react application, having to learn those two new
technologies is a big overhead.
But now that we've gotten really good at react and using create react app, I think it's about time
that I show you web pack and babble.
I'm going to show you how we can actually set up our react application to run Watpac and babble in a
very easy and efficient way.
I'm going to show you with as little code as possible so that you can understand what is happening with
Web hack as well as babble.
Both are actually quite simple, and with the newest versions, they've really reduced the amount of
configuration that you have to do for either.
So in this lesson, we're really, really going to look at the bare bones of what we need to set up
so we truly and deeply understand the concepts.
So with Watpac, what you can do is actually go to this link.
I'm going to provide you inside of your resources and it's going to take you to this repo.
This repo I have is just the most fundamental bare bones react implementation before any Web page has
been included.
So simply for this project so that you get a copy of it and then once it's finished forking, simply
clone it down.
So you're going to click your own and you're going to click clone and make sure to use https if you
are not set up your S.H. If you have set up S.H., then you can call with SFH, otherwise you https.
So just copy this key and what we're going to do is go to our terminal and we are just going to clone
it down.
Now, I'm going to call mine web project because, of course, I made this project, so I have the same
name already, but let's just clone down whatever name you want.
I'm going to call my Watpac project and CD into it.
Now, let's take a look at what we have currently.
And what we're going to look at is just inside our source folder, so so far it's a very simple application.
It has an app and all we import inside of just X is react our stylesheet.
And then all we have defined is this app div with a card div and inside as an H1 that says our reactor's
working the most simple app component that you can imagine.
So what I do is export this out by default and bring it into index.
Yes.
So as you're used to by now, this index as file is where we're going to enter from our application.
So in here, I also import react and react.
Dom, I import our app component that I just made and then I render the app and I replace the elements
with the idea of root.
We can find that inside of this index, that HDMI file that in the body there's just this simple div
with an idea of it.
This is as simple of a setup as possible, but we have a react component.
We have some styles and we want to output a optimize build with all of this converted into a version
of JavaScript that our browser can understand.
So we understand all this about react already.
We know about WABAC, we know about Babille.
What they do mostly is that Babul allows us to convert files into other files that our browser can understand.
That's where PAX purpose.
So this code we've written, this JS code, even the HTML and the success, all of this is currently
in a format where we're importing it in in a style that older browsers can understand.
This import style comes with S6 and ESX doesn't work for some browsers because they only support S5.
So this is what Web Pack's main goal is, is that Web hack wants to help us convert all of this code
into versions that browsers can understand.
So let's actually explore this.
In order for us to use Watpac, we have to bring it into our application.
So I'm using yarn.
You can use NPM if you prefer NPM.
One thing to note with NPM is that every time we install a project, you have to make sure that whatever
we install at the end you append dash, dash, save, dash, dev, because these are developer dependencies
and not regular dependencies with ya.
And you don't have to do this.
This is just the thing to keep note.
To get started, we need to add two packages, the first is Web.
The second is Web pack.
Keli, so it's got to be on AD.
So these two packages allow us to begin using weapons inside of our application.
In order to use weapons, there's two things that we've got to add to our actual application.
The first is a file inside of our room folder called Web Pack dot config.
When we run Web, Watpac will automatically know to look for this file.
And in order for us to actually run Watpac, we have to add a new script inside of our scripts object
here in our package that Jason.
So what will add?
Is this Bild script and this Bild script is just going to run Web hack, dash, dash mode production,
so this is saying that I want to run Web, use the configuration file, and then I want to spit out
a production built.
So this is similar to pretty much what we see create react up does when we run our build script in our
project.
Before it was just hiding all of this away for us.
The thing is that inside of our Wopat config, what we're going to do is we have to remember that here
we don't have syntax.
We have to use the old S5 syntax.
So in order for us to export anything, we have to say module exports equals this object because what
we're trying to export out of this file is this object of configuration options.
We're going to say module and we're going to define this thing called rules, so inside of Westpac,
it's got many modules that you can run.
The first one is rules, rules is a way to define --, what it needs to do based on certain file
types that it encounters.
Now, what do I mean by this?
Well, as we know, we are writing Jast code or ethics code.
Watpac doesn't need to convert CSFs code over into Jass code because with CSFs code, if it's using
SAS or for using some other version of access library, that does not come by default with most browsers.
We need a different set of rules than our JavaScript rules because we need a different set of lotas
than JavaScript loaders.
And this actually brings us to the concept of lotas, but we'll talk about it once we start writing
out the rules object.
So what we're going to say is we are going to say that this test string is what we want to match against.
So what type of file extensions we want to match against now here you're going to actually have to write
a little bit of regex and it's actually not so hard.
I'm going to give you a builder, but we're going to say that inside of these slash marks.
That we want to look up any files that end with the dot and then we're going to say jazz or jazz.
And then you add the dollar sign to empty or to end the actual test.
So this is just saying, I want you to find me any files with the extension jazz or that's all it is.
After this, we want to exclude our node modules because we don't want you to run or build any of our
node module code, the packages that we download are already optimized.
They don't need to run through any of these loaders.
They're already converted ahead of time or they should be at least a good library is.
And then what we're going to say is this use property, so they use property tells.
Watpac, what loader it needs to run and the loader is going to be the helper that actually converts
this code into the actual version, so you can kind of see Westpac as the coordinator and the loaders
as the actual packages that Tranz pile this code down into the version that we want it to be.
And here is where we're going to use Babille, because Babille is the library that helps transport JavaScript
and Jacks down into older versions of JavaScript.
So we're going to include in a couple other libraries related to Babille.
So we'll go back to our terminal and what we're going to do is we are going to say Yorn ad at Babille
core.
So we want the core Babul Library, we want at Babille Preset Env.
And this library, the preset end comes with transponding Essex down to SFI.
That's all that library does.
We also want Babille preset react.
Now, of course, Babille can convert everything.
It can convert view, it can convert angular, it can convert Aurora, they can convert all kinds of
different JavaScript libraries down.
You just have to pick the specific ones you want.
That's why it's all at Babille.
And then the name of the smaller library, one to include.
We also need to include the Bable loader.
So these ones were for our actual Babille configuration.
The Bible loader is just so that we have the Babilonia for Watpac.
And once we have this, we can go back to our application and now what we're going to add in is inside
of here, we're going to say the loader.
We want to use the Bible loader.
Now, what Bable knows to do is look inside of our root directory for a file called Babille Arcy so
they babble or C file is going to be the file that tells Babille what it needs to transpire down to.
And here we're just simply going to create an object where The Presets is the property that points to
an array.
And inside of this array, we're going to include those two presets we included.
The first one was preset Env, which, as I explained, converts Essex down to S5.
And we're also going to include Babul preset react.
So this compiles react down into S5 or another version of JavaScript Nacionale that our browser understands.
So if you've ever been curious, why is it that you can put Dorchester and our code always works while
under the hood, this is what's happening?
Create React is doing the exact same thing, it's just taking all of our docs and files and running
it through the babble loader anyways, that's why even though you're writing code and appending your
files docs, your code still works.
This is the loader that's doing that for you.
So hopefully with this, we now understand what it is that babble did babbles very simple.
It is a loader inside of a pack that converts JavaScript files into oler JavaScript files.
It uses certain types of presets that you pass to it.
And of course, there's other configuration options you can add.
If you want to be more explicit, you can find those in the documentation that I'm going to link in
the resources.
But this is the base that we need in order to convert our application down.
So what this hopefully we at least understand what babble does with JavaScript now, we can't test this
until the very end once we set up some other things, which we'll do in the next lesson.
But conceptually, this is all Web hack and babble do.
So let's move on with the next lesson.