Hello and welcome to the best Riak course online.
Wow, that's a that's a bit of a bold statement and OK, I may be biased here, but I'm definitely looking
forward to us diving into some fun topics and coming out the other end as great react developers.
This course tries to build onto each topic and gets more and more advanced as you progress.
Trust me, if you go through everything, you will come out the other end confident with react and be
able to manage or even lead react projects.
Your company.
Now, before we dive into Cotting building projects and learning about react, I want to take a moment
and understand why React exists, what problem does it solve, why it makes frontin development easier,
and also what principles we need to understand to be more than the average reactive up.
You see, a lot of times people learn a tool, a library or a framework without understanding the core
principles that make it great.
By learning these things first will have a foundation as we move through the course and understand what
the best practices are.
The goal of this course is not to be another Reacher's like thousands of others already out there in
existence.
The goal is to make you a reactive helper that can think on your own, make good architectural decisions
and lead projects instead of only following tutorials.
Therefore, in this section, let's dive into the important principles that will help us get through
this course.
If you are new to react, some of these principles may be hard to understand at first.
Rest assured that we will keep revisiting them throughout the course as we learn.
For those that have already worked with react, you may learn a thing or two.
So hang in there.
My goal by the end of this section is for you to be able to explain to other programmers the benefit
of react without writing a single line of code.
I do recommend that this section is something you come back to after you've watched through the entire
course.
All right, enough talk, let's get started.