Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to migrate user sagas over to TypeScript.
So first, let's modify this 2/8 file and you will see that this file is going to explode in typescript
errors.
A lot of typing that we need to do because of course this is way more verbose.
So to begin with, let's start from the top.
First, we want to migrate from Redux saga effects over to typed Redux Saga.
And now earlier we had just use type redux saga, but we can actually also use slash macro.
Slash macro will allow us to essentially leverage that Babel macro plugin.
What is the battle macro plugin?
So generally speaking, when it comes to using third party libraries or builders of third party libraries,
what they have to do in order for them to add additional steps during the code transformation or the
compilation step is they have to create something like a bubble plug in that you need to install.
This plugin is going to be unique to their library in order for the code to compile the way that they
want it to to interact with the Bible step.
However, Babel has defined a very clear step on how to actually create this type of tool inside of
BABBEL.
So it's kind of like you can see it as a standard interface for libraries to use.
That's what we installed the BABBEL plug in macros.
It's not actually made by BABBEL.
It's made by a great developer by the name of Clancy Dods.
But it's very popular because by installing just this plug in, if a third party library uses that interface
that is created by this BABBEL macro plug in, it doesn't actually require you to install any more additional
BABBEL plug ins.
So type like Saga has actually also integrated with this BABBEL plug in macro in order to create this
additional macro plugin and what it mainly does versus using type redux saga is it just simplifies the
final output of the actual actions that get created by the effects.
We won't really see those effects, but generally speaking, it's really helpful for us later on and
we'll talk about that later.
For now, what we want to use is this type redux saga macro.
So similarly, we're also going to update the other saga code we had so that we're also using the macro.
So now that we have switched over, let's talk about this.
Function star force you get snapshot from user on.
So first we notice that we have two type of course, both of these parameters that we're passing inside.
So the first thing we need to do is we need to import user from Firebase Auth, which is the type because
that's what our user auth is going to be.
And we can just cast this over onto the user on.
As for additional details, this comes from our Firebase Utils.
So here down here, we can just add in additional information, which is our type.
Moving on.
We know we need to switch this yield over to a yield star.
And looking inside here, what we notice is that I.D. and data, these are properties that may not exist
because the query documents snapshot.
At this point, we don't know if there is a guarantee that we will get this snapshot because create
user document from off.
If you remember, we could get null, which means that we'll return back void because then the function
exits or if it's not null and we do indeed get a proper user our object, then we will return a snapshot
for that object.
So as a result, what we need to do is we need to make sure that if this exists in the first place so
we can say if user snapshot, then we will actually try and yield out this value.
And there you see that this value is now clear, but this value now throws an error because it says
that we do not have an ID on the type of user data.
So sign in success is expecting a user data object.
Right here.
But the problem is that inside, when we actually append it again, we do append the ID from somewhere
else.
So what we can do here is we can actually extend this type to have the idea of string.
Because if you remember inside of our saga, what we were doing is that we were getting the ID from
user snapshot ID.
It doesn't actually belong on user snapshot dot data, which is what we have in Firebase.
We discussed this earlier when we first created this method.
We have to get the ID from the snapshot.
So now we have to, of course, extend what the actual action creator is expecting, because the ID
is not coming from the snapshot data, it's coming from the snapshot object itself.
So that's all we needed to do.
Next.
Of course, as with the air, we need to make sure to set this as an error.
Explicitly because our sign fail is expecting an error type.
And we know that when this throws an error, it's going to be an error type anyways.
And now moving on here again, the easiest way to convert all of these yields for them to work is just
to switch all of them over to yield star.
So let's first just do that.
Now moving back to our type area here, we see that we actually have an issue where missing a property,
the property that we're missing is actually the additional details being passed here as the second argument
inside of get snapshot from user.
But the third argument of call, the reason for this is because we did not make this optional.
So in order for us to fix this, we just have to define this as an optional parameter.
And now the call will fix as again, with this error, we just need to set this as error.
And now moving onwards, we can look at sign in with email.
Here.
What we have is that we know that Simon with email is getting called with a specific action.
The place where we call it is that whenever we take latest user action types, dot, email, sign and
start take land well past the action that matches into our actual saga.
So that means that this is actually a action that we are structuring.
The specific action that we are structuring here is in fact email sign in start.
So we just need to import that from our types.
This, I believe, is inside of our user action folder.
So we can just copy this and we can just say that this is what we are trying to do, structure all of
our values off of, and you'll notice we'll get email and password as strings because those are the
parameters on our payload.
Similarly inside of this sign in call here we again are getting back a snapshot from sign in with off
user and email and password.
As we can see, we get back a promise of the user credential.
We might also get back undefined.
The reason we get back undefined is because we might return early.
So this is why we might get undefined.
So what we need to do is we need to do a similar check as to what we had above here.
So what we'll say is that instead we're not getting back a user snapshot from here.
We're actually getting back a user credential.
But this credential, of course, might be undefined.
So we'll first do a check.
Is there a user credential?
If there is, then we will structure off the user from this user credential upon which we will yield
out a call in order to get the snapshot from user auth passing it onwards to our next saga.
As well.
We need to make sure that we are casting this air.
But there we go.
This is it.
We have now typed out roughly the basis for the majority of these sagas.
So what I want you to do is take some of these lessons that you've learned throughout this video and
try and type the rest.
I'll continue and we'll do it together in the next video.
But I want you to practice.
So try it out and I'll see you in the next video.