Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to implement React router, which is version six right now at the time
of this recording into our application.
If you're here from the previous two years of the last iteration of this application, you'll know that
we were running React router version five.
And this is the first major version update with a significant amount of changes in terms of just the
implementation syntax.
As far as how the actual library works and what it does for us, that is the exact same.
It follows largely the exact same concepts we covered in the last video when we walk through how a web
application, depending on the route and the suburbs you navigate to, will either decide to keep or
remove and change different components on the page.
And what those different components will be is largely up to our choice.
The library just helps us execute on those decisions that we make.
So let's talk about how we actually implement React router version six into the application.
So here, let's just walk through the docs really quickly so that we get a good, familiar understanding
of majority of how most react libraries work for us.
So you can either choose to read the docs or start the editorial.
The great thing about starting the trial is you get to go through a very simple setup of how that want
you to walk through the major features of React router version six.
I'm not going to do it.
I'm just going to show you how it actually is implemented because I understand how this routing library
works.
But if you're ever curious, go through this material and just follow the instructions for this tutorial.
It's really great.
You get to build a sample application and just see step by step how this routing is built from the bottom
up.
We're going to go through as well in our application, but this one is straight from the library creators
themselves.
But the great thing about the tutorial is they have to show you how to install the application and it's
honestly, really simple.
All we have to do is just initialize the actual library into our packages.
So here they're really just using Create React app the way that we have to create some kind of tutorial
application that you can walk through in case you don't have one.
We can skip all this because we already have all this stuff.
But what we really need is we need this part where we install the browser router.
But first we have to install the application.
So then saw the application.
You just want to look here, install react router dependencies and be installed.
React Router Dom at six, you can use npm.
I'm going to use yarn.
So let's go back to our terminal.
And let's install into our application rack router.
So we're going to say yarn, add react router Dom at six, so that's saying, Hey, give me rack router
Dom version six.
Now, the reason why it doesn't give you the latest one.
Sometimes, depending on recruiter Dom themselves and the package maintainers, they may be having some
kind of conflict between a lot of these different versions that they're supporting.
Version five may still be the most popular.
They may be rolling out version six.
Therefore, they want you to specify when you want six, even though it may be the major version they
support.
Again, a lot of times these libraries are heavily dependent upon by the majority of different applications
in production that rely on them.
So there's a lot of heavy decision making they have to make when rolling out major versions, especially
ones that have sweeping breaking changes like version six in this particular case here.
Version six also is not backwards compatible yet at the time of this recording.
Meaning that if you have version five and you upgrade your application's library to version six, your
application will not work because version six does not support the features that existed in version
five.
So this is a very important thing to understand about a lot of these libraries.
They may want to make updates and they may do so, but often times there will be conflict in how they
do it because of the fact that with the upgrades, maybe they have better patterns or better ideas of
how they want this library to work.
Now, sometimes in order to do that, they may not be able to support the previous working functionality.
When that happens, they have to come up with a strategy and different libraries and different companies
that support these libraries may have different strategies, which is an unfortunate side effect in
this particular case with React router version six.
Some students who have taken this course when we were doing version five may have experienced a lot
of frustration trying to use version six because it's not backwards compatible with version five.
This is an unfortunate side effect of the libraries decision when they rolled out version six.
So this is an important thing to think about when it comes to when to upgrade a library.
So with rack writer Dom, I want to highlight one thing is that oftentimes in them, they'll have an
upgrade guide.
So if you watch the upgrade guide and go through it, you will understand some of the key features in
the upgrade from one major version to another.
Usually, they'll lay out steps about what components or what features have now been removed and of
not being upgraded.
And similarly, they'll also tell you when you can actually directly update the version.
So here, if you read through this guide, it really lists out the major steps required.
First, you've got to upgrade your React version to at least sixteen point eight or greater.
So another thing to note about a lot of these libraries is that some of these libraries, depending
on the version of the library, you download it.
So in this case, React browser version six requires you to have a React version sixteen point eight
or greater version six of React router.
Dom will not work with anything lower than React version sixteen point eight, so that is one of those
considerations you may have to make when upgrading libraries.
Another one is when upgrading React router version five point one and above you have to remove certain
components.
I know these might not make sense to you if you haven't touched version five, but the main thing that
this really shows you is that they may want you to remove old features, and they may also want you
to refactor certain code patterns from those old libraries.
That's all these two really represent at a high level.
So that's one important thing.
You may have to do this first before you actually follow through with the final step, which is where
you upgrade the version of the library itself.
So these are some important things.
If you don't do these properly, you may see a ton of breakages across your application, which may
be significantly more difficult to resolve once you've actually upgraded.
So this is one of those important things that it's a really good moment to understand about a very particular
case that does happen a lot when working with React, which is that some of the supporting libraries
that you use may go through major version changes.
When that happens and there are breaking changes, there is a process of going through the upgrade with
them.
It's oftentimes kind of painful, but it's definitely one of those things that is a great moment to
really understand how these libraries work with your application, but also the general development
cycle and life of a application that you're building in production as a professional developer.
So I just wanted to highlight this thing because it's really on top of mind and we actually went through
it together inside of this course.
Now, for some of you who have not gone through it earlier when we did version five, this may not be
as relevant to you in terms of the actual experience of building out the application and the capstone
project, but this is still a very good learning moment to understand that these things can happen.
And I just want to guide you through some of the steps that you can take in order to go through these
kinds of upgrades.
So it's really not that scary.
It seems way scarier than it is, but it's just one of those things that you just want to follow the
instructions and go through application.
Take it slow one by one and then finally make the upgrade.
So now that we have installed rack router version six and I've gone on this little tangent right now
about explaining some of these library changes, let's actually implement React router version six into
our application.