Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to discuss and jazz, particularly regarding React as we saw when using
CSI, and says there is a high chance that you may rely on your human error to create issues with styles
clashing when writing your CSI rules.
One of the big advantages of using React is the fact that we're allowed to leverage these new libraries
that are called CSI NJ libraries.
What they allow us to do is leverage JavaScript to build out the CSC for us.
What this means is that the JavaScript will dynamically build out unique class names that are tailored
to specifically the components that we're trying to style.
What this allows us to do is scope our styling exclusively to components, which gives us a huge advantage
of never, ever even having to worry about these issues ever again, with stars clashing between components.
In order to get started with star components, we need to install the library.
So here we are back in our terminal where we're going to install star components now.
Style components, which is the name of the library, is really just one flavor, of course, in jazz.
It's arguably the most popular format.
There's actually another one called emotion style, but that has arguably almost the exact same structure
as style components.
If you learn style components, you've learned emotion.
The main thing about the difference between the two is which one came first and a couple much more significantly
nuanced points that are important for our learning right now.
It's not components is most arguably by and far the most common in jazz library that you'll come across
in your React development.
So it's important that I teach you this specific library.
So here inside of our project, what I want to do is I want to replace all of our current SAS styling
with style components, and I'm going to walk you through the basics, as well as some of the more advanced
usages and architecture patterns that can emerge through the usage of style components.
One of the other big advantages that we get is that because we're doing it at this point where we have
so many components newly styled, it's very easy to get a lot of practice which you'll definitely get
to do.
Once we learn some of these basics, so where I want to start is the navigation component.
In order for us to transform a sandbar into style components, the first thing we need to do is actually
switch it from SAS over to Jess.
You can do GSX, you can do Jess.
It's really up to you.
Personally, I prefer GSX, even though really what we're writing is Jess, but you'll see why.
Sometimes Jess is more important here.
What's happening is that because we've converted this over, these rules no longer apply because this
is SAS.
In order to use the library, though, it all comes from this styled keyword that exports from style
components.
What this stock report allows us to do is generate components, so here I'm going to go, Hey, I want
to make a navigation container, which is the div component that this dot navigation was, if you remember
inside of our navigation component.
This Dave was really the one with the class name of navigation.
So our styling was targeting the navigation class name, but now we want to make a new component for
it.
And the component gets built by saying I want to call style and OnStar.
There's a method called Div, and this div will give us back a div that we can then apply styles to
using these back text right after.
Inside of these back text is where we're going to insert our style code so we can actually directly
just cut this right out and place this inside.
This is considered valid style components.
So before we do anything else, I'm just going to comment this out and show you how you use this.
So once you generate this, you actually do need to export this out as well.
So let's export our navigation container.
Let's copy this and let's comment out this, actually.
No, we're going to leverage this because what we need to do is import directly from our note navigation
styles file.
We don't need the touch ASX.
Here with navigation container, what you can now do is actually comments out all of this code because
there's a couple of things I want to show you before we even do any of this.
What you'll do is replace the div right here with this new navigation container.
If we save this, of course, are now bar is going to be empty.
But once you go into your application, what you'll see is that it's technically still there as a component.
Now, when you inspect it, this div right here is our style component, we see all of the styling that
we added.
But notice how this says Egg KP Oh, this is a uniquely generated class name.
This style gets generated on builds so that when we are working with our style components, there are
no clashes that will happen because style components will ensure that every one of these components
that we write now has a unique class name.
And this way, the styling is also going to be locked in to that class.
So by doing this now, we can really be sure that there will be no overlap in our styling with one another.
So this is the thing that really gives us this big benefit.
Let's unstyled this or uncomment this code.
Sorry and continue styling.
Next year, we need this logo container.
So another great advantage is that you don't have to just leverage this div or dot span or DP, usually
on style.
It comes with all of the different HTML based elements that you're used to using, like top button dot
span.
As I mentioned, paragraph H1, H2, H3, they're all here, but let's say you want to see style over
an existing component.
You can do that by using brackets.
So first, let's import Link from React router Dom.
And now, in order to use it, all we need to do is copy the component, come down here and create a
new component.
So I want to call this one logo container.
So you're naming convention follows exactly how you name a React component, because that's what they
are.
They really are just components.
And here, I'm going to say styled.
And then in order to use the link, I'm going to say bracket link.
I'm going to pass the link into styled like this.
And now I can add these back techs and once again insert the styling that's relevant.
So here I'm just going to copy and paste this over and get rid of that.
And now we have our logo container component.
So let's continue.
We still have a nav link as well as nav links container.
So here nav links container.
This is a div.
If you remember coming back to our navigation component, you'll have to keep going back and forth.
Natalie's container is a div that contains all of the links on our right hand side.
So here what I'm going to do is I'm going to create export content, navigation or nav links container
like this.
And this is going to be a style divide.
And then I'm going to paste this in.
So actually, according to our naming convention, once we're inside, I don't even need to name this
container.
Now I can just call this now links like this.
Similarly, the internal actual nav links I'm going to explore a new component called NAV Link, which
is a styled link component that will contain the code that makes them navigation links.
And now let's just get rid of this coat.
Let's save this and I'll show you how to use them.
So what we need to do is import the remaining lower container nav links and nav link.
So here, let's import in.
We need our Navy links container.
For now, links, we need nav link and then finally, we need the logo container.
So what we do now is we just replace the corresponding elements, so here.
Logo container.
Up to the class name, because we don't need that anymore can now be replaced.
Like so now links can replace this div.
Like so.
Now, remember, you still want to keep your methods, what will happen is that even though this is
a logo container, it will forward all these props over to the underlying link component.
So this will still behave like a link component.
Inside here, our link is now enabling.
So for these links.
This will continue to work.
For both these links that have a to property, because these are actually link components.
But now you might be wondering, well, you are with the benefit of using the class name, we could
apply the styling, but now aren't we look to specifically whatever component it is that we generated,
you would be correct here.
However, style components has actually given us unique props that can fit into any generated component
using styled meaning that because we built this nav link component ourselves using the styled library,
what this now allows us to do is actually give it an as keyword and as allows us to pass a string of
what component or base HTML element.
We want this to be rendered us.
So here we want it to be rendered as a span, not as a link.
And if we save this now and we go to our application, what we'll see is that everything is working.
All our styling is the same.
But notice how inside of this component right here again, you see all these uniquely generated classes.
Now, of course, these two are the same because they're both nav links.
But let's say that we sign in right here, Mike at Gmail.
I want to sign in.
But notice now that the sign out is indeed a span, so it's smart enough to be able to know, Oh, you
want this as a span, I'm going to give it to you instead and change the underlying component to the
corresponding element you want.
Extremely powerful.
So this is one of the beautiful things that we get now with style components.
But the main thing again is that now all of these components will uniquely generate class names that
we can now leverage in order to properly protect ourselves from having any style clashes.
Now that we have this, what I want you to do is start going through all of the components and just
start restyling them in the next video, I'm going to talk about one of the emerging patterns we can
do by adding stock components to our buttons.
So do everything but the buttons.
And in the next video, I'll show you how we can do buttons and a new pattern that emerges through stock
components.