OK, everyone, let's continue with modifying our application to be more mobile responsive, so the
next thing I want to update is our header component.
So our header right now is not optimized for the mobile view, so inside of our hairstyles, I'm just
going to modify the actual width and height to be a little bit more aligned with the actual browser
view inside of a mobile device.
Now, inside of this heter container, we are going to just paste in that same media query that we had
before.
Because we're using the same media query in any of our mobile style changes, so here what I'm going
to do is I'm going to write it so that what I want to set in terms of the actual header container is
I want to shrink the height to 60 pixels instead of 70 pixels, just literally shaving off 10 pixels
here.
I want to make sure that there's some padding all around the header of 10 pixels, and then I'm going
to have a margin bottom of 20 pixels so that we push the content down with our new header.
So with that, we need to now modify the actual size of the components inside of the header, but the
header is shaped more like how I want it to be.
Now, inside of the actual logo container, I am going to add in this media query again, and what I
want to change is I want the width of this logo to be way smaller.
So I only want it to be 50 pixels.
And then I don't want any padding anymore.
I just want a padding of zero.
So now if we go back and we see we see that our logo is more aligned with where we want it to be inside
of this header now.
I also want to make sure that the options container, so that section containing the option links we
have that navigate us to different Web pages.
I want to make sure that that is now taking up more of the space of the header than before.
Before it only took up 50 percent of the total width of the header because with so much real estate
space with a Web view, instead I'm going to do a width of 80 percent.
Because the only other thing on this browser page, when we're in this mobile view or in any of you,
in fact, is just the logo.
So now with this with this way, we have way more space.
As we can see.
In fact, everything still works, which is really great for us.
We just need to make sure to update our views, like our homepage, to also be responsive.
Now, what it is that I want to change is I want the menu item to fit in a nicer way.
So what we can do is go into our menu item styles.
And modify them so that they have a similar media query and then render a different shape on the actual
menu item container.
So as you remember, we set the height based on this size property, which does dictate to it how big
it should be based on which image it is.
Because when you remember inside of our Web view, the men and women sections are larger than the three
other sections that we have.
Now, what we want to do here is we want to actually modify this height value so that it stays pretty
consistent regardless of size.
So what we can do is at the end, append our media screen query and what we'll just say is simply height,
two hundred pixels.
Now, media queries have a higher specificity than anything else inside of our styles.
So no matter what styles inside of this here, the media query, if it has the same style, will always
overwrite the styles here because media queries always have a higher specificity order than regular
selectors.
So now if we go back, we'll see that our elements are aligned much better because the heights are statically
two hundred pixels and the widths will always adjust.
So the screen will try and fit these elements on the page in the right order that they have access to.
And then the moment that a new one starts on a new page, it fills the remaining space.
But the height is always set to a specific static two hundred pixels.
So with that, we now have a mobile view.
Now our home page is set up, the next thing that we need to modify is our shot page.
Our shop page is going to be a little bit more complicated because our shop page, it doesn't look terrible.
We have these elements.
But the problem with this is that this item you have to actually click it in order to see the add to
cart, which you'd then have to click instead with a mobile view.
This button seems too small in order to just put here the style and the actual design needs it to be
a little bit more deliberate in how we can actually add items because we want our users to be able to
add items as easily as possible.
So what we're going to modify is both the collection preview as well as our actual collection item.
So let's go back to our application code.
And what we need to do is go to the collection item styles.
Now, I do think actually I have a slight typo in our collection item here.
I accidentally put collection styles.
Dot styles such as this should actually be a collection item that style.
Such as?
So if we make that modification, we also have to make sure that we update it here now, mine automatically
updated it for me because my vote code is intelligent like that.
If yours is not, you just got to make sure to modify the place where you imported all of these components
in so that it's pointing to the right route.
Just a little typo, right?
These things happen to everybody.
So inside of our collection items, styles, what we're going to do is we are going to go into this
collection item container and we are going to modify how large this width will be.
Based on.
The actual mobile view, so inside of here, I want the width to be 40 view with meaning that it takes
up 40 percent of the total width of the full view.
Then I need to overwrite some of these hover features because these hover features I don't want inside
of my mobile view with our mobile view.
I don't care about the hover.
You don't actually hover that much with touch as you're used to it.
The mobile.
So what I'm going to say is that the image just unset, the opacity unset pretty much says that this
was never set in the first place.
So there's actually no image styles.
Here on the hover effect of the image when you're inside of this medium sized.
For any buttons in here, I also want to unset the opacity as well.
So now if we go back to our application.
OK, we'll see that we're looking at the wrong file.
This is probably because we didn't save this file, so once my visa code actually updated this route,
it didn't actually manually save the file for me.
So I had to manually make that save.
And now here we'll see.
This looks a little bit more tightly coupled because the width is larger.
The only reason it's still stacking like this is because we need to update our actual collection preview
view.
So what we'll do here is we will go to our collections preview.
Styles and inside of the preview container, we need to write our media query, so let's copy back our
old media query here.
And inside, we are going to say that I want this now to have a.
A line items property.
So this allows us to have everything centered.
Whenever our content is inside of this display, Fleck's.
Now, I know that this is a lot of success that we haven't touched upon before, if you're unfamiliar
with success, this might be completely new to you.
Honestly, this case is pretty extensive in terms of what rules there are, I'm going to link the flex
box ruling documentation for you.
It's actually an amazing resource to read through because it's really a matter of where the more you
practice with, the more that you'll see.
It's really comprehensive and it's difficult for me to cover inside of a course on reac because I'll
have to spend so much time on actual CSFs things.
So if this gets confusing for you at any point, I will definitely include a version of our application
where everything is converted to be mobile friendly for you.
Otherwise you can pause the video and read up on some of these styling rules.
If my explanations are not fully clear and you don't have the full context of everything, but it's
really just a matter of doing this on your own with practice, right?
So one of the other things that we have to do after we did this, a line items, is we need to modify
our preview container as well so that instead of being a display flex, what it will be is a display
grid.
Now, this is a new feature that I will also link the documentation for.
And this is another version of Display Flex.
We've actually used display grid before inside of our application, and it literally just lets us place
elements inside of whatever this top level component is in a grid like shape.
So here I'm going to say grid template is always going to just have columns where it's one F.R., whatever.
If you remember from that lesson on grids really quickly, one half hour just means whatever space is
remaining inside of this screen, meaning that there will always be essentially columns.
And the two columns here will each take up one full portion of the application, which means that they
are equally 50 percent of what space is available inside of this preview container.
And then I also want a grid gap of 15 pixel.
So grid gap is pretty much just.
The spacing between these elements, so with this now.
We see that our application looks more like that grid I was telling you about, right, there's always
two columns and they always take up one F.R. of space.
They're also 40 of you within size.
And there's a 15 pixel gap in between all of these items.
So now our application looks way closer to what we need it to be.
Now, the only thing missing is our actual button, so what we're going to do is we're going to go back
to our collection item styles and we're going to modify the button itself so that the button is always
displayed whenever we're in a mobile view.
We're going to say that the display is block instead of display none, so block is the default you can
do block or inline block.
We're going to make sure that the opacity is zero point nine.
We're also going to set a Menwith value where we unset it, the reason why we have to unset it, even
though it's not here, is because the button leverages custom button and custom button is a custom button
container with a Menwith of one hundred and sixty five pixel.
But that's too big for mobile view.
That's pretty much half our screen, so we just want to unset it.
And we also want to modify the padding so that what it'll do is it'll set a top value of zero 10 pixels
on the right, zero on the bottom, and then 10 pixels on the left.
So this way, we're getting zero 10 pixels, zero 10 pixels, in fact, you don't even need this.
This syntax is also the same way.
We just put two values for padding it, saying zero for top bottom 10 pixels.
Left, right.
And now if we save this.
We'll actually see that our button is always present, if we click this, we'll see that it still works.
Our items are being added to our check checkout.
Our collection preview is pretty close to what we actually want it to look like.
Now, at this point, I definitely encourage you to take a crack at trying to modify the styles for
the rest of this yourself.
It's a good exercise to maybe work on some success that we haven't really touched upon too much of in
this course, because this is a Riak horse.
Once you've played around with the stars, you can always check back to the GitHub for what it is that
we have done.
Now, I will also include a GitHub link of everything we've done up until this point right now.
So you have something to reference against.
But just like with all the other exercises that we did, this is a great chance to take some time of
your own to play around with some styling.
So good luck with that and always refer to the completed version and see how your styles match up to
mine again, mine is just my own attempt at the solution, right?
It's totally up to you how you want your application to look in a mobile view.
So with that, good luck with the exercise and I'll see you in the next lesson.