Welcome back, everyone.
So let's leverage our start success and fail option types inside of our category actions.
So what we need to do is we need to first create these three new actions.
So, first of all, one is going to be fetch categories start.
And as you guessed it, this is just going to be the action, of course, that tells our application
or rather our reading store that we are starting to fetch categories here.
What we're going to do is create an action and all we need to give it is the fact that this has the
type start.
There is no payload required.
Our reducer already knows that the moment we see this action, all we're going to do set loading to.
True.
That's all it is.
Nothing else.
So here that is our start action.
The next ones we need are going to be success and failure.
So let's define success first.
So here inside of success, this is pretty much going to be what we had here, except instead of categories,
we are triggering this action as the success action.
Similarly, the payload that we're going to pass to it is going to be the categories array, which is
what we want to send through.
Next.
What we need is fetch categories failed.
So if each category is failed, of course, we'll call the correct.
And then we're also going to pass error as the payload.
And now we have our three methods.
What we need to do is we need to now figure out how to create the thunk action that will trigger the
correspondingly correct actions.
So these three are synchronous and they're not even.
They're just regular actions.
A thunk is going to be a action that we say specifically fetched categories.
Async like this.
I like to call them async.
In fact, Redux also recommends that you declare your thunk actions with that last word async so that
we can look at this action creator function and know that it is indeed something that is asynchronous
and a thunk.
So as I mentioned, it's just a function that returns, a function that gets a dispatch.
This function can in fact be a async function, which is what we're going to use, because with this
async function, what we want to do is we want to be able to determine how we are fetching these categories,
what to do when it succeeds, and what to do when it fails.
Currently, we have this functionality inside of our shop component.
This is all we actually really need because this dispatch, instead of happening here now, we're going
to do it inside.
So first, let's bring in our get categories and documents.
And now what we're going to do is we are going to wrap this entire function inside of a tri catch block.
Because what we're saying is that, hey, I want you to try and run this asynchronous method.
If at any point inside it throws an error, which it will.
If are a wait call on get docs for some reason fails, then this async function is going to throw an
error which we will then catch.
So here this is pretty much our basic format to begin with.
The first thing that we're going to do is we are going to dispatch the fact that we started fetching
the categories.
So we're going to dispatch calling our action creator.
That's category start.
And then what happens is that inside, if we succeed from this awake call, then what we're going to
do is say fetch categories, success, and here what we're going to pass to it is the actual categories
array.
And then, of course, if we have an error, we will dispatch our fetch categories failed and pass the
error through.
I also forgot to wrap this in a dispatch as well.
So this is our new asynchronous function.
This is our thank.
So what I want to do is use this inside of the shop component.
So instead of calling set categories, I'm going to say fetch categories async.
And we're, of course, still going to dispatch this as our action crater.
But now we don't need this anymore.
In fact, this function isn't even asynchronous anymore.
It's just a regular dispatch that triggers the moment this component mounts.
And now if I save this.
Now, if we come back to our application here, we very clearly see that our action is being logged.
Now, of course, this is redux longer.
So there is no type to define because it's just a function.
So here, though, what we see is we are indeed dispatching this asynchronous action as a function.
And then further down we see, oh, there's our fetch category start.
And then right here, down here we see fetch category success payload is indeed are categories, items,
and then we see our categories gets updated with the correct array.
So this flow is the way that we now have hooked into our actual redux flow with a thunk.
And what we've really done is we have essentially moved out the synchronous and loading code into a
thunk instead.
This means that all of this asynchronous behavior of fetching is all handled by Redux now, because
through this thunk now, this shop component does not have any need to understand or maintain and balance
any async, await actions or any of the actual asynchronous coordination.
All of that is now just driven by an event.
All our component nodes.
Is that the moment I start, I'm just going to dispatch an event to say, Hey, start fetching something.
Whether or not it succeeds or fails is not governed by our actual component anymore.
That now all lives inside of this middleware, which is a very clean separation of logic, it allows
us to get even more granular an individual contribution of each of these different functions.
Now, because now this responsibility is no longer up to our component.
Our component simply consumes data and shows data here now inside of Redux is how we actually fetch
that data.
And this is why there's a very popular move towards bringing in a asynchronous Redux library like Redux.
Thunk When you get to a point where you want this action driven architecture and you want to separate
out this asynchronous behavior, it typically happens when your project scale is quite large and you
have a lot of asynchronous behavior happening in your application, and this is what we've just done.
We have moved out that category, fetching into this action creator.
So now that we've done this, the next thing we need to do is figure out how we can leverage the loading
value that is inside of our category reducer to make our code a little bit more user friendly.
So that's what we'll do in the next video.
So I'll see you there.