Hello, everyone, and welcome to this lesson on building a blog Web site with Gatsby.
My name is Iowa and I'm one of the instructors alongside Andre that teaches the Riak course from zero
to mastery.
Now, in this lesson, I am going to talk about Gatsby and how we can leverage Gatsby in order to build
a blog website.
Now, before we continue, I do want to note that this lesson assumes that you know the basics of react
and graphics.
Well, we also make the assumption that you understand some of the caveats behind some of the libraries
in the reactor ecosystem, such as react router.
If you are unfamiliar with this, we do teach us in the course.
Otherwise you may have to become more familiar with these concepts before proceeding with this lesson.
You can definitely watch this lesson still, but you might not be able to understand all of the code
that will end up writing inside of this section.
Now, if that is not a problem for you, then let's take a deep dive into what Gatsby is in the first
place.
So, as I mentioned, Gatsby is a framework that is written in react.
It's a framework that has already combined together some of the best react ecosystem libraries into
one bundle and as an opinionated way about how you should use it in order to build a static website,
in order for us to actually understand when we should use something like Gatsby, we have to understand
some of the competing technologies that you've definitely at least used or heard about.
So let's take a look at this image.
Let us go over one high level concept in react so we know that React is a front end based UI rendering
library.
We write code, which is a combination of JavaScript and JSM, in order for us to compile that code
that we've written and react down into Jackson HTML using a loader like Web pack as well as a trans
pilot like Babille.
Now those files are the files that any webpage that our browser loads consumes in order to build such
a web page.
So when we build our websites and react, we might be writing Riak code, but there is some compile
step along the way that builds them into JavaScript, CSFs and HTML files that our browser is able to
consume.
Now, keeping this in mind, let's take a breakdown of three technologies that we see in the react ecosystem
that try and solve the problem of how you develop react applications.
Now, those are Gatsby Create React App.
And next Shabaz.
Now you've definitely heard of Create React app and you've definitely used it.
If you've taken this course, create react app is a very quick way for you to start up a react application
and it leverages what is called client side rendering.
Now, what client side rendering means is that it leverages the browser in order to build out the HTML
that gets served whenever a user navigates to any page on your react application.
So if you were to see this browser here, when the user navigates to the home route and then loads up
the home component, what happens is that the code that we've written is built and passed to that user's
browser engine.
Now that engine will end up being the one that actually generates the HTML required for that home page
and then loads it up onto the browser.
The same thing happens whenever they navigate to any other route, such as collections, but the main
idea here is that the browser engine is the thing that is generating the HTML pages that the browser
needs to load related to our REACT application.
Everything is rendered on the client side, so on the browser now racked up is a great tool when you
want to build a really dynamic website in react, but you don't have a lot of static images that come
by default with the actual application or a lot of really deeply nested and really complex logic that
ends up building your pages.
Now, when you do have a website that is performing slowly and can exceed the amount of power that our
browser engine has, then you want to use something like next, James.
Now, if you've never heard of NexGen, it is a framework that allows you to write, react and leverage.
Server side rendering, server side rendering is almost the exact same conceptually as client side rendering.
Except instead of letting the client or the browser engine be the actual thing that ends up compiling
and generating the HTML code for our browser routes.
Whenever our users navigate to any of our pages, we let the backend server build and generate the HTML
files that the user needs in order to view the home root, the collections route or any route for that
matter.
So whenever the user navigates to another route, for example, like our home, then this will communicate
to our backend servers that they need the HTML related to home.
So the server will start to generate using our react code, the actual HTML required.
And this is way more robust because our back and server is more powerful and it's capable of generating
it really quickly compared to our browser.
So you want to use next Jass when you need to build a really robust and large website that might end
up having really complex logic to build out your views.
Now, the main thing here to remember, though, is that next shapes and create react app are both dynamically
generated, meaning that we directly generate the HTML whenever the browser navigates two different
routes.
So this is all live generated, whereas something like Gatsby is what's called a static generated website.
So what this means is that all of the code that builds to the HTML pages that end up comprising our
application is all done at the build step.
So similar to when we run, build with create react app.
When we push our Gatsby code up to a server or up to a hosting platform of some kind, they will run
the build script, which will automatically generate all of the static HTML that our browsers end up
using in order to display the views, which means that none of this code is generated dynamically.
It's all generated way ahead of time when you push your code up onto your server.
So this is the main difference with Gatsby.
So it's really good when you want to build static websites that generally don't need to dynamically
change the views that often by doing so.
This is actually exactly what we need for a blog website where much of the actual content is already
predetermined.
It's already written.
So all we want to do is just display a bunch of blog posts and navigate between them.
And Gatsby is the perfect solution for that.
So in the next lesson, I'm going to teach you how we can get started with Gatsby.
So I'll see you in the next lesson.