Hey there, it's is my face.
I'm usually sitting in front of a computer, not in front of a camera, which I'm not comfortable with,
but this is the Army video, and I want to just absolutely thank all of you because we have officially
had one hundred thousand unique students, which is insane.
Absolutely mind blowing.
I did an AMA video when we hit a thousand students and I thought that was just extraordinary.
And to be at one hundred thousand now is absolutely incredible.
I feel extremely lucky.
I feel extremely blessed.
And not to get too sappy here, but I'm very, very thankful for you watching this video right now because
I don't really do any marketing.
And it's it's all grown out of word of mouth.
So thank you for telling your friends, your family, your kids, whatever it is.
I am extremely thankful that I get to do what I do.
And it's all because of you.
All right.
So no more sappiness.
Let's get to it.
I asked you on Dischord some questions that you might have for me.
There were a lot of questions.
Unfortunately, I won't be able to answer all of them.
I don't want to make this into a boring one hour video.
So I pick the ones that I thought had a lot of people interested in them.
And hopefully I can give you some some answers.
Keep in mind that you should form your own opinions and decisions based on this.
This is just one person's view.
My view.
It doesn't mean that I'm 100 percent correct.
If I thought that, then I would have a YouTube channel.
But take it with a grain of salt.
These are just my opinions.
I may be wrong.
I may be right is just what has worked in my life doesn't necessarily mean that it will work for you
or the answers are right for you.
All right.
The first one here, we have Nick Salaat who asks, what's the best way to get into machine learning
and artificial intelligence?
That's actually a question that kept coming up.
A lot of people are interested in machine learning, data science, anything related to A because it
is extremely popular and a hot topic right now.
I actually have a course coming up on it that that tries to tackle that question because machine learning
right now, it's a bit of a buzzword where it it solves all your business problems when in fact, maybe
it's not necessarily so.
And I think there's developer interest to learn about machine learning, as well as business analysts
and business decision makers to use machine learning and data to improve their profits and their business.
So I don't really give you an answer for that one, but it's one of those topics that I think in order
to learn about it, you should at least learn to code be become a web developer force or perhaps have
some understanding of business data data analysis before you get into it.
All right.
Next, the next question is from N.K. Talk about your life as a developer from start until now to learn
from you.
Well, I think some of you know, from my previous anime, I did not come from a computer science background.
I came from a business background.
I did also a minor in psychology and learned to code in my twenties.
I'm thirty three now, by the way.
Hopefully I don't look thirty three, but that's that's my age.
And yeah, I would break down the developer lifecycle into three phases.
So the first one is where you're just learning, you're learning to code.
Everything is completely new.
You feel extremely overwhelmed, overwhelmed.
You don't know what to learn, what person to trust, what mentor to have, what course to take.
That's a really big challenge.
And getting to the point of understanding and being able to build something from scratch yourself.
I think that's the first phase.
The second phase was when when I was employed for the first time and the first couple of years working
as a developer where you feel the imposter syndrome, where you feel like you just don't know enough,
or somehow they hired you by mistake.
And while everybody else around you is smarter than you, that phase really goes by.
The one advice that I have for that phase is to honestly be comfortable with being uncomfortable.
That is, ask as many questions as you want.
Don't feel like you're raising your hand and asking question.
It's going to make you feel it's going to make others look at you like you're dumb or not good enough.
The more questions you ask, the better you'll have the answers and you'll find that the successful
people through this phase are the people who ask a ton of questions.
When they don't understand something, they try to learn and try to grab as much experience as possible
from those around you.
And then the third phase is when you start to become a little bit of a senior developer, when you start
to get confident.
Your abilities, you perhaps start to lead projects, perhaps other junior developers look up to you
and ask you questions.
One of the biggest things with that face of a developer is to not almost get a God complex where you
feel like your opinions are the right ones and everybody else's is absolutely wrong.
I've seen way too many really good developers get overconfident in themselves and have really strong
opinions where they don't take anything else into consideration.
I think through that phase, if you're able to understand everything, it has pros and cons, everything
depends on the situation.
And that you're not only used graphics.
Oh, I only use typescript.
And dynamic languages are trash when you avoid those strong opinions to almost make yourself feel like
you're smart, you're doing something wrong there.
You want to be open to ideas, open to suggestions, and not forget to keep growing from that phase,
because as you start to get more and more recognition, maybe feel more confident, it's very easy to
think that you've reached the pinnacle and you need to stop learning.
This whole industry is all about learning and constantly evolving.
And what, you know, two years from now will probably be different than what you know.
So those are the three phases, kind of the ones that I went through.
Obviously, I'm teaching now, but for me, learning doesn't stop.
I'm constantly learning.
I'm constantly trying to improve myself, both in teaching, but also as a developer.
And I hope that that is the case with you as well.
All right.
Next question.
Next question is from S.G. How many countries have you visited during the last year?
Any suggestions to travel while working remote?
So for some of you that don't know, I, I work completely remote.
I carry my recorded recording equipment online and I set up my studio wherever I am in the world.
So my courses have been recorded in in Ecuador, in Nicaragua, Colombia and Greece and Romania.
Pretty much anywhere that I'm traveling, I bring my recording equipment, set up my little studio and
and record.
So last year I traveled to, I would say, about seven or eight countries where I lived.
And then in then long term, my favorite was I actually recorded The Master, the coding interview course
in a little house on the side of a volcano in Ecuador, where the last house at the very top of the
volcano.
So we had to hike down and grab groceries every time we needed to eat or wanted to cook dinner and hike
back up with all our groceries.
That was a lot of fun.
Any advice for remote?
Honestly, if it's one of those lifestyles that it sounds nice, but it also requires a lot of dedication
and and commitment to to work instead of just not being committed to a schedule and making it really
easy to go off and pretend like you're busy without actually accomplishing anything.
So you do need to have a bit of structure.
But for those that are self-motivated and determined enough and can keep track of tasks and don't get
distracted, often, it's it's definitely a lot of fun.
All right.
This next question, I think I got asked maybe five times from people like Durjan, supah scrammed block,
all of them essentially said, why did you quit your full time job?
How come you're not a developer anymore?
Well, let's say that I'm still a developer.
I do a bit of consulting work on the side.
The reason that I quit my developer job was mainly because I wanted to I wanted to travel a little bit
and take a break.
I had spent a couple of years working for other people and working on projects that perhaps I didn't
care too much about.
I was working for other people's passion projects or businesses.
And after a while that that kind of gets old, or at least it did for me, where I found that I stopped
learning as much.
It was just repeating and doing the same thing over and over.
So I decided to quit and kind of figure out what what I want to do next.
And along the way, I decided to record some videos, my first course to mastery, to just keep myself
busy and keep doing something and and help people who were like me, where they didn't have a background
and wanted to get into web development, but there wasn't a clear path for them to do so.
So I recorded that course and it took off and all of a sudden this became my full time job and now I
would one hundred percent still go back to being a full time developer.
But I'm having so much fun teaching.
I still get to code every day.
I still get to learn every day.
And if anything, I think this way have a bigger impact on on people's lives than.
I did when I worked on a single project, so that's why I quit my job and at the end of the day, it
was one of the best decisions I ever made.
I have another question here, which is, what is my biggest regret?
I feel like I'm in an interview right now, so I'll give you my interview answer in case you ever get
asked this in an interview.
So my biggest regret, honestly, it's there's nothing I'm really, really happy that I learn coding
when I did in my 20s and not when I was young, because when I was young, I was able to learn different
skills.
I was able to learn about business, about about psychology, about communicating with others and people.
And those skills helped me get my first job as a developer, although maybe I started to code when I
was a lot later on in life.
It's not like I didn't do anything before my 20s.
I was learning different skills.
And for those people that perhaps are thinking, am I too old to learn to code?
Or I'm in my thirties and there's people, you know, in their teens that are learning to code right
now, there's no way that I'm going to be able to keep up, keep in mind that most likely have skill
sets that other people don't.
And when it comes to regret, honestly, there's nothing.
As long as you're learning every single day and learning something useful over the years that's going
to compound.
And honestly, every single mistake, every single decision that you make leads you to to where you
are now, which sounds a little hokey pokey.
But but it is true, honestly, the there are no regrets if you're learning, you're never going to
have regrets in life.
All right.
I'm just gonna ask me, what annoyed you the most about being a developer?
I usually don't get annoyed.
I'm pretty easy going.
But the one thing that I did notice was that as people get more and more experienced, they tend to
form really strong opinions and everybody wants to feel like they're part of a group.
And I think we see that a lot on Twitter and YouTube and all these people, really strong opinions that
kind of gang up on other people that have different beliefs than them.
I think it's very easy in the developer community to have something like that where you're thinking,
my react team is better than your angular team or typescript and static typing is the way to go or rest
is dead.
And let's all use graphics.
Well, I think when you have that type of mentality, it's it's really, really hard to actually have
smart discussions and and and decisions within a project and becomes really, really easy for those
who feel superior to others and feel confident in their opinions to really impose their opinions on
others, especially junior developers that, you know, are susceptible and have less experience.
So they start to believe these senior developers that perhaps have really strong opinions.
And in turn, that kind of creates this wave of more and more people that think it's a good idea to
have strong opinions and debate with others and argue with others and and telling people that their
code stocks and their code is the right way of doing it.
I think that was a little bit annoying to deal with because because I think it influences junior developers
a lot.
And I don't think it's a good attitude to have when working with others.
I think being a being somebody senior, being a lead, being a project lead means you're a person that
doesn't put other people down, but it lifts others.
And that was a little bit annoying because I thought that I saw that that was a little bit prevalent
where everybody's trying to almost appease each other and be a better developer than though this person
and this person, instead of all of you growing together and learning together because there's enough
developer jobs for everybody, you don't need to beat out everybody to be the number one developer.
So that mentality was I was a little bit annoying to me.
But then again, I worked in Toronto and Silicon Valley, and I think those areas especially have have
really, really strong, individualistic philosophies.
All right.
This is another question from from where and how did you learn and become a developer?
So when I started to learn to be a developer, I probably spent, I would say twenty dollars.
I think I bought a book on HTML and access and the rest was all online for free, just using online
resources.
The only difference was that when I started to learn there were very few resources online.
I think I used one blog post that that told me to use Photoshop and -- and and some tools that actually
didn't even need.
But it was really hard to find resources online when I started to learn.
So I essentially just try to grab as many resources as possible and create my own curriculum.
But it's not like it is now, I think right now we have a lot of resources online, it's a lot easier
and there's more of a clear cut path to become a web developer.
So I'm a little bit jealous.
But I also did the same thing that you probably are doing, which is watch a lot of online courses,
read a lot of books, read a lot of articles, and most importantly, building my own projects and coding
as much as possible.
But nothing beats actually coding.
You can watch videos all day, but if you're not doing anything, if you're not producing anything,
that's not.
It's like watching a tennis match and trying to become a better tennis player.
It's just not going to happen.
We have a Jamie who asks, what's the best way you could practice code?
Is it good for him?
Is it good by imitating someone else code for practicing again?
Goes back to my last point.
The best way to practice code is to code.
The the more you code, the more you practice, the better it is.
But keep in mind that the best way to code is to solve your own problems, create your own projects.
I actually don't recommend just watching all my videos and following along without coding because then
you're not going to be able to do things on your own.
The best way to code is to code by by doing your own thing.
You can watch a hundred videos on people coding and follow along.
But if you don't understand why we're doing things, then when you're left to your own device, you're
not going to be able to do anything.
So the best way to code is think of a project today.
Think of a task that you have to do over and over in your life and see if you can automated with code.
That's the best way to to learn.
Kailin, what you ask?
What is your favorite text stack?
My favorite test tech stack is the one that lets me accomplish my goal as fast as possible.
That's a very vague answer.
But honestly, anything that lets me finish fast and deliver something fast is my favorite textbook
because I tend to work by myself or in small teams.
I really prefer things that are efficient.
So, for example, I'm not a big fan of TypeScript because although you get type safety and static typing,
it's a lot of extra code.
It's the same reason that I personally am not a big fan of Java programming, not because it's not a
great language, but because for my personal use cases, I'm not working at a big company with thousands
of developers for, let's say, a financial institution.
If I'm building a personal project, I'd rather use something quick and easy, like Python or JavaScript,
to write a few lines of code and accomplish a goal.
So there's really no favorite text that the stack that allows me to accomplish the goal the fastest,
which happens to be usually dynamically typed languages and usually the languages that I'm comfortable
with, I don't need to learn something new until I have a need to to learn something.
All right.
Moralez Junior s Moralez Junior.
That's what it is.
Any advice on escaping the golden handcuffs and going freelance?
I have a cushy non developer job at Google and it's hard to imagine leaving when a family and a mortgage.
But I long for freedom.
And this this topic of freelancer is another topic that has come up many, many times.
So let me address it right now.
I, I get to work remotely.
I get to work for myself, which I feel very fortunate, fortunate about, and I'm extremely lucky.
But when it comes to freelancing, I actually am against freelancing.
Obviously every situation is different.
But let me explain why I think freelancing might not be the best option for most of you.
Not all of you, but for most of you.
You see, when it comes to freelancing, let's say you are just starting to learn.
You're just learning to cope.
If you go straight into freelancing, you lose the ability to work with others, to learn from others
and actually be in a company and understand how their processes work, how they work with developers.
You gain a lot of experience by working on projects with others, with other developers, working with
management teams, working with with project managers, scrum masters.
That's a really, really valuable experience that I really recommend for people just getting into coding.
Now, let's say that you've had a couple of years of experience.
You've worked with teams, you have that experience.
Should you go into freelancing?
I think you should go into freelancing.
If you have a clear edge or a clear advantage over others.
For example, you have an existing client base and you have people that really trust your work or you
offer a really unique skill.
The problem with freelancing right now is that you're essentially battling with thousands, potentially
millions of other freelancers to get a job.
A lot of people might go to places like uptalk or any type of place where you can bid on projects.
What happens is in those scenarios, people just bid and it's a battle to lower and lower prices.
So what happens?
You eventually become an employee of a contract that you probably didn't charge enough for.
So it's really hard for you to compete with people that keep lowering and lowering and lowering prices.
And you'll see that if you're a freelancer, that's what will happen unless you have an established
client base, unless you have a really distinct advantage, maybe you're extremely skilled in graphic
design and you're well known, then, yes, maybe you can charge more for it.
But people that are usually looking for freelancers are usually looking for the cheapest price.
And when you do that, you stop valuing your time.
You stop being a slave to the person that created the contract and you're trying to fulfill somebody
you're trying to fulfill and please this person so that they give you a good review for the next contract
job.
I think freelancer jobs are can be good, but there's also a lot of issues that come with it if you
want to be a freelancer or perhaps be your own boss.
I think there's better ways for you to to go about it.
I think there's smarter ways to go about it instead of competing with others on price.
So I know that's not really helpful, is just my personal opinion when it comes to freelancing.
But it is a question that I get asked a lot.
Freelancing essentially involves you taking a lot of time finding clients, working a lot for clients.
And at the end of the day, why not just work for a company that already has the clients for you so
you can gain that experience?
You might think you have the freedom of being a freelancer, being your own job, but instead your you
are an employee of whoever your contractor is.
That's my advice.
I know it's not it's not very, very helpful.
But like I said, it's not for everybody.
I think there's there's better opportunities for you to work remotely.
You can work for remote companies.
There's tons of websites right now of showing companies that hire remote workers.
I think that's a better option for you than being a freelancer, because the reasons that I mentioned
previously, Jati Evars eight ask how is life as far as time spent with family and doing what you like
now as an instructor and before when you work for a company, do you enjoy work more now or before?
When you work for a company hands down?
I absolutely love what I'm doing now.
I wake up every day and all I can think about is, is work and what I'm going to teach or what video
I'm going to record or what coding challenge I'm going to do.
I am I feel so extremely lucky to be at a point in my life where I absolutely adore and love what I'm
doing.
And I wouldn't I wouldn't trade it for anything in the world.
Being a developer was absolutely great, working full time for a company.
I loved it and I had a lot of friends.
I got along really well with with my bosses, with my clients.
But having having the freedom to to work on what I want to work on my projects.
But most importantly, knowing that the work that I do maybe impacts just a little bit a little bit
of of the world, I think is a really rewarding feeling.
And I'm extremely thankful to to know that, you know, not everybody's going to love my courses, but
at least there are some that do enjoy my courses and gain a bit of help in their career through it.
And that is the most rewarding feeling.
And honestly, the past two years since I've started to teach have been some of the happiest moments
of my life.
And I know this thing isn't going to last forever.
I know I'm not going to teach forever, but I'm really appreciative of this moment to have this opportunity,
at least for now.
All right.
Mr. Luciferase asks a safe, secure and stable life, being a skillful employee, working for someone
else or dreaming big and starting a business on your own and being your own boss, what path do you
suggest?
Honestly, it really depends.
I think everybody wants the ideal work for yourself, own your own business, work remotely, live wherever
you want.
It sounds sexy, but it's it's not for everybody.
And, you know, I before I started teaching, before I was a developer, I started a bunch of businesses.
I was running, surfing, yoga, retreat in Nicaragua.
I was doing adventure tours.
I was doing adventurous businesses.
I was trying all these different things that in the end weren't extremely successful.
But there are a lot of fun and.
Meanwhile, I had friends who were doing their MBAs, there were becoming lawyers, and, you know,
they have really nice life right now.
They have to have families.
They're very comfortable.
And there's actually there's actually an advantage there as you start to work at a company and you see
people leave that company, most people think, oh, I should I should leave, too.
But you can also look at it as an opportunity for somebody else has left.
Now, you are one step closer to going up that that corporate or company ladder.
So I think it's not it's not one is better than the other.
It really depends on why you prefer what kind of lifestyle you prefer.
Do you want more of a stable, comfortable life to make sure that you can provide for your family?
Or are you at a stage in your life where you can perhaps take more risks and you're OK with the highs
ups in high high downs, high ups and downs that may pay off?
Not in the end, but I think every day if you're working towards what your ideal life should look like,
eventually you will get there.
But don't expect to get there overnight.
It's it's hard work.
Nothing comes easy.
There's no easy solution.
So all you can do is kind of work towards that goal and learn every day and improve every day and eventually
you'll get there.
But it really matters.
It's the best thing you can do is to have a plan for yourself and write down what you value.
And based on those values and what makes you happy, decide what type of path you want to take.
I got all philosophical there for you.
All right.
Let's get back to some coding.
Justin Hey.
Justin asks, How do you decide to learn next in this ever changing landscape?
From Braddock's graphic, you all react to angular view SSR.
There's so much to learn, so little time.
So I guess how do you decide what to learn then and how you actually learn to make time for it?
I think this is actually something I, I'm pretty good at or I think I'm good at.
And that is because when I started to learn how to code, I realized how much is out there.
I've become I've become really good at selecting only the right things to learn.
There's the famous Parado Principle which says the 20 percent usually accounts for 80 percent of value.
So what's the 20 percent that's going to give you 80 percent of a value in learning and things like
you all, for example?
They're extremely popular.
So a lot of people want to learn it.
But at the end of the day, how many how many people actually use graphical in production?
How many people have actually built something with graphics?
All that creates a value.
I like to look at technologies and see see what's what's hot and what's trending, but not necessarily
jump really deep into them until there's a clear need for me to learn it.
So, for example.
Yes, yeah, I know a bit of yes, but I want to call myself an expert because I haven't had to use
the you know, I can use react or I can use angular.
So being selective in why you learn instead of trying to learn everything is going to be better long
term strategy over the course of your career, because learning never stops and the more you learn,
the more you start to realize that it's not about the syntax, it's not about learning the libraries.
It's not about reading the documentation from start to finish.
It's about understanding the higher principles.
The why was this tool built?
Why are we doing things the way it is?
What problem is it solving?
Being able to understand those and discuss those is going to be really, really important because at
the end of the day, the fundamentals is is what matters, not the syntax.
If you learn the fundamentals, if you learn to think like a developer, think about systems and how
things communicate.
That's a lot more valuable than learning the newest react Hoke's API.
I mean, that could still be important.
But but as you can see, I'm very selective in what I learn.
And I'm not I'm not trying to learn ten languages at the same time.
If I want to learn something, I'll dedicate maybe a year to get a really, really good at something
and then move on to the next thing.
So really being picky, as if you're dating a new technology and making sure that it's the right one
is the way to go.
Oh, and with that said, you obviously have to enjoy what you're doing.
If you don't enjoy learning, then that's going to be really hard.
So that's just something that has to come for yourself and being able to enjoy the learning process,
because that's that's going to be your biggest asset.
If you enjoy learning, you're going to learn more.
Adrien asks, How long do you plan on continuing doing courses?
Because, well, this isn't going to last forever, right?
Honestly, I'm not sure I'm it's been close to two years now that I've been doing this.
I don't imagine doing this for for a lifetime.
There's only so much I could teach.
I'm going to keep going until I.
I stop enjoying it right now.
I really enjoyed the process.
I get a lot of reward by by hearing your your reviews and how pleased you are with the courses.
So that really drives me to create more.
But eventually I will have to stop.
I can't just keep creating courses.
They they do take a lot of time and effort.
So I hope that I can keep going for for a few more years.
But one day maybe you retire and and spend a little more time with family or move on to something else.
But for now, don't worry, I'm not going anywhere.
Balloon asks, Do you play any instruments?
No, I am the least musically talented, artistically talented person you'll ever be.
I took piano lessons, guitar lessons when I was a kid.
And I'm I'm hopeless.
Thank God coding exists and thank God sports exists, because if if I had to do anything in the arts,
I would be I would not be very good.
Garrison asks if it would be really inspirational for all of us.
Who or what do you want to do with the next ten years of your life coaching business?
Looks like he is the same age as me.
So just asking what's what's the next ten years of my life look like?
The next ten years of my life is going to involve learning every day I want to, whether it's coding,
whether it's different things.
I have different hobbies that I want to keep improving at.
I really like surfing, so I want to become a better surfer.
And there's so many things that I really want to improve.
So honestly, every single day my goal is to learn.
I want to hopefully have a family by then and have a house and and just enjoy life.
And hopefully in 10 years I'm retired, being able to being able to spend every single day with my son
or daughter and just enjoying life.
But honestly, what I'm doing now is not much different than what I hope to be doing ten years from
now, because I am really, really happy with with how life is right now.
And I wouldn't really change anything.
Dorion, again, do you think all the races you do and yoga and exercises help you mental clarity and
have helped your career as a developer when things get rough?
Yeah, so fun fact.
I'm I'm also a yoga instructor on the side and I do, I do a lot of adventure racing as well.
And both of those things I think actually really help with being a developer and dealing with different
situations at work.
I think for adventure racing it it puts you into situations that are extremely uncomfortable that you
have to just survive through.
And then with yoga, obviously, it's still in your mind, especially with meditation as well.
I think those are extremely important, especially when compared to coding, when you're staring at
the screen and everything is usually fast paced and it's really, really easy to get lost in your head.
I think balancing out coding with something that's complete opposite, like yoga and meditation, again,
not to get a little hippy here, but I think doing different things is is important and being physically
active, being mentally strong.
Is this is your vessel and this is your body and you should take care of it and it'll only improve you
as a developer and as a coder.
So I one hundred percent think that although for some people it may be silly to meditate, although
for some people they don't actually enjoy exercising, everybody has their different things.
But I think doing something other than coding is really, really important for that balance.
And to not burn yourself, burn yourself out assim PubMed, ask about interview and the fact that he's
really worried about interviews and that he doesn't know enough.
And honestly, just keep this in mind because because this is something I hear from so many people.
Everybody is just a child trapped in an adult's body.
No human knows everything perfectly.
And most likely the person sitting across from you that's asking you a question on a on an interview
doesn't know everything, has their own insecurities, has their own areas that they're not an expert
in.
So go into an interview knowing that this person is not God.
It's not the ultimate smartest person that you'll ever meet.
They have their flaws and their issues.
And if you start to realize that there's no such thing as a perfect developer of perfect kotin, everybody
is just trying to pretend like they're smart.
Everybody's just trying to pretend like they're an adult.
Remember everybody, just a kid inside, trapped inside an adult's body.
You start to realize that this.
All world that we live in, this whole system that we're in is just a game just like your Khoder, just
like you're a programmer and you're trying to create a system.
This is simply a system that you need to learn to adapt to and to try to essentially beat or improve.
So put yourself in their situation.
They want to feel important.
They want to feel like they're doing a good job.
So maybe asking them questions during the interview, maybe praising them for something that they did,
even though they're the ones being interviewed, is going to make them feel better.
That perhaps will make them ask you better or easier questions again.
Think of it as a system.
Think of it as a game and realize that there is nothing.
Nothing is extremely serious and important.
Everything is just a game they can play and that you can improve.
And if you start looking at life, good interviews as a as a game, I think it becomes a lot more fun.
And it also remove some of those insecurities.
I don't know if that answer help, but kind of went on a tangent there.
But hopefully that that helps a little bit.
All right.
Last question, because this video is getting a little too long.
So Charles mentioned it asks, what's the difficult day for you at the moment?
Your courses are very that's very kind of you seem to be your healthy way of living in your sporty attitude.
It all must be worth a course on how to balance your life and the way you do things while you quote.
I guess I kind of already talked about this, but my my everyday life usually involves in the morning
drinking coffee, reading articles and catching up in the industry, learning a little bit.
I really like Morning for Learning and then I usually either record or plan recording or edit videos
in the afternoon.
Then around one two o'clock I usually go out for a run, do some exercises, try to get outside, not
stare at the screen and and be active.
And then I come back, I usually check out my emails, answer questions, go on Dischord and chat with
other students.
And then usually by five o'clock I'm done.
I don't do any work.
I stop whatever I'm doing because I know after five o'clock, for me personally, I'm not productive.
So I usually spend time with family, with my girlfriend or do social activities or maybe go play some
tennis, go play some soccer, go for a hike just to relax.
And I usually go to bed at ten o'clock.
Not that very exciting.
I don't I don't enjoy going to bars or clubs anymore.
I'm, I'm an old soul and at o'clock I'm ready for bed and I'm ready for the next day.
So a pretty, pretty boring day.
Nothing too exciting.
But it's it's it's what I like right now.
Anyway, this this was the and video again, I want to thank you.
I cannot believe that there's one hundred thousand students that are taking my courses.
And honestly, if it was just me, I would never get to one hundred thousand students.
Every single one of you that talk to others recommend my courses that really help me get to where I
am.
And I cannot express how thankful I am for for everything that that you have done that you have shown
support for.
And I am I hope to continue to keep impressing you and keep helping you with your learning journey.
And, yeah, I'm I'm really, really thankful.
So thank you.