Welcome back, everyone.
Let's start typing out our form input component.
To begin, we want to convert this over from Gsx to TSX, both the form input component as well as these
styles.
And first you'll notice immediately that our form input label has a type error.
The reason is that shrink is a nickel, and the reason for this is because the form input component
for form input label is a component and we have not defined any props on it.
So we're trying to use props on this component despite the fact that the props are not defined.
So here, defining props for these style components is the exact same as defining props for any component,
because these are really just components.
So here we'll say type form input.
Label props is going to be equal to us receiving some shrink value, which is optional.
And this is a boolean.
And what we'll say is that form input label props needs to be passed to this component as the props.
So the great thing about style components is that you can just pass it as a generic to the style dot
label because by default that's the definition.
They take some generic value and then add it as the actual props that it expects to receive.
And now you'll see that shrink is indeed a boolean value.
So now we can save this and then go back to our form input component and start typing this out.
So as you can tell, as I mentioned before, we are really just leveraging the underlying input component
in order for us to extend all of these additional features onto it.
But the input component, just like the button component, has corresponding attributes that we want
from React.
So we're going to import in input HTML attributes.
And we're also going to implement EFSI because we need this to be a functional component.
All going to do now is we're going to type out these form input props.
So this is going to be first the label value, which is our unique value, which we expect to be a string.
And then from here we are going to create an intersection with input HDMI attributes.
So we want all of the input HDMI attributes of a HTML input element.
And now we are going to say that form input is of type functional component with the form input prompts.
So now we've solved our props issue for the type.
However, the problem here is that if you look at this, there's a chance that the other props object
is undefined.
Assuming that no props are passed.
So here, what we can say is that first, if this is the case, what we want to do is we want to ensure
that this shrink always receives a boolean because shrink is receiving essentially a Boolean value.
So what we can do is we can say Boolean on.
This value like so and the first thing will check.
Is there other props?
So is other props value?
Is this exist?
If it does, then can we render other props that value?
Well now will notice that length might not exist because on this particular case we don't know what
we could get back.
Length might not exist on the value coming back as a number because inputs can receive both strings
and numbers.
So if that's the case, then we need to do another check to ensure is this going to be a string.
So here we'll say is type of.
Other prompts value equal to a strength.
If it's equal to a string as well, then finally, I want you to check if there's a line.
And now we are now correctly passing and properly typing through our form input.
Now that we've done our form input, let's think about where they might get used.
The places where we insert inputs is in both the sign and form and the sign up form.
So let's type out these forms.
So again, we are going to convert this over to a TSX file.
Now first off, to begin, we can check in our sign informed on styles and we see that none of our stock
components receive props.
So we don't need to type any of these.
We can focus exclusively on our sign informed component.
So here we also noticed that our sign in form doesn't receive props, but our handle submits and our
handle change do receive props.
Now we need to type these.
We've already typed handle change before, which essentially is what we passed the on change of an input.
So we can expect similarly then that handle submits is going to follow a similar pattern where we received
some kind of event from React.
What kind of event is it?
We can just convert this over to a function signature and we can just put e hover over it.
We see that it is of type form event, so we need to import inform event in order for us to actually
type these two fields.
So first, we're going to come up here and we're going to say, give me the form event and also for
the change handler, give me the change event.
Using these two now we can say that the event that we receive from handle submit will be of type form
event.
And we're going to pass it as always.
HTML form element most likely.
And that's exactly what we see.
Similarly for our handle change, we are going to pass in change event.
With HDMI input elements being the type of change event that we're registering.
Now we save this, we see we have no more type arrows for our sign and form so we can move on to our
sign up form.
So let's first convert these files over to TSX files.
We notice they're inside of our styles.
There are no props, so we don't need to worry about typing this one.
We can now just do our sign up form component.
With our sign up form component, we notice that we actually have some leftovers that we aren't using
from our inputs.
We can just get more of that.
And now again, we see that there are two different type areas.
Have the two different events first, cement and for channel change.
And we also see we get an error code.
Now, the first one I want to tackle is just the event.
So as always, just like we did with React, we are going to bring in two events.
One is the form events for the summit.
One is the change event for the input.
So I'm going to say that this handle events is a form event of the h html form.
Element.
And then for our handle change, this is going to be.
A change event.
For a simple input element.
Now what about this error code?
So here you might be thinking, what is this error?
Well, we're actually catching this error inside of our author start, which is what sign up start gives
us back if we catch.
So this is where we may not actually get the error that we expect.
What we need to do is we need to get the off air.
So this is where inside we can say, okay, if we get some kind of authentication error, we need to
import in most likely some kind of error from Firebase.
And the chances are.
It's actually something that exists.
So inside of Firebase Slash Auth.
There are two types.
One is the author's r-type.
And here we see there's even off error codes.
So what's great about this is that we can take this off air and we can actually directly modify the
code here so that we're not even hard coding these values.
We actually get these directly from Firebase.
So the first thing we need to do is say that this error code is a specific type of error.
So error as off error because we know this is an error from Firebase on.
Decode must exist on the author because that's where we're reading it from.
And now, instead of matching this string ourselves, we can say off error codes, dots.
And then now we can just find the one that we had before, which is email exists.
As you can see when hovering over this.
This was the same string that we had earlier off email already in use.
So amazing.
We don't even have to now reference our own dependency of figuring out what that string was.
We can save this now and now we have our forms also fully typed.
So that is really great.
We've typed our forms.
We've typed our inputs.
We've also typed our buttons.
So now that we've typed this, let's start typing something else that might be a little challenging,
which is our SVG icons.
So let's tackle that in the next video.