Welcome back, everyone.
In the last video, we discussed accessibility of data based on context, API and Redux.
In this video we are going to reinforce that, but primarily also discuss the flow of data and how the
structure of our code changes.
Even the high level concepts change a little bit, which we'll cover inside of this video.
So let's start with context.
Context, we can mainly see as being separated into two portions.
We have UI components and then we have contexts with reducers.
These context reducers are of course the components that wrap the corresponding UI components.
So imagine if we had three different components in our app component one, component two and component
three.
And then we are two different contexts context A and context B, let's say that context wraps around
component one and component two.
As we saw in our last video, let's say Context B wraps around component three.
Now, let's say respectively, each of these contexts also have their own reducer, which they're using
for state management.
So this is what we wrote in the last few videos where we use the use reducer hook.
Here.
The flow of data for context A is we're going to have a dispatch that fires actions into reducer.
A because user reducer, as we know, gives us a dispatch unique to that reducer.
So we might pass that dispatch directly to components one and two, or we might create action generator
functions as we did inside of our contacts and then pass that down.
Remember, that was our set current user or that was our set is open.
Those are all dispatch action based creators.
So component one, a component to of course will then in turn potentially dispatch actions that update
reducer, a reducer, a state.
Then we'll have some values which get consumed by component one and component two.
So this is the flow of data.
The components drive actions into the reducers, the reducers then drive their corresponding values
to their components.
This is going to be the same flow with context.
BE You're going to have component three dispatching actions to reduce or be using reducer bees, unique
dispatch and then reducer be of course is going to pass those values to component three, which is what
context be wraps around.
So this is pretty much the flow of data that we've seen with our context.
Now let's talk about Redux.
With Redux, we still have UI components.
So let's imagine that we still have the same three components.
But now we also have this Redux store, and the Redux store structure is going to have three separate
reducers.
These are still functions that return objects and those objects just carry the state of that reducer.
So nothing here has changed.
Everything you know about reducers is exactly the same.
The difference, though, is that we have three different reducers.
For example, you can have more, you can have less.
It doesn't matter.
But the idea is that you have A, B and C reducer.
These reducers all combine together into something known as the root reducer.
The root reducer takes each of these and combined them into one giant reducer.
From this reducer we will then pass state into component one, component two and component three.
You passed the entire state object.
You don't just pass reducer A's value or reducer B's value.
You pass the entire state object through to component one, component two and component three.
And then similarly, what will happen is that these components of course, are going to dispatch actions,
but it's one dispatch method.
Remember with context, each use reducer gives you a new dispatch that goes specifically to the respective
use reducer hook.
Here with Redux we have one dispatch, one dispatch action.
Essentially you're going to dispatch actions using the one dispatch, and all of these reducers are
all going to receive those actions.
But what happens is that we have to determine in the corresponding reducer what to update.
So these actions may update reducer, a may update reducer be or update reducer see.
In fact, the same action can update all three reducers if these three reducers choose to update based
on that action.
But this is the different flow of Redux.
So the main thing to understand is that there is a much more singular story.
So as a result there's a singular dispatch, and then it's up to our individual reducers A, B and C
to determine if they want to update their state appropriately.
So in the next video, what we're going to do is we're going to take all of these concepts and we're
going to focus on working with them in the code base.
So join me in the next video where we will take all of these high level concepts and push them into
Redux CO.
LC see in the next video.