In this lesson, we are going to explore the most common building block of a saga, which is a generator
function.
Now, the generator function is a new ish feature that was brought into the JavaScript ecosystem and
native to JavaScript now.
And what it is, is a function that resembles a sink away.
Now, it's not exactly a sink away.
It's got almost a different flair to it, but it's very similar in the sense that with our async await
functions, we await our asynchronous events, our promise based events, where we pause the execution
inside of an async function whenever we see the Wacol.
Well, generally, your functions are very similar in the sense that they also pause their execution
whenever they see a specific key inside of the function, and that key is called a yield.
Now, I'll show you what that looks like when we write our first generator function.
In order for us to do it, there's actually a special syntax we actually have to declare with our old
school style of writing function declarations.
So we actually got a write function.
But what we do is we put the star.
To declare that this is a generator function and then what we can do is we can name our function, so
I'm going to name it again and it's going to take no parameters for now.
And all this function does is it calls console dialogue a.
Just the letter A.
And then a console logs the letter B.
Now, when we instantiate this function, meaning that when we invoke it, we actually get back this
generator object, which we can cast as some variable G.
Right.
I'm just going to name this constant G and it's going to be equal to us invoking Djenne, the function.
Now, if this is a regular function, the moment I invoke Gen.
Console log and console log B will be logged out to our browser and then G would just be set to undefined
because functions that don't return anything would just return undefined.
But in our case, when we invoke this gen, we see that nothing has happened.
In fact, if we were to log, we see we get this weird gen suspended generator kind of object, right.
So this is a generator object.
And what we do on it is we call DOT next on it and what DOT next will do is it will actually resume
the execution inside of our function.
So at this point, when we invoked it for the first time, we instantiated this generator object that
actually is aware of the code inside of this function.
But the execution inside of the function is paused.
So until we call Genden next.
This function actually will not run our console locks.
The moment I do, we see that it does, it logs out A and B, but then you see that we get back this
object from calling DOT next.
And what it is, is an object with a value prop and a dozen prop.
The dumb prop is a boolean telling us if there's anything else in the function to run or has it run
through its entire course, which we know it does, because all we did in our function was console log
two things.
Now, this will change once we start using the yield and the U.S. will also give this value of value
and I'm going to show you how that works.
Let's refresh and let's make a new function, right?
So, again, we're going to call it Jen, but this time we're going to take some integer value.
And what we're going to do is we are going to yield the value that we pass in the next call.
We're going to yield I plus 10.
So that's all we've done is essentially we're saying we write this function, right, Cudgen, it takes
some integer value, some number, and then it yields that number that we pastan and also yields then
the number plus 10.
So now we're going to set some G value equal to Argin initialized with the value of, let's say, actually
five.
Now, what happens when we call G Dorton, we know that we are going to actually get back that similar
object that we saw before.
Right.
You remember when we logged at the site, when we invoked next the first time that object with the value
key and then the Dungey?
Well, I'm actually just going to make sure to hold on to that value.
So going I call it G obj.
Right, right here.
And now, when I call it, you'll actually see that when we see what's on our jobs, right, our jobs
is equal to that object, except now value is the I value that we yielded out the first time.
And we'll also see that done is false, meaning that there's more that we can actually continue the
execution on inside of our generator function.
If I were to call G Dot next again this time, right, and let's send it to another object, let's call
it just George.
Right.
Well, now we'll see that George has the value of the next yielded value, which is five plus ten,
which gives us 15.
It also now sees that Dunn is still false.
If we were to call next one last time, then we see that the done is true, but there's no value that
gets returned in the undefined.
Now, this is the main thing to remember with yields.
The moment we call yields inside of our generator function, the yield curve is pretty much telling
our generator function.
OK, I don't want to do anything with this.
Right.
I'm just going to resolve it.
However it is.
If it's an asynchronous request, I'm going to resolve the request.
I'm going to pass that value out into this object that we get back.
Right.
And I'm going to set it to the value prop.
Now, you might be wondering when it's done, is there a way for us to get a value in this function?
Well, actually, there is the way that we would do it, right.
Let's just copy this is we would actually cast it as the return value.
So the last thing we can do is say return twenty five and now if we did the same thing as we did last
time with Gen five, if I do got next.
Next, right.
We see that this is up to earth second yield, if I got next one more time, while the final value that
gets resolved is our return from our function, and then the done is true.
But the main benefit is that the yield will invoke the value of whatever it's yielding and return it
outside of our generator.
This is primarily what generators are used for.
It's just if you want to stash multiple executions, but you want to control when you want to move and
continue the execution in this function onwards.
And this is the basis of Sagas Saga's work on this yield based format, because they need to know and
give us control over when we want to continue with an execution of the block of code that we've written.
Or we want to do something with the first.
Now, it'll make more sense once we start writing it, but I just wanted you to see this generator syntax.
I did not want you to be confused by what we're about to write, because what we're about to write is
going to look kind of different from code that we've written before.
The closest comparison I'm going to draw again is to async away.
But now that we've seen this as well, we just need to remember that whenever we see yield, we just
need to know that our code is stopping at this point, even if it's asynchronous code, just like async
away.
So let's dive into implementing sagas into our code base.