Welcome back, everybody.
In this lesson, I'm going to show you how you can set up your environment so that you can follow this
course with all of the tools that I have and that you'll see throughout the course along the way, I'll
mention some alternatives that you might use.
It's entirely up to you because these are all just tools.
And I simply have my own set up that I use throughout this course.
Now, the first thing you need to install is your editor.
So if you already have an editor that you prefer, such as Sublime or Adam or even an idee like Web
storm, you can totally use that.
I like visual studio code, so that's what I use.
So in order for you to get Visual Studio code, simply go to this link that I'm going to provide you
and your resources and then hit the download format button.
Now, what this will do is this will trigger the installation, so simply choose the place where you
want to download the actual TVs code.
So I'm going to choose desktop and this will download the zip folder for you.
Then you simply just open up the zip.
And now you'll have your visual studio coat application where you saved your zip folder.
So now if I go to my desktop folder, I see it right here.
So just double click to open it.
And then allow your Mac to open visual studio coat because it's downloaded from the Internet, you need
to give it permission.
Now, once you've given it permission, Visual Studio Code is up and running, so you now have the same
editor that I use.
The only thing I would suggest you probably do is add the code shell command to your terminal.
Now, we'll explain more about what that actually is in a little bit later.
But right now, in order for you to add it, you simply hold command shift and press P, then you're
going to type command.
And here you'll see shell command install code command path.
So simply click that and then it will install the code command to your path.
Now, once you have your path set up, you are now able to use the code DOT command to open up files
and folders inside of your terminal, which we will do a lot in this course.
Now, what is the terminal?
Well, the terminal is actually going to be the main way that we navigate around our application, as
well as modify our files as you'll see in this course.
Now, by default, Mac comes with a terminal.
So in order for you to access it, simply go to your spotlight search and type in terminal.
Once you have that, just open up the first thing you see, and this will be the terminal that you can
use throughout this course.
Now, with this terminal, what we need to do next is actually install node.
Now, the easiest way for us to install node is actually to use something called End VM, which is node
version manager.
Now, in order to install and VM, simply go to the link that I'm going to provide you inside of your
resource folder.
And then once you navigate to this link, scroll down to this section called Installation and Update
and simply copy this line and then paste it into your terminal.
What this will do is this will clone down the NBN package and then add it to your existing shell, which
is the thing that we're running inside of our terminal.
Now, once we have an VM, we have to actually close our terminal and then relaunch it.
Now, once you have reopened your terminal type in commandership and pvm.
If you see nothing listed, then this means that SVM is not yet loaded to our shell.
So what we have to do is we have to actually scroll down here and we can see inside of these instructions
right here on OSX, if we see that there's no end pvm script than what we have to do is first check
if we have a Basche profile.
Now, you can do this by simply typing Nanao and then this till the sign sgot Basche profile.
Now, if you hit this and nothing occurs, meaning that there is no Basche profile, instead of NENO,
replace this with touch and then run nano profile again because touch will open a new Basche profile
for you.
So inside of our profile, if at the very bottom we see nothing related to end pvm that we need to add
this line of running source Basche RC.
So let's just add that in right now.
You can also copy paste this in if you want.
Once we have that, we just need to save by hitting Command X. It'll ask us if we want to say we hit
Y and then we hit enter.
And now what we need to do is we need to type source Tilda Agbank profile to upload and rerun our profile
that we've just made changes to.
And now if we type in LVM, we'll see that there's something here instead of an PVM command not found.
So now we know we have an PVM.
So now what we need to do is actually install node using NBN, and the way we do that is we can actually
first figure out what node version we want to run.
So let's go to the node website, which I will link to you as well inside of your resources.
And here we'll see that the latest version is ten point one six point zero, so we don't need to actually
manually download this from the website we can use and VM.
So go back to your terminal and you can type in nvm install.
Ten point one six point zero or any other version of note that you want to use now, you can also type
in N.V. and VM install node and this will give you the latest version of Node.
So for us, I'm just going to use ten point one six point zero and now this will install the appropriate
version of node that we need.
Once it's done, installing what we need to do is make sure that we use it.
So in order to do that, we can just say nvm use ten point one, six point zero.
And now we'll be using the right version of note, we'll also see that MPM was installed as well and
NPM is what we're going to use to manage the packages, which are the libraries that we use inside of
our JavaScript applications.
So this is really good.
We have both of them installed now and we can check by typing No Dashkova as well as NPM Dashboard.
And here we see that we have both installed on our computer.
So at this point, it's actually perfectly fine to continue with the course.
You have node, you have NPM, you have your terminal and you have your editor.
Now, the thing is that I use Riaan instead of NPM Yohana, simply another package manager that Facebook
made during a time when Empt has some issues.
But NPM is perfectly stable now and both are pretty equal in terms of the features and the speed regarding
package management.
So if you want to use NPM and not install yarn, you can definitely do so.
You can simply look at the different commands with NPM that you need in order to run commands instead
of using the yarn ones that I do.
But if you want to use yarn, just go to the yarn link that I provide you and your resources.
Scroll down to the installation script and then copy that line right there.
Then you go back to your terminal, we clear it and then we paste it in.
And now this will install yarn into your computer now, once you have yarn, you just need to check
whether or not it's there.
So simply tienen yarn, dash v and if you see a version now, you also have yarn.
So now you're able to do everything that I do in this course with yarn and you can switch between yarn
and MP freely.
Ideally, in one project, however, you should use either one or the other.
You should not use both NPM and yarn in the same folder.
Now, keeping that in mind, you are fully set up to move on with the course.
So I'll see you in the next lesson.