Welcome back, everyone.
So now that we're moving into our big capstone project, I have actually set up a repository just for
you.
This repository contains all of the code that we are going to write.
I've also set it up in such a way that it should be relatively easy for you to work with.
Primarily, I want you to code with this repository.
And the way I want you to use it is more as a reference.
So as you go through the lesson, you're probably going to follow all the steps just like mine.
So inside of your own laptop, on your own terminal, you're going to instantiate your own project and
you're going to follow along and code along as you do.
However, if at any point you feel like you want a direct copy of my code, what you can do is you can
clone down this repository simply by hitting code and then clone.
And this will just bring your repository down into your terminal.
So let's just take an example.
I'm going to come down here to clone, and I'm going to do.
Most likely a TPS because it's the most simple one.
And what I'll do is I'll just do say, get clone and then type in the repository.
And here this is going to clone down the project and I can just CD into it and I have the code.
One of the things that you may have to do that's different from mine is that you most likely will need
this repository on your own GitHub.
So for your own GitHub, it's going to be a little different because you cannot make changes and push
that code into my repository.
The reason being you do not own this repository, I own this repository.
If you want a copy of this repository that you own.
You need to fork this repository.
So when you hit fork up here in the right corner, it will say, Oh, let me fork this project into
your own account.
So I've set up a temporary account here just to show you what happens.
And now here you see you have directly forked down this code.
So once you fork down this code, you can actually clone this specific repository down into your code
base.
So earlier, if you look, you'll notice that I had cloned this and this is my copy, my repository,
not the one that I just forked over.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to remove this one.
So that we don't have that name.
And now if I clone down this repository, actually let me copy this again.
If I clone down this new forked repository now, this is tied to the version that is forked to my profile.
So in this particular case, this would be your profile and now you can make push changes to it because
you own this copy.
Now, one important thing I want you to pay attention to is these branches here in the top left corner.
By default, this project sets you at less than one.
But throughout the project, you'll see that there are numerous branches and these are all different
checkpoints for the code.
But what I want you to notice is this main branch.
Maine is pretty much the branch that has the latest version of your code or in this particular case,
my code that I've written for this project.
Maine is also going to be very important because this is pretty much our production branch, which means
any code in Maine is supposed to have the code that we want to be displayed live.
So if we were to deploy this code base, we are often deploying it from the Maine branch.
So the reason why this main branch is important is because in most typical projects that you work on
in companies, the main branch is the one that is considered your production branch and that's where
you're going to be merging changes into it.
But of course, because we're the only person working on this code base, we're not going to really
care about that.
And the Merge strategy is as much.
But the reason I mention is just because typically all of their final code should be on the main branch.
So let's talk about these other branches, though, we know that main branch is the one that should
have all of the actual code, we want to be our final code.
But let's say, for example, what happens is that you are working on your own code base, let's say
not off this fork.
And what happens as you're working on it is you make a mistake of some kind.
Let's say for some reason, you can't figure out why your code is just not running anymore and you just
want to get a specific version of the code base up to where we've done so that you can at least have
a clean start moving forward.
Let's say at that point, you check your resources folder and it says, Hey, I'm on lesson 12.
Well, if you look at the branch itself, you'll see all of the code.
But what you can do is you forked and then cloned this project down.
You actually have access to all of these branches, so you can just say, Hey, get check out meta lessons.
Well.
And now this will have all of the code that you have up until this video, which is referencing lesson
12.
What you can do is you can code from Lesson 12.
This branch directly or what I suggest you do is you branch off from this lesson to all branch.
And what that does is it creates for you, your own branch that you can write code against without impacting
or affecting all of these lesson branches.
So if you were to say check out Dash B, so I want to say, Hey Git, I want you to make a new branch
for me and I want you to use less than 12 as the basis.
Just by doing this from Lesson 12, you're going to say, OK, create a new branch from this as well.
I want to call it my main.
For example, you can name it whatever you want.
I just called it my dash main.
Just so that it's clear that this is my code here, this code base now is the same as Lesson 12, so
whatever changes you make are going to be made to my mate instead of being made to lesson 12.
And when you get to certain sections inside of our code or inside of the course where we want it to
make a deployment, you can now deploy from your own my main branch as long as you pushed this branch
up onto GitHub in your forked repo so that GitHub actually knows that this branch exists because right
now all of this is being done on our local computer.
So a lot of this has to do with just very basic gate strategy.
But now you have your own branch based on the code of a branch inside of my code base that you will
see referenced throughout this capstone video course.
And this is pretty much it.
If that ever gets a little confusing, you can always check the Read B.S. down here, where I walk through
all these steps, particularly down in the branching strategy, which will cover everything that we
talk about.
So that's it.
Now that you know about how you can leverage this repository for your benefit, fork it, clone it and
then work off of that using this branching strategy that we've discussed.
And with that, let's get started with building out our project.
I'll see you in the next video.