Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to pick up our graph you, Alison.
So this repository inside of your resource folder contains a repo that I have made for you, which is
branched off roughly from lesson 25, which is where we had just finished setting up everything for
nullify.
The reason why we branched off from here is because there are a couple differences and nuances of GraphQL
that we want to implement that directly correspond to what we do later.
So GraphQL is actually a replacement for Redux.
It's very rare that you will utilize both GraphQL and Redux.
The reason being that GraphQL has its own way of keeping track of the data and typically speaking,
graph quality data querying kind of runs in conflict with Redux.
Now we'll discuss that more once we get to the actual implementation section.
But inside of this repo, I want you to copy the repo and then I want you to go to your actual application
and I want you to clone it down into a new folder.
Make sure that you're not in your previous crown closing folder so you can just clone that down.
And then just make sure you go into your new folder.
Once you finished it.
Now, once you're inside of your repo, what I want you to do is I want you to yarn add in two packages.
The first is at Apollo slash client.
Apollo is going to be a frontend client that allows us to make requests for GraphQL as well as receive
responses for GraphQL.
And it comes with a bunch of bindings for React so that we can actually get GraphQL data and make GraphQL
requests within our components.
That's the first thing.
The next thing I want you to add is the GraphQL library itself.
So with these two different libraries, we are now going to be able to actually utilize it inside of
our application.
While all of this is installing, I want to talk about GraphQL and the syntax.
So to do this, what we're going to do is go back to our.
Web browser.
And I want you to go into your resources folder and look for this graphical playground link.
This will take you to crown dash clothing dot com where I have made this website for you, which is
known as a graphical playground.
A graphical playground is a place where you can make queries in the graphical language directly against
the database or the graphical server that's connected to the database graph.
Q All sits between the database and the server, and what it does is it allows you to format your requests
in the manner that we discussed in the previous video where we pass it some object that looks roughly
like the data you want.
Now, let me show you what is inside of this playground.
Over on this side.
Here is where you will enter in the information that tells graphic your what you want.
So here you'll see.
Write your query or mutation online.
One A query is a request for data.
A mutation is a request to modify or add data.
That's mainly the two different things that you can do inside of GraphQL.
It's all queries where you request data and it's all mutations where you ask to update or create or
delete data.
So you can see these kind of like your rest API in a way.
Down here is where you include any additional variables, which we'll discuss when we start talking
about doing queries and mutations.
Over here is where you will get a response when you hit this play button.
Once you have a correct query or mutation, the data will show up here.
This is also going to tell you if you have an incorrect query or mutation.
Any response back is all going to happen here.
There are also two additional tabs here.
The first one I want to talk about is the schema.
The schema represents everything that you can make inside of GraphQL.
So we have queries and queries define the different types of requests you can ask for.
Remember, we have to tell GraphQL what we want, and the name of what you are asking for is actually
defined by the person who wrote the server.
So these queries I created, you'll see that I made three different queries for you.
There is collections where you get back an array of collections.
Now, what is a collection?
A collection you can see down here as the type.
This is very similar to what we wrote in TypeScript.
Collection actually replaces category, as you know, inside of our main application.
The category, of course, represents the collection of clothing.
And inside of a category, there were category items here.
Instead, I have called it a collection.
And in a collection there are items.
So if you look at this definition signature of the type, you'll see that we have I.D. So the idea is
any identifier.
But in GraphQL, there is capitalize ID to signify that this is specifically meant to be unique.
It's in the format of a string, but it's also unique.
That's why it is I.D. in caps.
You'll also notice that there is this exclamation mark.
The exclamation mark signifies that this field is mandatory.
This is not a optional field.
Without it, then it's optional.
There is a title which points to strength and the strength similarly is also not optional.
It is mandatory.
Next you will see items, items points to an item type, meaning that this is going to hold a collection
of items or an array of items.
The array is designated by the square brackets and inside will state what that type inside the array
will be.
So of course they are items also necessary and the array also necessary.
So that's another thing.
Coming down here, you will see the type of item and here you will see again.
Identifier must be unique.
Hence the capital ID name of string price.
A float float is a number.
The only thing is that it can be decimal place, which is why you will see float also necessary image
url which is a string and then collection a collection.
And the reason why there is this is so that GraphQL can connect an item so that it belongs to a specific
collection.
It's really just the way that graphic glass sets up on the back end.
Primarily, you will not usually be querying for this collection, but you can if you wanted to.
If you are fetching an item and you wanted to know the collection it was in, you could also reference
the collection.
So this again defines for you what the types will be and then ask for the queries.
We'll talk about that in the next video where we'll actually start querying GraphQL for some data.
But for now, I just want you to know that if at any point you wanted to look at what your data that
you can ask for, it looks like, because again, we're asking for very specific parts of the data.
Always open up the schema to see what you have.
Okay, let's jump into the next video where we will start working with the queries.
I'll see you in the next video.