Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to talk about a couple performance optimization hooks that React has given
us access to.
The first one I want to talk about is use callback.
And to understand use callback, we need to understand how function declarations inside of a functional
component work by understanding how React treats functional components.
As I mentioned before, whenever you render or re render a functional component, React is going to
go through line by line of this entire function every single time.
Hooks by nature are more optimized for this process, but any variables you declare.
So if we were to hard code a variable, let's say ABC which equals a string.
ABC Whenever this component renders or renders and it hits line 20, react is re initializing this variable
with this string.
Now with variable casting, this is pretty performant.
It's extremely minimal and has very little cost.
But when you take something more complex like casting a function, this is definitely more expensive.
Even with anonymous functions inside the return call, react is re initializing this function every
single time, including our named variables as well.
These are also being re initialized every single time.
And the reason why this is happening is because React doesn't know whether or not this is something
that is brand new or it isn't brand new because it doesn't know if any of the scoped variables inside
are referencing new values.
React just operates in a way where it just behaves like regular JavaScript.
I see a function definition I'm going to define and initialize the function.
So for us, generally speaking, this is not that costly.
So this harkens back to what I was saying.
Last video Do not over optimize your code if you don't need to.
But let's say you're working on an application and you have hundreds of components that are rendering
on the page and each and every one of them is initializing a function every single time, and numerous
of those are constantly re rendering.
In that case, these little, little performance bumps may improve your actual overall performance.
So how does use callback work?
Use callback is a hook that takes two parameters.
The first is the actual callback that you want to memorize, and the second is a dependency array that
determines when it's time to re memorize this function.
Now when we talked about memoirs and we were talking about memoirs, Asian with selectors and the way
that we were master selectors was that if the parameters do not change of that function, then you will
always give you back the same output that was memorization with selectors.
Memorization in this context is that React is doing something similar.
Essentially this callback, it does not need to re initialize.
As long as this dependency array value does not change, then react will always give you back the same
function, not the return of the function, but the actual function itself.
React is memorizing the function.
React is not memorizing the output of the function.
And that's a very key difference to remember because of the fact that React is memorizing this function.
Now React does not need to re initialize this function every time it comes and hits line 20 on a render
or a re render.
The only time it will is if any values inside the dependency array changes.
Now here you'll notice that the dependency array mentions that you're missing a dependency which is
navigate.
This is where it kind of talks more about understanding how React uses references that determine if
this value is new.
Inside of React and most of the time with these third party libraries that create hooks.
When you think about this use navigate hook.
It's giving us some function navigate that we can use to navigate to different parts of our application.
Generally speaking, unless the structure of your application is constantly changing from a root level
in a dynamic manner, this navigate is going to be the exact same reference, which means that every
time React renders or renders this cart drop down component and hits line 18 this navigate, it's automatically
going to know, Oh, this is the same value.
I don't need to get a new one from use navigate.
So as a result, navigate is never really changing, so you don't actually need to pass navigate into
your dependency array on line 22.
React doesn't know that though use effect or use callback most of the time as we notice, we get a lot
of these warnings, but they don't know that this reference is doing that.
So as a result, React will give you a warning.
There is a dependency that's inside that.
I'm not sure if it will or will not update.
Maybe you'll get some errors if you don't include it.
The problem with adding it and it's not really a big problem, but it is a concern and why there's two
camps on this.
When you add this dependency, it kind of sends a mixed message that you can expect this callback to
re initialize this function and that navigate is something that does change or can change or most likely
will change.
But this is actually not true.
Generally speaking, we don't expect navigate to ever change.
So this is where two camps sit on this topic.
Some people say add it.
As long as you understand that navigate something doesn't change.
There's no harm in adding it.
Other people say that it makes your code a little bit miscommunicated.
It's saying that you can anticipate navigate to change, which is why I'm even adding it in the dependency
at all.
I'm expecting something to change.
So again, this is where really it depends on the team and the person that's coding out your code.
But the main thing to understand here at the very least with use callback now are function is memorized.
We don't really need to add it to the dependency array, but now that we have this memoires function,
we can now expect that this cost is not going to be there to re initialize this function every time.
But if you miss adding something to this dependency array, you may actually come with a couple of bugs.
And that's what we're going to talk about.
And through talking about, that will also better understand what's actually happening with use callback.
So join me in the next video where we'll discuss that.
I'll see you there.