So when the last lesson we added in our Babbo loader so that we can convert our jazz and jazz files
down into five jazz files that our browser can understand.
What we're going to do now is we need to actually bring in another loader because we need to actually
tell Westpac what it should do with CSX.
It actually doesn't know how to render and bring in Keziah.
This is a thing that we have to do with Westpac.
What we're going to bring in is two new loaders, one loader is called the style loader and the other
loader is loader.
Now style loader is what allows it to convert different types of style files.
The seller actually allows us to import in files into our react component files.
The actual loader is what converts CSFs into a version or not even a version.
But it's just what allows the cows to be read by our JavaScript files.
We can use a saslaw if we want it to convert SAS over as well, but you always need access loader and
style loader, so we're just going to bring those in.
Style odor as well as cislunar.
Now that we have those two loaders in, we're going to define a new rule and here we want to say.
That.
For any file that ends in success, so just like our Jass, it's following the very same conventional
pattern, except we don't need these brackets because we need the brackets when we do the OR but we
don't hear in this context.
We want to say for any CSFs files, we want to just run them through the two loaders and you can take
an object with multiple options or it can take an array.
And here we're going to pass an array because we want it to run through two loaders.
Keep in mind here that the order does matter.
Loaders evaluate from right to left and we want to render the loader first before we do the stallholder.
So because we're going right to left and we want stallholder to be last, we're going to say stop Loader
first and then CSFs Loader second.
And that's all we need for CSFs.
The last thing that we need to do is we need to make sure that we can output and build a HTML file that
we can actually finally read in our final production build.
In order to do that, we need two more tools.
So going back to our terminal, we are going to add in HTML loader, which, as you're familiar with
now, it's simply just a loader.
But we also need HTML Web plugin.
So the HTML loader is the thing that lets us read our HTML file inside of our REACT application, but
the Web pack plugin is what allows us to actually place the output somewhere.
So what it's going to do is it's going to build all of our HTML files and it's going to create efficient
chunks, as we saw in our performance optimization courses, where there the HTML bundles with the JavaScript
for each page.
And this plug in actually helps us do that.
So here we're just going to add these two libraries.
And once we have that, let's go back to our rules and let's add another one.
So here, what we want to do is we want to say in order to use our HTML plug and loader, it's pretty
much going to be the exact same as what we saw with the style loader and the jack loader we need to
test.
And just as we saw, we're going to write.
That we're matching anything that ends in didymo.
And then we're just going to use.
The loader.
HTML loda.
So as simple as that, the only thing now is that after rules, we have to actually bring in that cement
plug in that we were talking about.
So there's another property called plug ins.
And instead of plug ins, we're going to call new and then we got to call the actual plug in, so we've
got to bring that plug in into our Web config file.
So we're going to say consed html web pack.
Plug in.
Is equal to require HTML Watpac plugin.
So we're bringing it in here.
We want to instantiate an instance of it and we're going to pass to it a configuration object, this
object is simply going to take the template of the actual file that it's going to use as the index HTML
starting point in our REACT application.
So we wanted to take this one that we have in our source, because this is the one that renders the
div idea of root using the object code and all of the index code that we have here.
What's going to happen is that inside of Babilonia, Babille loader always by default, tries to go
for a index inside of your source folder.
That's why we always define index us inside of source.
So it's going to find this file.
It's going to run this code and it's going to use that index HTML file that we supply to the actual
HTML plugin as the file that it needs to run the JavaScript on, which is where we're going to end up
using our reactant render in order to replace that div with the idea of root with our app component.
So it's actually the combination of those two loaders together inside of our web pack that ends up producing
and providing outside the new JavaScript and HTML files that we need for our final build.
So finally, with this template, we're just going to pass it the string to our indexed HTML.
And this is our Web config, a lot of new concepts.
But honestly, if you think about what it is that we wrote, it's actually quite simple.
We're just following along with some simple rules and using loaders.
It's just all configuration with Web hack.
That's really all it is.
Of course, I'm going to link all of the documentation for this so that you can see what other options
you have, understand a little better, what else you can do with these different options.
But this is just a bare bones setup so that we can run our web pack and render our reachout.
Now that we have all this, let's just run built because we've got our config setup.
We've got Watpac.
Well, it looks like we have a little error here.
Oh.
I put this in the wrong place.
This should be one lower.
So plug ins comes after module.
And now let's try this again.
So it's going to run the Web, build, can't find app inside of app.
This is a syntax issue.
So inside of index such as this should be Abduh RSX.
Because our loader is looking specifically for this, it does not default.
So that's actually one of the things with WABAC, let's fix that.
Let's try this again.
So my autocomplete will automatically try and correct, sometimes without doing the ASX, as you've
seen throughout this course, as I've imported multiple files together.
So this is just one of the caveats and nuances with Web.
If you want that feature, you actually have to write it yourself as a config option.
But now we finished our built.
But let's actually go over what just happened.
We ran into a couple of minor errors.
This is very normal with configuration of web.
This is why the track team and actually many Selli tools, even for angular and view, try and hide
this away from developers because it's so error prone.
There's so many little nuances you can miss with Westpac that it's really frustrating to work with in
that sense.
That's not to say that it's not worth learning.
It definitely is worth learning, at least what's happening.
But the tools, as Andre mentioned in an earlier lesson, an entire team is dedicated to helping you
build and set up your configuration with Web and Babel to the most optimized degree possible.
It's worth knowing what's happening under the hood, at least like demystifying what Web hacking people
do, but writing it from scratch could bring you a lot of headache.
And the configuration options are pretty much just things you have to do by memory.
And looking at the actual configuration, there's no real logic beyond what it is that each configuration
tool is trying to do for you.
But now that we have our final bill that we see that succeeded.
Inside, we now see we have this new disk folder and an e-mail, so let's actually open this up in the
terminal, but let's open up our index.
Let's reveal and find her.
And let's just open it up in our browser.
And then we see we see our component render our react is working.
So we know that our loader is working and we know that our web hack is all working.
And that's pretty much it.
This is all Web hack and bable.
Do it, transpose it down.
It builds it into a final indexed e-mail as well as manger's bundle that we download as we saw in a
performance section.
So this is actually what's helping Web pack, is helping improve our performance by bundling these files
for us when we make these requests.
That's why we included the HTML bundle.
This is the main advantage of Watpac Web allows us to increase our performance because it sets up a
lot of these things for us.
The REACT team by default assumes and must use web hack.
All of these new technologies and frameworks all leverage Watpac under the hood to help them optimize
the performance and build the code that you write in angular or in react down into a readable version
for browsers.
But now that we finally have our weapon and our configuration options, we understand what it is that
weapon does.
Dig around with the documentation, play with it a little bit yourself if you want to, for example,
include the SAS loader, I can include a link to the SAS loader, just trying to follow the instructions
and see if you can fit it in.
Right.
S file and see what happens.
So hopefully with that, you understand, at least conceptually at what Watpac and Bable do, that's
not to say that for your projects, especially when you're on a new team, that you suddenly write this
yourself from scratch.
If you also want, you can create a new create react app application, inject it and look at how complicated
that code is, because now you at least have a better understanding of what it is that Watpac is doing.
Look at the Babo RC as well and see how many configuration options there are.
Compare and contrast that with the documentation and you'll at least see all of the available possibilities
that you have in front of you with Web hacking babble.
So hopefully you've enjoyed this lesson and I'll see you in the next lesson.