Welcome back, everyone.
In the last video, we hosted our Web site at Low-fi.
But what we noticed is that if we navigate into deeper roots than our base route when we refresh, what
we see is that we get this page not found.
So in order for us to fix this, I need to explain to you why this problem is happening and it has to
do with web servers.
So to begin, let's imagine that you are on your left side, a user, this user is on a browser and
trying to access your website.
Here I'm using Crown Cleveland.com, but you can replace this with your net lo-fi URL.
None of it matters for the point of this example, but the main idea is that you're trying to access
some website that is now live and hosted by Nullify.
So when the user tries to access this base route of Crown Clothing dot com, what happens is that this
browser actually makes a request to net the files web server that's hosting our build script.
So our website is deployed.
Yes, but this access and these files still live on some web server somewhere, which is being provided
by nullify.
So this user is going to say, hey, I want to request any resources for this slash end point.
What happens here is that nullify web servers like, Hey, do I have anything for that slash end point?
Yes, I do.
I'm going to send back the index that HDMI out now.
This index to HDMI file is going to represent the built version of our website because on this page,
HTML will be the JavaScript tags and the CSS tags that is the built version of also our React code or
style components code.
All of our code is now living inside of this HTML file.
So what I happen is that the website will take these files and it will start building out the website.
So at this point, what will happen is the JavaScript now loads onto the page.
The JavaScript includes all of the React code that we've written, as well as all of the libraries were
leveraging.
So at this point, what happens?
JavaScript contains React, React router Dom, everything that we've built throughout these lessons.
Using this, it will look at the website and say, Oh, what do I need to match?
Remember, this is a single page application, which means that it's building out all of these different
pages that live on these routes, which is what our router is doing in React, right, Dom.
So it sees, Oh, I'm on the base route.
What base elements do I need to build?
In our particular case, we know we need to build the directory.
So the corresponding HTML, CSS and JavaScript for that page gets built, and that is what gets used
to populate that page.
Now, let's say the user already has our JavaScript code now.
What happens when they navigate further to shop jackets is that our JavaScript code, which contains
our React router, DOM code and all the code to configure what routes get, what components we'll see.
Oh, this users now trying to access slash shop slash jackets, there is going to be some root matching
that happens through the rack router dom roots components that we've written.
And then the corresponding element, which is the category element is going to run all of our contacts
get pulled, all of our data comes in.
And that in turn builds the correspondingly correct HTML and CSS files that need to be used in order
to build that page.
So this is really what's just happening from a single page application standpoint.
But the key thing to remember is that at this point, the reason why this worked is because we were
asking for the slash endpoint.
Our net off our web server understands, oh, whenever anyone tries to access the slash endpoint, send
back the index HTML and then the index HTML and the corresponding JavaScript React and React router
DOM code that's in there is going to be the resource that will take over any additional routing that
happens on the browser.
Because at that point, there's no more need to communicate with the web server for more resources unless
required.
The main thing is that now all of our routing is handled on the front end by our single page application.
However, if when starting, the very first request you make for is instead four slash slop slash jackets.
This point net lit by a web server, does not have anything to serve for that route because we expect
our frontend application to be the one that actually builds out the page.
Before single page applications were a thing.
A Web server, what essentially have all of the different pages for every one of these endpoints?
So then when a user requests for it, it would send them back the web page.
We're not doing that anymore.
You can't do that with server side rendering, but our application is a single page application, so
that does not happen.
Instead, what happens is that now if a web servers like, Oh, I got no resource for this shop jackets,
which is why we end up seeing that error where there is no page found.
In order to fix this, what we need to do is we need to say, oh, whenever you request a resource for
any endpoint at all.
Always send back indexed HTML.
So on this initial request, whenever they try to access anything, we send back indexed HTML indexed
HMO will render our real code.
And from that real code, we're going to then be able to determine, oh, from this group showed this
page.
So that's really why all of this is happening and we can solve this really easily by creating a redirects
file.
Now, back in our application, in order to build this redirects file, we need to go into our public
folder and make a new file called underscore redirects.
This underscore redirects file is specifically for net low-fi.
It tells net lo-fi If you ever get any root requests, I want you to redirect to this other root.
And with a specific status.
So for us, we want to match any root at all, which is what this slash wildcard is going to represent.
If we remember inside of our own routing, we've seen this wild card before.
This just means match any root at all.
That follows Slash.
What you want to redirect towards is index indexed HTML.
So here we're saying, Hey, if you get a request for slash anything, redirect them to index HTML,
which in turn will send them indexed HTML and then just return a status of 200.
That's it.
Save this file.
Go back to your terminal and just add this and make a commit.
Because as I mentioned before, we've set up our GitHub repo now to be connected to our net low-fi.
So as long as we make a push request adding redirect for an alibi.
And we push this up.
Nat Lo-Fi when you go back to your native, for instance.
You should see that your nullify is rebuilding, so through this rebuild, as I mentioned, we're connected
now.
So this is one of the great advantages.
Through simply pushing to GitHub, we are rebuilding our web site and now we just wait for the bill
to finish and then we can recheck and see if we fix the error.
So there we've just published live, and now if we go back to this website.
And let's navigate deep into jackets again, if I refresh.
There we go.
We don't get the far, far anymore, and the reason for this now is that when not if I received that
request for shot down jackets, it's still just going to send index HTML, which is going to build out
our website and rely on the single page application nature to fix everything.
That's it.
Our website is now fully deployed and live and any further changes you make as long as you push to the
correct GitHub repository branch that is building towards a website, you have a easy to update website
that you can really quickly maintain and really quickly deploy changes to.
This is an end end process that we now have built in.
So that's it.
This is as far as the base library of React goes and 90 percent of the patterns that you're going to
use on the day to day when it comes to building react applications in exclusively the React library.
What we're going to learn next is going to be some additional.
I want to call them tangential libraries or patterns that exist in the greater react ecosystem.
This is where you're going to learn about things like TypeScript integrations, things such as redux
and state management within that state management.
We're also going to learn things such as side effect event handling with things such as dunks and sagas.
And then beyond that, there will be topics on testing different things around existing React libraries
that kind of make building react applications a little different.
We're going to talk about integrating with tools like graphical in general.
It's just now from this point forward, a lot more of the potentially optional parts of the React ecosystem,
where depending on the company you work at, you may or may not use these powders at large.
But a lot of the times you're probably going to encounter them at one of these companies, you're definitely
going to encounter one of these optional.
Perhaps I want to call them libraries and patterns because a lot of the companies are shifting towards
these solutions at scale.
So it's still very important, and I do want to equip you with that knowledge.
So that is what you can look forward to in the upcoming sessions.
But as far as the Base React library goes, building our capstone project, deploying it live and then
seeing and interacting with it.
This is it.
Thank you, everybody.
I'll see you in the next section.