Before we continue, I think it's very important for us to take some time to better understand JavaScript
asynchronous event handling.
Now, that's a mouthful, but asynchronous event handling is a huge part of not only JavaScript, but
also the react ecosystem.
Now.
With Essex, there was promises that got introduced as a means of handling asynchronous events, we've
already used them a little bit when we used fetch in our monster's Rolodex project.
But let's take a deeper dive into both fetch and promise as well as the new S7 syntax of async await.
These are three things that we're going to use a lot in our application.
So let's first look at what we had before promises so we could understand how promises were.
Now, I've got some pseudocode here, but you can imagine what it is that this code is trying to do.
We have some function called get user, which fetches that from this link, right, of Facebook's Kashiwa.
So we're fetching our Facebook user, Iowa, and then we give it this function, which is called a callback.
Inside of it is either going to get the successfully retrieved user or an error if something goes wrong
along the way.
If there's an error, we want to throw the error, right, if there is no error, then we want to get
the user ID and set it to this concept of user ID.
And then we want to pass that into this new function, get friends or we give it the user ID and maybe
that fetches friends from whatever back in API.
It is.
Right.
We don't really care.
And then we give it also another call back, but this time similar to what we just did with Arget user.
It's either going to give us back our list of friends or it's going to give us back an error.
If something goes wrong, we'll do the same thing right.
If it airs, we want to throw the air because we want to stop our code, right.
If there is an error.
And then we want to get our friend John from that list of friends if there is no error.
We want to do some find right, however, is that we get them and then we want to get his posts in a
similar method as the one before we give posts John.
Right.
It gets it from whatever back end and then we give it another call back.
Posts error, if error, throw the error, if there is no error, I want the first post and then finally
I want to get the comments for the post, similar method, similar callback before we finally end up
displaying the comments.
So this was as is as much of a mouthful to say as it is to read, reading this code is really difficult
because it's this massive pyramid treelike shape of nested callbacks.
And what we affectionately refer to this as is callback hell, because this code is extensively difficult
to read and debug.
Now, with the introduction of promises, its aim was to extrapolate out a lot of the stuff, and the
reason for it is because this code here, these functions are all asynchronous functions.
We don't know when those functions will complete.
And we have to nest a bunch of other function calls inside of each other because each one depends on
the result and the return of the previous one.
In order for us to get our friends, we need our user ID, which we get after we fetch it right.
And in order to get the posts, we need to get our friend after we've gotten our friends list, after
we've gotten it from our user, like it's just this long, repetitive process.
But this is also part of our coding.
A lot of the times this is what we'll need to do in order to eventually get that right.
Final set of data we need.
So Promises has simplified this and Promises was introduced in Essex.
So let's take a look at what it is.
So let's get rid of this for now.
Now a promise is instantiated with this constructor, so we'll say, consed, my promise is equal to
new promise and then the promise is given a function.
And in this function, it gets past two things a resolve and a reject.
Now, what is the resolve and what is the reject?
Well, a promise is kind of exactly as what it's named.
It is a promise that this object will eventually have a value.
It will either be a resolved value or a rejected value.
The result value we use when our API call, for example, is successful.
Our reject call we use when our API call gives us an error, but the promise will be in a state where
it's pending until either the resolve or the reject has been called.
Now, what does that mean?
So let's say we have some.
Set timeout and said time out is just this function that takes a callback and a time as a second argument,
that time is in milliseconds.
So we're saying after one thousand milliseconds or one second, we want to run this function and the
function we want to run is resolve with the term.
I have succeeded.
By doing this, we are saying that after one second, I want this promise to call the resolve key with
this value of I have succeeded.
So when this happens, when resolve finally gets called after one second, our promise now holds this
value that we pass to the resolve.
And in order for us to access it, we have to say my promise then.
And then we passed the dot, then a function where value will be the resolved value.
So now we can finally console log the value.
Now, let's open up our terminal and run this and see.
Let's say we run our code.
We will see that after one second it logged, I have succeeded because our promise has resolved this
value.
Now, reject will work in a similar way, except in how we end up accessing it.
What we would do is let's say we have some call where we say let's say we have a conditional.
And we'll just set this to true for now, right?
If it's true, then we want to.
Resolve our code.
Otherwise, we want to reject with I have failed.
Now, if we set our conditional to false right, we will hit our block and it will reject and the only
way for us in our promised code following the instantiation to access the rejected value is to chain
on a dot catch.
With the cash, we will get the reject value.
Inside of the callback that we pass to it, so if we were to console logit.
Then now we will see we get the I have failed.
So what we're getting with this promise is control over what we want to do with asynchronous events
if they succeed or fail.
Now, sometimes if we're just using that time out, there's no reason to reject, and that's perfectly
fine if we just want to defer our promises resolution, right.
And we're using a set time out and there's no reason to reject, that's perfectly fine, too.
There's no need to call reject.
Right.
We can only just resolve, but by having a reject, we are able to control the separation of a successful
API call back from an unsuccessful API call back.
And that's the main benefit of using promises, is because when we make an API call, we don't know
whether or not that will work 100 percent of the time.
If we call a server, we don't know if that server's down.
We also don't know if we made a mistake in the parameters that we're passing in that API call.
Let's say our back end is expecting a user ID, right when you fetch at a certain end point, you don't
give it the rights or ID or you forget to give it an ID, then that API call will throw you back with
an error saying that's not right.
You didn't give me a user ID.
Well, we want to handle that differently then we want to handle a successful API call.
And that's why we have both this resolve and reject, because we're able to separate our concerns,
our successes in the then callback and our failure.
Our error is in the reject callback, which is in our catch.
There's another thing that we can do with our promises.
We're actually able to chain then together because the callback that we pass to it, whatever gets returned
right in this case, we're returning console log, which actually doesn't return anything.
It just returns undefined.
But let's say we were to return our value, but we want to add a bunch of exclamation marks to it.
Right.
So we're returning a new string plus four exclamation marks.
What then will do with that value is it will wrap it inside of a resolve promise.
That way we can change then on it.
With our new value.
And then console log that new value because.
The DOT then has wrapped this value in a resolve promise, you can only call DOT then on a resolved
promise, right?
You can't call it on a normal string.
Right.
And the only reason we're able to do so is because each dot then is wrapping the value that gets returned
from the callback, that they get passed in a resolved promise.
Now, we can do this as many times as we want, because every then will be rapping that return in a
resolved promise.
And we actually have seen promises before, if you're keen, this actually looks a lot like when we
used fetch.
If we look at this code, we see that factsheet looks very similar to the promised code we just wrote,
the reason for this is because Fetch returns us a promise.
When you call fetch, it's returning you a promise value while it makes an API request to the you are
all that you passed it.
If the endpoint, for example, throws an error, like, let's say we don't have the right permission
to access it or the server is down or we misspelled the actual end URL.
Well, instead of giving us back a value factual, actually also reject that value in the promise that
it gives back to us, if it's successful, it instead will resolve it, which is how we're able to get
a dot then response, because that response is what that fax gave us back.
We convert it to a JSON object, right, by calling Jason on response.
And as I mentioned before, it ends up wrapping that JSON value in another resolved promise, which
then passes to the next dot then which we then finally a.
So if we were to look, that's what's happening here.
That first promise is what gets return from the fetch a pending promise.
Right.
Because it's not resolved or rejected.
But once that comes back, it's successful, it resolves it internally and then the dot then gets called
because it resolved.
If we were to say, mess up this URL.
Right, so now we know it's false, right, if we catch instead, let's not conceal lock the air because
the air is quite ugly.
You can imagine we do whatever we want with the air.
Right.
But I'm just going to console log the string I have aired.
If we run, this will see that the I have air string was the one that got canceled because the catch
occurred, right, because the get call from our fetch failed and it came back with an error and internally
fetch rejected that error on our promise object.
Now, while the chaining of our promises is rather easy, there is a little bit of complexity when it
comes to figuring out how to structure our actual promise wrapping.
The good news is that with S7 there was a new function that was introduced called Async Away that allows
us to better handle how we write our asynchronous code.
So let's take a look at that now.