Welcome back, everyone.
Inside of any TypeScript project, there is a very likely chance that some of your libraries will throw
an error where you will see here, it will say could not find declaration file for module and then the
name of your third party library.
What this means is that for that library you need to most likely install a separate types library,
which essentially will add TypeScript and typing to all of the specific required exports or modules
or whatever inside of that library.
So that's generally very simple.
Most libraries have a at two types, and in fact, you'll even see that they will tell you to suggest
to try and save inside this specific library.
So they always begin with at types slash and then the name of the third party library if it's not automatically
included in the library as a dev dependency.
A lot of projects due the popularity of TypeScript will automatically install those for us.
In fact, if we go into our package dot JSON, we will see that we already have a couple of these types
files.
And the reason for this is because when we included Create React Out, it installed a lot of these typescript
files for us by default.
So all we need to do in order to get rid of this error is yarn add at types.
Slash redux lager.
And now once TypeScript has finished resolving this, we can now just rerun our nullified dev just to
make sure that everything is working.
And now that we've saved this and we go back.
There we go.
We see that the issue has gone away.
If we go back into our starts, we also see that Redux Lager has also been resolved.
And that's it.
If you ever encounter any of these type issues again, most likely just look inside the docs for that
specific third party library.
Chances are there is a correlated TypeScript module for that library that you need to install.
So that's just one additional thing about TypeScript migrations that you've got to keep in mind.
I'll see you in the next video.