Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to migrate the car context over from using you state and use the fact to
use reducer.
So I want to discuss use reducer strategies when it comes to migrating some of these more complicated
contexts like we have.
To quickly go over what we did.
We know that primarily inside of our car provider, we have a bunch of use states that track for individual
values that we then read from the car context.
These are the is cart open, the car items, the cart count and the cart total.
What we've determined is that we are exporting out from this context different methods that a user can
fire or a developer can fire in order to update the current cart items.
And then whenever these car items get updated, what we do is we then also derive new car count and
new car total and then respectively set them from their use state setter functions.
So what we need to do instead with a reducer is we want to extrapolate out these four readable values
into a reducer because reducers only, only, only store readable values.
So how are we going to do this?
Well, first, what we need to do is we need to think about the shape of our final output.
So the easiest way to do that is to actually create the initial state object first.
And this initial state object is going to include all of the readable values that we currently have
inside of our context, because the context is just storing these values individually inside of their
own.
You state they also already have their default values.
So this initial state just gives us the object that we need to keep track of when it comes to what our
actual reducer should return.
So let's create that reducer now.
This is going to be our cart reducer.
And as you remember, it's a function that gets the state as well as the action object.
And then what we need to do is we need to structure off the two properties that come on the action,
which are the type and the payload.
Once we have the type and payload, now we determine with these two values from the action, what do
we need to return as the updated state?
So here, when we start thinking about this, oftentimes, you know, you need a reducer and it gets
a little confusing.
So it's important that you just set up the reducer first.
You know, you need a switch statement and the switch is going to be off the type, you know, that
you're going to have some default.
And the default is most likely always going to be us throwing a new era where the error is going to
be us saying un handled.
Type of and then the type in heart reducer.
And the reason, of course, as we do this is because our cart reducer should only be receiving actions
that we have accounted for.
If there is for some reason, we're getting an action that we have not accounted for.
While we shouldn't be receiving that action, or it tells us that we have written code that we have
not covered, if we're expecting this reducer to receive an action and we need to respond to it appropriately.
After this.
Now we need to think about our cases.
So when you think about the case of what you're going to do in your reducer, here is a very important
distinction about your reducer and a best practice as well.
Your reducer should not handle any business logic, meaning that inside of a reducer, if we were to
receive some items, some of you might be thinking, Oh, let me just create actions, for example,
like an add to cart action.
And this action should receive or should be in the shape of the action object or the type, let's just
say is add to cart like this.
And then the item that I'm adding as the payload is going to be the item to add.
Let's just assume that this might be a valid way to create this action.
There is no problem with us dispatching out an action like this.
This is perfectly readable code.
But the reason why you don't want to do this is because now inside of your reducer, your reducer,
in order to appropriately respond to this, might have to be something like this.
Well, what you do is you then inside say, okay, I need to figure out what these new car items are.
So that's the add card item.
So I might say something like return back, of course, but their state and then car items points to
add to cart item and then the payload as we know, the payload is the item to add and then add to cart.
In fact, we can even here we know that our add cart item needs also the cart items.
So we can even just say, hey, give me the state BCAA items that is currently there.
And then, of course, pass the payload.
Now, this logic may work, but the problem is that this makes your reducer a lot harder to read.
So what you should do instead is actually make it so that your payload should already be whatever you
need to update.
Because now, if you think about it inside of add to CART, we also need to update the cart total.
And the cart count.
So how are we going to do this?
We're going to write additional logic to take the output of this item inside of this code somewhere
so that we can conditionally decide, Oh, we need cart totals and the cart total is going to take this
car items, reduce function off of the new items we're getting in which we receive back from add to
cart item.
You see how it already gets really convoluted.
We have to figure out all these conditional checks so that the right logic is happening here.
Right.
You can see how we do new items like this is equal to add items to cart and then of course we need to
get the new cart total.
Like this is equal to new items.
Reduce as we wrote before.
And we just have to then update it here.
But this makes your reducer, as you can see, really bloated and hard to read.
This makes it very difficult as well for us to make these changes, because you can imagine if we had
multiple case statements, we're looking at a giant reducer function and we want to keep our functions
as light and tight as possible.
Even if the reducer functions, all this reducer should care about is really just updating the state.
It should not worry about anything regarding how to update that state, as in like what values, what
business logic that state should end up in.
Instead, that should all be passed to us.
Our reducer should simply be the one saying, Hey, I got some payload, I'm going to update it with
the appropriate values.
So to do that, what we need to do is split up some of this logic.
So to split the logic, you want to think about dispatching an action that already includes all of the
values that this needs.
Now, before we start thinking about it being add to CART, that was just my example.
You want to think about the type here.
What's the type of action we want to set?
Well, we can actually take inspiration from what we've written here inside of our typical hook based
flow.
We have these values that we get from state and then what we do is we respond when the items update
so that we actually generate the new total and we generate the new cart count and then we set them respectively.
So instead, technically, we could include cart count, cart total and the new items all inside of
one action.
And as we can tell, based on our logic, it's generic.
If cart items changes, then we generate a new count, whether it's clearing an item from the cart,
whether it's adding a quantity to a cart item, whether it's decreasing the quantity of a cart item,
the cart count function and the cart total functions are all generic enough.
It's really these actual adding, removing and clearing that are unique.
So in this case, what we can do is we can actually create a generic action that says, Hey, whenever
cart items get set, then what I want you to do, I want you to update the state with the payload.
And this payload is going to contain the shape that we want.
So it's going to have the car items on it or the new card items.
It's going to have the car count on it.
And it's also going to have the cart total.
And these are all going to be the new values that we finally want to store.
And that's what we should do inside of this code.
So that is going to be my challenge to figure out how to create a new function that can encapsulate
all this so that you can dispatch a correct action that will then update according to what we've written
here.
So give a crack at that.
You're going to have to write the function in here.
And just to give you a bit of a hint, it's going to be something I like to call it, something like
update card items, reducer.
This is a function that is just going to receive the new card items.
You can even call them new car items if you want to be explicit.
And what they're going to do is they're going to have to utilize the code we already have inside of
our effects.
And then respectively update the actual.
Reduce our value.
Where you call this function.
That's my challenge to you as well.
So figure out.
Based on what I've mentioned here, how you're going to split up this logic and write out this function.
And then next video, we'll do it together.
I'll see you in the next video.