Welcome back, everyone.
In the last video we learned about how to type values in this video, we are going to start typing out
this actual component where we're receiving these props.
So one thing I want to talk about is typing objects as well as typing functions.
Let's start with typing functions.
When we think about this functional component, this is really, as we know, a function that has a
specific return of some kind of HDMI element.
Other than that, nothing prevents it from being just a normal function.
When you want to type a function.
The way that you have to type the signature.
So here, let's say we were typing some kind of function.
We don't actually know what this function returns yet.
This is just a placeholder for now.
But as we know, we're typing.
We use the colon.
And then here we need to define the actual function itself.
So if you think about the conditions of a function, important things of the function are the parameters
that it receives and then the return value of the function.
A function only cares about the types internally to itself.
When it receives properties, it has to receive the actual types that it's expecting to receive.
So you want to type the parameters coming in as far as TypeScript is concerned.
Whatever happens in the function is not TypeScript business.
But what comes out of that function as a return value, that is TypeScript business, because TypeScript
needs to ensure that whatever you're returning from the function matches the type that you tell is going
to return.
So the actual syntax of typing is going to be a curly bracket representing the parameters and then a
fat arrow followed by the actual return type.
Now let's say we have a function and this function gets three values A, B and C.
Similarly, what you're going to type is going to also be A, B and C.
But here, what you're going to do is you are going to define the types themselves for these parameter
values.
So first, we actually need to match each variable in the parameter A, B and C.
What you're then going to do is for these parameters, you're also going to use a colon, and this colon
is going to say what these values are expected to be.
So here, let's say for a it's a string, let's say for B, it's a number.
And let's say for C, it's a Boolean value.
What you need to return from this is now dependent on what the actual return of the function is.
Let's say, for example, after all of these different calculations, what we return back is also a
boolean.
Let's say it's true, for example.
What you need to do here is that you need to return a boolean so you can just state that the value you
can expect to come back from this function is going to be a boolean.
But we also have functions that don't have returns.
Sometimes we just run a function and it doesn't actually return anything.
If that's the case, then what we want to say is that we returned back.
Void and with void.
Void is a special type that essentially says, Hey, this is going to be nothing.
It's very much like undefined in JavaScript.
You just expect no return back, no specific type.
And now with this, that's how you type A function.
There are more complexities of typing functions that we will uncover as we go along, but this is pretty
much the basics as far as we are concerned.
So now the reason why we need to learn how to type a function is because we have these three types where
the third one is a function because it's a handler.
But what you'll also notice is that this is actually a structure statement inside of our function.
So what we're de structuring off is actually one variable called props.
And props, as we know, is a object.
So how do we type objects?
Inside of TypeScript, you have two options for typing objects, and they're very unique.
You actually have to define them ahead of time as either a type or as a interface.
Now timezone interfaces are very similar.
They used to be more different when TypeScript first came out, but over time their overlap is significantly
greater now.
The key golden rule to remember about types versus interfaces is that interfaces are extendable very
similar to class components.
If you remember with class components, you can extend one class component from another and inherit
all of that class components, original methods.
Similarly with interfaces, you can actually do the same thing.
So let's say we were to define an interface.
First, use the keyword interface and then you have to write the name of this interface that you want
to call it.
So for us, if it was search box properties, then we would say I because all interfaces start with
an AI to designate that they are a interface.
I search box props.
This is some kind of object.
Then you put a curly braces defining to this typescript file that this is now interface.
The inside is going to represent the shape of the actual object you're trying to define.
So here, because we're looking at class named placeholder and on change handler, we would say class
name.
Now class name needs to point not to a value, but the actual type, which we know is a string.
So that is going to be how you type these key value pairs inside of TypeScript with an interface.
Similarly, we could say placeholder.
Which is also a string.
Now, if this place holder is an optional property, you can put a question mark here.
This will now tell TypeScript that what you can get here is either string or null.
It's essentially the equivalent because with an optional placeholder value, we're essentially declaring
to TypeScript, Hey, you can expect a string, but I might not always give it to you.
Now as for the actual on chain Chandler.
The reason why I started this conversation about types and interfaces is because I was talking about
interfaces are extensible.
So what I mean by this.
Okay, here we have our props.
We've typed two of them.
We haven't typed the on change handler.
We have this interface that defines the object shape and the corresponding values that we're expecting
if we do colon.
And then I search box props here.
So we're saying that the props that you're going to receive is of this type of I search box props.
You'll notice that we see on change handler does not exist on our type.
What we could do, of course, is simply just add it as the third parameter here inside of this interface.
But when I say that you can extend essentially you can do this actually a couple of ways.
Let's say, for example, we had some random additional interface.
Let's call it change handler.
So I change handler props.
And this takes some on change handler.
As a prop and what it receives is some actual function definition.
So let's say it's a which is a string and then it returns back void.
Let's use that as the example.
What you can do is you can actually say interface I search box prompts extends I change handler and
now what you'll see happens is that this I search box Bob is now passing because what happens is that
or I search box props is extending what ever was inside of here so this is actually getting added into
this I search box props props as well.
So we're inheriting whatever additional props were on this.
I change handler props as far as typing is concerned.
Another thing that you can do with interfaces is you can actually overload them.
So if we write this twice, TypeScript under the hood, it is going to also combine these together so
that your AI search box prompts now contains all three of these values.
This is designed pretty much mostly for object oriented programming style inside of JavaScript.
So most likely you're writing Node or you're writing some angular code, which is also more object oriented.
But the main idea with TypeScript here is that it's giving you this ability to write interfaces that
are extensible as well as composable through this overloading, which is where you're saying, hey,
I'm going to define this more than one time.
I just want you to combine all of them together into one final shape.
This is interfaces.
The alternative is to write types.
Types are very similar to interfaces, but we lack both of these functionalities.
We do not have the ability to overload and we do not have the ability to extend.
So we'll talk about types in the next video.