Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to type out our middleware.
So our custom middleware is the logs.
We want to rename this to logger that to us.
And as you can probably guess, since this is a middleware, we're going to need that middleware type
that we had seen from before.
Middleware, of course, coming from Redux.
What we're going to do with this middleware is we need to pass it some arguments, one of which is going
to be the root state value that we had created ourselves.
This middleware is going to be of the type middleware.
Now, when you hover over middleware, what is it that it takes?
Well, first, it takes some template dispatch extension.
This is an extra dispatch signature added to this middleware.
And you add it essentially as a type.
So if you want to add more onto your dispatch, you can do so.
But ours barely does that.
We are never going to really modify the dispatch with this middleware.
It means that if you want to add that functionality onto your dispatches, you're able to do so.
Some libraries like to do that.
We definitely don't need that.
So for us, we're just going to pass an empty object or an empty type saying that we're not extending
it at all.
The second argument is going to be the state.
This is the state of this middleware, and we are receiving the root state.
Third argument we don't need to pass anything for.
It's the type of dispatch that doesn't matter.
We're not changing anything.
We can just leave that empty.
And there we go.
We've typed out our custom middleware.
We're done typing everything inside of our Redux folder except for our sagas, and we'll learn how to
do that in the next video.
I'll see you there.