Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, I want to discuss a little bit more about these rerun ring cycles and how it reinforces
what we kind of already know about React and Re rendering.
But it's still good to really understand this mental model.
So let's walk through this here inside of our navigation component.
We know that we're leveraging this current user that we get from use context.
But in order for me to show you a couple of things, I'm going to change up how some of these components
are calling different things.
And you just have to follow me here.
I'm going to stop console.log and current user in our navigation.
What I'm going to do instead is inside of our sign up form.
I'm first going to just console dot log out.
The word hit.
And what I'm also going to do is show you inside of this component.
So when we refresh and run our application for the first time, when our sign up component mounts,
we see a hit from sign up.
This is perfectly expected.
What I also want to do is I want to turn on paint flashing.
So this is from the rendering tab.
If you remember inside of the three dots down in more tools when you select rendering, this will show
up and then I want to click paint flashing.
The reason why I want to do this is because I want to show you.
Right now, our sign up component, despite being nested inside of our top level context component,
remember user provider is wrapping up inside of app is sign in, sign up navigation.
Everything is a child of app.
But what you'll notice is that despite the fact that when we sign in, we know we're setting user inside
of that top level provider.
What you see, though, is that hit does not rerun.
This is just the initial call when we mounted for the first time.
So clearly, this component is not getting called at all.
What happens if we actually took into the sign up form?
So I'm going to keep the console.log hit, actually, and what I'm going to do is I'm going to bring
in the use context hook and I'm also going to bring in.
The user context object.
And what I want to do is I just want to hook into it something to say Val is equal to use context user
context.
Now what happens?
Well, because now I've hooked into the context.
As long as user context values change, this component is going to rerun.
So what we should see.
Is that when we refresh?
Everything mounts for the first time, of course.
But we see that initial hit value that comes from our sign up for.
And what will also happen is that when I sign in to my user and the provider updates notice that hit
gets called again.
The reason for this is because the sign up form is hooked into the context using the use context.
Even though we didn't do anything with any of those values, React doesn't care.
The fact that you're hooked in means that this component needs to rerun this function.
At the very least, that represents our sign up component.
However, notice that none of the actual portions of the DOM updated despite the fact that React reran
the code, it did not actually really render anything on the DOM.
And the reason for this, of course, is because nothing changed on the Dom.
So this is where that virtual dom and the actual reconciliation steps that we walk the way back in the
beginning of this course prove itself again.
So this is one important thing.
I want you to know if you have multiple components that are all listening to a context, even though
they don't use the actual values, for example, just as we see here, we're just initializing the value.
We don't actually do anything with it.
The fact that you're hooked into the context will cause react to rerun your function.
Now, it doesn't mean that it will re render anything to the dump, because it only will, if you're
GSX values, actually update based on this value.
However, what you still need to think about is the fact that all of the code up until that return statement
is still getting called.
That is a very important thing to know.
The fact that this code is getting called could be a performance problem if you have hundreds of components
that are all hooked into a context.
So this is just something to really consider and think about.
But now that at least we understand that the way that react decides to re render things is still within
the exact same knowledge that we had about components and how they re render things, really not much
has changed.
You can kind of see use context as just a glorified hook into another component that will re render
its subsequent hooked components whenever this component updates in some way.
And the only way that this component updates is if we trigger it to update using you, state use effect,
whatever that we designate, and we'll talk more about this in the next upcoming videos.
But I just want to clarify this particular point about components hooking into context and getting recalled
or not necessarily rendered, but at least the functions getting rerun.
So now the one to stand this, let's get rid of this code that we have here inside of sign up form.
We're going to keep this code right here because we will need to update sign up form.
But that's my challenge to you.
I want you to utilize use context and user context for sign up form.
So also set the user when we successfully authenticate with email and password.
So do that, and then I'll see you in the next video.