Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to discuss the use callback hook further.
In order for us to do that, we're going to have to modify this a little bit.
So in order for us to modify this component, I want to duplicate this button.
And what I'm going to do is I'm just going to say that this button has the text update.
What happens here is that we know our component will essentially rerun and render every time items updates.
So we're going to rely on that in order to make sure that we understand when our functional component
is being rerun.
Inside of go to check out handler.
I'm going to change this function.
And what I'm going to do is I want to log out some value that we store inside of you state.
So I'm going to bring in the U.S. and I'm just going to call this temp value.
And I'm going to initialize it with the value a.
What I'm going to do inside of this callback is just console.log the temp value.
And then what I'm going to do on this button is that whenever you click this button, I'm going to set
temp to be.
And that's all I'm going to do.
Now what's going to happen?
Well, let's save our coat.
And let's come back to our application.
Here's an application.
What I want to do is click, go to checkout.
As we know, we are console logging out our temp value.
Here.
What's going to happen is that when I run this function.
And add a bunch of items.
What's happening again is that our application is re rendering, not our application, but our component.
Go to check out what's still log a nothing change there.
If I hit update, though.
Now I know that temp has been updated to beat, but every time I click go to checkout it's still logging
a.
And the reason for this, despite all of these changes, is because the function is memorized, meaning
that the scope of all of the values inside of this function are all being kept and memorized.
React doesn't know that it needs to update this because temp on the outside has changed.
Even though we called Septem, a React has re rendered this component every time in the re render cycle.
It sees this call and it says, Oh, this is a memoirs callback because it used the use callback hook.
I don't need to re initialize this function ever.
The only way that that can happen is when you add that to the dependency array.
Now if we save this and when we come back to the application, if we refresh.
Now on initialization.
When I click the go to checkout, I get a when I click update and then I click go to checkout.
Now notice that it says be.
So this is an important error that you want to understand about your dependency array with use callback.
If you anticipate anything inside of this function that it needs to rely on in order to run the purpose
of this actual function, make sure you include it inside of your dependency array, because if you
don't, then react simply, just memorizes the value.
And that is how this you'd call that works.
I hope now through this example, you get a better idea of what it is that's actually happening under
the hood with this use callback hook.
So now let's just revert our code back and now we've got idea.
At the very least, you can now go through your application and you can wrap these inside of a use callback
if you want to, just to see and just to work with it to understand how to add things to the dependency
array and get your code to work consistently.
But it's very straightforward.
The main idea is that you're memorizing the function, not the output of the function, but the function.
So that's it.
Now that we get that, let's move on to the next video.