Welcome back, everyone.
So now that we have Iraq, Rotterdam and we have an idea of how routing works, let's just go over with
our final application what it is that we need to build.
We know that inside of our actual application, we've simply implemented this component.
The directory component, what we need to do now is we need to separate the couple pages that we have.
We know that this directory component primarily lives on the home page, which is the page that you
have when you land on the website.
We know that there's also a shop page which will render this directory of all of the different collections
that are available.
And then we also know that deeper down, we have this further library page that contains the products
for a related category.
So what we want to do now is we want to think about what we want to break up.
So currently we have no pages, no routing set up.
Everything lives on the main page.
And even on this main page, we notice that this navigation component also is intended to persist while
we navigate through the website.
So this kind of harkens back to that lesson where we were talking about how routing works and what we're
essentially saying is that the home page should be the component that renders when your URL is just
the base you are.
This navigation bar should always persist, no matter what different page you navigate to, and then
at the very least, we'll have a couple of other pages based on this route changing.
So let's start implementing some of this stuff with React Router Don.
Let's go back to our application in order for us to confirm and tell our application that we want to
use React Router Dom.
What we need to do is we need to actually wrap this entire application in a broader component that react
router Dom gives us.
I want to do it in the index chassis because this is where we render the app as its entirety.
So I want to wrap it as well in this same file.
To do so, we need to first do is we need to import the browser router component.
From React router, Dom.
If you're wondering why there's a browser router, the browser router is the generic router, it leverages
the URL in order to keep track of the history of where the user is navigating through.
And it behaves, as you typically would expect, any kind of routing based on URL to behave.
There are other forms of routers inside of Iraq, Rotterdam, but you won't really use them a lot.
And at least for our application, most of it is going to be working with the browser router.
The other variation ones you can take a look at once you understand essentially how routing works overall.
There's just a couple nuance detail differences between them, so it's still relevant for you, primarily
right now just to focus on the browser router.
Now, the browser router, as I mentioned, is a component, so that means it behaves like a component.
There's an open tag and a closing tag.
And what we want to do is we want to make that the parents of our entire application.
So we want to make sure that we save this and what happens now is that because we've wrapped our application
component inside of our browser router component, we can access all of the different features that
come in rack router Dom specific to this browser router that is now going to control our routing inside
of our nested application.
If that sounds confusing, don't worry, it'll make sense once we start going through it.
So let's start thinking about what we need to break out right now.
App represents our entire application.
However, it renders the directory directly.
We don't want that anymore.
Instead, now we want to render a home page and the directory kind of just lives on the home page.
So in order to do this, what we want to do is we want to actually set up some components to help us
and these components.
We're actually going to make a new folder for and we're going to say that these are our roots.
Roots is a folder that will hold all of our root top level components.
So let's do one.
So we understand what we're talking about here.
I'm going to make another folder inside of the Roots folder called home, because that's the root we're
trying to make, and I'm just going to call this home doc component Dutch RSX.
This is not some specific naming structure you have to follow for rack right or Dom to work, but this
is just the way that I like to break up this application.
So it's very clear to me what the separation of concerns is because the components inside of the roots
are related to roots.
They're not these generic components that we're building that we can use in numerous places.
Essentially, these home components are these root level components are really only used for routing,
and I'll talk about more about that once we get to the portion where we use them.
But first of all, we want to do inside of our home component that I've just set up here is we want
to actually replicate what we had inside of our app because this right now reflects almost the entirety
of our application homepage.
So just copy this entire file over.
Paste this in.
And instead of app, let's call this home.
Similarly, we want to make sure that we make sure to export home as the default.
So nothing new here.
This is really the only difference.
Another thing we might have to do is we have to fix this relative pally, because right now we're probably
not actually going to the correct place.
So what we want to do is leverage the auto complete, and from here we know that we're going to see
home.
What we want to do is go to components.
So there we are, pointing to our components folder and then that in turn will point to directory and
get the directory component file.
So here this home component is really all we're looking for.
So just to make sure it's still working, what we're going to do for our entirety of our app now is
just import home.
Routes, home home component.
And instead of rendering all of this, I want to just render.
The home component.
This is just a test of this component works, remember, even though it's nested inside of the Roots
folder, it's still just a generic component.
It's just a functional component that returns what we had before inside of our OPG's.
But now we're just exporting it as a component and then just returning it.
So it's just an extra step of rendering an additional component, but everything is the exact same.
Let's just go back to our application.
Make sure everything is working.
Everything is still working.
So let's go back.
What we want to do now is we now want to actually leverage routing so that we know how the routing works.
With this actually being the thing that only renders when the URL is pointing to home.
So to do this, what we need to do is we need to import the roots component from REAC Rotterdam.
So Roots is a specific component that we get back.
And we also need to import a root component is with these two components that we can actually assemble
the routing at our application level.
So I want to take roots and just as we did, we want to wrap.
Anything that is going to be reportable inside of this Root's component.
Let me just fix this bracket here.
And fix them in.
So what essentially routes does is that it allows this application to register these root level components
that will then in turn render a specific component when it matches this specific route that you're looking
for.
So how do you know what route you're trying to match?
Well, the way you do that is you actually give it a specific path.
Variable path is going to be a string and the string is going to try to match whatever you give inside
of it.
So when you want to match, say, just a slash.
This, in turn, will say OK when I match path slash, meaning that because this is at the base you
are, I'll level when we just land on the URL, then I'm going to match.
So you can kind of see slash as in, this is the end of the path we're trying to match there.
So this is the relative path.
And what I'm going to say here is that the moment this matches, I want you to now render this element
element in this particular case is the component.
And this is going to take literally a rendered component and I'm going to render in the home component.
So now I want to save this.
And what we should expect to see in our application is that nothing has changed.
So here we see everything still working.
Let's just also quickly open up our developer counsel.
We see there are some genetic errors for dev tools or not errors, but warnings.
So everything is actually still working as we expect.
But in case you're a little confused about this, because we learn a lot very quickly and we have to
kind of scaffold some of this out before I can deep dive into this topic, let's just take a look at
this.
As I mentioned, if you want routing to appear in your application here, we have to say, Oh, there
are these routes that I'm going to leverage and show you in these components.
You're saying that by using this routes component, I expect there to be some routes inside.
And the moment you match a route where the path value matches the string, then I want you to render
this element.
So let's be even more experimental.
I want it to specifically be when it's at home, then I want you to render the home element.
Here we go back now we actually see.
Remember, we're on the base route, which, as I mentioned, is the single slash, as you can see here.
We, in fact, even get a warning that says no roots match for location slash, which makes sense because
we are not rendering anything for this route.
We are trying to match slash home.
So if we navigate instead to slash home, here we see the component render.
So now we can see how we're rendering specific components based on the route.
As in the earlier that we are specifically navigating through.
So here we are enabling that functionality.
As I mentioned, I want you to render specific components based on the URL, which is exactly what we're
doing.
So if you're a little confused, don't worry, we'll do a lot more practice and we'll do a lot more
experimenting with this library because it's a little complicated if you've never come across routing
before.
So don't worry if any of this was confusing.
Rewatch the parts of this video where we walk through implementing these routes because there's a couple
steps and they're all pretty and crucial.
We'll definitely explore them, though, in the upcoming videos.
So this is how we set up a home page.
Let's continue in the next video.