Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, I want to dive a little deeper into this observer pattern that we're now seeing from
this on off state changed.
So let's talk about it in the sense of thinking in streams, when you think about a stream, you can
think about a sequence of asynchronous events, such as a click when a user clicks onto a button or
on the website.
If you are listening for that, click.
You actually don't know when that user makes any of those clicks.
Because a user might click, they might wait five seconds and then click again.
They might wait one second.
They might make one hour.
The concept of an asynchronous stream is just one where it's a sequence of most likely the same kind
of event, but just with an indefinite amount of time between them.
So here you can visualize it as if there is a start of a stream.
So let's talk about this click stream and then the user clicks.
Three seconds pass by.
They click again.
10 minutes passed by.
They click.
And then suddenly, let's say they click three times in a row really quickly.
Still subsequent clicks, though, but just with very short intervals of time between it.
And then maybe they click one more time after 30 seconds and so on and so forth and so on and so forth.
The idea with the stream is really just that.
It's a sequence of events meaning that there is an order to them in time.
As I mentioned before, the key thing here being that there is a variable amount of time between these
events and that is really the main thing about streams.
The part of why this is interesting as a pattern is because we are able to react to each of these events
inside of this stream.
So you want to see the stream as a observable.
There are libraries such as art suggest that essentially encapsulate this concept.
But the main thing for you to focus on is that this is just some kind of asynchronous stream of events.
The part where you interact with it is where you use a listener and a listener is really just a class
or some kind of object that has three key methods on it.
The first is the next method.
Next is called every time a new event in the stream happens.
And what will happen is that that event will get passed to this next function.
And then for us, we're really just saying, Hey, here's a callback is expecting to receive an event.
And then what we do with it is up to our code next is really just pointing to our callback, which is
really what that callback was when we passed you on ofstate changed.
This is exactly the next callback.
There is also a error callback, and this error callback just says, Oh, do something whenever we throw
an error.
And then finally, there is a complete callback.
So for streams, streams might actually close, meaning that at some point we might say, Hey, I know
I'm done sending out events from this stream.
So let me just tell everybody that there's no more events coming.
If the stream is open, we can anticipate more stuff to come.
If it's closed, it's most likely complete.
So how this works is that we need to in some way subscribe from our listener to the stream.
And this subscription is really just saying, Hey, let me start listening to what happens in the stream,
and you can listen at any point when the stream is going, because remember, this stream is happening
in time, so it's possible that maybe we are listening at the start of the stream, meaning no events
have triggered yet.
So in this case, what's going to happen?
The first event fires.
It goes to our next function, so our next function gets called.
Similarly, the next one fires.
We call the next function again.
The next event fires, we call the next function again and so on and so forth for the remainder of the
upcoming events.
The one thing to note here is that the moment that this stream, let's say it's done, though it will
complete, which we will learn.
So our listener will find that out from the stream because the screen will actually say, Hey, I'm
done.
And the moment it says it's done, it's going to fire the complete method of every listener that's listening
to the stream.
So here complete runs and maybe based on whatever callback we have there, it will do something to clean
up or whatever it needs to do in order to know that, Oh, I'm done using this stream.
But as I mentioned before, we might actually subscribe when a couple events have already happened.
Let's imagine that in our stream, two events have already happened, maybe 30 seconds ago.
By the time we subscribe, we will not get those two events because they're in the past, it's already
over.
What we can do now is just start listening for the new events.
So when the third event happens in the stream, then we'll catch it because we've subscribed already.
And similarly, we'll call next and then any future event that happens.
We will also call next on and be aware of them.
So this is one important thing to know about subscription models.
The other thing is that similarly, as before, when it completes, the complete callback gets called.
So as far as this model is concerned, it's really just understanding the nuances of the timing of these
streams.
But generally speaking, the actual logic is very simple.
You get some event you fire next, once it's done.
Once the stream is complete, you fire complete.
Oftentimes, we don't fire it either.
This is just a pattern that emerges.
So essentially, as long as you're subscribing with some object that has these three methods next,
Aaron complete and they all three point two different callbacks.
The actual observer stream will be the one that actually will call these methods to whatever is subscribed
to them.
So imagine that we had a complete stream, for example, in this particular case, you might subscribe
to an already completed stream.
If that happens, you will not get any of these events because once again, all of these events have
already done and the stream itself is already completed.
So now.
Let's talk about this Arafat method.
How does this happen in extreme events?
Let's imagine one event has fire so far.
We subscribe, and now we start listening for subsequent events after the first one.
Remember, as I mentioned, the first events fired.
We have no knowledge of it.
When we subscribe, let's say a new event happens, event two again, we call next and then we call
next again.
But then suddenly, let's say something breaks in the stream.
For some reason, we get some kind of error.
You can imagine with API calls, asynchronous events, there are chances that maybe there's a network
delay, maybe there's a server error.
Something happens in this process.
When that happens, we get informed by the stream that there is an error, then our listener is in turn
going to call the error method.
So this is very similar to you can think about it as if you have a promise with a promise.
When you get an error, it'll reject this error.
Callback that we have is pretty much the same thing.
So this is what's really good about this model, because essentially now you're able to react consistently
in this way from these streams.
The last thing I want to mention is that a stream can have any number of listeners, any number of different
listeners can have different reactions to what happens in the stream.
But each of them just need to subscribe to the stream.
So whenever we were working with our on off state changed, all we were saying is that, hey, I want
to start listening to on off state change the moment we invoked the function and we passed that the
callback.
Similarly, with that on off state change, we can also pass that an air callback and a complete callback
as arguments three and four.
We're just really using the first two arguments, if you remember inside of our code base.
If you want to think about us opening up the listener with this method.
The moment we call this method, we're saying, Hey, create a listener for me using this callback.
So what's happening here is that this on off state changed invocation is actually behind the scenes,
creating a listener for us.
You can imagine it like that.
And on here, it's going to take the next value and set it as our callback.
We can actually call it with more parameters.
As I was mentioning here, you can see that in that list, we were looking at the off the next or observer,
and this is the callback trigger on change.
As I mentioned, there is an error parameter we can pass as number three and a complete a callback as
number four.
So here you can imagine that we could have passed an error callback if we wanted to and then a completed
callback.
So this is pretty much just that same model.
It's just that behind the scenes, this on-off state change is just building out this actual.
Listener model for us, so this is really all there is to know about this observer pattern.
It's honestly rather simple once you wrap your mind around this concept of an asynchronous stream,
but once you really just understand how it works as far as you're concerned, all you know is that you
need to give it a call back.
And as I mentioned before, we need to also clean up this listener.
So that's why it returns us back a unsubscribe.
So essentially, what happens is that on this unsubscribe method, it will clean up this actual method.
And oftentimes with this unsubscribe, also it will call if you were to pass it a complete callback.
It will also call that which is why when you hover over, you see that the program completed callback
trigger when observer is removed, and that often also happens in the cleanup phase now that we've finished
up with everything we need when it comes to isolating our authentication.
What I want you to do before moving on is just commit your code.
Push it up and then join me in the next video.
I'll see you there.