Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
In this video, I want to quickly show you how you can get your environment set up so that you can coat
along inside of this course if you are on a Windows computer.
Now, in the Windows computer, there's a couple of different terminal options you have the main one
that I think is very useful is the one that comes integrated with Visual Studio Code.
The benefit of this as well is that because I use visual studio code as my editor, if you're unfamiliar
with EDS, you can easily use visual studio code and you'll be able to follow everything that I'm doing
with my editor because we both would end up using the exact same editor.
So in order to use visual studio code, I'm going to paste for you a link inside of your resources that
you can use to get the talent.
So simply hit download for Windows and wait for the download to complete.
Once your visual pseudocode finishes downloading, simply go to the folder that you set it in.
So in my case, it's in my downloads folder.
And just simply double click to install it.
Now, inside of here, you're going to be asked for a license agreement, so simply accept the agreement
and then you'll have these boxes that you can check.
Now, I would probably check all the ones that are unchecked, but what this allows you to do is access
visual studio code through different settings on your computer so you can use it to open up your projects.
Simply hit next and then install.
Once it's finished, we can simply launch Visual Studio code and then inside a visual studio code.
You now have your editor.
So in order for you to actually open up the terminal that I have here, simply go up to the terminal
tab and hit new terminal.
And this will now open up the terminal that you have by default set up inside of your Windows computer.
If you have installed other shells, you'll be able to select them from the dropdown.
But in my case, I only have power, which is the default shell that comes with the computer.
So what I'm going to do now is I am going to actually install a different one called Get Back Now with
Get Getback.
You are now able to access the underlying get projects and give folders that we will use throughout
this course because we want to push to GitHub.
So use the link that I provided for you and simply download.
Now, this will download this the same way that we just downloaded Visual Studio code and just save
it wherever you want to, once it's finished downloading, go to the folder where it's downloaded to
and simply run it as well.
Now, this will ask you if you allow it to make changes now you want to hit.
Yes, because this will install bash instead of power shell, which comes with much easier to understand
controls.
Now, here it I'll ask you if you wanted to allow you to install different things, and in my case,
I just want to add another icon on the desktop so it's easy to launch.
And then by default, it'll ask you whatever you want to use, so usually them is the one that most
people are comfortable with or visual studio code, which we just downloaded.
If you want it to be the one that opens whenever you want to modify files and text files.
But we'll explore that a little later.
For now, I'm just going to stick to them and hit next.
And then I want to run it from my command line.
And then I want to also use open SSL in order to validate my get, you can just hit next for this.
And for here, you can also use get bashes, own minty terminal emulator.
So this one is entirely up to you.
I personally, I'm going to use the get provided minty and then I'm just going to hit next.
Again, experimental is up to you.
Whether or not you want to opt in or not to these new commands, it does not really matter.
I'm not going to opt in.
And I'm just going to wait for the install to finish now, once everything's installed, simply hit
finish and then go back to your visual studio code and close it.
So we need to actually access the new terminal because we have a new shell.
So to do this, just reopen Visual Studio code after you've closed it.
And then inside of this dropdown, what we're going to do is we are going to hit select default shell.
And we are going to choose our get back.
Now, this will switch our main terminal whenever we add a new one or whenever we open our terminal
to use our new get Batia and the way to do that is now you simply hit this plus icon, which you'll
see is now Basche, and then you just close your old power shell by switching back to it and hitting
the garbage can.
And now you have Basche set up as your main terminal.
Now, if you see these colors, when you switch to bash, that means that you are running the Mincy
emulator, if you remember in those settings when we were installing GET.
So this is actually a quality of life emulator.
It just makes different things in the terminal prettier as well as easier to understand and reason about.
You can, of course, run other emulators if you want, such as DSL, which is what I have when you
watch my course, but in our case, Menti is fine for windows.
Now, what we need to install next is node.
Node is actually what's going to allow us to run JavaScript inside of our terminal.
What we have to do is we have to go to this website of no jobs and simply download the installer equivalent
to whatever bit your windows is.
So minus 64, I'm just going to download the 64 bit one.
Once it's finished downloading, open the folder and then just run the node installer.
Now, node is what we need in order for us to run our JavaScript as well as manage our JavaScript packages
for all of the applications that will be building.
So simply hit next, accept the licensing agreement install node.
And then hit next again and finally install.
Now note also comes with NPM, which is no package manager, and we want to yes here as well when it
asks if it allows us to make changes to our device.
And no package manager is what allows us to manage different versions of note now the versions of note
all come with different features and note is always being updated.
But we want to just use the latest version of Noad at the time of when you watch this video.
And usually that's what this link will recommend you as well.
It'll try and give you the latest version.
So simply wait until our note is finished installing and once it's finished, simply had finish.
Now we have to make sure that node and AMPM are properly installed on our computer.
So the way we do that is we just have to close our visual studio code and reopen it again because we
need to see and load a new version of our terminal.
And once our terminal comes in, we simply type in no dash.
And we should see some number, so this will tell us the version of note that we currently have installed.
If we had NPM Dashkova, we'll see the version of NPM we have installed.
Now that you have NPM a node, you can actually run through this course, the only thing is that I use
yarn as my packaging manager instead of NPM.
Now, yarn and NPM are pretty much the same thing.
The only thing was that there was a period of time where NPM was kind of buggy.
And what Facebook did was they created yarn so that it was a more efficient package manager.
But NPM has since then caught up.
Now you can easily Google all of the commands that you need that are the same replacements for what's
used in yarn if you want to just use NPM.
But if you want to use yarn, I'm going to show you how to download yarn.
So simply copy the resource that I've given you inside of your resource folder that says yarn and then
paste it into your browser.
And once you're on this page, make sure your operating system is Windows and your version is stable.
Then you just click download installer.
Now you'll see here that it says that we can only do this after we've installed no gess, which we just
did.
So with this, once it's finished, we simply go to where we've installed it and run the installer.
We're going to accept the license hit next and then finally hit and stop.
We want to allow it to make changes and we finish and now we need to go back to our visual studio code,
close it again and rerun it, because we need to make sure that we have the version of yarn installed
on our computer.
So what we can do inside of our terminal is just type yard Dash V once it's finished loading.
And we should see the version that we just installed and with this, your environment is now set up
for the rest of the course.
So I'll see you in the next lesson.