Welcome back, everyone.
So now that we've typed out all of the appropriate actions, let's import them in so that we can utilize
them inside of our reducer.
Now, we don't necessarily need all of them because our reducer only responds to sign in.
Failed.
Sign up failed as well as sign.
Out failed.
And then we have sign out success.
And we also have sine in success.
So these are the five actions that our reducer response to.
We know that our action needs to be of the any action type, so we'll import in any action from Redux.
And here we can just cast it like so.
We also want to type out.
Our initial state.
So our user state, which is going to be current user, which is some user data and user data of course
comes from our Firebase Utils.
But it's going to be user data or it's going to be null because both are valid states that we can receive.
As well as our initialization state as well as loading is going to be a boolean, an error is going
to be of type error or no.
Now as mentioned, these are read only.
So let's make sure to make these also read only.
I may have missed this actually inside of our previous reducer for the cart.
So if I did, we'll go back.
We'll update them later.
But here inside of this reducer, we're going to get rid of this, the structure.
And then we're also going to cast the initial state to be one of the user state.
And that it's just a matter of doing the correct switches.
So first we're going to say sign in success.
Don't match our action.
Then we are going to return.
The current state.
With action, not payload like so.
Similarly, if sign out success don't match.
What the action.
We will return with current user set to know.
And now for these three sign out.
Failed, sign in failed and sign up failed.
How are we going to write this?
Well, this we're going to match with just a bunch of your statements.
So we'll say if sign in failed, don't match on this action or sign up failed.
Don't match on this action or sign out failed.
Dot match on this action.
If any of these match, then we are going to just spread this through.
Pass the payload because it's going to be an error.
And then it's just a matter.
Of keeping the return state.
As the default fallback.
And that's it.
This is now our user reducer.
So the last thing to type is the user selector.
So of course, as we can see from our selector here, this is just pulling off the user, recurrent
user.
We can actually even improve upon this by importing the create selector from where you select.
We can import in user state.
From our new definition and we'll export content select user reducer, which is equal to something that
gets us the root state.
And we're going to return back.
These are state.
And we're just going to pluck off that state value and select current user here.
It's just going to be a new selector.
That is going to not receive that object.
Instead, we're going to say select user reducer and we'll get back is the user state upon which we
will pluck off the current user like so.
Create selector I spelt wrong.
There we go.
And now here, this is not in a typescript file.
So let me quickly remedy that.
Again, we know that we have not type state, but at the very least we have now modified our user selector
so that essentially we have this entry point into the user slice and then we create a selector to pluck
off the current user.
So earlier we didn't have that, but now we do.
And there we go.
We have typed out the majority of this user store file.
So very quickly, let me remedy that issue that I mentioned where inside of our cart reduce our type
definition.
I did not make these read only as I should have.
So that is also done now.
And we make them read only, of course, because we just want to say, Hey, these values will never
update the state.
Value should not be beautiful.
It should only update if you return a new object.
So this just prevents anybody from coming in here and modifying it.
Like so saying state dot, for example, state dot is open like this is equal to false.
You'll notice that it throws an error.
This assignment cannot be done because it is real only.
So that's why we do this.
Because it really enforces that pattern that we want these state to be completely immutable.
So now that we have typed out all of these reducers, we can finally now address this type issue where
this state is not typed up.
And that's what we're going to do in the next video where we will finally start typing out the last
touches inside of Redux.
So we're going to type out our source and then we're going to type out some of our middleware.
And even after that, we'll type out our sagas.
So join me in the next video where we'll tackle those topics together.
I'll see you in the next video.