Welcome back, everyone.
So in this video, we want to actually start styling our products.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to go into my components and I'm going to create a new folder called
product card.
So inside a product card, we need to create the usual files, we need to make a product card component
Duchess X, and we also need to make a product card styles.
So product card dot styles dot SAS.
Inside of a product car components, what do we need?
Well, first we need to import in that stylesheet that we've created.
So let's do that.
And as far as the product card itself is concerned, let's think about what we need to do.
So we know that we need a product card component, which is just going to be a functional component
for now.
Then I'm just going to explore out by default, the product cart.
So as we normally do, we just scaffolding out this component.
Now, what we want to do is just take a quick look at the actual finished product.
We have some kind of container.
We have this button inside.
So we're going to need the button component.
Then we have the name, we have the price and we have an image.
So let's start building that out here.
First, I'm going to make a device that's going to contain all of these elements that I'm talking about.
So that top level parent a small component.
And I'm going to say that this is the product card container.
It's going to contain all of our product card stuff.
Then inside is going to be an image, and this image is going to need a source, which we'll figure
out later.
Inside at the bottom there, we have some kind of a footer, so I'm going to call this div the footer
and I'm going to give it the class name of footer.
Then inside, we're going to need to list both the name as well as the cost.
So for the span, I'm going to call this.
The name and then I'm also going to create a duplicate where the class name is going to be the cost
or the price, whichever one sounds more intuitive to you.
I'm going to use price.
After this, we need to use our button, so let's import in our button component.
So I want to say I want to impart the button from the button folder.
And then I'm just going to apply this button.
So this button now.
If we remember.
This button is white first, then black, unlike our typical button, which is black to white.
So this is the invert, so I'm going to say that the button type is equal to the string inverted.
And as for the content inside, it's just going to say add to cart.
And I'm going to save this, and this is pretty much it.
Now what do we need to do?
We need to actually fill in these remaining values.
What is the image?
What is the name?
What is the price?
So here what I'm going to do is I'm going to assume that for this product cart, you have to pass us.
The product and product in this case is going to be the actual product data that we had.
So we call it shop data right here.
So we know we have ID, name, image, URL and price.
So we want to assume those are the same values we're going to get inside of our product cart.
So here, what I'm going to do is once I get the product, I want to structure off what I need.
So I know that I need the name, I need the price and I need the image URL and this we're going to structure
off of our product object, then inside of name.
I'm going to call the name inside of price.
I'm going to call the price.
As for the image, I'm just going to set the source equal to the image URL.
Images also need an alt text, and this alt text is primarily for screen readers.
So what we can do is for the screen reader value.
We can just describe what this object is, so we can say that this is the name because our names for
our products are generally pretty descriptive.
And that's it.
We're going to save this, and now we want to use our product card inside of the shop component.
So here I'm going to import in product card from.
The appropriate file, so we need to go up through our pages, into our components folder, into our
product card and then get the product card component, and then what we'll do is we will replace this
entire div with the product card, and we're going to say the key is still the ID.
But now we need the whole product.
So actually, we can't even do this.
We just want the entire product because that's what our component is expecting.
So I'm going to say product ID instead of just the ID structure, and then I'm going to pass down the
product as a whole into this product cart.
So now if we save this and we come to our application.
What do we see if we refresh?
Well, actually, it looks like we have an error, so let's debug what this errors.
Here we see that product card nothing was returned from render.
So this means that inside of our product card, we're not actually returning the correct thing.
So this is my mistake inside of this component, we need to make sure to return back this value.
So now we come back and let's refresh.
Here we see that we have our product cards.
So this is pretty much in, it's just that we don't have our styling set up.
So as you guessed it, inside of product styles, I want you to paste in the product card styles file
that I provided for you in your resources folder.
Now, once you've pasted this in, if you look inside, what you'll see is that we have some really
big cards.
Now the reason these are big is because it's adaptable based on the environment that uses them.
So where is it that we use our product cards?
Well, we're actually using them inside of our shop component.
So inside of our shop component, our products are contained in a div, and this div is going to be
what actually determines their styling.
So let me just show you I'm going to give a class name to this div, which is products container.
And then what we're going to do is create a shop that style stores file.
And let's make sure to import.
That stockpile, so we don't forget about it.
And then what we'll do is we'll target this products container that we just created.
I'm going to use display grade here because I want to show these in a grid format.
I want the columns to be in four equal sizes.
So here you'll see that repeat for one half hour just means repeat four times one f r one f r just means
one.
Evenly distributed and equal distant size.
So if you have 100 pixels and you have for what of one f r, then that means that you're dividing that
100 by four, giving you 25.
So this means that we're saying that is equal.
And then I want gaps between.
So the column gap, I want it to be ten pixels.
So this is the gap between the columns and then the row gap I want as fifty pixels.
So now, if I save this and I come back here, we see we have our component.
That's it.
A lot of this was just some freestyling, but again, I don't want to waste too much time on styling,
there's a lot of little details with styling that takes up a lot of time.
That is not worth it when it comes to learning react.
But in case you are curious about learning some of how KSAZ grid works, I'm going to include a link
to general documents around this grid that is really helpful.
The best way to learn science as a grid is really just to tinker around with it.
And I've given you kind of an environment.
You can tweak some of these values, try out some of these values in the docs and just see what the
differences lie.
So now that we have our product cards, what we want to do next is actually start seeing if we can add
this to our cart.
So that's what we're going to do in the next video.