Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to learn about Stripe and integrating with Stripe, as well as setting
up stripe so that we can start writing our code to make payments against it.
Strava is arguably one of the largest payment platform services ever made, and right now it is one
of the most popular, if not the most popular in North America and Europe.
In order for you to get started, you need to have a stripe account.
So to set up a stripe account, you get the sign in and then inside of the sign in page.
If you do not have a stripe account already, you scroll down here and you hit the sign up.
Once you've gone through the sign up process, join me back here where we will take a look at the view
that we first see with the dashboard.
So once you've done that, come back and let's continue.
Welcome back, everyone.
So once you've signed in and registered, you will see this page.
You'll notice that you're asking and being prompted to activate the account.
The way to do that is that you have to give it your payment information, as well as your banking information
and your business information.
So normally when you have a business, this is where that step becomes important, because only when
you do that are they allowed to legally let you accept payments.
Here, though, we're just working with the actual developer experience.
And the only difference is that once you actually have all of this validated and activated, you can
flip this from test mode to live production mode.
As you can see here, it says, please activate your account to access live data.
For us, this does not really matter.
The actual coding experience for us is the exact same and all we really need are these two values.
If you scroll down here, you'll see for developers there is a publisher of a key and a secret key.
These are the two keys that I was talking about earlier.
The secret key being actually the most important one.
The publishable key, as you can tell, means that you can display this publicly.
It's not a concern if people know what that key is.
The secret key, though, is something that should be hidden.
So this secret key should live on our back end or our serverless functions.
What we'll talk about once we get to that section, the main thing I want you to do is remember these
two values.
We're going to have to go back to them later when we actually start integrating with Stripe.
Now the first thing we need to do is install the actual dependencies so our React application can work
with Stripe.
So let's inside of our terminal run yarn add at stripe slash stripe dash juice, which is the JavaScript
library that allows us to make Stripe payments.
And then we need add stripe slash, react slash stripe JS.
This is the library that gives us the react elements and react bindings so that we can interact with
the Stripe library inside of the react environment in a significantly easier way.
So as these are installing, let's go back into our application.
The first thing we need to do is actually register our application so it knows to use Stripe.
Stripe provides us these react components known as Stripe elements that we can use, such as the card
component, which is that component we saw when I was typing in the credit card information.
Stripe knows how to do that and use that in order to actually perform a payment, making the process
significantly easier.
But we have to actually register the application the same way that you what a provider.
So to do this what we actually need is going to be from the React integration from Stripe.
So here I want you to run imports and then elements.
From.
Stripe.
Slash.
React.
Stripe.
Jazz.
This elements is a component that you want to wrap around your app.
So this is similar to a provider.
Any components inside of this?
Elements will now have access to the stripe elements that we will use later.
But we actually have to pass this elements component something so that stripe knows that this is registered
to us, meaning that this React application, when it makes requests, goes to our specific account
in Stripe.
Now this is where we're going to need that publishable key, and the way we're going to use it is inside
of this source folder.
I'm going to make a new folder that helps us with Stripe.
You can also put it inside of your utils folder.
It really does not matter.
But since we have a usual folder actually let's use the utils folder here.
We're going to make a new stripe folder and inside we're going to make stripe charges or stripe dot
utils such as this is going to create and instantiate for us our Stripe instance.
So in order to do that, we need to import load stripe from stripe, add stripe, dash, stripe.
JS Load Stripe is what runs in order for us to actually know that this is our stripe instance.
So here I'm going to export out a contact called Stripe Promise and this is equal to us calling load
stripe and here we have to pass it the publishable key.
Now as I mentioned, the publishable key is perfectly fine for us to expose, but just for our own security
with these keys, we might as well put it inside somewhere safe.
This is where we're going to use something called env dot end is a environment file that we can add
that makes it so that only our application has access to these files because essentially it puts it
on your process environment.
It doesn't actually make it expose able anywhere inside of your code repository.
So the thing to do that we have to first out of file court and now because this application is made
in create racked up by default, the frontend React application allows us to use this dot and it's actually
already installed when we installed our Create React application.
The only thing though is that in order for us to use it, we need to make sure that any variables we
define include starts with react, underscore app, all caps.
So here I'm going to say react, underscore app, underscore, stripe, underscore publishable, underscore
key is equal to the string value of the publishable key.
So here I want you to go back to your application, copy the publishable key value and then paste this
into this section right here.
So once you've save this, you will now have access to this value.
The one thing, though, is that we never want to actually push our file up into GitHub.
So what we have to do is in the get ignore add dot env.
So now get what?
Ignore our environment.
Moving on.
What we're going to do is go into our stripe utils.
Yes.
And now we can use this by saying process, dot, environment, dot, react.
Well, actually, here you can just directly copy the name.
I can't remember sometimes all these variable names.
But what happens is that under the hood, react will merge this file with our process environment.
So now all of those key value pairs we have are accessible on process.
And so now this is essentially going to load our stripe instance with our publishable key, which identifies
our application to Stripe as our application.
Then we're going to take this Stripe promise and we're going to import it into our index chassis because
as you can guess, this is what we need to pass into our elements that we get from React.
Right?
So here go to utils folder stripe, stripe, utils.
Strike promise here.
We're going to copy.
And then inside of elements right here, we are going to pass it as stripe equals stripe promise and
that's it.
This is what we need to set up so that we can start working with Stripe now and create the corresponding
components.
So again, dot end was the new thing.
If you want to add more environment variables that are accessible in your frontend application, you
want to always add react underscore app.
This only works of course in Create React app, but this is.
And so now that we have this, let's move on and start actually coding out our new Stripe components.
I'll see in the next video.