Now, the next one we're going to look at is Filter.
So to understand filter.
Let's go back to our browser console.
So filter is very similar to a map in the sense that it's also going to take a function that gets iterated
over each element in our array.
So let's do this again, except this time I'm going to say my array is equal to one three five seven
nine.
Now, filter is exactly as it sounds, we want to filter out the elements in our array based off of
the function that we pass it.
And Filter will also give us back a new array instead of modifying my array.
So what we're going to do in order to use filter is we're going to write a filter and just like earlier
with Matt, we're going to get the element as the argument over function and what we're going to return
is actually a true or false value.
So let's say, for example, I wanted to filter out anything that was less than five.
Well, I would essentially say if the element.
Is greater than four, right?
So whatever returns true will be the thing that gets kept in our array, so whatever element we'll get,
Captain R.A. is based on whether or not the evaluation of this is true.
So if, for example, we just return true, what we would get back our whole array if we return false.
Right, we would get back nothing.
So if we want to just whatever was five or greater, then we would say as long as the element is greater
than four.
Because if the element is one, one is not greater than four, right?
So that will be false and that's why it'll filter out one and three.
And this array that we get back is a new array, my array is still the same array.
And that's what filter is, so remember, that filter also returns back a new array, except it filters
out the anything where the function condition returns false, anything that returns true, it'll keep
in the new array.