Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we're going to type our heart icon.
So to begin, let's switch these over to TSX files.
And as you can notice, card icon taking no props, no problem.
But when we look inside of our icon component, what do we notice?
We notice that here.
TypeScript can't find this module for savages.
The reason for this actually has to do with our test config.
We need to tell TypeScript to include checking for alternative file types and then typing them inside
of a react world.
Now this is where we need to actually declare a global type, just like we did before when we added
something to the window.
If you remember, we were working with Redux dev tools.
So inside of our component.
First of all, we need to do is we need to create a global file that we can add some additional typing
to.
I'm going to call it custom done deportees.
Now, the data to us is some special file that TypeScript is looking for.
So let's add it inside the source.
When I make a new file called Custom Deportees.
Inside of our custom dot dots, we are going to declare a module where we register any path where we
go star dot SVG.
So we're recognizing any pathways again, remember, we're importing.
So TypeScript needs to be able to import the appropriate modules because that's really what we're importing.
All of these are considered modules.
We're importing any module that ends in a SVG file according to the following the rules.
Now first, we want to just register the fact there's something in here that we want to export.
We're going to say can't source is equal to a string because essentially that's what's going to come
out of it.
And then we're going to export by default source.
So that's how we're going to get the files.
It's just going to be some value that gets initialize and then it's going to export it out by default.
In order for us to declare these as register of all TypeScript modules in portable and exportable.
So by default, we need to append this type of export so that TypeScript knows, Hey, you're exporting
something from this.
It's going to be a string because all files actually get converted to strings.
And then once you import that in React knows what to do with it, it'll pass it appropriately.
React is already doing all that under the hood.
It's really typescript that needs to register that.
So let's save that and let's include this new custom that deducts file inside of our test config.
For us to do this, we can include it inside of our include and we can just say include source slash
and then custom.
Yes.
And now that we've included this inside of our config so that we know that, hey, inside of here,
I want you to register these as specific files as part of your configuration.
If we go back to our icon, we'll notice that we're no longer getting that module where we can successfully
see that this is a module where we can bring in the SVG.
But now we're seeing, Oh, this is no longer an exportable member.
What you're exporting is a string.
You're not actually exporting a react component.
Now, this is where in order for us to turn this into a component, because remember, react under the
hood is already doing all this.
We just need TypeScript to register that this is happening.
We've got to extend upon this module.
So first, what we're going to do is we're going to import in React and we need to require this from
React.
What we're going to do with this rock library is we're going to export cost a react component.
So we're going to say react components, which is the name of what we're importing, remember?
Right here.
You want to think about these imports and exports?
First, we're exporting by default the source, but we can also export a member, which is what happens
here when you do a named import.
Remember, with these squiggly braces, you need some cortes to be exported.
That's the only way that we can make sure that we can import it inside of these squiggly braces.
This means that we're importing something react component.
That's why when you don't need the as shopping cart, this needs to be something that is actually exportable
as a value from this file.
Seeing as shopping icon is just us renaming the variable, but react component needs to live as a valid
variable inside of this shopping bag.
The SVG that TypeScript can register is actually valid.
Again, this is what we're saying here.
We're saying, hey, there is some constant that is going to be exported called react component and
this is going to be of the type React DFC.
It's a functional component and what it is is a SPG.
Props.
So again, this is a functional component.
We have SVG props being passed in and the props is going to be an SPG.
S v g e element.
So these are just settings that need to be set.
If this seems confusing again, once you go through enough of these typescript patterns and documentation,
you're going to essentially figure out what are these components.
Mainly this is a lot of configuration with TypeScript that we just need to do.
I'm not actually typing anything through some deeper knowledge of all this stuff.
It's really just the fact that I've read through a lot of the documentation, so I understand what's
needed in order for these components to actually render and their types.
But that's what we need to bring in now.
And inside, we now notice that this is working because essentially we've defined what this react component
is.
If you have a over it right there, you see we have a React FC with SBG as the props where the prop
types are based off of SVG element.
Now because we did it for this one.
It will work for all the others.
If I remember correctly, our navigation routes component also has similarly an import where we're bringing
in some react component like so.
So here we can, in fact, convert this one as well.
So first, I'm going to convert the styles to a CSX file.
And I'm going to convert the component also to TSX.
And now looking inside again, this component, if you have a rare component, you notice it is a valid
prop.
Looking through this file, there are no type concerns because, again, this is a very straightforward
component.
We're using all these hooks that are already typed for us, so there's nothing additional that we need
to type.
We started with Redux.
All of our Redux portions are all properly typed.
So there we go.
We now learn how to type SB G's inside of React.
Chances are whenever you need to do anything with SB G's inside of React using this very common pattern,
you just need to also declare this additional module and then include it inside of your test config.
Now that we know this, let's continue typing the rest of our components.