Welcome back, everyone.
Let's continue finishing typing out these different user sagas.
So here for is authenticated.
It's just an error casting as we have to do.
Here inside of sign up.
Where do we actually call our sign up saga?
So if we scroll down, we notice that we call our sign up Saga on sign up start.
So this happens when we get that action, sign up, start.
So here, let's scroll up and let's bring in the corresponding action type.
So this one, as I mentioned, is going to be our sign up start, which we will bring in and set as
the action that we receive for this parameter.
Similarly here we are also calling our create auth user with email and password, which is very similar
to our sign in auth user with email and password.
At the very least, what we know is that we are getting back a user credential, so we are going to
replicate the code we have above where we get some user credential upon which we perform a check first
to see is it not undefined, then we will structure off the user from the user credential upon which
we finally actually yield out the next subsequent call.
Now sign up.
Success gives us a error call here.
So here we see that user is authenticated by this credential, but user is not assignable to the parameter
type of user data.
Now the reason we're throwing this error is because our sign up success has defined user to be user
data.
So this most likely means that we actually mistyped our sign up success definition.
Here we are defining user as user data, but this is most likely incorrect.
We're actually expecting this to be of the type user that we get from a user credential.
So the reason why is because when you sign up, you are authenticating.
When you authenticate, it does not mean that you have an instance of the user inside of our firestorm.
User data is the data that comes from the user snapshot, which is an instance inside of firestorm data.
The user that comes from a user credential is just that author information.
Again, I know it's very confusing because a firebase and its naming conventions, but here we know
that what we need to bring this from is firebase slash off.
So with the user now what we can do is properly fix our typing issue.
So inside of sign of success, we need to update it here and we also need to update the action itself
because the action definition most likely has it as also user data.
So let's fix that.
Let's save this.
Go back to our saga and now we see that everything is fixed.
We know that this is correct because we follow the string of our logic, but also because our sagas
were working, which means that the saga code is correct.
It's just that our typing was off.
So moving on we now need to also type this sign up failed.
We'll say this as error.
Similarly, we also need to type our sign out failed as error and then our sign in after sign up.
This saga gets called specifically after sign up success.
So we need to get the action for sign up success.
So let's import that in.
Here.
We were missing a comma.
And let's bring in sign up success.
And now we'll just scroll back down to our sign in after sign up.
And cast the appropriate action, which should also fix our type error.
So that's it.
We've finished typing out our user saga.
So again, this is probably the most complicated portion of our code, but with just a little bit of
thinking about everything that we've already learned, as far as typing goes, we are very easily able
to type everything now and make it TypeScript compliant.
So now that we've finished typing our user saga, what we want to do next is we also want to make sure
to type our route saga.
So our route saga here, we also want to.
Convert this to.
Eight dots.
Yes.
While.
And of course, instead of Redux saga of facts, we will bring in our typed Redux saga slash macro.
And we need to switch this yield to a yield star.
Save this.
And there we go.
We have now also typed out route saga.
So now that we have all of our sagas typed, we can now begin actually typing out the remainder of our
code.
So one quick thing before you start typing out these components, there's a couple of things we're going
to have to adjust as we go.
But first, let's just do a quick check and make sure that we have no type errors.
We see that our code is still working.
We see that our ADD to CART is working.
So all of our sagas are properly typed.
All of our code is valid.
So now that that's done, let's move on to typing our rather complex react components that we've made
inside of our crown coding application.
I'll see in the next video.