Hello and welcome back.
So in the last lesson we learned about what it is that Gatsby does at a high level now in this lesson,
let's actually take a look at what we're going to build.
So what you'll end up building is just this basic blog website.
In this lesson, there's not that much styling to it, because what I'm trying to show you is just the
basic concepts in Gatsby in order to get you up and running.
Now, how you end up actually styling your blog or adding features to your blog is entirely up to you
and definitely part of the coding challenge.
Now, the blog itself is very simple.
It simply has a list of all of our blog posts that you can navigate to and navigate back from.
But the main thing to keep in mind here is that a lot of this content is actually dynamically generated
inside of Gatsby.
I'll show you what I mean.
It's actually really interesting because Gatsby style of setting up this blog is different from how
you would typically write it in a react application because of a lot of the plugins and APIs inside
of Gatsby in how it generates this static website.
Now, we're also going to learn how to host our blog on Nat Lafi.
So Nat Lafi is a company that offers this amazing back and service for you to host static websites.
And the free tier of net lafi is extremely generous.
It's way more than what we need for our blog.
And it's incredibly easy.
It actually gives us continuous deployment pretty much right out the gate with GitHub.
And what that means is that we're able to push our code to GitHub connected to Net Lafi, and whenever
we push code to that GitHub repo net, Lafi will automatically redeploy and rebuild our website and
update r u r l with our latest code.
So that's a really, really great service that we can leverage while using Gatsby because we're building
static websites.
So now that we know what we're building and where we're going to host it to, let's actually take a
look at how to write this code.
So let's go to our terminal and what we're going to leverage is The Gatsby, Seelie.
So Seelie is a command line interface, which is a tool that we can use to quickly set up and build
Gatsby projects pretty much just like create react in order to use it.
We're going to leverage aspects which, as you remember, is a new feature that comes with a later version
of NPM that allows us to leverage packages without having to download them globally on our computer.
So using NPCs, I'm going to say Gatsby New and then Gatsby blog.
So what this does is it will initialise and Klown down using the Gadsby starter, a new Gatsby project
for me.
Now, there's actually a lot of other starter projects you're able to leverage.
And all you would do is after seeing Gatsby blog or whatever name you want for your gas project, you
say space and then you link the new star that you want to actually leverage.
And Gatsby provides all these starters, depending on what kind of website you're looking to build.
In fact, there's even a Gatsby blog starter that Dan Abramov, the creator of Redox and a very, very
prominent member of the reactor core team, uses to create his new blog, overreacted.
Now, you can totally take a look at this afterwards, but let's just get started first to understand
all of the nuances in using Gatsby.
So once we've actually created our New Gatsby blog repo, let's see into it.
And let's just open up the code and see what we have.
Now, you'll see right away that our folder structure comes with these different files here inside of
the source folder.
We have something that we might be used to seeing with our REACT projects, which is a components folder.
We have an images folder that holds some images and we have these pages folder.
Now we're going to talk about the pages folder.
But first, let's just take a look at these four files we have here.
The Gatsby browser dodges The Gatsby config, Duchesse Gatsby No Duchesse and Gatsby Ezat.
So you can actually get server side rendering with Gatsby if you follow some of the instructions with
the gas BSR API dock.
Now, we're not actually going to do that in this course, but it's nice to know that you can achieve
it with Gatsby.
So if you're curious to see how to implement it after this course, you can definitely take a look at
these docs.
Gatsby Noad we're going to use in order to build out some of the more server required, things that
we will definitely explore in this course.
So for now, just understand that this is where we end up writing some of our node related code.
Now, The Gatsby config is actually the main file that we're going to focus on inside of this lesson,
at the very least, that Gatsby config holds a lot of the configuration options that we need in order
for Gatsby to know what to do.
Now, this site metadata is actually data that we can pull into our components using Graph QR inside
of Our Gatsby project.
So if we wanted access to a title, this description or the author in any way, we are able to leverage
graph and pull this site metadata right out of this Kaspi config object.
These plug ins are additional little libraries in Gatsby that allow you to do different things with
different files.
So we'll definitely explore this later.
But you can see these as kind of additional helper libraries that transform the way that we're able
to use Gatsby.
And we'll take a better look at this in a later lesson.
For now, just understand that this plugins array is where we would add any new plugins that we want
for Our Gatsby project.
Now, Gatsby does have a lot of configuration and a lot of plug ins, so you can definitely take some
time and read a lot of the documentation that's available for many of the plugins that come by default
with the starter.
There's also going to be a lot of Gatsby concepts that we're going to cover.
And honestly, you kind of have to just follow through with this lesson in order to understand at the
end how all of these pieces come together because there are so many moving parts in order for us to
end up building our blog.
But Gatsby does try and make it as easy as possible.
So as we build out some of these features, we're going to go back to a lot of these files to better
understand what they're for.
Right now.
I just want to introduce you to the base files so that we understand what we're doing.
Now, one of the big things is actually to look at a package that Jason and looking at the scripts we
see that it does provide us with quite a few.
Now, the main one that we want is actually Gatsby develop because Gatsby develop is what we use in
order to serve up our website on localhost.
So let's actually just test that first.
So what we'll do is just run, npm, run, develop.
And what this will do is it will build up our New Gatsby application and it'll actually give us two
routes.
The first one will be localhost eight thousand.
That is going to host the actual website.
The second you are, all they're going to give us is localhost eight thousand, underscore, underscore,
underscore, craft, QOL.
And this is going to be a graphical playground.
But we'll look at that in the next lesson in this lesson.
Let's just navigate to localhost a thousand in order to see what it is that we get.
So by default, we get this Gatsby default page and we see that there's some routing that's set up for
us, so we load this little astronaut and if we go to page, it takes us to a different page at this
route and we can go back to our home page.
Really simple, really quick.
They've just set up something here for us to just build off of.
So now that we see this in the next lesson, let's take a look at how the code actually translates to
what we see here.
So I'll see you in the next lesson.