Now inside what we need to do is we need first the collection reference.
So just like we got it before, I'm going to say collection reference is equal to collection passing
at the DB, but also the aforementioned collection key.
Here, though, we know exactly what the collection key is.
It's the categories key because we just made this collection.
Then what we want to do next is a little bit more complicated and convoluted, honestly, but unique
to our store.
What we need is we need to generate a query, and from that query, we need to get docs.
So we need to import two new methods from Firestar query and get docs.
After I write this, I'm going to explain a little bit about why we set up our code this way, primarily
to guard against Firestorm.
And this is often not even unique to our store, but front end development as a whole typically falls
under this trap.
Or you could argue, JavaScript development as a whole falls into this trap.
But what we need to do with the query is we need to say, Hey, I'm going to generate a query off of
this collection, ref.
So I'm going to use the query method by passing in the collection, ref.
This gives me some object now that I can get a snapshot from.
So I'm going to say query snapshot is equal to a weight of calling.
Get docs on cue, so get docs.
Here is the asynchronous ability to fetch those document snapshots that we want, because now it's all
encapsulated under this query snapshot.
From here, we're actually able to access the different documents snapshots off of query snapshot dot
docs.
This will give us an array of all of those individual documents inside, and the snapshots are the actual
data themselves.
As we've seen before, we use snapshots.
But here, what we want to do is we want to reduce over this to create this structure we've been discussing.
So here I'm going to say Konst category map, which is what we're trying to build, is equal to query
snapshot dot docs dot reduce.
So we're reducing over this array in order to finally end up with an object.
So here, for the actual structure of my reduce, my first argument, of course, is the callback that
gets invoked on each document snapshot.
And then this is the final object we want to create.
But this is the initial instance of it, which is an empty object because we're building out the map
as we go.
The first argument is going to be accumulator.
The second argument is going to be dock snapshot.
And then from here, what we're going to do is we're going to first need to structure off the values
of the data of this stock snapshot.
So I want the title and I want the items, and I'm going to say, Hey, take this doc snapshot, give
me the data which will be the object and then take off the title and the items.
Then what I'm going to do is I'm going to say the accumulator at the title value is also need to be
lowercase.
If we remember our title is actually, as I mentioned, uppercase, this value is going to be equal
to the item and then I return my accumulator now that it's been updated.
So now what this will be is the actual category map that we've been building out, and I'm just going
to return this, as is.
So if you're looking at this and you're like, wow, what are these queries, this get talks, this
is async and then we need to reduce over.
And yet somehow here on the docs we get like these documents snapshots?
I know this seems confusing, and quite frankly, it's changed every single instance major version of
Firebase.
It's actually one of the more annoying things about how Google builds out Firestar is they do make it
backwards compatible.
You can use the previous versions if you take in this course before of how you build out these different
data models.
Fetch this data.
Store this data.
But here, the main thing that I want to highlight what we're doing is we are creating these helper
functions, and the main thing they do is they isolate the areas that are application interfaces with
things that might change in this articular case, its third party libraries.
The third party library might change their implementation, but at least we're isolating them all into
these individual functions rather than directly using these Firestar and authentication methods throughout
our application.
Because if we did that, then let's say Firebase or Fire Store changes the way they work.
Then across our entire application, we need to change all of those different places.
Whereas now we've at least isolated them all into this one file into these individual functions that
are clearly defined as to what these functions are trying to do.
For example, with this one, we're trying to get our category map here.
If they change the implementation here, we just need to change this one function.
Anywhere that's utilizing the category map is still just going to rely on this one function.
So as long as we fix the function, then we know that as long as we're a category man, our code is
still going to behave throughout the rest of our application the way we need it to.
And that's why we structure our code this way.
So this is one important thing you need to remember because unfortunately, the world of JavaScript
development moves very quickly.
Libraries are constantly changing, patterns are constantly changing.
Frameworks are constantly changing.
We need to figure out these patterns so that we can at least the best isolate and minimize the impact
that these changes have on our code base from working.
And this is one of them.
So now that we've generated our category map, let's actually see if it is indeed working.
I'm going to copy this method that we just made, and I'm going to move it into our product context.
So here now, I'm going to replace this ad with our get categories documents.
And then what I'm going to do is I am going to call use affect now.
Use effect is going to simply just call our get categories.
But one thing I want you to know and this is a new thing we're doing with use effect here.
This method is an async method, which means we get back a promise.
So the promise of this value doesn't resolve until our way of get docs is complete.
And then it has start to run through all of this to build the category agreement.
When you're using an async function inside of use, the fact you don't want to pass a async callback
like this, you want an inside of your anonymous callback, actually create a new async function.
So here I'm going to say const get categories.
Map is equal to an async function.
And inside of this async function, we're going to actually perform the async call.
So here again, Conte's category map is what we get back is equal to our a call of categories and documents
any async things you need to do inside of a use effect.
Wrap it in an async function and then what you need to do is then you call this method at the bottom.
So to show you, I'm just going to console.log the map and then after we've defined it, I'm going to
invoke it.
And of course, I only want to run this when this provider gets mounted.
So I've I save this, I go back to our application.
What we'll see after it fetches is here we go.
This is our categories map.
We have an object that contains our hats and our jackets and our men's and our sneakers and our women's.
This is exactly what we wanted, and now we have all of the data we need to actually finish flushing
out our shop.
But again, the main things that we've learned here are two new lessons.
One, we got a better understanding of why we set up all these utility functions because we want to
minimize the impact that changing third party libraries have on our code base.
And secondly, we also learn about using async functions inside of use of that.
We want to make our own new async function within the callback.
And then what we want to do is we want to call it inside of the same callback after it's been initialized.
So now that we have this working category map, we need to actually change up the structure of what
we called this provider, as well as make some new components.
So that's what we're going to do in the next video.
I'll see you there.