Welcome back, everyone.
In this video we are going to tackle converting out a lot of our Firebase user methods into a saga.
So what do I mean by this?
Currently inside of the application, we actually have a bunch of Firebase methods that are asynchronous
methods, but we're keeping them inside of our components.
So when you think about our sign in with Google method that calls of course our signing with Google
pop up, or if you think about our sign in with user email and password, a lot of these methods we
are currently baking into our components.
If you think about our sign up component, we also have a similar create off user with email and password
method, also asynchronous and all interacting with our Firebase API.
Finally, we also have this observable listener that we instantiate on the app, and all of this code
currently is living deeply nested inside of our components.
With Saga is we can attempt to remove these and put them into Saga so that our components are more free
from this asynchronous code.
In order for us to do that, though, we have to think deeply about what we're trying to do.
So one thing I want to know about this off listener is that unless we are inside of a component, we
don't really have a way of keeping track of some kind of listener and then unsubscribing at some point.
What we should do instead is convert this over into a promise based single check to see if there is
a user.
So there is a couple modifications we need to make in order to convert this into a saga based flow.
But through doing this, we will see a interesting pattern emerge with sagas.
One thing I do want to mention is that this is not necessarily the right way to do it, because Firebase
has been optimized through their author listener for us to essentially write this code very simply.
There's nothing wrong with the way that we've coded out our app, our sign in and our sign up.
This is simply a way for us to code out Saga so that we can see what happens inside of a flow where
we don't have something like an observable listener for authentication.
And it's also another way for us to get more practice in terms of writing out off flows through sagas.
So this is a very important thing.
I do want to highlight one thing as well is that we need to be able to convert a lot of this code over
to asynchronous but more promise base code in order for this to work as well, because generators,
as we know, are essentially async awaits.
So in order for us to make this work, though, we need to start by converting this on off state listener
code over into some type of single check.
So instead of having a listener that responds every time a user state updates.
Instead we're going to wrap this in a promise inside of Firebase Utils.
So first things first.
Let's define this function.
This function is going to be called get current user because that's what we're really trying to do.
We're trying to see if there is a active user that's been authenticated already.
And what we want to do, of course, is convert from a observable listener into a promise based function
call.
So here what I'm going to do is I am going to return back a new promise with this promise.
We have the resolve and we have the reject, which are the positive and the negative handle cases for
a promise, resolve goes down the path when you successfully retrieve the value that you want back.
Reject is what happens when you usually get some kind of error that you want to catch.
So what we're going to say, using a little bit of cleverness is we're going to say, okay, we know
we have the unsubscribe from on off state changed because we get back the unsubscribe from the listener.
So what we want to do, because this is a promise, is we don't want this listener to stay active.
We want to unsubscribe the moment we get a value.
Now, this on off state changed is what we get back from Firebase.
We're not actually using the listener that we created for the actual application because now we're trying
to modify it.
So on off, say change takes the off object and then it takes the callback.
And the callback, of course, gives us the user off when it successfully gets a value when it first.
Then Stanulis is the moment instantiation and it gives us the user off.
We'll know immediately from that user off whether or not there was already an existing user logged in.
If there is or isn't, doesn't matter to us.
The key thing is that we have the value and immediately we're going to unsubscribe.
So we're going to close the listener.
If we don't do this, there will be a memory leak, meaning that that listener is always active inside
of our file.
But we don't want that.
We don't want it to take up more memory.
So once we unsubscribe, we are also going to resolve with the user off because now of course we have
the actual user on.
Now remember, this listener itself is asynchronous, so we're going to resolve the moment we get the
value anyways.
Once we're done with this.
The other thing that this on off stage change takes is a third optional parameter, which is a callback
that runs when an error is thrown in the process of trying to fetch for the user off.
This is where we're going to pass our reject.
Reject is a callback that takes the whatever you passed to it.
Usually it's an error and it will actually reject it to the promised notes to reject.
In this particular case, we're passing reject to this on our state change listener.
The reject will pass the error into it, and then everything will behave as we expect it to.
So this is our get current user.
If I copy this and I go into our app JS and what I'm going to do is I will remove all of this code that
we don't need anymore.
And what I'm going to say is, hey, just get current user.
Just so we can test this might actually end up being the way that we set up our code.
But I want to test this function to see if it works.
Inside of get current user.
Remember this gives us a new promise so I can actually call dot then on it and then we'll get us back
the user off which we can console.log.
So here, if I save this and I go back to the application.
There we see it lot.
This is our user because we have assigned a user and it runs when our app mounts for the first time.
So using this method, we have now managed to essentially move out of that listener.
So what we can do now is put this inside of a saga which will trigger a check.
From here on, we need to now migrate the majority of the code that we have across the sign up form,
the sign in form and this object into a saga and a series of new actions that will all perform these
behaviors for us.
So now I want you to join me in the next video where we will continue breaking this up and thinking
about these flows.
But now in the context of sagas, I'll see you in the next video.