This is a big one.
This one I hold dear to my heart.
And it's the idea that things will never be perfect.
No matter how hard you study, no matter how many videos you watch, how many books you read, how many
projects you built, your code is never going to be perfect.
A lot of people hold off on shipping a product or building something because they think they still need
to improve something.
They still need to learn or they still need to add that feature at a buck.
But the problem is that this is a continuous cycle.
It's never going to be perfect.
Things are always evolving and there's always going to be different ways that you can refactor code.
Make things maybe more efficient, cleaner looking.
The problem is when you have this mentality of, oh, I'm going have to wait until it's absolutely perfect,
is that you end up just bottling all this productivity inside you.
But until you put out your work, until you do something in the real world to solve a problem, everything
is internal.
All that code that you write, if nobody sees it, if nobody uses it, it might as well just not be
there.
So keep that in mind.
It's better to just start doing something, start putting something out there, start releasing that
product, because no matter why you do, it won't be perfect.
What you want to do is constantly improve.
And the best way to improve is to get feedback on your code from other people, feedback on your product.
So I guess what I'm saying is stop watching these videos.
Close your laptop well, don't close your laptop where programmers, but close this video, open up
your code editor and start writing your project.