Welcome back, everyone.
So in the last video I talked about separating out this new function that will allow us to dispatch
the appropriate payload so that we can update our reducer with the correct value.
So in this video, we're going to talk about how to actually generate those values.
And also, let's think about where we're going to use this function.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to write a little comment here so I know what I want to do
with this function.
In the end, what I want to do is dispatch new action with payload that looks like this object.
We should have new car items.
We should have the new cart total, and we should have the new cart count.
Once we're inside, though, we need to figure out how to get these values.
As I mentioned, the actual optical items reducer.
This is a generic function that should already be receiving the new car items hint, hint, nudge,
nudge.
That kind of tells us where we're going to use this.
But in the interim, we need to figure out how to get the new car total and the new car count from the
new car items.
So that's really another thing we need to get.
We need to generate new heart total and we need to generate new heart.
So utilizing these three things, let's actually build out this function.
So first we have to figure out how to get these new items into update cart items reducer.
So here we already have these three different helper functions that explicitly, as we know, give us
the new cart items.
So here, instead of setting them, let's just cast them to a variable called new car items inside of
the function.
And similarly.
We're going to do that in each of these areas like so.
So now that we have the new card items, let's just also run our function, passing them through.
And we can pass this to each of our three functions.
And now the card items that we receive we know will be the correct card items because we've already
made sure that our functions do exactly that.
They give us the new array for what these cards should be.
Then we want to do is we want to generate the new car total and the new car using these new card items.
And luckily for us, we kind of already have the code that does that.
So here we can actually just copy this from our effects, because what they do is they work off of car
items changing whenever it changes to the newer car times that we need.
So instead of reducing over car items, we now can just reduce over the new car items that were getting
in to get the new car count and the new car total.
Now that we saw these two, the last thing we need to do is dispatch the new action with the appropriate
payload.
So here, what I want to do is instead of using all of these values.
I am going to.
Figure out how to use use reducer to help us do this.
So first, let's think about use reducer.
User reducer, as we know, is where we're going to get the actual dispatch that we need.
So to do that, I know that I get state and I get what's dispatch like, so.
And then from use reducer I need to pass it both our cart reducer as well as our initial state.
As for dispatch.
Now we can actually just dispatch away the new action that we want to generate.
The type here is going to be set car items as a string.
And the payload is going to be an object where car items.
Is new car items.
Where the cart total is the new cart total.
And the cart count.
Is going to be new cart count.
And that's it.
That's all we really need.
Now we can get rid of this.
But here we actually noticed that we need our car items from our new use reducer.
So to do that, we can strip off cart.
Items.
In fact, we know that we have to pass both items car count, cart total and is cart open all through
into our context value.
So let's actually structure off all those values that we have anyways.
So we also need card count and we also need cart total.
Now, if we save this, we see that our warnings are gone, but we still have set.
Is carp open?
So this is going to be a new function that we have.
But we'll figure that out after we finish cleaning up what we have inside of our car provider.
So we finished setting up our method.
We finished setting up our action, create our functions, if you want to call them that.
And we finished setting up this reducer that has set items.
Let's just make sure to test that all of this is working.
And the best way is to just quickly make sure for now this is always going to be true.
Because by doing this now, technically, it's unstoppable, which is perfectly fine.
Oops.
Actually.
Sorry.
Let's just set an empty function.
And let's set is cart open to true by default.
Because I want to be able to see the car to make sure that all of my methods here are working now that
we've converted them over.
So.
Yep.
We see our cart.
Let's go into shop.
We add items.
We see that everything works.
We go to our checkout.
We see that our remove item works.
And we see that a clear item works.
So all our code is still working.
But now we need to make sure that we do our is card open.
So here before if you remember we had a center function that we were using with you state.
Now instead we need to create and dispatch a new action that will set the actual is cart open value.
So here I'm going to flip this back to false.
And this is going to be my challenge to you.
I want you to update this cart reducer and create a set is cart open method.
That is going to be a function that will update our card reducer with the appropriate value for our
card.
So do that for me and then join me in the next video where we will tidy up this car context as well
as figure out some minor optimizations and utility functions that will make modifying our reducers easier
in the long run.
I'll see you in the next video.