OK, now let's talk about includes.
Now, includes is a little different from the way that we've been writing the other Arae methods that
we've covered so far includes is essentially a method that takes a single argument.
And that argument will be any element that we want.
And what it does is it checks inside the array to see if the element that we pass that exists in our
array.
So let's try this out.
Well, let's first make our array, which is equal.
Two, let's say one, two, three, four or five.
If we do, Meyera includes.
Three.
Well, see that it's true because three does exist in our.
Now, if we were to say try something like nine, then we will get false, because nine is clearly not
inside of our.
The second argument we could take in are includes is the index in which we want to start searching.
So what do I mean by this?
Well, our array is actually indexed from our first element to its last element, starting from zero
and counting up by one.
So one is our array element at index zero.
Two is our element at index one.
Now I know what this example, maybe it's a little confusing.
So let's do another array.
Let's use const newera equals these three objects while new array.
At index zero is our first element, right, our first object is one.
Element at index two is our last one, because this is zero, this is one, and this is two.
One thing to keep in mind with using includes and our second argument, let's say in our original example
with Meyera.
We wanted to see.
If the number two exists starting from our third.
Index, this means that it's starting from for it's going to check if four includes our two, it doesn't
or a five has our two, which it doesn't.
So here we'll see that we won't get false.
So essentially.
If we were to try this, except instead we were to start from our second index, well, we'll find that
it's true.
Because starting from two, it'll see that two is included, starting from this part of the array onwards.
But this is essentially how it works with includes when it comes to using what are called primitive
types.
Now, I'm going to explain what those are, but first I'm going to show you why this is important.
If with our new array, let's say, for example, we wanted to find our second object with ID too,
if I did a new array includes and then I tried to find the object with ID to.
Well, we'll get false, but why is that, even though this object looks exactly like the element that
does exist inside our array?
Why would we get false?
Well, this is because of the way that JavaScript references objects versus primitive types.
Now, what are primitive types?
Well, let's actually look at this diagram here.
In this diagram, imagine there's a memory bank and this is internal to JavaScript inside this memory
bank, JavaScript has a reference to every primitive type and there are six of them.
There are strings, strings being anything that we see between quotation marks.
So this is a string, is a string.
Boulin is true or false, nul is the null object, undefined is also undefined, a unique primitive
type numbers.
So this is any integer, so that's a whole number.
And also any float, so any decimal number, these are also all primitive types that fall under the
category of number and symbol, which is a bit more complicated, but it's essentially a unique thing.
We don't really want to go too deeply into symbol because we're not really going to use it, but these
are the six primitive types and these primitive types all exist inside of JavaScript Memory Bank.
Now, when we set a constant or a variable equal to a primitive type like, say, the number three,
what JavaScript is doing, is it setting it's creating this new variable that we want called A and it's
pointing its value to the number three in its memory.
So it's actually pointing to three in memory.
When we set variable B.
To three, it does the same thing, it creates this new variable called B, and then it also points
to the same three points to three in memory.
If we set variable C to be.
It's actually not pointing to our value of B. Instead it points to B, which then points to our value
in memory of three.
If we were to see this in action, let's say we did var B equals three.
And Vassy equals B.
If we look at sea, we'll see that the number is pointing to three, if we changed be to five.
BP is now pointing to the value and memory of five, right?
It's not really setting a value, it's we're we're saying that our value of B wants to point to the
five that's in JavaScript memory, but C is still pointing to three.
So C is not always going to equal whatever B becomes.
C will only point to the value that B pointed to when we set it.
Why was it that this didn't work well inside of JavaScript?
Anything that's not a primitive type so not any of these six types is called an object and an object
is unique.
Whenever an object gets instantiated, it gets its own unique reference in memory.
Now, before we explore this, what is an object?
Well, everything else in JavaScript that is not one of these six primitive types, as we mentioned,
is an object.
Right.
So arrays are also objects.
And you can essentially just see objects as collections of things that have properties that have values.
So my array.
Right, the arrays that we've created, they all have properties, right.
Because they have these methods on them.
And methods are pretty much just properties that point to functions.
That's why we're able to use them like functions.
But we call them with the dot notation like it's a property on the object.
Right.
And we're used to seeing objects as these curly braces with key value pairs inside them.
Well, you can pretty much see that as everything else in JavaScript.
That is not one of those six primitive types that we're talking about now.
Whenever you see an object get instantiated for the first time or for any time, for that matter.
What you're seeing is JavaScript store that object as a brand new reference in memory.
So what do I mean by this?
Well, let's say we made a new const object, one which equals to this object with the idea of one.
This I object gets a new reference in memory.
Even if we were to make a new object to right, let's say we were to point it to a different object,
but it looked the exact same.
This is actually going to be different if we do object, one equals object to it's going to give us
false because what JavaScript is comparing.
If the reference in memory is the same, it's not comparing whether or not this value of this object.
Is equal to each other.
It's comparing if they're both pointing to the same place in memory.
This only works if we were to do something like we did earlier when we pointed our value of sea to be,
but instead if we were to say point our consed obj three.
Right.
So this new concept we want to point to object to.
Well, now we'll see that OBJ three is pointing to this object.
Now we can see that because both Object three and Object two are pointing to the same object in memory.
If we do a comparison, we'll see that it's actually true because the reference and memory is the same.
Now, the interesting thing about objects is that if we change the properties on them, if we add them
or or modify them, they'll always point to the same object reference in memory.
So if I were to do object to dot, ID equals 17.
Well, now I object to is it 17, but object three you'll see still points to the same object in memory.
So that would be how we would get our includes to work is we would actually do const O one right equals.
A new object with idea of one constant two is equal to another object with idea of two.
Const 003 is equal to an object with idea three.
And now we'll say consed newest array is equal to or one 02 and 03.
So now if we were to display it, we'll see that inside our array is those three objects that we just
made and now if we do newest array DOT includes and we were to point to let's say, oh, one will find
that it's true because what we're referencing is that pointer in memory.
So even though our array is this array, the elements inside are not new objects, but they're all pointing
to the same elements in memory, which is why when we do the includes, the evaluation is true because
that's essentially what includes is doing under the hood.
It's checking if the reference that we're passing in.
Right.
Is equal to the any of the elements inside by their memory reference.
So this is a bit of a longer lesson because we have to understand this very fundamental thing about
objects and how JavaScript stores things in memory, but also how includes works when comparing and
trying to find if an element exists in the array.
We'll definitely explore these concepts a lot more as we code, and they'll definitely make more sense
why the code we write is structured the way it is based on these rules.