Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we're going to learn how to leverage our products that we've inserted into our shop
page in order to build out our cart.
Our car is primarily comprised of two things.
We have our car icon with a number inside that tells us the quantity.
And we also have the car dropdown, which contains different items inside of it.
As we add, items will notice that the numbers will increase, as well as the total quantity.
If we add the same item in order to build this, we need to take this product and actually transform
it, potentially into a format that this cart is able to take so that it can accurately account for
the quantity.
There's numerous ways to do that, but we'll talk about it in a little bit later.
First, let's just initialize and set up our cart icon, and we can start with building out the dropdown
as well.
So inside of your project, I want you to go to your assets folder and add in the shopping bag SVG icon
that I've included for you in your resources folder.
So here you'll see what the SPG looks like.
So what we want to do now is actually create a new cart icon component that is going to contain both
the count of the cart items as well as the SPG itself.
So let's make a new folder called cart icon, and let's add the relevant files.
We need a cart icon, dot style dot size and we need a cart icon dock component Dargis X.
Inside of the car icon component, we need to import in our styles file, of course.
And then we need to initialize the car icon functional component.
And then we just need to export default, this cart icon.
Next, what we also need is we need to import in the SVG, so as we did with our logo, we say react
component as and then whatever we want to call it.
I'm going to call it shopping icon and we want to import it directly from the file location.
Once I have this shopping icon now, let's think about what our car icon itself should return.
We want to return back a div that contains both the SVG of the shopping icon and also a span that holds
the actual number, which is the count of items we have so far.
So let's initialize it as 10 for now.
And what we also want to do is we want to make sure that the styling of this works so that the number
overlaps with the shopping icon in order to do that.
We need to provide some class names that make these elements targetable by our CST.
So here I'm going to call this the car icon container.
I'm going to call this shopping icon with the class name.
Of shopping icon.
And as for the span, let's call it with a class name of item count.
So now let's save this and then inside of Kodak on styles.
I want you to paste in the icon styles file that I've also included in your resources folder.
Now, once you've pasted this in, what we're going to do is we're going to add this into our navigation
component.
So here inside of navigation bar, what we want to do is we want to import in our new car icon component.
So let's just figure out where this could go.
Let's say it before the contexts.
Let's import in the car icon from our correct placement.
Go up to the components folder inside of components or go to card icon and then card icon component.
So as far as the icon itself is concerned, we want to place this inside of the actual options container
because it sits right beside all of the options that we have.
So here this is actually one of those cases where you kind of want to think about the structure of what
you have.
We can place it right after our last sign and link.
Like so and then if we save this, we go to our application.
What do we see when we refresh?
There we go, there is our icon.
So right now, there's no interaction with it, but it's placed in the right place.
One other thing that is different in our application and the final output is that there is this additional
padding around the entire application.
So let's also add that in.
To do that, what we're going to do is go into our top level style sheet, which is our index, not
SAS.
And then inside of body, I'm going to add padding 20 pixels, 480 pixels.
So what this is saying is I want 20 pixels on the top and the bottom, and I want 40 pixels on the left
and the right side.
So now there we go.
We get a little bit of padding, so it looks a little bit better.
After this, what we need now is to actually build the down, so similarly, what I want to do is I
want to go into my components and I want to create a new folder called Cart Drop Down.
And inside of car drop down, I'm going to make both the relevant files.
So the car drop down dot styles dot SAS, as well as the cart drop down dock component such as sex.
Inside again, let's import our stylesheet.
Let's initialize the cart drop down component.
Just the base scaffolding, and then let's export as default, the cart drop down.
As for what we want to return for now, let's just create this div.
And inside of this car drop down, really all we need is before we think about what's actually inside,
let's just do a basic div.
And let's give it a class name of cart drop down.
Container.
We'll have some area here where we'll just make a temporary div just so that we hold the place, and
let's just say that what this will contain is are cart items, for example.
And then after that, we want a button that will allow the user to go to the checkout page, which is
what we have inside of our final application.
So we're just recreating this structure here.
So this means that we need to import in the button component.
So let's import in button from.
Button.
Component.
And here we just place the button and inside, we'll just say go to checkout.
Like, so so let's save this.
And now inside, as you guessed it, with cart drop down dot styles, I've also included your final
third stylesheet for this video in your resources folder.
So just take the cart, drop that style sheet, paste it in.
Now, once we've pasted this in, what we need to do now is we need to move this into the correct place
so that when we actually interact with it, we can see it.
So the place that this needs to go is also into the navigation component because it's essentially going
to live relative to the navigation bar.
So here I'm also going to import in our cart drop down from.
The components.
Components.
And then the car to drop down car drop down component.
And where I want to place this is I want to place this outside of this actual options container, so
all of these nav links.
These are not important to me, but I still want this to be within the actual navigation.
So here I'm just going to add it right after.
And now if I save this and I go back to the application.
If I refresh.
We should see it up here, right here.
So that's good.
This is what we're looking for.
So we want to now add the functionality where we can toggle the actual showing of this card.
This is where I want you to make yet another context, because that context is going to contain the
information regarding the items into the car, as well as whether or not it's open or not.
So that is another challenge I want to issue to you.
I want you to create some way for us to be able to store the state of whether or not this cart draw
dropdown is open or not.
And I want you to trigger it on click.
So give that a try.
Figure out how to create that context using the knowledge that we have so far and then buying the ability
to turn it on and off or hide and show this.
Using that logic.
So do that and then join me in the next video where we'll do it together.