Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to learn about another optimization hook called Use Memo.
The way that use memo works is that it allows us to memorize the return value of a function very similar
to the way that we have already become familiar with inside of Select.
The only thing is that we are not passing parameters all the time inside of our functions in React.
A lot of our functional components rely on outside variables, such as variables defined by the state
or defined by the scope and the props.
So as a result, use memo is a little different.
I have here created a function that makes it very easy for us to extend the time it takes for something
to finish.
So what I can quickly do is create some function and all it does is it just console dot logs, the start.
And a console that logs the end.
But what it does is it inside will delay for 2 seconds.
On top of that, what I also want to do is I want to set some value count.
And I'm going to use a used state value here simply to do so.
So here instead of our go to check out handler, this is just going to be some function that sets the
count value equal to the current count value plus one.
What I want to do from this function is I want to return 100 plus the count.
So essentially when this function fires, what it's going to do, it's going to log start.
It's going to wait 2 seconds.
It's going to log the end.
And then inside of this func value is going to be restored, 100 count.
So we can actually even call it let's call it 100 count just to be even more explicit or hundred count.
I don't know if React doesn't like us using numbers inside of our variables.
And here I'm just going to say that some content, Val, is equal to us running her account every time
this component renders.
So again, this is a very computationally expensive function just to give us 100 plus the current count
value.
And then what I'm going to do is.
I'm just going to.
Comment on all of our items and just simply render the value here.
So if I save this and if I go back to my application.
And let's just refresh.
So here inside of our application, if I were to click, go to checkout, what happens?
Count increases by one and we see the start.
There's a delay and then end and then we finally see this number.
UPDATE So what we're seeing is that there is a lot of delay because this is a computationally expensive
calculation.
But the problem with this is that if I add to cart, the component of a render count will not need to
update.
But in spite of that, as we know with our functions, there is a very expensive calculation that happens
before finally the end starts and we saw this application unfreeze.
Notice that when I click Add to Cart here, even though I've hovered off, we're still in a hover state
inside our product cart because the application is frozen due to our delay.
So despite the fact that our account value is not updating, our really expensive function is getting
recalculated every time.
Now what use memo does is it memorizes the value inside of this hook.
So when we pass it this function callback, what will happen is that won't count.
Well, initialize use memo will calculate the value inside of this function.
And then it will memorize that value somewhere.
So any time you reference it, it will now be using that memorized value unless whatever dependency
you pass inside, this dependency array changes.
So now let's say I add at the count, I'm not going to add the dependency array yet.
But here, if I save now, I come back to the application and I refresh.
Let's see what happens.
So on mount, of course, as I mentioned.
Start needs to actually run and runs after the delay.
So nothing has changed about the delay.
But at the very least, now we have our value.
But if I were to add these values.
Notice how it's not rerun during our cart.
We're also not stuck inside of that delay.
So this is essentially what happens every time the component is re rendering.
React is going into that use memo hook and whenever it sees that line right here on line 30 and it knows,
hey, I've already calculated this value before I was going to give you back whatever you get back from
this value, and now I'm always going to get back that initial value.
The problem, of course, as we can see, is that even though we're increasing the count, this number
is not changing.
So this is where you want to add in the dependency array for use memo any of the variables that you
want to track so that essentially whenever that variable changes, react will recalculate the output
of this very expensive function and then cache that value.
So now if we go back to our application, we see our initialization is slow.
We have our 100, we hit, go checkout again, delay, and then the end and then finally the value updates.
But at the very least, it does not block whenever this component renders.
The only time it's blocking and it needs to re compute.
Our expensive function is when the actual dependency array values change.
And that's it.
This is how use memo works.
It's primarily for when you have expensive functions that need to re compute and they depend on these
values inside of your functional component.
If you want to memorize those values and make sure that they don't get interrupted or they don't get
rerun unnecessarily during a re render cycle, then you use the use memo hook.
So that's a difference.
We can use memo and use callback.
Use callback memorizes the function itself.
Use memo.
Memo wise is the return value of the function.
So now we understand.
Use Mama and use callback.