Welcome back, everyone.
In this video we are going to talk about use params.
So use params comes from react router v6.
When we type this, you'll notice something interesting happens.
First, we're going to convert category component as well as the category styles.
And looking inside of styles, of course, we see no props, so we don't need to worry about that.
But when you come in here, what do you notice?
You'll notice here that category might be string or undefined.
The reason for this is because use params gives you back from an object of potential parameters inside
of the URL.
Any matches that exist from the object.
The problem here is that we know inside of our code this category can only be rendered if the root matches
that URL parameter.
Think about it, this category.
It lives inside of the shop component.
We know that the only way that this component will ever render is if this path matches with the category
value already in the URL parameter.
For us, it's an absolute known that this component will never render unless this parameter is present.
But react, router and TypeScript do not know that TypeScript only knows that use parameter can return
you back these params and this params could be empty.
If that's the case, then what we have to do is we have to tell TypeScript that we are expecting there
to definitely be a value.
So what we can say is that we want some kind of type actually not even exportable, let's just say a
type of category root params.
And this is going to have category.
Now what we want to do with these parameters is we want to tell TypeScript, just assume that these
are always going to be present.
Use params actually can take a value.
If you hover over it, you'll notice that it can take a string value.
And what is the string value going to be?
Well, here we're going to pass it not just category root parameters, but we're going to say, hey,
these are only keys of category root parameters.
The reason we do it like this is because if there are additional parameters, we want to be able to
have them accessible.
So saying, hey, this is a key of category root parameters means that you're either going to get a
category or you're going to get any other additional values that are potentially parameters that are
viable.
But beyond that, we need to enforce that.
There are definitely going to be these parameters.
So here we're going to say as category root parameters, meaning that you can assume that this is not
optional, this must be a string value.
So here now.
These category is no longer going to be undefined.
It's definitely going to be a strength.
So now we can now properly identify that these categories are always going to be present.
So this is one of those things about use pram.
You need to be able to enforce that.
Hey, I know logically that because this is in a route, this must only render if that category is actually
inside of the URL.
So in order to do that, you're going to have to use this pattern.
Now, the last component that is going to be a little bit interesting to type is going to be our payment
form component.
Now payment form.
The reason why it's interesting is because we are interfacing with a third party library, which is
right, and typing around a third party library is always going to require us to have a bit of finesse
in understanding how it works.
So to begin with, we check again.
Our style does not have any props in the components.
No problem.
We don't need to worry about it.
What about the payment form component?
Well, first off, we see that our payment handler component has a problem because again, we need to
type this according to the form, the fact that this is indeed a form type.
So we already know that we need to bring in some of those react elements that we have already done in
order to type out a form event.
So let's bring that in.
And now let's type this out as an HTML.
Form element like so.
But inside you'll notice that here we see that card must receive a valid Stripe card element.
We cannot pass in null.
NULL is not assignable to the card for this payment method.
So this means that elements that get element, car element might potentially return us back?
No.
If this is the case, we need to perform a type guard check.
So we've done this before, but we need to probably get a little bit more consider of how we're going
to do this.
So first, I'm actually going to cast this as a variable.
So I'm going to say contact card details is equal to elements like element of card element.
If this card details right here is not present, we can say if bank card details or even more explicitly
if card details is equal to null, then just exit.
Now what you'll notice is that when we switch this out over to card details.
That now it works because we're essentially saying, hey, if it's ever, no, don't even continue.
Only continue if there is a valid card details.
So this is one way we can do it.
Another way that you can do it is using a very strict.
Type guard or type predicate function as we've done before.
I'm going to show you this one as well.
If valid card element.
This is going to be equal to us receiving some card value.
But what is the card value?
Well, it's either going to be a stripe card element, as we saw earlier when we checked inside of this
card details or it's going to be no.
So to do that, we need to bring in stripe card elements.
Now Stripe card element actually doesn't even come from React Stripe JS inside the documentation, they
actually say they bring it in from Stripe itself, the Stripe library.
So here, let's just say that we get it from at stripe slash stripe dash j as it is a stripe card element.
And here again, we'll cast this card, either two stripe card element or no.
And what we'll say is that card is stripe card elements if it returns true.
So how do we know for sure that this card must be a Stripe card elements?
Well, if the card is not equal to null, then this must be a Stripe card element.
If it's not no null, it can only be a Stripe card element.
And now we can even get more explicit without check.
And we can say if.
This is.
Invalid, meaning that it is not equal to a stripe card element, then return.
Otherwise it must be a Stripe card element, which is exactly what our type card does.
So two different ways you can do it.
This one is more typescript friendly because it is a type card.
So we're going to do this one because it's more consistent with our code.
And there we go.
We have actually typed out the majority of what's challenging.
My challenge to you is to type out the remaining of these components.
You've already seen the majority of the patterns.
You can now type the rest of these as a bit of practice.
If you want even more practice, you can undo this and then type it out yourself as well.
In the end, what I'm going to give you is the actual you are.
I'll link or the GitHub repo to all of these components being fully typed.
Honestly, nothing else is going to be a total shocker, but you can read through it and make sure that
your typing versus my typing is pretty much the same.
But we'd already done 50% of everything.
And from this point forward, now we are going to use TypeScript inside of our projects.
So I'll see you in the next video.