This is our final e commerce project, we're going to have navigation and routing.
That takes us to different pages of categories of items and from these items, we're actually going
to be able to add them to our cart.
And from our car, we're actually going to see these things directly update.
And from this car, we're going to be able to check out increase or decrease these items again and see
the live changes in both our checkout page and our car page, remove items.
And actually integrate with a stripe API so that we can handle payments.
Now this is actually going to be a test version of Stripe because we don't actually have items to ship
and we don't actually want to process real payments because this is just a portfolio project.
But the matter of switching it is simply a change in the actual stripe website it you're going to actually
learn what it is to actually build using the stripe API.
And beyond that, we're also going to integrate with Firebase to handle our authentication and our storage.
So with Firebase, we're actually going to be able to authorize our users using Google so that we can
sign in with our Google accounts.
And once we sign and we're also going to provide a sign of feature.
And a sign up and sign in with email and password feature, so it's going to be a really fleshed out,
fully complete e-commerce platform, just like you would build for a real e-commerce company.