Welcome back, everyone.
In the last video, we created this get current user method.
In this video, we're going to set up our actions so that we can utilize it inside of our sagas.
So what I want to do is I want to go into the user types and here we're going to start adding some additional
types to replicate all of these different methods we need to encapsulate.
So let's think about what we have.
We know we now have this new check user session, which is going to call that method that we just created
together.
Additionally, we also know that we have different forms of sign in, such as our Google sign in which
we're going to create our Google sign and start for.
And we also have that email sign in.
So similarly, we're going to do an email sign and start.
One thing I do want you to understand, though, let's go back to the code we have for Google sign and
start email sign is start as well as check user session.
So previously let me just undo this so that we can at least see the code that we had before.
So here inside, we have now encapsulated this method inside of our new get current user method.
The thing here is primarily this create user document from off.
Essentially what we do whenever a user signs in, signs out or signs in with Google, we are passing
them through this create user document from off.
This methodology is now going to live inside of our saga.
The thing, though, is that no matter how the user signs in or signs up, they all pass through, create
user document from off.
All of our off updates get triggered inside of here, which is what actually stores the user inside
of Firebase in one of our tables, and then we extract it as a user document.
So this means that all of our Google sign and star email sign in check user session, these are all
actually flowing through the same sign in.
So here what I'm going to make is actually a sign in success, just a generic one, which whenever you
successfully sign in with email or Google, you're going to pass through the same sign in Success Saga.
So we want to trigger a signing success with that user object that we receive.
Similarly, this means that we also want a sign in failure, a generic one as well for any failures
in our ability to sign in.
So this is enough for us to at least start with some of our base sagas.
Now, of course, we can always add more as we go, but I'm going to copy these five over as well because
I want to make new action creators for them.
So in order to keep track, I'm just going to put them here.
And the new action creators we're going to make is one corresponding for each of these actions.
So I want to say export content check user session is equal to create action and then us passing in
our user action types.
Dot check user session.
Next.
What we also need is the Google sign and start.
So I'm going to export content.
Google sign in start is equal to a create action passing in user action types dot google sign and start.
Well also going to need a similar one for email sign and start.
Which is equal.
To us saying this action.
Create action and then user action, dot, email, sign and start.
The thing that we know about email, sign and start though is that we need an email and a password.
So these we're going to pass through as a payload inside of an object.
Similarly, we know we need sign in success and sign in failed as well.
So let's say sign in.
Success is equal to us receiving some user object or user off.
We'll figure that out once we start coding it out.
But we use a placeholder for now and we'll say Create action using user action types dot sign in success.
And then we'll pass the user through as the payload.
And of course we have a similar sign in failed.
This, instead of giving us the user will give us an error and we will call sign in failure.
With the air.
Actually, you know what?
Let's call the sign in failed instead of failure like that.
There we go.
So let's copy this over and let's update the corresponding action as well.
So there's our new action creators.
As for the reducer, we need to update as well.
Inside of the reducer.
We are now again no longer setting this onset current user.
Additionally, we also need to add is loading.
Because now we're going to be fetching as well.
We should also probably add the error states which will default by now.
And now what we want to do for this case, user action types set current user.
We still set current user, but now what we want to do is we want to attach it to most likely sign in
success.
So here we can say user action type start.
SIMON Success.
Modify the state's current user with the payload.
Now whenever we get a sign in failure.
Here.
We'll say sign in, failed and we'll return back.
With the state.
We can set error equal to the payload.
And there we go.
This is at least enough for us now to begin checking to make sure if our users are going in or if our
errors are going in.
So let's go into our user folder and make a user dot saga, dot as.
In order for us to write our sagas we know we need are four different generators we need.
Take latest.
We need put.
We need all.
And we need call.
From Redux.
Saga slash effects.
We also need our user action types.
Additionally, we now need some of our actions.
So let's bring in the ones we made.
We made a sign in success.
We made a sign in.
Failed.
We also made a Google sign in initials or a Google sign and start as well as email password sign and
start.
Now those though, we're probably going to dispatch from our sign up form and our sign in form respectively.
So we don't need to make those in here because those actions will be dispatched from the components.
Finally, what we also need is probably some utility functions from our firebase, but again, we'll
figure those out once we start actually coding out what's necessary.
So the first thing we want to do is start instantiating our actual aggregator function for users.
So here I'm going to say function star user sagas.
And inside, as you know, we say yield all.
Call and then whatever.
So I guess we write.
Upside.
We don't need the constant.
Just export function.
User sagas.
And here now we want to set up the different entry sagas we have.
So let's start with just the one that we made the on check user session.
So here I'm going to say export.
Our generator function on check.
User session.
This method is going to yield.
Take latest off of our user action types.
Check User Session.
When this triggers what we are going to call is a thing that will run that new function.
We create it inside of our Firebase Utils.
So let's bring that in.
Utils.
Firebase.
Useful.
And the method is the last one we just made here.
Get current user.
So here we're going to make a new saga that will call our get current user.
So let's think about what we want to call this.
Let's call it something like it is user authenticated because then at least we'll know whether or not
there's an authenticated user in our system.
So let's export out a saga.
Is user authenticated?
Like this.
And then inside is going to be a tri catch block.
Now I want you to take a second and think, what are we getting back from our get current user?
If you remember, we get back this user off object.
So here what we can say is cost user off is equal to yield.
And then we can say call, get current user.
Because we are not actually passing in any parameters.
We don't have to pass any subsequent arguments.
But this is still going to call this just with no parameters.
What we'll get back, though, is the user off if successful.
If it's successful.
And user off is not equal to not because remember user off can also be null null being there is no signed
in or authenticated user such as when we sign out or if we are signed out, then if that case we don't
really want to do anything because there's nothing to do with this null object.
We only want to use it if there is a value.
Now what we want to do with this user auth is essentially pass it to a new saga which will handle creating
a object for us inside of our firebase, which was what we did before inside of our listener.
But now we're going to move it to a saga.
So I want you to take a second and think about how to do that.
In fact, try and do it yourself.
In the next video.
We will move on from this and then tie all of the other methods of email sign and Google sign in to
that same saga.
So join me in the next video where we'll do that together.