Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to set up a nullify function.
So the great thing about net lifetime is that it makes it very easy for us to use these serverless functions.
Under the hood they use A.W. Se Lambda function, which is essentially a specific resource on the cloud
configuration that allows us to create these functions that run for 10 seconds roughly.
So that's just enough time for us to actually create this request, wait for the response and then send
it back.
And the way that we create them is inside of your root folder.
You're going to make a new folder called Net.
LFI By default net, Levi is going to look inside of this net file folder for another folder called
functions.
And any functions that you define inside of here, which are JavaScript files it will build for you
during your build step.
So we'll actually proposition and create the correct resources so that it can serve up your functions
whenever requests get made to them.
So this is the first step.
The next step is to actually name the function files.
So essentially whatever the name of the file is, is whatever the name of the root will be.
So here I want to call this create dash payments.
Dash intense.
Yes.
Because what we're making is a payment intents.
Now, in order for us to make this work, we need a couple back and specific libraries.
Specifically, we need the ones that allow us to work with Stripe.
So to do this, what we're going to do with these Netflix functions is they share the same package JSON
file as our root application.
So we're going to add them to the same exact package JSON.
So go back to your terminal.
And what we're going to do is we are going to add in through the same package.
Jason, remember, you're going to yarn add stripe, which is the stripe library we need for our back
end.
And then the other one we need is end.
Now remember when I mentioned that Crate React app has been under the hood while for us we're not in
create app land when we're working with our serverless functions, it's like a brand new node environment.
So what we need is going to be as well for this application.
So now let's add these in and then what we're going to do is go back to our application and inside of
your and file your file net life functions is going to share this same file in local testing.
When we actually deploy this internet defined, we will add these variables manually into the environment
section of Notify, but we'll talk about that when we get to the hosting section.
What I want to do is be able to access this.
So to do that, you need to go into your stripe and add your secret key here.
So I'm going to call it something a little bit more obvious.
So something like Stripe Secret Key, because it's not for react up, but I'm just going to add Stripe
key is equal to the string.
Now, I don't want to show you mine.
You should never show your secret key to anybody.
So just paste it and make sure it's a string.
Go into.
Your developer section of.
Your Stripe dashboard and then just copy the secret key.
You have to click it to reveal it and then copy it.
But that's what I want you to do.
I want you to copy it and then paste it into your secret file.
And then when you come back, we'll have assumed that you've done that.
Okay.
So I'm going to assume that you've done what I said.
Where you copy your secret key, put it into your file, and now back inside of our server, this function.
What we're going to do is we are going to require the moment that this mounts.
We're going to require again and we're going to run DHCP config on it.
Now you might notice that the code we write here is going to be a little different if you're unfamiliar
with Node primarily, we actually aren't using a lot of six features.
So this is one of these things that we're kind of going back to writing old school vanilla JavaScript.
So if you're unfamiliar, don't worry requires pretty much just an older version of import.
So we're requiring the files or essentially importing in the library and we're running config, which
will essentially attach all of those secret variables on the M file onto our process environment.
Once we have that, what we're going to do is we are also going to get Stripe.
So Stripe we're going to say require from stripe.
And now once we get this, what we're going to do is we are going to pass it our secret variable.
So here we as a process import stripe underscore secret key because that's the name that I gave to my
variable that has the secret key.
And now that we have this, we can now start working with the actual function, the function that is
housed inside of this file.
It is the main export.
So to do this, you're going to say export stock handler, which is again the old school way of saying
export that we're used to.
And this handler is equal to an async function that receives an event.
And then what it's going to do is that this event is pretty much the request and the response if you've
ever worked with expressed before.
This is essentially a stripped down version without express.
It's just a very basic function that will receive this event request and then do something with it.
So here I'm going to write a try catch block.
And what I'm going to say is that when you send me this event, I am going to make a payment intent
to Stripe using this Stripe library in order for me to make a payment intent, though, there's a couple
of things I need to know.
I need to know the currency and I need to know the payment method that I'm going to accept as well as
the amount.
So here I'm going to say, okay, I'm going to assume and this is something we need to know and pass
in, we're going to pass the amount as a integer and essentially it's going to be a value.
So let's say if it was $100, we would pass in 100, followed by two zeros.
So it's essentially incense.
There's no decimals, so it's a whole number.
So we just got to think about whatever we're passing through.
If we're assuming it's dollars, just multiply it by 100.
This amount is going to come from the event body, but because it's in JSON, we need to pass it.
So we can say Jason pass event dot body.
So on that event body is going to be some value amount and that amount is going to be the actual integer
we use.
Then what we're going to say is, okay, I'm going to make a payment intent.
So when you say const payment intent is equal to a weight because again, this is us making a request
to the Stripe server to say, Hey, I want to make this payment.
We're going to say Stripe dot payment, intense, dot create.
So this is from the Stripe library.
We're going to create payment intent and pass that an object where we're going to give it the amount,
we're going to give it the currency.
And here I'm going to say USD and then we're also going to say underscore payment method types.
This is going to be an array which accepts the different payment types that we can perform for this.
I'm going to say it's just credit card because I'm not taking any other payment types.
And then once this is done, we're going to return this back.
So we're going to return an object with a status code of 200.
And we're also going to pass back a body object.
And this is us JSON string flying.
An object with a payment intent as the key value.
So that's all this is doing.
So essentially we're saying, hey, if you give us this value and we succeed in getting a payment out,
we're going to send this back to you.
If there is an error, what we're going to do is we're going to log the error for ourselves inside of
our development environment so that we can see it.
And then what we're going to do is return back status 400.
And here we're just going to pass back the air.
And that's it.
That's all we need for this function.
Now, in order for actually to test this function, we need to actually leverage something called the
net, the seal of the seal, which will allow us to build our entire project in the kind of environment
that net life I would, but doing it locally on your own computer.
So we have our function set up in order for us to hook this together and test it.
We're going to need Net Seelye which we'll learn about in the next video.
So again, what we've done now is we have set up a very basic function that receives a request where
we expect an amount value.
We then pass this into stripe to make a payment intent, which as it sounds like it's an intent to make
a payment that stripe registers.
And then what happens is that we return that intent back to the front end.
If successful, if unsuccessful, we return back a 400 with the error.
Very simple.
And now we're going to hook this together with the net.
If I see a light.
So I'll see in the next video.