Welcome back, everyone.
In the last video we learned about the change event handler and the receiving of input elements as an
argument for what this function defines.
Now this function by default, returns void, which is what change event handler assumes you're going
to do.
You don't need to return anything because it's not expecting you to receive anything.
But if for some reason you wanted on your change handler to actually register some type of return for
whatever reason.
Another way that you can actually define this function is you can bring in the change event.
Change event is the event definition instead of the actual function definition.
And what this means is that you can define your own function definition.
So you can say, I'm going to give you some function where I expect to receive the event of change event
where the change event is registered to H HTML input element.
If you remember earlier when we looked at the actual change event handler, when we hovered over the
parameter, we noticed that we were receiving the change event as well, where we were passing the actual
type.
So before we do that and take a look at that, I'm just also going to now explicitly return void because
that's what this function does.
If you want to return something else though, again, you could put something here like your boolean
or your string or whatever this change event you happen to return.
For whatever reason, this is just another way that you can define this.
But going back to this change event, I also want to bring in this change event handler.
And I just want to show this side by side so we really understand what's happening here.
So when I hover or change event handler again, we receive some generic T which is equal to an element
and then that gets passed to change event.
So essentially this is change event.
Change event here is expecting some value t in order for us to tell it what type of element this change
event is for.
So really this function that we see right here is really just us typing it out like so.
More manually.
That's really just something I wanted to highlight to you if you wanted to define your own function
normally.
If you look at this actual definition and you see that there's a change event that is being defined
in the actual function type definition, you can use that very easily as well and write your own function
definition so you get more granular control, such as if you wanted to pass back or return some specific
type or if you wanted to even add additional parameters for some reason.
Again, this main idea is that oftentimes when it comes to typing with third party libraries, you really
just got to read the types.
It gives you a better idea of what the functions do, but it also gives you more granular control with
your typing as well.
And this becomes especially important as we start interacting with more and more third party libraries.
So that's it.
I just want to highlight to you that there are numerous ways that you can type out.
These third party interactive parameters that you're passing.
So here, let's just use the change event so that we can be more explicit in what we see.
So with that, let's type the rest of our project.