Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to learn how inside of our rendering cycles we may actually be getting
extra renders that we do not need in order to better optimize our application.
So inside of your resources folder, I want you to download this Chrome extension, the React developer
tools offered by Facebook, which is also now name matter.
Once you've installed it, if you come back to your application, what I'm going to do is I'm going
to reset our cart, so I'm going to remove everything from the cart.
And then what I'm going to do is go into the shop page and I am going to open up the developer console
inside of its own window.
Inside of here.
What I want to do is I'm going to click these arrows and you're going to see these two new little tabs
added.
One for components, one for the profiler.
We want to focus on the profiler.
The profiler allows us to record any interactions that happen inside of React, and this will pick it
up.
So first, what I'm going to do is I'm going to start profiling and then what I'll do is I will add
some cart, so I'll add one, two, three of the brown brim hat, one, two, three, four, five of
the blue beanie and then one of the brown cowboy hat.
Now, if I come back and I start profiling, what you'll see is this flame graph that will display where
it will show all of the different components and their interactions during this time.
I want to zero in though right here on the CART dropdown component.
So in here there is a timeline that is showing all of the different things that are happening inside
of our components.
But inside the CART dropdown, what you'll see is the breakdown.
You'll notice that we have our style div, which is our container, and then deeper inside there will
be additional components.
This one right here, this component is actually our cart content because it's sibling is the button.
So if you remember inside of our checkout, there is a container here that holds all of our car items
and then there is a button.
So for us inside of this container, right here is the different car items that we have.
So depending on your timeline, if you click through it, you will see.
There will be more car items added and there will be different interactions that happened during this
time.
What's happening on this car item is that this car item has a render at each of these interactions.
Now what you'll notice is that there are one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine
interactions.
There are nine render interactions because even though we added nine items each time we add an item,
this whole list is getting re rendered.
The reason it gets re rendered is due to the fact that inside of our CART dropdown component we are
updating cart items.
Car items inside of select car items is giving us a new array back and react is re rendering through
the map every single cart item.
As a result, React does not know that this car item doesn't need to re render.
Luckily for us, due to the fact that with React, it is smart enough to know that the key value is
being tracked and therefore it doesn't have to do all of the rendering process, but it is still wasting
extra renders.
As we can see, we added nine hats, but each hat is also getting re rendered nine times.
It's only the first hat.
The first hat that got added in that component is getting re rendered all nine times.
So we don't want that.
In order for us to improve it, we can actually bring in this memo method that gives us and what we
do is we wrap it around our functional component.
And as you can guess, with all memorization that we've learned up until this point, unless the actual
value changes, then we don't need to re render this component.
So now if we come back to the application and what we want to do, we want to clear our profiler.
Let's refresh everything.
Once it loads in, I'm also going to make sure to clear out the checkout.
And now when we come back to our shop.
What I'm going to do.
I'm going to start profiling.
And again, I'm going to add three of the brown from hat, five of the blue beanie and one of the brown
cowboy.
And now if we go back and we start profiling.
Now what we'll do.
We already see inside a cart drop down.
That once we narrow down.
So again, top level container, cart items, container.
And this one right here, this is our brown brim hat, the first item if we click on it.
Notice now there's only three renders.
The reason for that is because when the actual item changes, brown from have of course needs three
render.
The quantity is updating, but now React is smart enough to know that it does not need to re render
this component later on when those other components were added.
In fact, if we go back up here and we check later inside of the time cycle.
Notice how this is when the second car item got introduced.
So of course, that was the first card item.
The second card item, then the third card item.
These are all, of course, brown brim hat.
But the fourth item is when we added in that beanie.
So this is the first time the beanie shows up.
And notice how there are five renders because we added five beanies.
But if we go up, what you'll notice, as are at this instance, when we've moved on to this fourth
event, this is our car item.
It did not need to render.
It even says did not render.
So this is how we explicitly know through that memorization.
Now we are not unnecessarily additionally rendering our components.
So this is one of the advantages.
And using this profiler, you are now able to also profile throughout your application and try and see
if there are any places where you need additional optimizations.
And combined with this memorisation tool, it allows us to properly update the appropriate components
and render the appropriate ones we want to target only when they need to be updated.
So this is a really handy tool.
You pretty much just need memo and the profiler.
Check around the application, click around profile some events, read through some of the components,
see if there's anything that really needs optimizing.
The only other place where this might happen is inside of the check out component, because as we know
inside of check out, we do also map through the actual car items for the checkout.
So here with the checkout, we can also just simply wrap this inside of a memo.
And.
I'm going to leave it to you to profile it yourself first before wrapping the memo to see what happens
inside of your code base.
And just double check to see as you clear items as you increase the items, as you remove the items.
What is the profiler telling you?
Then once you memorize it, what is the profiler telling you afterwards?
Get comfortable with the profiler.
It's a pretty handy tool.
But again, always remember to not over optimize until you need to.
If you sift through the profile, you might even see that some of the initial time is between memorizing
and not.
Memorizing may increase again because the memorization cost is there.
So there we go.
Now that we understand how to optimize profile and memoires our functional components, let's move on
to the next video.