Welcome back, everyone.
In this video we are going to replace that set is car open function that we had before from a used state
into a new action creator that fits inside of our reducer pattern.
So here let's first create this method set is cart open.
And this is going to be a function that receives a Boolean value.
It's this Boolean value that we use to update is car open.
So all we need to do is just dispatch a new action object where the type goes to whatever we want to
call it.
So I'm going to call it set.
Is cart open?
And the payload is going to be the boolean value.
Then we can just pass this function.
Through into our value.
And now all we need to do is make sure that our producer is prepared to receive this value.
So inside, let's just make a new case statement.
Where we're listening for set is card open and then what we do instead of spreading payload is we say
is card open is going to be the new payload value.
Now, as I mentioned before, and some of you might have already done, these statements should be stored
in some type of contact somewhere so that we don't make mistakes when we're typing out strings.
So let's make a concert.
Cart action types object like so.
Which is equal to an object.
And inside I will receive set car items which goes to a string set car items and set is cart open which
goes to a string set is cart open.
And now I can just update.
All of the places that call the old strings.
And now let's save this and let's make sure that everything continues to work.
So let's go back to our obligation.
And there we go.
We see that our set is quite open, still works.
We see that adding to CART still works and we see that we can toggle even with CART insight.
So that's the migration.
It seems a little bit convoluted and complicated.
I definitely feel you there.
Oftentimes when working with Redux, it does have this weird feeling about it.
We're not even actually working on Redux right now.
We're working inside of context, just using the use reducer hook.
But the primary thing around reducers is really just that there is this added value that we get for
being able to separate what sets state into these separate action creators.
We kind of had something very similar with our effects, but each effect was calling its own separate
set state.
Now this is all being handled in one dispatch in order to update three appropriate values.
So this new strategy is really just so that we can congregate some of this logic into one separate function.
And primarily remember that the good time to use reducer is when one update needs to modify multiple
readable values inside of your state somehow.
So for us, this is an exact time to use a reducer because we want to update three separate values,
because whenever our reducer spits out a new object as the state is, when the provider and the context
decides it's time to rerun.
Whereas before, every time we were setting state, technically speaking, yes, they were batching
together and react is smart enough to know that.
But at least now it is a little bit more clear that whenever our set cart is getting call, three values
are updating, whereas before we were less certain about what's happening here.
Plus, this logic is a lot clearer.
You know that it's all happening in one function rather than happening through two different effects
and then split over three different other set states.
So now that we have this, let's talk about some optimizations we can make.
One thing that we noticed is that every time we have to generate this object, what we can do is actually
create a helper function.
This helper function I'm going to create inside of our utils.
So here I'm going to make a new folder called Reducer.
And inside I want to make a reducer utils.
Doc, just file.
This is going to be a create action function that receives a type and a payload.
And all it does is it just returns back for us.
An object like so very simple.
The only reason we do this is so that we don't have to type out the name of these keys, which oftentimes
leads a little bit more to human error.
So this is really just a more nitpicky kind of optimization we can make.
I'm also going to remove these unused hooks that we had before.
And of course I'm going to import in our create action from our utils folder.
Reducer.
Producer Utils.
Now, let me just make sure I'm properly exporting this.
No, I'm not.
So let's just export out cost.
And then what we'll do is we will use it in any place where we have to dispatch.
So here, instead of generating this object, like so what I'm going to say is that I want to dispatch,
create action, passing the type as the first argument.
And then this payload object.
As the second argument, which is our payload.
And then I'm going to remove.
This call like.
So let's just make sure your brackets are correct.
And also I'm going to do the same for this new dispatch here as well.
Think the first one.
Let's take the bullion here as the second argument.
And now let's just once again go back and make sure that our code is still working.
Yes, it is.
Everything works.
Once more.
What we're going to do is we are going to go into our.
Use our context.
And we're going to do the same thing we need to import in our create action.
From our utils.
Reducer.
Reducer, utils.
And then what we're going to do is just update the dispatch in the same way we're going to pass the
first argument being our action type.
And then the second argument is, of course, our payload.
And now we save this.
And now let's just make sure everything still works.
We go back to our application.
We see that we're signed out.
We sign.
Just like that.
The sign in.
Everything still works.
So our code is up to date.
And this is it.
This is pretty much how you use reducers inside of your context.
Now, again, inside of our user provider, do we need to use context?
No, not necessarily.
But if this were to scale, at least we've already set up the reducer so that it's easier to scale off
these values.
If we were to do this with car context, this is actually the exact place we should to use the reducer
because as I mentioned before, three different readable values update every time we need to update
the cart.
The only additional consideration that really needs to factor into whether or not you want to use a
reducer is also going to be up to your team.
Some teams prefer to keep everything in the realm of just react components with you state and use effects.
Most though if you're familiar with using redux before will like using reducers because it's a familiar
pattern and it has proved that it is scalable.
So now that we know how to use our reducers inside of React using the use context as well as the use
reducer hook, in the next video, we're going to talk about Redux as a library.
Redux as a library takes this concept of reducers and extrapolates it out into an entire Redux based
ecosystem.
And we're really going to dive deep now that we at least have a good idea of how reducers work into
using Redux as a library, as well as the ensuing additional complexity that comes with using a library
like Redux for state management.
I'm also going to talk about when you want to use context with user reducer versus using Redux in the
next video as well.
So stay tuned and join me in the next video.