Welcome back, everyone.
In the last video, we learn about nested routing and the outlets that in turn will render whatever
the nested matching route will be.
So here what we see is that this directory component is staying persistent despite what gets rendered
as a sub route.
So what we know then, is that perhaps we can leverage this pattern for our navigation bar in order
to continually render our navigation bar, regardless of what path we navigate to.
So let's leverage this idea.
Let's go back to our application, and let's actually think about what we need to create.
We need to create some top level navigation component.
I was going to call it navigation for now.
We can rename it after.
But for the purpose of this lesson, let's just make it very clear this navigation component is going
to contain a div inside of this div.
I'm just going to put some kind of div placeholder that has an H1 that says I am the navigation bar.
We'll fill it with an actual navigation bar after.
But with just this, we know that this is going to be some component that always lives on the page.
It's going to be essentially the parent level component because it holds the navigation bar in sign
out.
Whatever's underneath the navigation bar should render the home page or the shop page, respectively,
depending on the part.
So to do that, we're going to utilize an outlet.
So why don't we set this up first and then I'll explain in detail what's happening in case this is a
little confusing.
So this navigation bar should be at the top level, so at the very top level, this should nest everything
and it should nest it under slash.
And the element that it points to should be this navigation component.
Inside of here is where we now want to render our appropriate sibling components.
So instead, remember shop is nested under home.
We don't want that anymore.
We want these to be siblings of each other.
And I want.
This home, just to be explicit, let's just keep it home for now.
And now let's nest these inside of here.
Now, if we save this, well, we should see is that when we're on the home page?
We just see our navigation bar.
If I go to my home.
I see the directory.
If I go to shop, I see the shop edge.
So so far, the navigation bar is persistent.
But when we learn on our website, we do want just this base, Pat, to show the directory instead of
having to go to slash home.
So how do we do this?
Well, instead of pattern matching path like this, we can actually use the term index and index is
an attribute.
If you pass index like this, it's actually equivalent to saying index is equal to true.
It's just shorthand.
But what this tells this route is that when you match just this slash, so with nothing on it, then
this should be the home component.
That's what you render at the outlet level.
So match this slash when it's empty as the base component.
So we know that we already have a parental component, but render whatever the base is inside of the
outlet.
So here now, if we save this, we go back.
We see that we don't have anything we don't flash on, but we see our directory.
And now if we navigate to slash up.
We should see the director disappear and we see our shop page.
But the main thing is now we're persisting this navigation bar.
So this is actually our top level component.
This outlet will now, in turn, render everything else in sight.
So we have no leveraged that specific pattern utilizing the outlet that we had previously in our home
component, but now we've moved it to the top level navigation component and this top level navigation
component is kind of like the template.
It essentially represents the thing that should always be present.
And the thing that we decided to be president was going to be this navigation bar component inside this
outlet.
This is what we'll swap based on the remaining route matching inside and this pattern matching this
deeper nested route matching.
You can do continually, however, nested deep you go.
And that's the big advantage of rack, right?
Or dump.
It takes a little bit of time to wrap your head around this concept, but you'll get a lot of practice.
But here we can see how we leverage this outlet pattern now in order to persist.
The navigation bar.
So we're definitely going to leverage this pattern a lot throughout the rest of this application in
the next video, let's style this navigation bar looks closer to what we actually have in our final
application and then we can continue building out our roots and building our pages.
So I'll see you in the next video.