Think of a progressive Web app, more like a running list of things you can do than a static list.
It's going to evolve over time.
But the idea is to make user experience, as we know, as close as possible to a native app.
By the way.
Maybe you don't trust me, maybe you think that this progressive Web app is just pure hype and I'm just
teaching us something that won't exist in two years.
Well.
Companies like Twitter.
Have adopted progressive web apps, so much so that Twitter has moved all of their mobile Web traffic
to a react progressive Web app.
Alibaba, dotcom.
Yeah, they use a progressive Web app, Lyft and Uber uses a progressive Web app.
Lyft, for example, has a goal of making their progressive Web app a hundred percent parody or have
complete feature set that their mobile phone has.
Their mobile app has to be the exact same as their Web app.
And there's tons of companies that are adopting progressive web apps because it is so beneficial.
Let me show you a few examples to really emphasize and make you understand what this is.
One of the great examples that I like is this pogo index dot org website, a very, very simple website
that shows you Boeckmann information.
Everybody loves that.
Now, this is a progressive Web app.
Well, how so?
If I go open up the developer tools.
And you see over here, if I click on the icon that shows toggle device toolbar.
And I scroll down here.
Well, show me the mobile view of this app.
Let me scroll down so we can see it fully and we see over here that it looks pretty good on mobile,
I can even turn it around.
And we also have the menu that's working.
But the cool part about this is if I turn off my wi fi.
Which usually gives us that blank page with the dinosaur on Chrome saying we don't have an Internet
connection.
Well, check this out.
This still works.
How cool is that?
If I had this on my phone, even though I don't have an Internet connection, I'd be able to still check
out all these Pokemon's.
All right, let's turn back the Wi-Fi.
And take a look at another website, and this is the Hacker News, progressive Web apps.
And you can think of it as a playground where people try and rebuild the hacker news website using a
progressive Web app and you can see here, it gives us the lighthouse score.
It gives us some important metrics like how fast our Web page loads.
And you can even look at the code of people that have implemented this.
Now, let's click on The View app over here for one of the examples, and we see over here that we just
have a simple Hacker News website.
The cool part about this, and this is a thing that we'll talk about later on in the videos is if I
open this tab now, let's scroll this tab up now.
And we go to application.
Scroll all the way up to what we call the manifest.
We see over here that there's a add to home screen button and this add to home screen button appears
for mobile users.
If I visited the site multiple times, it's going to have a pop up and you might have seen this while
browsing the Web as well that says, hey, do you want to add this to your home screen?
You see over here, if I click that, I get this little notification.
If I click on ADD.
I can add the application will keep the name the same.
And now on my desktop and now on my desktop.
Look at that, I have Prepacked Hacker News app.
Straight on this desktop and it.
Opens up right away if I turned off the Wi-Fi.
And open this up again, we see that it still works.
How cool is that and you still see the you are albar because this is a browser, but if we were on a
mobile phone, you actually wouldn't see this.
You are albar and it will feel completely like an app.
Very, very cool.
You see here that we don't completely have full features because you still need Wi-Fi for some parts.
But that's OK, right?
Good.
Because native apps work like that to.
There you go, starting to load now.
All right, so I think that's enough examples to prove to you that maybe we should consider doing this
whole progressive Web app thing.
In the next few videos, I'm going to show you the three most important parts to build our own progressive
Web app, and we're going to talk about these three topics so that our friends app is going to be a
progressive Web app by the end of this section.
And Bruno is going to love us for it.
I'll see in the next one.
Bye bye.