Welcome back.
In this video, let's talk about all the tools we can use to actually run our tests, remember, our
tests are just JavaScript, so we could just write simple JavaScript files with maybe if statements
that says, you know, if the same function as these two numbers together, then return success or otherwise
return test fail.
So we could do that.
But that's tedious.
And as developers, we want to use existing tools to make our experience or our speed of development
faster.
So this is going to get overwhelming, but let's look at testing tools.
I tried to organize for you a way to think about tests and the testing environment and the Web development
land, so I'm going to explain this.
And if this is a little complicated at first, don't worry.
We're going to come back to this and go over this at the end of the section, and it's all going to
make sense.
So the very first thing we need in a testing tool is something called a testing library, pretty self-explanatory.
This is the scaffolding giving us the ability to use some function calls and some new methods for us
to actually write our tests.
Again, think of this as scaffolding or building the structure around our tests.
Probably the top three libraries for that is Jasmyn, there's just and then there's something called
Moka.
And like I said, these are just npm install libraries, so they're available on NPM and you can add
them to build your scaffolding.
The next thing that you need right over here is something called an assertion library.
And in here we have again Jasmyn that comes with its own assertion library, we have just once again
that comes with its own assertion library and then TCHI here that usually gets paired with Moka in order
to have an assertion library.
An assertion library provides functions that are assertion functions.
I know that's confusing.
It's essentially a tool to allow you to test that.
The variables contain the expected value.
Now, that still sounds confusing.
So let me show you.
We're on the TCHI Assertion Library here, and you can see over here that they use something called
BDD or behaviorial driven development, and by installing this library, we can use all these words
and they just look like basic English.
What an assertion library does is says expect that this object that just contains a equals one and then
it chains all these words together to test our assumption.
So let's say expect that this object to not have property be it reads like English, right.
It simply test condition one against condition two.
So this is going to return false because you're right, this object won't have property B.
And they have a lot of things that we can add.
We see that another one is expect this object to have all keys, A and B. It kind of reads like English
and this makes our test really easy to read and understand.
The next thing we need for our test is something called a test runner.
And a test runner is something that allows us to run our tests, remember, if we go back to our app.
We had to do AMPM.
Ron.
Test.
And this runs our test.
Let's press a to run all the tests and something is magically running all these tests.
That's what a test runner does.
Going back to our slide again, we now see that Jasmyn and just include a test runner and their library,
and then Moka also has its own test runner.
And then I've added another one over here, which is called Karma James.
And this allows you to run tests in the browser.
Hmm, what does that mean?
Well, a test runner can run tests in different environment.
Let's have a look.
You see, usually our JavaScript works with the DOM to make our Web app what it is.
But when we're running tests and and this is what karma does, allows you to run your tests on the browser.
But why wouldn't we just always run our tests on the browser?
Well, that is because it takes a lot of time.
We have to run every single test through the browser using the browser APIs.
Ideally, when we run tests, it's super, super quick because most tests are set up so that if a developer
hits save on their terminal, it's going to run to the test.
If every time they needed to start up the browser and run through everything, well, that would be
really, really slow.
So other options exist, such as puppeteer by Google, which is what we call a headless browser.
It's a node library which provides a high level API to control the headless version of their browser.
So think of it as a stripped down browser that makes your tests a little bit faster.
But it can also be configured to do things such as generate screenshots, pdf of pages.
It can automate form submissions, you can do UI testing with it, you can monitor keyboard input,
you can do a lot of cool things with it.
And then finally we have something called geston.
And just dumb, as the name suggests, is an end JavaScript implementation of the dump.
So it's not the real Dom, but a fake JavaScript version of it.
And remember, the dam is that tree like structure that shows the nodes on our webpage and that's what
makes up our UI.
So just dumb implements this in JavaScript so we can have a DOM like API to work without actually needing
the browser.
If we go back to our tests.
And let's run this again, I'm going to run NPM run test, you'll see over here that we asked Scripps
Test Dash Dash ENF.
It went by quickly by you saw that we are using Jass Don there.
So that our test run really, really quick.
All right.
So that's a test run.
Next, we have something called Mock Spies and Stobbs.
And in here again, Jasmine and Jess come with their own version.
And then if you're using something like Moka, just like you had to add an assertion library, you'll
have to add something called sign on.
There are obviously other libraries, but this is the most popular.
Now, what's all this?
Mock Spies and Stubbe business?
Well, spies provide for us information about functions, how many times they were called and what cases
and by whom, Stubing replaces selected functions with a function to ensure that the expected behavior
happens.
And then Mock's is kind of like faking a function or a behavior to test different parts of a process.
So this might be really, really good for integration tests.
Now, I know that can get a little bit confusing.
So let's take a look at Sinon.
Sign on over here if you go to their documentation, let's click on Stobbs Free scroll down.
We see that what is a stop doing?
We're simply using the library sign on dot stub, which is a function.
Now, we can use it in a way where this function can be called with arguments 40 to.
And make a return one so that when we run, call back.
Forty two, it returns one and what we do call back dot with arcs, it throws an error.
Again, this is something that we'll go over later in the videos.
But you see here, that stub is we can fake functions and make them do what they expect.
For example, sign on can be used to fake a server during our tests, we don't necessarily want to send
request to the server every time we're running tests.
But ideally, if a function is using a server, we can fake it with a stub so that the function still
runs and we can just test that one piece of code.
Like I said, this is really hard to explain without a little bit of a demo, but don't worry, we're
going to get there.
And then the final piece of the puzzle, we've talked about scaffolding, about assertion libraries.
We talked about test runners.
We talked about these Stobbs marks and spice.
Finally, we have something called code coverage.
And code coverage is provided by libraries like Istanbul.
Just has code coverage already included, but has actually Istanbul running underneath the hood.
And let me show you what a code coverage might look like.
Luckily for us, we can just do ampm test, dash, dash, dash coverage and don't worry, we'll talk
about how we can do this in our apps.
But if I run this, you see the Jazz Domme here.
I get an outputted file of the coverage and you see over here that I have my robo friends up and I have
some green, some red, some yellows, and this is a test coverage that shows me what percentage of
the statements, the branches, the functions are covered with tests.
You see here that I've written some tests for the constant stage's file, some actions that just file,
and also for some of our components, some of our card lists, components, and that we have one hundred
percent coverage for those.
But then we also have things like the header file that is missing some test, and it even shows us which
lines we're missing testing.
And that is Istanbul underneath the hood, giving us a report of where we're missing tests.
Now, although these are a lot of libraries, they all have the same goal in mind and they all actually
are written in very similar fashion.
So once you know one, it is really, really easy to pick up another one.
Don't get overwhelmed by this, just like with anything.
There's a lot of tools for the job, but we'll come back to this.
So it all makes sense in the end.
Just keep in mind that the syntaxes are very similar, so you'll be just fine.
And I also want to let you know that probably the most popular Jasmyn used to be very popular, but
it has now been overtaken by two things.
One is, just as you can see, just as nice because it has everything in one place.
You can just install this library and have all these little features that you need in a testing framework.
Another popular one is Moka, combined with Tchi and Sinon.
And this is, again, probably the most popular setup, but that's also because just as Alan you are,
most of these libraries follow the idea of behavioral driven development, which is we describe what
a function does and say what behavior we expect out of them.
You remember the TCHI assertion, right?
If object has this properties, we expect it to have this property A.
All right, does your head hurt yet?
Luckily for us, if it wasn't for Kerry racked up, we would have to npm install all of these again,
set them up and add them to our scripts to run all these tests and test coverages.
But as you can see with Priore ACTTAB.
We have everything out of the box.
Again, the best minds in the community are working on maintaining Creary ACTTAB to always keep it up
to date as all of these libraries update as well.
Don't worry, though, I'll show you in the upcoming videos how to actually set this up yourself as
well.
One other note in our tests over here.
Create react app uses just and that's because just was created by Facebook and if you remember, React
was also developed by Facebook, which is kind of nice because they use it in their own production environment
and these tools are used together to work really, really nicely.
And by the way, there's other testing libraries, we have a VA that does parallelism really, really
well, which means Iran tests, runs tests really, really fast.
And then you have something like tape that is really low level, simple light library.
But as I said before, don't get.
In short, if you get anything from this video is that if you just want to get started and looking for
a fast framework that can handle everything and has everything in one, well, just use just if you
want very flexible extendible configuration where you can plug in some things, then use Moka.
Mokas a little harder to set up because of all these things that we need to add on.
But it's more flexible and like I said, open to extension's.
One last note in our test, we're going to use two things that are sort of unique to react.
One is something called snapshot testing that comes with jest, which allows us to do some really cool
things that I'm going to show you later on.
And then another library called Enzyme, which was created by Airbnb and helps us write tests better
for reactor components.
Don't worry, I'm not just showing you these things because I think they're cool and trendy.
These are implemented and most Riak projects that you're encounter, and it's pretty much become the
standard in the react ecosystem to use these libraries.
So we're going to use them to.
At the end of the day, though, we can agree on one thing.
All these libraries have really cool logos.
I'll see in the next one.
Bye bye.