Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to style out the cart icon with style components, so as normal we are
going to first convert our style sheet over to a chair sex.
And the key difference in this component is primarily that there is an SPG in here.
Now, one thing I want to note about converting and targeting SDGs is that you can even do this without
star components.
So I'm going to show you how I would tackle styling this specific component.
Normally you got to think about your components when it comes to whether or not you want to make a brand
new component to wrap it, or if you want to target some other way.
So the way that we want to target the shopping icon is we know that there's some styling that's going
to be applied on this component.
And as I mentioned before, we can actually directly just target our own components, including these
SPG components.
So here what we can do is we can actually say export contest shopping icon.
And instead of this being shopping icon, let's call this shopping SPG because we want shopping icon
to be the name of the store component that we expose.
I'm going to say styled on this shopping SPG component and then what I'm going to apply is the styling
here with the width 24 and the height 24.
And then we can just stop everything else as normal.
So here I'm going to do.
Carl Icahn container.
Which is astounding.
Let's just fix that.
That will have this width.
Now, as I mentioned before, instead of doing it this way, you could have also technically targeted
it with the SVG.
Like so?
Which is the typical styling way, but this way I find it a little bit more within the alignment of
house style component wants you to write your components.
And then the last thing is our item count, which I believe is a span.
Yes, it is.
So here we can just paste in those styles that we had.
And we can save this and now import this into our component.
So of course, now we already have this coming from our stylesheet now.
So we got our shopping icon, a cart icon container, as well as our item count.
So now our shopping icon can stay the same.
This will replace the div right here.
And then the item count, of course, will replace the spam.
And there we go.
If we go back to our application, we see that everything here still works.
Our icon still has the styling, it's still at the appropriate size.
So now let's stall the next thing, and this is our directory item.
So the directory item styles are pretty comprehensive.
Plus, there's one additional thing that we're going to learn through styling the directory item because
right now we actually apply a custom style property using what React gives us as this style prop.
We actually don't need this because we can pass props directly into all of our components that we make
with style components.
And this is actually a very, very powerful thing because now what we can do is we can treat these components
as if they were regular components, but there's a little bit of syntax we have to learn.
So let me show you so first, we import stuff from style components.
And now what we need to do is let's think about what it is exactly that we're trying to do here.
So first things first, let's talk about the targeting.
This component needs to target a background image class.
We can actually make a component for this background image, but we have to make it in the order in
which it will get called.
So if inside of directory item container, one of our styles targets this component, then we need to
have that component already declared.
So here I'm going to say Konst background image is equal to a style div, because that's what this background
image is.
So this style div is going to have a couple styling on it by default.
So the first one is going to be all of these styles.
So let's just copy this over.
And then when it's going to have is typically when you use this background image, as you can see here
in this, did we pass the stop, but we can't do this anymore.
Instead, what we're going to do is we are going to actually pass this as a value and we can call it
image URL.
You can call it whatever you want.
It's really just the prop name that we're going to access the same way we will later inside of our components.
So let's imagine instead, I pass image URL into this component.
The way that I can access is I can actually say background image is going to point to and then I'm going
to string interpolate because this is just a tactic string.
So now I can actually access the different props that get received in just the way that you would like
a component.
You write a function.
And what this will be is props, which means that we can d structure off image URL because that is being
passed in as a prop.
And now what we can do is we can return back a string that says your URL wrapping the image URL.
It's the same thing that we had before, but now we're passing in as a prop and then rendering it within
the CSC of our background image.
So after this, now we need also to look inside.
Notice how we're also targeting a body.
We're changing the opacity when this component gets hovered on.
So we actually need this body first before we can target it inside the component.
So I want to say body is equal to a stop div and this style div is going to accept all of this styling
here.
And also inside it targets the H2 and the pea tag.
So if you're wondering with this H2 and this is it worth creating a new, separate style component for
it?
Well, this is where you need to think.
If you know that your component only has one H2 and one paragraph tank inside of this body div, then
you don't need to.
If you start adding more tools and you want different styling, then you can start splitting it up more
at a granular level into more different style components.
But generally speaking, it's based on how you would normally write your CC anyways.
So this is one of those things.
It's just really a matter of thinking about your composition and what you need and what you don't need.
So now that we have both the background image and the body, we can finally do export content directory
item container.
And here it'll be equal to a stop to.
And inside, let's add these styles, so this hover style is very important.
We want to take this over.
And inside notice on the hover.
So here we target a background image instead of what we're going to target is directly the background
image.
So component that we have and the same thing is going to apply for the body.
And that.
Is pretty much all we need unless I'm missing some other stuff.
Let's just double check.
Oh, I'm missing these these styles right here for first child and last child relative within.
Side of our directory item container, but I think this is it as far as this large, I actually believe
this is not being used anymore, so we actually don't need this styling.
So let's just clear out that old CIUSSS.
And now let's import this and use it in our directory item component.
So here I'm going to import.
From our directory item styles.
And now what we need is the background image.
We need the body and we need the directory item container.
So here at the top level, we're going to get rid of the container.
For background image, we are going to get rid of this device while making sure to pass the actual image
your value still through.
And then for the body, let's just get rid of the do.
And.
It looks like perhaps.
There is a bit of an issue here.
Oh, oh, I'm missing a opening tag.
There we go.
OK, let's go back to our application.
Let's go to the homepage and there we see we have everything working.
We can also capitalize these titles if we want very easily with a little bit of CSI magic.
We can just go to the H2.
Which is actually inside of the body and here we can say, Tex transform uppercase.
And now if we save this and we come back.
We should see that all of our titles are now uppercase, cased.
OK, so this component, the primary thing I want you to realize is that you can pass whatever props
you want into these style components.
This gives you a lot more power in deciding what rules you want to generate inside of these components.
You can even determine if you want to add additional styling here and there by using this pattern.
So this is another great benefit that we get with style components.
You can treat them like components and they can receive props.
So now after this, the last thing we need to start is going to be actually one of the more complicated
components, maybe the most complicated one, which is our form input, and we'll do that in the next
video.