Welcome back, everyone.
So let's get started with building out Crown clothing to begin with.
We're going to scaffold out and set up a project using Create React app, which you really should be
using 90 percent of the time.
The only time where you don't want that is when you really want the customizability that comes with
Webpack, when you actually want to scaffold a project from scratch.
Most of the time, though, you're not going to want that because you'll have to do a lot of those optimizations
yourself and create React app is literally a team that's dedicated to figuring that out from tons and
tons of different large enterprise projects that are pushing reax boundaries.
Generally speaking as well, when it comes to setting up your own custom webpack or setting up a custom
babble, you can pretty much just inject those files and still get the benefit of a lot of the default
scaffolding set up that you get with create racked up as well.
So generally speaking, I would say most of the time always use Create React app to set up your projects.
And to do that again, we're just going to run NTPC's, which is just this helper that brings down the
library and then installs our project and then gets rid of Create React app so it doesn't take up more
memory than it needs to.
So you're going to do Ampex Create React app and then the name of your project, which I'm going to
name on Crown Clothing.
You can name yours whatever you want.
You may or may not get this prompt that's going to ask you if you want to install, create, racked
up locally.
Just say yes, and then you just wait for this to finish.
OK, so everything is installed now, and we're we're going to do is just seed into our project and
let's open it up so that we can get rid of some of the files that have been generated for us that we
don't need.
So as we saw before, will get generated this app?
Yes.
And primarily what we don't want is we don't want everything here inside of our app.
Most of this is not really necessary for us.
Perhaps we'll keep the divide, but let's just make our own dinner for now.
And inside of this divide, let's just also say.
Hello, world.
So at least we know our application is running.
Oh, sorry, this auto tag closure is doing a lot of funky stuff right now.
As a result, we also don't need the logo.
We also don't need the CSIS, really, we just need our app, and I'm going to change this over to a
narrow function just because I'm much more familiar with Essex.
And this is it.
This is all we need our app to be for now, inside of apps, yes, we don't really need any of this
either.
And for the remainder of our project were primarily going to write actually in a variation of CSE's
known as SAS, which is stylish or sassy CCS.
And it's just an easier, more composable way of writing or CSR.
In fact, once we learned that SAS writing style of CIUSSS were going to migrate over to a JavaScript
CSS library, but we'll discuss all of that later right now, don't worry too much about it.
We can keep the indexes.
We can also change it later.
For now, we can keep it.
There's not much significance to it.
And then finally, inside of index jazz, here we have everything that we need.
We can keep all this.
Everything here is good.
Primarily speaking now, our project is pretty much set up, so now let's just save everything and start
up our application just to make sure that everything is working as expected and the terminal I'm going
to run yarn start.
This might take a little bit of time to boot up, depending on your computer.
And automatically, it should take you to local host 3000.
Here we see our Hello world, so we know our application is working as we expect.
We want to do now is we want to start setting up the basic outline of our application.
So I kind of want to generate these five different category cards per se.
Let's call it that.
So let's think about what this component might look like.
We know that there will be an outer container that is going to hold these five different cards.
And in each of these cards themselves, we have what looks to be another container, so this can be
another device.
Inside of this, there's an image, there is yet another container, and then inside is two different
text fields.
So let's just build that.
So coming back to our application instead, I'm going to generate one outer div.
And just so that we can be clear for ourselves, let's also add class names on these that tell us what
these different components are.
So let's start with class name on this outer div, and I'll call this the categories container because
that's pretty much what this is.
And then inside we have these five different.
So I'm going to create one placeholder for now and this one, I'm going to call it the category container
because that's really what it is.
It contains all the content in our category.
Inside, we have an image, and for now, this doesn't have a source.
So let's actually comments it out just to use it as a placeholder.
So we know that there is an image eventually.
And then within this image, there is yet another container.
That is going to hold the two titles that we have.
So this one, I want to call this the category body container.
And then inside of here, let's say there's an H2 with hats as one of the texts.
And then there is also a paragraph tag.
And this one will say, Shop now.
So we know that there are five of these.
So let's copy this and just paste this five different times.
And now that we've passed the Senate.
Let's see what we have, we have hats, jackets, sneakers, women's and men's.
So let's say hats, jackets.
Sneakers.
Women's.
And men's.
Let's save this.
And let's go back to our obligation and see what we have.
Let's refresh.
And that was it.
We have our hats, we have our jackets, we have our sneakers, we have our women's that we have our
men's.
So this kind of gives us our layout.
We haven't applied any styling to this yet, which we will do in the next video, but you can see how
it's pretty much just the exact same way we were starting with our Moses Rolodex.
At this point, really, that's all it is.
You're going to start your project arguably the same way you start any project you just want to start
working from the outside in.
But now that we have a project set up, let's start actually styling this and installing in the next
video a tool that will help us write easier access.
I see in the next lesson.