So with every Gaffey project, because Gatsby rules with graphic you all by default as its query language,
you're able to actually access a graphical playground by going to localhost eight thousand.
Underscore, underscore, underscore graphically.
Well, this will load up this playground that shows us all of the queries we're able to make inside
of graphics.
Well, now this is really good because we're actually able to do a lot of different things with this
graphical query list.
For example, by default, we're actually able to access every single file inside of our directory.
Now, when I say this, what do I mean?
So if you look inside of your Gatsby config, you'll see that there's this plug in here called Gatsby
source filesystem.
Now, Gatsby source filesystem is a way for you to actually access the nodes that represent the files
inside of this directory with the name and the path.
The name just essentially allows us to tell Gatsby what it is that we want to put this under when we
query for it.
Now, what are we calling for is actually going to be any files that lives inside this path that we
provide it.
So here we see that we're string interpolating this directory name, which pretty much just represents
whatever the final directory structure is.
And I want to go into our source folder and then our images folder.
So right here.
Now it's named images, because what it's trying to do is get all of the image files.
Now, if we go back to our graphic, you all will see that what it is that we got is actually this thing
called all file.
Now, inside of this explorer, you'll see this list of all the different queries that we can access.
So if we wanted to actually see what that plugin was giving us, if I do all file and I hit command,
enter or control, enter, if you're on a windows, you'll see that automatically populates with these
properties of edges node and then the ID now edges represent the actual path to that file that we're
pointing to.
So meaning that edges will be the array of the number of files that we have inside of our images folder.
Now, inside of every edge will be a node and that node is the representation of what that file is.
Now, the node Gatsby will convert for us.
But what that means is that if we look inside of this list, we'll be able to see what properties were
actually able to pluck off and look at.
So if we do absolute path and if we do relative path as well.
If we hit enter again, we'll see that we're pointing to each of our image files and now by using this
query, we're actually able to get all of the files that we want inside of our project.
So if we wanted to, for example, store different data inside of these files in order to actually represent
our blogs, we're able to do so using this all file query.
Now, we're definitely going to explore that because this is really how it is that we're going to build
out our blogs.
There is a couple of things that we have to make sure that we do.
First, though, one thing is that while we're able to see a representation of our files, we cannot
actually get the data in those files.
Yet in order to do so, we have to make some modifications to Gatsby.
And what we're going to write is going to be a little bit different than anything else you've probably
ever written before.
Now, what we want to do is we want to start actually building our blocks.
There's a couple of things that we have to do in order to set this up.
The first is that we have to write the files that will hold the data of our blogs to begin with.
So these could just be individual blog posts with some text on them.
Now, the way that we can actually build out the blog content and get access to all the styling is to
use something called markdown.
Now, if you're unfamiliar with markdown, markdown is what is used to build.
Many of the read means that you see inside of GitHub.
So you'll see that we have access to these different titles.
We got access to the static linking.
We can put all of these images inside and we also get access to these code blocks inside of markdown.
So markdown is a pretty consistently structured and very supported style of writing text that Gatsby
also allows us to use.
So if we wanted to write our blogs and get styling, you really just need to learn a little bit of markdown.
And I will give you a markdown cheat sheet that tells you all of the different styles you can apply
and markdown when you start writing your blogs.
But I have some pre written.
So what we're going to do is we are going to make a new folder that is going to hold all of our markdown
files that represent the blogs we're about to make.
So go back to your application and what you're going to do is make a new file inside of your source
or sorry, a new folder.
And we're going to call it markdown pages.
Inside of Mark Down pages is going to be each marked down file that represents each blog post you're
going to write.
So I'm going to make a new one and I'm going to call it ice cream and I'm going to kind of ice cream.
Dot M.D., now M.D. stands for markdown.
Now, inside of this, I'm just going to paste my markdown code that represents the first blog that
I'm writing, and I am also going to give you this resource as well just so that you can walk through
with me before you actually make your own markdown files.
Now, you'll notice at the top here, there are these three dashes.
These three dashes represent what's called the front matter.
And the front matter is just kind of like some data that you can pull off of this markdown file and
have it represent perhaps some data that you want to display inside of a snippet rather than the entire
content of the actual blog itself.
This can also hold any metadata so you can just see the front matter as metadata and we're going to
explore how to actually use it inside of our graphical queries.
So other than this one, I actually also have another markdown file that I want to make and I want to
call it my first amay M.D. and similarily.
I have the other file here for you.
And here you'll see that I'm embedding an iFrame now this iFrame points to a YouTube link of the first
amay that I did a couple of weeks ago, but this thing is actually going to be what you get from YouTube
as an embed link so you can put this inside a markdown as well, because markdown ends up being computer
HTML.
And that's another great thing about using markdown.
Is that using these to markdown files, we're now able to represent our blogs very dynamically because
if we wanted to write new blogs, we simply just add new markdown files that represent our blogs.
And then after we write the remaining code that will dynamically build out our blog posts will be pretty
set in terms of our blog Web site.
Now, the one thing that we do have to do is we have to make sure that we're actually able to access
these markdown files, because as you remember inside of our config right now, all we're doing with
this file system is simply accessing images.
If we wanted access to markdown, we can just duplicate this block of code here.
So copy paste it down, except I'm going to change this name over to markdowns.
And instead of the path pointed to images, I'm going to point to our new markdown pages path.
So let's save this and what you have to do is you actually have to restart your server whenever you
change any plugins inside of your config.
So while we get hot reloading with a lot of the metadata or into the files that we change inside of
our general structure, we do not get it with our config plug ins.
If you change the plugin, just restart your server.
And once it's finished building, we're going to go back to our graphics and we're going to take a look
at what it is that we get.
So if we refresh now and we enter, we still see our original image files.
But now we see that we also have our markdown files.
So now that we're able to access the node representation of these markdown files, let's actually figure
out how to pull the data out of them in order to dynamically build out the pages that we need inside
of our application to represent these blog posts.
And that's what we're going to do in the next lesson.
So I'll see you in that lesson.