Welcome back, everyone.
In the last video, we learned about nesting components inside of the rotting structure, and we're
starting to set up our initial navigation bar component.
In this video, we are going to dive deeper into actually styling it out and structuring our code according
to our folder structure.
So the first thing that I want you to do is I actually want you to take this navigation component and
put it inside of your roots.
So I'm going to make a new component or a new folder for our component inside of our Roots folder called
navigation inside of navigation, it's going to follow the same format where we have a navigation dock
component Dutch sex file.
Then we're going to go back to OPG's.
We're going to cut out this code for navigation, and we're going to paste it inside of our navigation
component file, then we're going to copy this outlet code.
Because that's where we need.
The outlet.
From recruiter Tom, because we're going to be using the outlet in order to actually render these Nasdaq
components inside of our navigation.
And then I'm going to export default navigation, the same setup we've been doing all this time.
Now inside of us, because we're now no longer leveraging navigation that we had to find inside, we
need to import it in and we also need to get rid of outlet because it's no longer a dependency.
And here we're going to go up to our Roots folder.
Our navigation.
And our navigation component.
And now all our code should work the exact same.
So let's just check.
We see that we have our navigation bar.
And we have our navigation bar on our home page, so everything's still working.
When we look at our application here, our final application, this is what we want the navigation to
barge a look right now, it's just some text.
So let's start building it up.
Let's go back to our navigation component, and let's remember what these dives are.
This outside dive is almost like a dive that contains everything, so the entire page.
Instead of using a div here, we can actually use a fragment and a fragment is something that we get
from react.
It's essentially a component that actually renders to nothing when it actually gets mounted on the DOM.
The whole reason of using a fragment is because of reax roles where our component must have a parent,
a top level parent containing component.
A fragment is useful if you don't actually want to render some specific moment.
For example, if I just want a div that represents the actual navigation and then I want the components
that represent my pages down below.
I don't need a wrapping div.
I can just use a fragment.
So with this fragment, once it actually finally renders, nothing's going to render on the page, I
will check this out.
So let's save this code and let's just give this class name for now.
Navigation so that we know what we're looking at when we look inside of our home.
So let's save this.
Let's go back.
Let's refresh.
And let's just inspect the elements on this page.
So here inside of elements, what we see is that this is our navigation.
And then right away, it's our route.
This route is the entry point.
If you remember, we use react on to render targeting this div.
But other than the navigation and then the inside div that contains the homepage element of directory.
There is no other wrapping div.
So as you can see, there's actually no fragment on here.
And that's the beautiful thing about rock fragment.
Very useful.
So let's go back and now style the rest of our navigation.
So we have this navigation component, and what we know is that there is a logo component here.
So for now, just going make a do and inside I'm going to say logo.
We're actually going to import in the logo SVG file, and I'm going to explain that after, but I'm
just setting up the initial basis of the application first.
There is also a div, an inside of the div, this is going to hold all of our links.
So here we can say that this is the Lynx container.
Because that's what it's going to contain.
It's going to contain all the possible links that we can go to.
And then inside of here, we're going to actually have links that take you to the different pages or
routes that are available.
So inside of here, let's import in the link component, and Link is essentially an anchor tag.
But what it does is that it actually appropriately, dynamically uses the correct browser that you have
installed and it will take your application to that specific place.
Now, this is not so important for us because it behaves pretty much just like an anchor tank inside
of a browser router, which is what we have.
But if you were using other types of routers, that might be a little bit of different behavior.
That's not so important right now, because right now, all we need to know is that this link component
is what we utilize in order to leverage proper routing, just like we do with anchor tags.
Now, because we're probably going to want to stop all these, we should also give it a class name.
So I'm going to give you the class name of Link.
We can't even call it novel link if we want to be more specific.
In fact, let's call this a novel lynx container.
So here is NAV Link and then inside in order to tell this link where we want to go.
We give it the two property and here we just match the string we're trying to navigate to.
So I want to go to shop.
Inside of the link, we put some text, let's say we say shop.
And then finally, this should be the very formative basis of our component.
So once again, because we want to stop this, let's just see what it looks like.
First, we see there's a large logo and then we see their shop.
If I had shop, it takes me to shop.
Right now, there's no way of going back other than pressing the back button.
But we want our logo to be the thing that will allow us to actually go back as well.
So the great thing about Link is that it's just like an anchor tag.
Whatever you wrap in a link will give you that navigation functionality.
So let's make a new link that we wrap around our logo.
As for the link itself, instead, this class name should be our logo container because that's what
it is.
It contains the logo.
We might want some different styling for it than we do for our navy links.
And then instead, where it should navigate to is the slash, because that is where our home page lives.
So now if we save this and we go back to our application.
If we click shop, it takes us to the shop.
And now if we click logo, it takes us to the homepage.
So here everything behaves the way we want it to.
We've got in some navigation behavior now, all thanks to the link component that we get from Rotterdam,
which again behaves like anchor tags, but with a little bit of additional functionality, according
to the needs of Rak Rotterdam.
And finally, we have separated out our navigation component into its own component, so a lot of good
work with navigation now in the next video, what we're going to do is we're actually going to bring
in that Crown SVG for our logo and we're also going to start styling out this navigation.
So we'll see you in the next video for that.