Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to install the net lavishly, which stands for Nullify Command Line Interface.
It's a terminal tool that we can use in order to simulate the net left by environment.
When it comes to building out our application, which also involves allowing us to build up our net
of AI functions so that we can interact with them in a local environment.
Similarly, the net lovi seal is going to take the place of our typical dev server.
So that's what makes it really handy because again, it's simulating our build process for us.
So what you can do is cancel your current build server inside of your terminal.
And what you're going to do is you are going to run AMPM, install Dash G, so we're going to globally
install onto our terminal or into our computer.
The net la lovi dash a lot.
So Wallace is installing.
I'm going to talk a little bit about what this cloud enables us to do.
Using the clay.
You can essentially control as much of the net platform as you want through the net lo fi website UI.
The only difference is that with the CLIA, you can do it all through the command line.
This is useful when you want to run programs that actually perform some of these functions for you.
So if you want to programmatically set variables, update different things on the actual website profile
that you have.
You don't have to go through the interface to do so.
You can do it through the CLIA.
If you are a power user like that, CLIA are very useful for that reason, primarily because they give
power users the ability to do everything they need to.
So here we see that it's done and in order for us to make sure it works, we just run net la fi in our
command line.
What we should see is that there is a list of instructions that we now have access to.
So the primary one that we want to do is first log in.
So if you run a net le fi log in, this will connect your net live easily to your log in instance.
So if you hit this, it will prompt you with whether or not you want to open up the browser to a net
Levi account.
Now.
I, of course, am already logged in.
So what you can do when it prompts you say yes, it'll take you to notify where you are, sign in,
and once you sign in, it'll redirect you.
And now your credentials are linked to your.
Now, if I see a light, once you have the seal, all you need to run is net le fi dev and now or have
it is that it will spin up a development server and build our project the way that you typically would
inside of net lovi.
So whatever it takes for net lovi to spin up your actual website, it's doing the same thing.
The other thing that happens is that we are now also running our network function.
So what happens with the CLI when it builds is it will go into your net file folder inside of your root
folder and it will find a functions folder and build all of those folders as well.
So inside of our functions, of course, we have the one file which is our create payment intent.
And now this is set up.
So what we can do is we can now test it.
So inside of our payment form, what we were doing before was we needed a payment intent in order for
this to work.
So as we know inside of our create payment intent, it is expecting an amount of value.
So this is where what we need to do is pass a amount value in as a request to our net of function.
So as I mentioned, not only works with functions as if they are API endpoints.
So in order for us to do this, what we're going to say is, okay, let's make the request in order
to get this payment at ten.
So I'm going to say const response is equal to await fetch.
Now here you're going to pass it the route relative to your application URL because net the file will
build all of our functions relative to the route.
And the way it works is that go slash dot net la fi slash functions because for us we're putting it
inside of the functions folder and then slash the name of the file.
So here it's create payment intent.
This is going to be the root.
Then we pass the fetch object that is going to define what we're trying to do.
So the method here is a post method.
So that's what we're saying.
The headers is going to be a object where the content type is equal to application slash.
Jason.
So here we're saying, hey, I'm going to send you this body in JSON format and the body is going to
be JSON string of five and it's going to be an object where we pass a mount and let's just do 10,000
for now.
We'll hook up our actual selector for the actual total, but we'll do that after.
Let's just verify everything works.
Once this fetch completes, we will say Dot.
Then I want the response and I just want to convert this to JSON before I actually resolve it back to
my actual response.
I don't want to have to go through that extra step, so I'm just doing my dot then here.
Once I have this, then I'm just going to consult dot log the response.
And what I want to do as well is I want to take the payment handler and attach it to the on submit of
the form container.
So essentially what we're saying is that whenever this form submits and remember any button inside of
your form container will automatically be a submission button unless stated otherwise.
So for us, that's exactly what we want.
So we'll save this and let's go back to our application and here, because we aren't actually using
the card yet.
We can just submit the form and we should make a payment intent for that value of 10,000.
And here we see we log back our object with the response with the payment intent.
This payment intent has a bunch of fields on it.
But the main thing that we want is this client secret.
This client secret is what attaches an actual payment to the payment intent that was generated from
the backend.
So remember how I mentioned our back and tell Stripe hey, this user intends to pay.
I'm telling you the value that he intends to pay.
So give me back a handshake token, which is essentially this client secret, so that when I actually
pass you the payment details with this secret, you know that this payment is connected to that intent
to pay.
So now that we have this set up, what we need to do is actually build out the rest of this flow.
So I want to get off this client secret.
So I'm going to say const client secret is equal to response.
Stop payment intent.
Dot client secret.
Underscore secret.
Now we can do it like this or we can de structure.
You can do payment intents and then client secret like this as well.
This will also give us the appropriate client secret value.
We can console.log the client secret like this just to make sure that everything is working.
Again, some teams enforce that.
Everything is structured so that you know where everything's coming from.
It's a lot clearer if we hit pay now.
There we go.
We see our client secret.
And now with this client secret, what we're going to do is we are going to create the actual payment.
So to do this, we're going to say const payment result is equal to us calling the Stripe instance.
Dot confirm card payment.
So confirm card payment is the card payment method specifically for cards.
And here are you going to pass it as the first argument, your client secret.
And then the second argument is a configuration object where payment method.
So payment underscore method.
Is going to go to an object.
And on this object we're going to pass the card.
So in order to get the card element, we're going to say elements.
So this again, is the elements instance that we got from use elements don't get element.
And what you're going to pass this is the card element.
So the reason why this works is because inside of Stripe, you remember in our index, J.S., what we
did is we created this elements wrapper inside of here.
Any element can only exist once.
So there's actually a plethora of different elements that we can bring in.
We just specifically chose the card element.
I'll post a link with the list of the other elements, but here by saying get element and seeing the
exact specific element because again, only one instance of it.
What Stripe is going to do is actually get off all the appropriate details it needs in order to pass
this payment value that gets inserted in as a result.
So here we have the card.
And then what we're going to say is billing details here.
We're going to say name.
We can put whatever we want.
We're going to use the current username.
But again, we haven't hooked up the user anything.
So I'm just going to say using as a test.
And then ask for payment results.
What we can do is we can now check if we get back in error.
From Stripe.
If payment results dot air, then we're just going to alert that error.
So we'll say payment results dot error.
Otherwise we were successful.
So let's say if payments.
Result dot payment intent, dot status is equal to succeeded.
So this, of course, is what we get back from Stripe.
We'll say, if this is successful, then we will alert payment successful.
Either way, we'll get an alert depending on what happens.
So now we're going to save this.
We're going to go back to our application.
We're going to refresh.
And now that we are actually expecting to use the credit card, I'm going to go for two, four, two,
four, two, four, two.
Now, this is the test credit card.
0424.
You can use any date as long as it's in the future and then ask for a CVC and zip.
They can be whatever you want.
Key thing is that as long as this date is ahead of time and then the credit card is four, two, four,
two, four, two, four, two.
This only works in test.
It's Stripe's test visa credit card.
If we get pay now, we see that there is a secret.
We're going to attempt to make a payment.
And there we go.
We see the payment is successful.
And now if we go to our actual stripe dashboard and we go to developers, what we'll see right there
is a payment.
So we've got a successful call.
Additionally, if we actually want to see what happened, you can check payments inside of payments
here.
We'll see that these or all of those incomplete payment intents that we generated.
But the successful payment right here was because we successfully charged the card or the test card.
So again, as I mentioned, when you're back in net life, I function makes a payment intent.
This shows up here saying that, oh, somebody is intending to pay, but then the customer did not enter
the payment method, meaning they never actually completed the payment with the credit card.
And here this payment complete is actually because we succeeded.
But this is it.
We've successfully hooked into the full stripe flow.
We learned a lot of things.
We definitely learn about Stripe significantly, and we learn a lot about nullify functions.
There was a lot of steps that we had to go through in order to set this up.
But when you really think about it and boil it down, it's actually a very simple amount of code.
Beyond working with Stripe to make this work, and there are very key nuances about how you use their
Stripe objects.
Everything else is actually very simple.
So that's it.
In the next video, what we can do is clean this up a little bit, make it look a little prettier.
But we've pretty much written the bulk of the logic that is required in order to make this work.
Once we clean up all of our components, then what we can do is deploy this and see it live as well.
I'll see in the next video.