Welcome back, everyone.
So the form input is going to be the most complicated thing to style.
There's a couple of things we need to tweak, and there's a combination of all the little things that
we've learned up into this point about stock components in order to make this work.
So to start again, I've converted the file over to GSX and I'm importing and styled from style components.
There's actually another thing we're going to need, which is called the CIUSSS block, and what really
this allows us to do is encapsulate some success inside of a bloc that we can use as a variable and
inject into our different components.
The other thing is we need to convert these variables from SAS over into just regular JavaScript variables,
so we can actually say some color is equal to the string grey and we can say the main colour is equal
to the string black.
So really, that's one thing about star components is that instead of using SAS variables, you can
use regular JavaScript variables here for this mix.
And this is what I'm going to call a concert of.
Shrink label is equal to the CIUSSS block, and the KSAZ is also going to take back Tex.
And inside the tactics is where you add the styling.
So here they're styling instead of using main color like this, I'm going to use the JavaScript variable
of main color.
But here, really, what we did is we created those same Nixons and those CIUSSS variables as these
new JavaScript tables.
In fact, I'm going to call the shrink label styles so we know exactly what this is.
Next, all we're going to do is we need to create this form input structure.
So inside notice how we target a label, we target this label because we need specifically a way inside
of this group styles whenever something happens, such as when we focus on it.
So for this, I'm going to make this form label first.
As I mentioned before, you want to pick the things that are going to be targeted later.
So here what I need to make is this form input label.
I'm going to say Konst form input label is equal to a style label.
And inside, I'm just going to drop in all of these.
Now here, a notice how instead what we use is the shrink class, so what we can do instead now is utilize
a prop called shrink.
So we would do a very similar thing, but instead remember what we trying to include, though, is shrink
label styles.
So what you can do is you can actually directly say, Hey, I'm going to access the props right here
and I'm going to get off shrink, which instead of passing as a class name, we're going to pass it
as a Boolean.
And then I'm going to say, if shrink is true, then I want you to add in the shrink label styles,
which means that when this is true, this entire line is going to evaluate to whatever is here.
So this is just going to get applied like.
So imagine if when this shrink value is true, then we have these three styles.
Otherwise, we don't.
So that's really what this line is saying.
So again, very powerful, because now you can leverage your JavaScript inside of your style components.
This becomes extremely flexible because now you have all of the flexibility that comes with JavaScript
by default.
We also want to make sure that we are using the correct sub color.
And also that we are exporting this out.
So now that we have our form label, the next thing we need to do is the inputs.
So this form input.
Here, I'm just going to call this input because our component is called form input and because, again,
this is scoped within our component anyway.
It really does not matter.
So I'm going to call this style input.
And here I'm just going to bring in all of these styles.
So just like before, we need to make sure that anywhere where we're calling, we need to make sure
that we use our own components here.
In fact, I didn't wrap this either, because they're variables and we're working on strings.
So whenever you need to use a variable, you need to remember to use interpolation.
Oftentimes, I make this mistake, and it's hard to catch.
So let's do that there as well for barter bottom.
So now we don't have any more of those old SAS variables.
Focus is fine.
And here is what I was talking about.
When you focus on this input, we want to find the immediate nearest sibling, subsequent sibling of
the form input label, which we now have as a component so we can now target it.
Using JavaScript as well, like so and then whenever this happens, well, we want us to do is we just
want to add these shrink label styles like so.
And now this will just essentially render those styles whenever this gets focused.
And then the last thing we need is our group component.
So our group component is probably not going to contain that much else.
So I'm going to say group is equal to a stout div and what's remaining is these position.
Values, as well as targeting input password like so.
And that's it.
We have now recreated everything that we need to interview style components.
So now let's go back to our farm input component and let's actually utilize this.
So instead, again, we need to re-import in.
All of the new components we've made so form and put label.
As well as input.
And now we can start replacing, let's replace our of.
With our group.
Let's replace the inputs with our new form input.
And now for the label.
So our form input label, as I mentioned, we need to make sure that instead of using this shrink like
so as a class name, we can now pass it as a value and this value is essentially just going to be equal
to whatever we want it to be.
So here I'm just going to know that, well, if I'm using length anyways and it's truthiness is being
evaluated, I don't even need to do this ternary.
I'm just going to directly pass the number in because if the number of the length is zero, then this
will be false.
If it's greater than zero, then I'll be true and shrink will be true inside of my actual shrink value
prop.
So let's just test this now.
Let's come back to our application.
Let's go to the sign in and there we see our form input is still working.
The label is shrinking.
Everything works.
So here a lot of the complexity is just about thinking, OK, when I'm going to target these later inside
of the styling, I need to make sure that I declare it beforehand.
If this comes after this, there will actually not be a valid target when this is being evaluated.
So that's an important thing to think about the order of your stock components.
Otherwise, the other thing is just the fact that we are rendering a lot more JavaScript inside of this
component, and it just is so much more flexible to do it this way.
So that's it.
This is pretty much the majority of the hardest parts of the style we've touched upon, arguably all
of the different types of tools that we have in store components now.
This CIUSSS block, if you need to pass blocks of styles around and conditionally render them, this
is another really great tool that you can use.
So now what I want you to do is stand the rest of these components yourself.
If there are any components that you're a little concerned about how to do it or you want to test yours
against mine, there are numerous ways to do this.
There's no perfect right way as there is with any kind of styling or JavaScript.
What you can do is checking your resources folder for a complete styled folder of the repository of
this project, where I've stopped everything over to style components that is going to be the baseline
project moving forward for a lot of any other further optimizations that we make, because this is pretty
much the typical way that CSC and jazz components are really written in most projects nowadays.
But again, finish styling all of these components.
Compare your work against mine if you want to see an idea of how you can do it if you ever get stuck.
And that's it.
Best of luck.
Enjoy the challenge, and I'll see you in the next video.