Hello and welcome back.
So in the last lesson, we learned a little bit about this Gatsby's source filesystem plug in.
So plug ins are pretty much these tools that we can include inside of our Gatsby config in order for
our Gatsby processes to get these bonus features.
So, for example, our source file system, as we know, gave us access to that all file query inside
of our graph queue all queries on our web.
Now, the next thing that we need to add is actually going to be a new plug in that is called a transformer.
That transformer will allow us to take these files that we are pulling into our query, using the Al-Fadl
query, that gives us a no representation, but we actually want the data that sits inside of those
files.
So we need a transformer to do that.
The thing that we have to note, though, is that transformers tend to be libraries that we need to
install inside of our project.
Now, if you look inside of your directory, you might see a yarn log file.
If you see a yarn log file, it means that by default, this project comes with yarn.
If you see a package log file, then you actually don't have yarn installed.
Instead, what you're using is just NPM.
What we're going to do is we're just going to add this new file and depending on what you have, whether
it's yarn or NPM, just use the respective one in order for you to add a new file in NPM, you do NPM
install and then you type the name of the file or the side of the package that we're adding.
If you're using yarn, you're just going to do yarn add.
And then the name of the package that we're adding now, the name of the package is Gatsby.
Transformer, Remarque.
So simply add that in with your respective package manager, depending on how your folder structure
looks.
And what this will do is this will add in this new transformer object that we need to plug into our
application.
So you simply add these boxes here and you type in Gatsby.
Transformer.
Remarque.
Now, what Gatsby transform a remark does is it is a Plug-In that allows us to convert our markdown
files into data and to melt the front matter portion of our markdown will get converted into a data
object that we can access.
And everything in the actual markdown itself will be converted into HTML that we can use to build the
pages that we want inside of our application.
Now, keeping this in mind, the other thing we have to do is remember to restart our server because
we've added a new plugin.
In order for us to actually access what we're going to see with our transformer Mark is that once this
server finishes rebuilding, we get access to this new query inside of our graphical.
So let's just wait until this finishes building.
And we'll go back to our you and we'll refresh now what we'll see is this thing called all markdown
remark.
So if we add this and we simply fire this off, we see that now we only get two notes.
The reason for this is because these are actually our markdown notes.
So in order for us to see inside of the note itself, here we have our front matter where we have an
optional description, the title and the date, as well as this HTML block, which represents the actual
body of the markdown that we've written.
So we try this again here.
We see that the HTML holds the markdown, but now convert it into HTML as well as our front matter object
that holds our description, our title and our date.
Now description, of course, is optional.
That's why in some places we get null because we don't include one.
So we just have to account for this when we actually build out our blog template.
Now, another property that we see that we have is this excerpt.
Now, the excerpt, unlike the HTML, is what will give us this little snippet of what we're trying
to show.
So this is pretty much the body of our markdown, except it truncates it automatically for us.
Now, this is really good when we want to actually show or highlight something inside of our blog preview,
for example, where we don't want to show the full body, but maybe just an excerpt from the top of
it.
So we want to use this property inside of our index page, for example, or we actually list out our
blocks.
So what we're going to do is exactly that.
Next, we're going to go to our index page.
And what we're going to do is we are going to bring in the graphical query so that we can actually start
requesting for that data that we just wrote inside of our graphical.
So what we want to do is we want to copy this graph.
And then after where we export out our actual index page, we want to make sure that what we export
is a query.
So we're just going to export const.
Query, which is equal to this graph queue all request.
And inside, we're going to say it's a query and then we're going to copy over this object that we wrote
before, now, Gatsby is smart enough to know that if you explore out something that has this graph,
QoL almost body to it, that this is probably a query that you want to use and pass into whatever component
you're exporting out by default.
Now, we still have to export out our component by default.
And if we want to make this a bit more clear, we don't have to export it like this.
We can just copy our export default text and replace this index page like so.
So by default, we're just automatically exporting our function that represents the actual component
that we render render for our index page.
And now what we're going to do is we're going to get in that props object.
And on that object will be the data object that is our query return.
So using that data, we're going to now end up creating some kind of default look to our index page
that shows us our list of blog posts.
So what we're going to do is we are just going to make sure that there is a div here.
We can actually keep this issue at the top, it doesn't really matter.
And inside of this d'Hiv, we are going to have an H1 and in this H1, we're just going to say it was
thoughts.
Now, we do also actually want the total count of our blog posts, so we're going to do that.
Let's actually first remove this and what we're going to do is we're going to add a new property to
our all markdown remark called total count.
Now, this actually exists right here on our all markdown remark as a property called total count.
And as you'll see, what we'll get is the number of nodes that exist inside of this markdown remark.
So by doing this, we're now able to access it inside of our data object.
So we're just going to make an offer that says.
A JavaScript interpolation of data all marked down Remarque.
Total count.
And now if we save and we go back to our actual application.
We see that we have our count here now let's actually log out the data to see what else we have access
to before we continue, because the shape is actually going to represent the query.
But let's just make sure it doesn't hurt to always double check.
Now, if we open up our console, we'll see this object that represents our data.
On it, we see, are all marked down Remarque, and inside of it our edges, inside of our edges array
is each element that has our node property and then on the node property has those fields that we requested
in our query.
So as we can see, the object that we get back resembles the exact shape of the object that we passed
into our graphical query.
So this format matches exactly this format.
So that's really great for us, because now we know roughly what it is that we need to use on this element
in order to actually build out our blog previews.
So what we're going to do is we are going to make another JavaScript tag and we're going to say data,
all markdown Remarque.
Edges map, so we want to map over each edge and on each edge, we want the note object that we saw.
So each of these and what we're going to do is we are going to return back a div where the key is equal
to the node ID.
And then inside of each div, we're going to have a title, so let's just use an H2 for now and what
will render right here is our node front matter.
Actually, this might be lower case all.
Title.
And we'll also going to put a tab here that also loads the date.
I just have to let you a.
Just so that it's not too big.
And then after we have the span, we are also going to put a P tag and in the P tag is where we'll put
our excerpt.
Now, if we save and we go back, we see that our blog data is showing up.
So it's not solved yet, but so far it's all perfectly fine.
So that's one of the great things about Gatsby, is that by leveraging the flow that Gatsby expects
us to use, as well as tinkering around with some of the code, we're now able to pull in our markdown
files as the data that we use to actually populate this index page.
So this is great because whenever we add new markdown files now to that markdown pages folder, we will
automatically be able to pull it into our index just with our graphical query.
And as you would expect, our data would simply just populate out and give us new blog samples inside
of this index without ever having to modify that code.
So this is really great.
Now, in the next lesson, we're actually going to build out these blog post pages individually, because
right now we can't link to them.
We're simply displaying it in our index.
So let's do that in the next lesson.