Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to talk about adding our products into our cart.
So let's take a look at the final format and think about the current data that we have.
So inside, we know that we need to show the image, the name, the price.
And then this quantity.
So really, a core item looks kind of like a encapsulation of our product data, except there is an
additional quantity parameter.
So how do we transform our data from this over into this accurately as we add more items into the cart?
Well, that's actually going to be the meat of the logic, we need to figure out that whenever we add
some item into our cart, we have to check if it already exists as in cart item and if it does, then
we increase the quantity.
But if it doesn't, then we create a new cart item.
So that's going to be the logic that we need to tackle.
And really, we should do that before we start styling out the cart item.
So let's figure that out.
First, what I want to do is I want to make a new folder for the cart item, so at least we have something
to work with.
So here inside, I want to make the cart item, dot styles, dot sass, and maybe we don't fill it out,
but we just make the file.
And I also want to mark a cart item component dot GSX.
So inside, let's think about what we need for this cart item.
We most likely will.
Let's just first generate the base of the actual file we want to import in our style sheet.
We want to create the actual cart item component.
And then we want to export as default the cart item.
So now that we're inside the card item, let's just return for now, a device that will hold out the
actual total.
Of the HTML.
And then let's put an H2, which will have just the name so that we at least know what item we're looking
at.
And this name is going to come from, let's just say the item that we pass in here.
And then we structure off the name so far.
So all I'm saying is that I know that what I'm going to pass in is going to be some kind of version
of the product that we already store those product JSON objects.
But here we need also somewhere to keep track of quantity.
So this is where I'm just going to say that I'm going to assume that what gets passed in will also include
the quantity and I'm going to make a span that will show the quantity.
Like so.
So here all I need to do now is actually put this into the car itself.
The car drop down, which is where this olive.
So first, let's import in.
Our Carte item.
And then what we're going to do is we are going to say, OK, how are we going to get these items into
our cart dropdown?
Well, let's think about this a little bit first.
What is it exactly that we need to add?
We need to map over some kind of array, we know that.
And for every item that we map through, we want to pass this to the cart item like so.
So here, this array that we're mapping through is going to be kind of similar.
But the only thing is that the way that we get this array, it's not completely like the products,
it's going to be some variation of the products, as we mentioned, but with the quantity on it.
So to do that, let's think about leveraging our cart context.
Our car context already stores things related to our cart.
So what we could store is the actual cart items that are inside of our cart, as they're added.
So let's think about what the data shape of cart items should be.
We know that right now we already have products, so our products essentially are objects that have
the shape where there's an ID, there's a name, there's a price and there's an image URL.
All of these are same characteristics that we want on a cart item.
The only difference is that we also want a quantity.
So what we're going to store inside of this car items array is pretty much something that looks like
the product, except we also have an additional quantity.
So let's actually start fleshing this out.
What we want to do is we want to also figure out whenever you add something to this cart items, what
are we going to do to it?
Well, we know that in order for us to control the quantity, we probably don't want them to set directly.
This cart items array the way that we've been doing so with a separate set or function.
And then maybe you want to define our own method that we happen to expose something like an ad item
to cart where we explicitly control what it is that this item to cart function is going to do.
So first, let me initialize the cart items and then the set cart items.
You state look.
And by default, we're going to use an empty array.
What I'm also going to do is I'm going to now trying to find this ad item to cart method.
This ad item is a cart method is going to be a function that triggers whenever a user clicks on this
add to cart.
So that means that what we're going to receive from the product cart is going to be the product to add.
So that's the key thing to remember.
We're going to receive a product based off this product.
We need to decide, OK, do I need to make a new car item if this cart is empty of any of this product
that they're trying to add?
Or do I find the existing car item for this product and then just increase the quantity by one?
That's the logic that we need to add into this.
So what we can say is that we know that what we're going to set this cart items value to is the newest
up to date array.
So here I'm going to create some kind of helper function that's going to help me find inside of my existing
array.
Any carte items that exist that match the idea of this product.
And then if I can find it, I'm going to increment the quantity.
Otherwise, I'm going to make a new cart item.
So here, let me write out at least some pseudocode.
So I want to say, Konst, add cart item like this.
What we're going to receive is the cart items array.
Because this is what we're going to look through to try and find a matching product.
And of course, I'm also going to pass through the product ad because that's essentially what they're
trying to ad through.
So here I need to do two things.
The first is find if carte items contains product to add.
That's the first step.
Then what we do.
Is, if found, increment quantity.
And then finally, return new array with modified cart items, slash new cart item.
So that's kind of what we need to figure out for this function, because what we're going to do is that
this ad car item is going to be what we set our new cart to.
So we're going to call set car items calling out of cart item passing through what we have for cart
items here, as well as this product to add.
So my challenge to you is actually to try and see if you can figure out how to code this.
Remember, what we should get back is a new array of car items, except this product to add, has either
been added as a new card item or as an existing card item with an increased quantity.
So I know it's kind of challenging, but really think about it and really try and figure out if you
can do this.
And then the next video we'll do it together.