Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
In this video, we are going to discuss how we can extend our action creators so that they will be able
to perform type checking for us where they receive an additional action through a dot match method that
we're going to attach on to them.
And what this will do is it will check the action that it receives against the action that it's meant
to create.
And essentially, these action creators are now performing double duty.
They generate actions out of them, specific actions, but they also type check actions against the
action that they hold.
In order to do this, we need to leverage something known as a type predicate.
And a type predicate is kind of like a function that verifies whether a specific argument that it receives
is going to be a narrower type or not.
And I mean narrow as in more specific.
So let's say, for example, we had two different types.
Let's say we're one type which was alien.
And this had something where it was, I don't know, fly, for example, which is of type string.
Just as an example.
Doesn't really matter what that is.
Now, let's say there is also a type human.
And what it has is speak, which is a function actually let's make both of these functions so it's much
more clear.
If we had some function that checks whether or not this is a human, what should happen is that based
on this function, it will receive some entity or some argument, and this can be either a human or
an alien.
What should happen is that after this verifies that the entity is human, then the type that comes out
of it should be something that is narrow to the scope of human.
So that means that inside what our logic needs to do is that our logic needs to assume that this entity.
Is a human.
And here what we'll do is we'll say, okay, the speak method here should not be equal to undefined.
If this is true, then what we'll get back is that the entity should be, in theory, more narrowed
once we've run it.
So what happens here is that we need to add this additional type definition that the entity is human
like.
So.
So that's what this function aims to prove.
This function receives some argument value, which can only be either human or alien.
The logic itself essentially cast the entity as human.
The reason why we do this is if you try and call entity, speak like this, you'll get a type error.
You'll get a type error because Alien does not have the speak ability because this is a union type.
So you can't call again a method that doesn't exist on it.
So we have to say, hey, assume entity is going to be human and check the dot speak method.
Because if you call that speak in JavaScript on something that doesn't have it, this is just going
to be undefined.
But if you call it on something that has it, then it won't be undefined.
So in the JavaScript world this works, but in TypeScript it won't because unless you cast it, Texaco
is going to say, Hey, if I get an alien, I don't have the speak method, we know that.
But we want to leverage that.
We want to call it if it doesn't exist, so that we can check if the method on it is equal to undefined.
If it is, then we know it's not a human.
Now if speak is on it and it's not undefined, then we know for sure this must be human.
So if it's human, then the output of this function is this type predicate.
It's narrowed that the entity that I received must be human.
That's what this logic is aiming to do.
And essentially what it allows us to say is that let's say I get some value, some we for some reason
have some.
Value called Josh.
And let's imagine that when we called it, we don't know what he is.
We don't know if it's a human or we don't know if it's an alien.
If we say is human on Josh.
Like this.
Then inside, if I were to say, Josh, don't speak.
Then this should work because essentially as long as this passes.
Notice how even inside of a hover a josh automatically typescript knows.
Oh, this must be human because it passed this if condition statement and this type critical function
narrowed this down so that it must be human.
This little check right here, this is keyword that we wrote.
This is narrowing this type so that anything that passes this function means that whatever you gave
to it, if it's used later on, that type has been narrowed significantly smaller.
So that is the whole idea around type predicate functions.
And we need to leverage this in order for us to verify that an action we're receiving is a specific
kind of action, because that's what we're going to say.
We're essentially going to modify our code so that we leverage these to match those actions that it
receives.
If it is of this action that we know it's of this action, we can now leverage it inside of our reducer
and respond accordingly.
So this is the whole idea around using these matters, these type predicate functions, and that's what
we're going to do.
We're going to do that in the next video.