So we've learned that React takes care of domme changes for us using something called Virtual Don,
we learned that we build the websites with components and this idea of uni directional data flow where
data only flows one way so that it's easier to debug our code.
Then the final thing that really made react stand out is this idea of, hey, I'm just the UI, the
rest is up to you.
What do I mean by this?
Well, remember how with Angular it came with all these things built in that is angular JS.
It was a framework and a framework is kind of like a whole kitchen.
It gives the developers all the tools necessary to build an application.
So if you're a cook in a kitchen while you get the oven, you get the nice, you get the drawers, you
get the pots and pans, you have the stove, you have everything for you.
And this is how you cook or this is how you build a website.
It's very opinionated.
On the other hand, React said, hey, I only care about this whole idea of components and virtual dom
and I only am going to work with the view, the user interface, everything else that you need.
Well, you can just use other modules, other libraries and mix and match and have whatever you want
customized to your need.
So it was a library, a UI library, which is not like a kitchen.
It's more like, let's say the stove.
They gave you the stove to cook your soup on.
But everything else like knife cutting board spoon, well, you can pick whichever one you want.
It's up to you what you use to build that soup.
All we give you is this oven.
And the key idea was that because it was so small.
You can learn once and write anywhere.
What does that mean?
Well, react doesn't make assumptions about what technology stack use.
All we give you is, hey, here is this idea of components of a blueprint that we can use a massive
JavaScript object to make changes.
And here's also a robot that will interact with the DOM and makes changes for you.
But because of this, we actually are able because it only focuses with the UI, we're actually able
to move react to other places other than, well, let's say the Web, for example, we now can have
different robots that interact with different views.
And all they need is this main react library or blueprint of how to, well, look at a JavaScript object
and say, hey, change this UI.
So now you could have things like react native and this little robot can look at this blueprint and
say, change the view in a iOS and Android app.
And although it might not know anything about the DOM.
It only needs to know about views in a mobile app.
You also have things like React 360, which is VR apps, and again, using this blueprint of react,
I can use it for VR apps and this little robot or library can focus on VR.
We also have things like Electron and React desktop that allows us to build desktop applications and
they interact with Windows and Mac OS and Linux operating systems.
We even have things like react to blessed that work with the terminal and the command prompt.
And because of this reactor was able to use this concept and have developers that originally just wrote
for websites on the browser to now use the same idea and the same principles and the same JavaScript
code to build desktop applications, to build VR applications, to build mobile applications.
And this idea of cross platform really took off with react.
And you'll notice when we start building our projects that we actually import to libraries and react
the core react library, which is this little robot and the React Dom library, which is this specific
robot that only knows how to interact with the dump or the Web browser.