Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to tackle learning how to write SAS rather than CSI.
SAS is really just a much more efficient way of writing courses.
And let me break down how it works.
So first, we need to actually load in the ability for our application to consume SAS files.
In order to do that, we need to go back to our application inside of a terminal and we're just going
to run yarn, add SAS.
Luckily for us, create React app by default, when you include the SAS Library will set your application
in such a way that it will be able to render SAS styling.
We're going to break down much later how you can do that yourself with Webpack, because it's really
what it's done is that it's set up these configurations within the underlying web pack so that you can
actually leverage SAS files inside of your application.
So now that we have it fully installed, we are going to go back to our obligation.
And now what I can do is I can make a new file.
So for now, I'm just going to call it let's actually call it categories dot styles, dot SC.
So access is the SAS file type.
Once you have this in.
What is SAS versus regular CSIS?
So in order for this to work, let's look at an example.
Here we have a div and this class name is categories container.
If I had styling four categories container here, let's say, for example, I wanted to make the background
color red.
If I wanted now to target specifically the category container inside of categories container.
The way that I would do that in regular cases is, I would say first give me the categories container
class element, then go in and target the category.
Container.
And then inside of there, I could do something where I set the background color to green.
This way now I'm essentially saying, hey, I have styling four categories container and anything nested
within.
I want you to target it knowing that my KSAZ essentially is going to target it like so go into categories
container and then get the category container and then apply the styling.
If we want even another step in and try to target the category body container within this.
I would have to go even further.
Categories container, category container and then category body container.
And here I would do a background color.
Of Blue, let's say.
So just to show you let's just.
Actually import in.
This styling file that we just made category styles that asks us if we save this and now we go back
to our application, we see our styling.
It might be actually a little bit difficult because we don't have enough, I guess, like padding so
that we can see it.
So let's just make this more clear.
Let's do padding like this.
Let's just add a.
Padding value so that we can see everything that we've just written, so we save this go back.
There we see that the red on the outside is the container, we see the green on the inside is the inside
target, and then of course, this body container is the blue.
So this is how you would normally write your CIUSSS.
SAS, however, makes this much easier.
Instead of writing all this nesting on duplicated styling like this, it actually allows you to directly
nest these values within the inferred parent.
So here are categories container I can just write my category container code like this.
So category container knows, oh, I'm nested inside categories container.
You want to target category container within this specific parent class, so only give me the styling
if this class is literally a child of this class, which is what the previous code we had written was
doing.
Similarly, if you want the same thing here, you would move this inside of here.
So now it knows that only apply the styling to this category body container if this is a child of category
container and if category container is also a child of category is container.
So now if I save this.
Again, we refresh.
We see our code still works.
Everything here still works.
This is really the great advantage of SAS.
It makes our CSC code much more legible and a lot easier to write.
It's way more intuitive when you're reading it, and it's really self-contained.
And SAS is pretty much the format of CSIS that we're going to write for the rest of the course.
So now that you have your SAS and you understand the differences between SAS and CSC, unfortunately
again, this is not a success heavy course.
So we are really just going to import in all of our guests that I have pre-written for you or all of
the SAS, I should say.
So inside of your resources folder, I want you to copy the SAS code in the SAS file and paste it in
here.
So do that now.
So once you've pasted it all in, I'm going to quickly go over the structure.
I'm not going to really go over a lot of the CSIS itself because there's a lot of CIUSSS and going through
all of the different variations is really going to take up way too much time.
And we really want to focus on the react, not necessarily the CIUSSS, but primarily the main thing
I want you to notice is I did not nest the category container class within the category's container.
The reason for this is because we know that the category container is going to be its own component.
Typically, when we saw this with our monster's Rolodex, it were mapping through this were most likely
going to use this as its own component.
One quick thing that we didn't do that we want to make sure we do is leverage the ID and append that
onto this as the key.
Because as we remember, whenever we map the things, we want to use the ID.
So that's just one quick thing.
But other than that, all of our source code is now in.
So let's just save this and let's go back to our application.
And let's refresh.
We should see this warning go away, which we do.
But here we now see this looks much closer to what we have in our final product.
So now that we have this different styling, what we want to do next is we want to actually upend the
background image.
So let's do that in the next video.