Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, let's improve upon this add to car item functionality that allows us to take in a array
of cart items, which, as we discussed, is just a product with an additional quantity field, as well
as some product object that we're trying to add into this cart items array.
So as I mentioned, what we need to do is find the car item to see if there is one that matches inside
based on the product that we're trying to add, and if it exists, then we increase the quantity.
Otherwise, we just return back a array with the modified car items or a new car item.
So because we haven't really tinkered around with cart items, let's just imagine from the empty case,
we have a completely empty cart.
We're adding a product for the first time.
What we want to end up with is a cart with the object that has all of the fields from our product to
add, but also an additional quantity field that is equal to one.
Because what we're saying is that, hey, I'm essentially creating a new cart item, all of the same
fields as product to add, except there's a quantity of one so far.
So that's what we want to end up with.
So let's talk about this.
What we want to do is we want to say, OK, if this cart doesn't have an existing car item with the
same ID as product, and then we know for sure it is a new product, but we want all the existing car
items as well that are in here.
It just means that we have a new cart item to make.
So what we'll do is we'll create a new array and we'll spread through all of the existing cart items
that we have.
But what we're going to add as an additional is we are going to say, OK, I know for sure I need a
new product to add, except we're also going to add this quantity of one.
That's it.
This is all we're saying.
So whether or not cart items has anything in it or has other stuff, we're already saying that by the
time we make it to this line, we know for sure that all of these cart items don't match the product
to add.
So I want to make a new car item, which is just all the fields of product to add.
But with an additional quantity field of one.
So this handles the case where it's a new product.
But what about finding an existing product?
How do we do that?
So here's what I'm going to say is that Konst existing cart item is equal to a searching through the
items array using the Find method, which is very similar to Dot Map.
What you do to find is you pass it some callback.
And in this callback, it receives each element inside of the array.
So we're going to get each car item.
Then what happens is that we're expected to return a Boolean value, and if this Boolean value is true,
then this method will exit, giving you back the cart item that returned the true Boolean based on the
callback.
So what we want to say is that only return us back true and return us back to the car item.
If this specific car item has an I.D. value that's equal to the product to adds ID value.
So here that's how we're able to track whether or not the cart item matches one that we're trying to
add because they'll be the exact same product.
The only thing is that we just added additional quantity, but the I.D. values are going to be the same.
So that's what we're going off them.
Now, if this existing car item has been found, then what we're going to do is we want to return from
this method, meaning that we don't want to make it here.
We want to modify the existing cart items, but we still want to return back a new array because we
don't want to mutate our code.
Remember, with our code, we don't do mutations.
We always return a new array with new objects or only a new object if the field is different, meaning
the quantity is incremented so that only then do we return a new item.
Otherwise, we keep the old one.
So here what we're going to say is that we return items that map.
So we're mapping through the cart items.
And what we're going to do is take the car item and we're going to say, OK.
In this particular case, again, we need to match, does the car item I.D., is it equal?
So the product adds ID.
If it is, then what we do, so meaning that there's a match is we want to return a new car item object.
So let's spread through all of the values on this card item, except the quantity value is going to
be the item quantity.
Plus one.
If this is not the case, then just return back the original item.
So let's walk through this logic, because this part is a little bit convoluted, so we're saying,
OK, let's say we found a match in our car items.
If we do, then we want to return a new array of card items.
And here we're just saying, Hey, is this car item the same one that we're trying to add if it is returned
a new card item?
This means that we're doing a brand new object, but we're spreading through all of the old properties
of that card item, except now the quantity.
We're just adding one to that quantity.
If this doesn't match meaning that it's an item that is not related to our product to add, then just
return the car item.
We don't really care to improve it.
That is what this function does.
So this function now will allow us to essentially add new products in and keep track of the quantity
appropriately.
And because we're calling it whenever we call this add item to cart method with the product that we're
trying to add into our car items.
This will then give us back the appropriate array that we want to update for our cart items.
And now I just want to add this to our value because that's what we want exposed in the context.
And we're also going to expose cart items as well.
So now with this in mind, we can go back to our cart dropdown and we can use this context.
I'm going to import in the use context hook from React, and I'm also going to import in the actual
cart context.
So I'm going to import.
Cart context.
From car context.
And then what I'm going to do is I'm going to pull off this value now.
So before we were just mapping over that empty array, now we want a map over our contexts.
So our car items equals use context, passing in car context.
And here now I want to map over.
Car items.
I also want to make sure that we add the key, so Item I.D. also is allowing react to properly map these
key values.
Now that we have our cart, what we need to do is make sure that we also are able to add these products.
So let's go to our shop page, not actually our shop page.
We need to go into our product cart component.
Inside of product card, whenever we click this button is where we add that product to our cart.
So let's once again import in used context from React.
And we also need to import in the correct components.
So here let's import in our context now component, but the actual cart context.
There we go.
So now that I have context, I want to use it, and the way to use it is we need to get the ad item
to cart method.
So I'm going to say use context passing in the car context.
Add items to cart.
And then whenever this button gets clicked, I'm going to call add item to cart as a function.
Except I'm passing the product through.
So let's actually make this a function defined up inside of our function definition.
Like so and I'm going to call this one ad product to cart.
And then I'm just going to pass this through here.
Now, you might be wondering, why do we define this function up here instead of inside of the definition?
I'm going to explain this to you a little later when we start talking about optimizations.
One benefit is readability.
It's easy to look through this part rather than inside of all this nested GSX code.
But the other is it's easier to optimize, and I'll talk about that again much later.
But for now, let's test that everything here works.
So let's go back to our application.
Here we seem to have everything hooked up, and let's start adding there we see our blue beanie is being
added.
Our brown cowboy hat is being added and our red beanie is being added.
There we go.
Everything is working as expected.
So awesome.
Our code is working as we want and really the key thing here that was challenging was really thinking
about a way to keep track and update this cart inside of our context because the really challenging
thing is this function and thinking about this function where we know that we want to manufacture a
new array of car items that are based off products.
The only thing is that if an existing one is found for the product that we're trying to add in, then
we just want to increase the quantity.
Otherwise, we just want to keep it the same.
This is the biggest challenging part and requires the most thought when it comes to composing this feature.
So if there's this challenging, I suggest you actually get rid of this code and try it again yourself,
because only by practicing and really thinking about how this is done, are you going to get a better
grasp of why this all works.
So now that we have our cart and our car items, let's start styling our car items in the next video.