Welcome back, everyone.
So inside of your console, in order for us to start using Firestorm, you need to go to the Fire Store
database tab.
And here you'll see some kind of introductory screen if you click Create Database and inside of here.
Just start with production mode.
It's actually easier to weather production mode because all the changes are just the rules that allow
you to determine who gets to set different documents.
So just click production mode, hit next and then by default, choose your location.
I'm going to choose you as central because that's the one I'm closest to.
But you can choose whichever region that you feel like is closest to where you're at.
Honestly, it's not going to matter too much for the sample project anyways.
So I'm going to choose now.
I'm five U.S. central and I'm going to click Enable now.
It's going to happen is it's actually going to now generate the database for us.
So once it's finished, you should see this view right here.
Of course, as I mentioned, we have an empty database, so it doesn't even matter.
And what you're going to do want to do is you're going to want to click rules here inside of rules.
These rules define who is allowed to modify what documents inside of here.
We're going to really play with this a little bit later.
Right now, we just want to keep it as general and open as possible because we're going to be the only
people developing against it so that I want you to do is I want you to switch this allowed read right.
If from false to true and then you're going to hit publish.
What this will now do is that this will allow us to make any modifications we want to any document inside
of this database.
It doesn't matter.
We can read, we can write, we can do whatever we want.
So that's what we want.
And now that we have these settings, we can actually start implementing storing users inside of our
cloud store.
So let's do that.
Let's go back to our application.
And inside of our application, we want to go to our Firebase utils dogs now, just like Firebase app
and Firebase Auth, Firestorm, as I mentioned, is a different service, so we need to import some
methods from Firebase Firestar.
And just like we did with get off, we need to instantiate our Firestar instance.
So we need get Firestorm.
Well, we also need our three other methods.
We need the doc method.
And what this doc method allows us to do is retrieve documents inside of our Firestar database.
But how do you get that data or how do you set that data on these documents?
Well, this is where you need the get doc method and the set doc method.
So I know these seem like it's called getting the doc or setting the doc, but what they're really representing
is you're getting the documents data or you're setting the documents data.
Doc is what you need to actually get a document instance, but when you want to access the data on those
documents, you need to use get doc.
And when you want to set the data, you need some doc.
So I know this verbiage seems a little confusing.
This is just unfortunately how Firebase has decided to name these methods.
But once you use them, you'll get more familiar.
So now that we've imported our methods, let's actually instantiate what we need to instantiate.
So first, as I mentioned, we know that we need to create the DB.
So I'm just going to call this DB for database, which is equal to calling get firestorm.
Get Firestorm.
I accidentally auto imported up here that type, but we don't need that.
So once we've instantiated our fire store now, we can use it in order to actually access our database.
So this singleton instance allows us now to tell Firebase when we want to get a document or we want
to set a document or anything like that related to our database.
This is the database that we're going to pass because this actually directly points to our database
inside of the console.
So in order to use it, for example, what we're going to do is we're just going to create some method,
I'm going to call it create user document.
So I can even be more explicit.
Let's call it create user document from.
And what this method is, is it's an async function that receives some user authentication object because
that's really what we're getting back anyways from our Firebase authentication or Google sign it.
Whatever we were, council logging earlier, here is what we're going to want to pass, we want to pass
something specific and we'll walk through what that is.
But all we're thinking about right now is that we want some function that will take that data we're
getting from the authentication service and then we're going to store that inside of Firestorm.
So this is where things are going to get a little bit more confusing just because we have to follow
along with how we use these methods that we've imported.
So remember, what we need to do first is we need to see if there is an existing document reference.
So when I say reference, this is a special type of object that story uses when talking about actual
instance of a document model.
So just to be clear, I'm going to call this doc rough user doc ref.
And this is equal to doc, and Doc takes three arguments.
The first it takes is the database.
So we're using our Firestar database instance, so we're going to pass that as our first argument.
The second is going to be collection, so we know we're going to call it our users collections.
And then third is going to be some identifier that tells it what it was.
So do you remember?
Well, I showed you in our slideshow in the last video and I showed you the identifier was Nike Air
Max or Adidas.
NMD capitalized.
And altogether, if you remember, it looks something like this Nike Air Max like that, that identifier
is a unique ID.
So similarly, we need a unique ID for this to work.
So what is our unique ID?
Well, let's first look at our sign in.
We're going to console.log the response, and let's look at it to see what we have access to.
So let's go to our application.
Let's open up our console.
And let's just click sign in with Google.
Here, let's sign in and let's look closely at that object that were concealed logging here inside of
here, there's a couple of things like the operation type and what provider it's from.
We don't really care about any of this, whereas this user object, this is that authentication object
I was talking about that comes with the access token.
What we really care about is the fact that on here we get a display name, we get an email, we know
if it's verified and then there's some other information, such as a phone number, a photo URL.
But most importantly, there is a you I.D. This is a unique ID identifier that we get with this object.
So we might as well use this UIDAI as our unique identifier.
So right now, we're in the process of creating this user instance inside a firestorm.
So we've never done that before.
So what we can do is we can say, OK, what I want you to look for is off of this user off object.
This UID and I want you to use that as the unique ID to get a document referent.
What's interesting about Google Firestorm is that even though right now, as we explicitly saw, we
do not have a document reference inside of our database, we don't even have a user's collection.
But Google will still generate this object for you.
So let me show you what I mean.
Let's go inside of our silent component and let's import in the appropriate file.
From virus utils.
Actually, I'm already importing it up here, so I'm just going to move this up here.
And what I want to do is I want to call this method using responses, use our object.
Remember that was this specific object right here.
The one right here, it's off of user.
So I'm going to take that.
I'm going to destructor off the response because that's really all I want, and I'm going to pass that
in as the user off.
So it's out of firebase utils.
I'm getting this user off and then I'm essentially saying, Hey, give me the document reference.
Inside of this database under the user's collection with this user office, UIDAI.
As we know, we do not have anything inside of our collections.
We don't even have collections.
We just generated a database earlier.
So what this will log, though, when you see this inside of.
Here, let's refresh, because we just added some code.
I click sign in with Google pop up.
I click equalizing.
So now what's happening is it's giving us that response back and we're passing it into our new create
method.
And right here, you see, we actually got back some object.
This object is actually the object that represents some document reference in the database.
However, what we know is that we don't actually have a value, but here this idea is that you idea
we just used and the part, well, this points to our collection of users, but then it also points
to this UID.
But we know that nothing exists here.
There's actually no data we can get from this.
So why did Google create this for us?
The reason why Google did this is because this reference points to some now unique point inside of the
database.
There's nothing there for this ID, so Google is like, OK, there's no harm.
I'm not going to overwrite anything with this ID.
So by giving us this reference, Google wants us to use this specific document reference object that
they provided us in order to set data there, because it's already kind of pointing to some place inside
of our database.
You can imagine that there is now this user's collection that Google hasn't made yet, but it knows
that is pointing here.
And then inside of that user's collection is that specific user ID.
Now they don't exist.
But if we wanted to set the data, Google at least knows, Oh, I'm going to set it inside of users
for this specific ID.
That's exactly what Google is going to do.
So now that we have this, how do we actually figure out how to get in check some data?
Well, the way we do that is where we use that.
Method that I was telling about the get talk, remember this will try and get the data related to a
document.
So to do this, we're going to say, OK, contest user snapshot.
The snapshot is kind of like the data.
It's also a specific kind of object.
We're going to use a because Google needs to do this asynchronously, say, get the document for our
user doc ref.
Here now, what's going to happen if we save this and we also let's console.log use our snapshot as
well.
If we go back now, we refresh.
We sign in with our Google pop up.
Now, what's going to happen, as we know before, is we still see two things a lot.
The first we'll see is our user doc reference.
We've already seen that before.
But now what we also see is this new document snapshot.
This snapshot again points the same identifier, but this is a special object now because on this object
are different ways that we can check whether or not this document exists.
So I'm actually going to directly leverage a method called exists if you save this now.
And let's go through that flow again.
That's a refresh.
That's clear, our console.
Do our Google sign in?
I'm going to sign into EÜ.
What we'll see is false.
A Boolean, so using this object is actually a method on there called exists, which tells us whether
or not inside of our database does that reference and the data relates to the reference even exist?
Well, we know it doesn't.
We know we have an empty collection.
So that's how you can check whether or not based on a document and the data you're looking for in that
document, if any of it exists or not, it's utilizing this that we can create patterns to determine
that if there is a relevant place in the database for this data, give it back to me.
If not, create one for me.
And that's the flow that we're going to follow.
So I know there's a lot that we have to learn here about documents, document references and then documents
snapshots.
It's like, Wow, what are all these new things?
Well, the main idea is just that these are the tools that Google has determined to use faster in order
to best actually store things inside a firestorm.
So if it's a little confusing, don't worry.
In the next few videos, we're going to work a lot with it in order to better understand it.
So at least here we have a high level idea.
In the next video, let's actually start utilizing the snapshot now and writing out the rest of our
function to start storing this stuff inside of our database.
So I'll see in the next video.