Welcome back, everyone.
In the last video, we learned about implementing our navigation component, as well as utilizing this
link component we get from RAC Router Dot.
In this video, we're going to actually replace this logo with an actual logo.
And we're also going to implement some styling for this navigation bar to begin with.
We need to bring in an SPG that provided you for this logo.
So first, what you're going to do is you're going to make a new folder and you can call it assets at
the top level.
Inside of this assets folder is where you're going to place your SPG.
So inside, if you open up your resources folder, you should find this Crown SVG file and I want you
to drag that, download it and put it into your assets folder.
Here, you'll see that this is what the actual logo looks like.
And what you'll also notice is that if you look in the actual file itself, it's a bunch of HTML.
SPG is a scalable vector, which means that no matter how big or how small you make it, it will always
have these crisp, clean lines.
There will not be any of that pixelation that you see with PNG and JPEGs as you scale and reduce them.
So that's why they're great for logos.
So once you have it in, you need to actually use it.
And the great thing about React is that we can actually import these as components.
So here I'm going to say import react components.
I'm going to say that this is as the Crown logo, and I'm going to import this from.
Our assets folder.
And you can just directly use this like, so it'll be a component.
And the other thing we want to do is give it a class name of logo.
And now, if we save this and we go back to application.
We see that we have our Crown logo now.
We've got a shop.
There's the sharp edge and we click it.
It behaves the way we expected it to.
So this is everything that we wanted to do.
The next thing we want to do is we want to implement the styling.
So what you should do is open up navigation dot styles.
That's yes.
And that's your navigation.
Just like we always do, and what we're going to do now is you're going to go again into your resource
folder, download the navigation styles, file and then paste it in.
Now, once you've pasted it in, just save your styles.
File and remember to import this star file into your navigation component.
So let's just import the relative route, as we've always done importing navigation styles that says,
Let's save this and let's go back to our application.
And here we see that our bar and our styling has been implemented.
Now, one thing you might notice is that the shop link has this underline.
This is because the default styling that browsers apply on our anchor links.
So we don't want this and we want to change this behavior across all of our anchor links.
So let's go back into our application and we're actually going to make a couple tweaks to our index
dot SAS file.
So this indexed, not SAS file is the default applicable styles that we want inside of our application.
This essentially is styling that we want to do when we need to reset things or when we want it to apply
across everything, which is why that's where we put our font family.
There's two things I want to do.
The first is I want to modify our anchor tags.
And here I want to make it so that there's no text decoration, text decoration, none.
This will, first of all, get rid of that underline when you've got a link that's been visited.
And then I want to change the color to black.
And here, if we save this now and we go back, we see that our length behaves the way that we expect
it to in our final application, where it just looks like a black text.
Now, there is one more thing that I want to modify and to modify, I need to show you something.
Let's first inspect our element of shop.
Looking at this div here, let's say that inside of our styles, let's just imagine that what we did
is we added some hard with value of 50 pixels.
So here we see that this has a 50 by 70 dimension.
So 50 with 78.
If I were to add padding twenty five pixels now, if you highlight it, you see that the actual dimension
has gone up to 100 by 120.
So the overall width and height of our element has increased by twenty five pixels on each side.
If you scroll down, you actually directly will see a visual representation of this, so you'll actually
notice that border and padding will both increase the width of your element.
This is not intuitive.
What we actually want is for the panning to be accounted for inside of the actual width and height of
the elements that we have.
You don't want to add padding and add borders that will modify these values.
It just seems unintuitive because if I say that the width of this element is 50 pixels, the width should
never change.
The way that we're going to do this is we're actually going to say that I want this box sizing to be
border box.
This now instead, if you hover, you'll see that because of our padding, it's kind of thrown off the
placement of it in terms of where it's being highlighted.
But you'll notice that the width and height is still 50 70.
So this just means that if we actually add padding, we just need to make sure there are realistic values
something like five pixels, for example for this component.
But what we still want to do is make it more intuitive for us.
So we want all of our elements of box signing Border Box and remember all that does is it just makes
it so that you're padding and your borders don't throw off the dimensions of your component that you've
defined.
And to do this inside of our index assets SAS, we're also going to do star and then box sizing border
box.
This star matcher is a selector that matches everything, so anything that we can match will be matched
and it will apply.
Box signing bought a box on all of them, and that is the changes that we want to make.
And now we have pretty much our navigation component.
We can now easily add any new nav links into it by generating new links and putting them inside of our
nav links container and then our logo is done for our homepage.
And here now we see that this behaves exactly how we expected to.
This now is already starting to look much closer to our final application.
So now that we have this in the next video, let's actually start building out more of our application
and filling in more of these links.
I'll see in the next video.