Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to start working on breaking out this nested route of shop inside of shop.
We have mainly two different routes.
We have the base route, which shows these different collection previews of our categories.
And similarly, deeper down into the shop route.
We also have the individual routes that point to each specific category that shows all the products
inside of it.
So here, hat shows all of the hats and of course, jackets shows all of the jackets.
But notice how this value is dynamic.
What we're going to learn all of that in this upcoming section, but the first thing we want to do is
just figure out how to build this base section for our shop page.
So let's go back to the application.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to make a new component that is a preview of a category.
So of course, I'm going to call this category preview inside of this folder.
We need to set up our base files.
So I'm going to make a category preview that styles that source, and I'm also going to make a category
preview.
Dash component Dot GSX.
Nothing new here.
The component is going to import in these stylesheet.
And then we're just going to set up some base component category preview.
Equals a functional component, and we're just going to export by default.
Category preview.
Now, let's think about what this category preview is going to do.
So this category preview is going to live at the sharp component level.
Inside of shop component, what we're going to do is we're still going to receive this categories map
because we need to generate a separate preview for each of these different categories.
So that means that whatever's inside needs to receive both the title so that it can generate the appropriate
H2 title.
And then it needs to create the appropriate container that shows the first four objects.
So that means that for our category preview, we can anticipate that we will receive both a title string
as well as a product's array.
Then what we're going to return back.
Is we will return a div an inside of this div.
Is going to be the content.
So as always, we have an outer containing element and we always tend to call these the category or
the name of the component at least.
Dash container.
And once we have this now, let's think about what goes inside, so we know we have to display the title.
So I'm going to make an H2 and this H2 is going to contain a span and within the span is where I'm going
to have the title.
And I'm going to uppercase it.
Now, you might be wondering, why is it that we have a span inside the H2?
Well, remember this H2 becomes clickable and becomes a nav link for us.
So what I want to do is I want to make sure that this only is clickable on the text, not the H2.
The way that we're going to set up this container is that is going to use Flexbox.
So that's going to actually make it so that the entire H2 spans across the entirety of the width, which
we don't want.
We don't want all that clickable.
We just want the span and you'll see once we actually add in the styling.
So I'm going to add a class name here of title.
And then what I'm going to do is I'm going to add a div and in this div, this is where it's going to
contain all of the actual products.
So this I'm going to give a class name of preview.
And then what we'll do is we'll take the products away we receive.
I remember we want to filter out anything but the first four.
So here what I'm going to say is that I want to get some callback.
This callback is going to get the product, which I'm going to ignore.
So I'm going to use an underscore saying that I don't want to use it.
And then the second argument of this is the index, which is the index inside of the array.
So the placement in the array first element being index zero, second being index, one, third being
indexed to, et cetera, and onwards.
And what we want to say is that we want to filter it out if the index is greater than four.
So we'll say, Hey, keep it if the index is less than four, because greater than four, as we remember
with filter, whatever evaluates to being false is what gets thrown away.
So here we're saying, hey, as long as the index is less than four, so the first four indexes because
it starts from zero, I want you to keep these products.
And then after we filter them out, then we can map through them.
So here we pretty much just do what we had before.
We're going to take our product and then we're going to pass it to some product cart component that
we need to import it.
So let's import in product card from.
The product car component, folder and file.
And here inside, we're just going to render the product card.
And of course, we're going to give it the key of the product ID.
And then product goes to product.
Now, again, inside of your preview styles, I've included the file for you, so please copy and paste
that from your resource folder.
So now that we have this, paste it in or we need to do now is use this category preview component.
So here, let's import this back into our shop component.
And here we can just say instead of importing the product card, we're not doing that anymore.
We're importing directly the category preview, which will replace the need for a lot of what we have
inside.
Now, let's just say category preview goes up one more into components.
Slash category preview component.
And now what we can do is start replacing this coat.
So instead, this fragment, I'm going to use a div, and for this div, I'm going to give it a class
name of the shop container.
And then inside of here, we don't need all of this fragment code or we do need, though, is we need
the actual objects.
So let me also fix this because instead of doing one line return, we now need to do multi-line.
The reason for this is because I need to set the products to a contest because I want to get this out
of my categories map using the title.
And then what I'm going to return is this category preview, which we've already determined needs to
utilize.
First, I'm going to pass the key for the title.
I'm going to pass it a title, which is the title, and then I'm going to pass a products, which is
products.
So now, if I save this, get rid of the need for the fragment up here, if we go back to our application,
here we see it.
Everything is as we want it to be.
So we have our previews showing our four different elements.
Awesome.
So this is a preview.
What we need to do now is actually start building out the next route, which is where when you click
this title, it takes you to the corresponding shops hats route and shows the full collection.
So let's figure out how to split up our nested routes now that we have our collection preview in the
next video.