Welcome back, everyone.
So I know we're learning so many new concepts in TypeScript and it's very overwhelming.
We learned about discrimination unions and their flaws and being used inside of the reducer pattern
despite their popularity.
We're learning about these type predicate functions that help us narrow down the type of variables inside
of JavaScript world.
If they pass this type predicate function.
In this video, we actually start to learn two more types before we can start figuring out how to create
that action creator extension.
And what we need to learn is we need to learn intersection types and we need to learn about the return
type.
So let's start with the intersection type.
Let's say we had some type human and this is just some type that has a name property that's equal to
string.
Let's say we also had some type alien.
And on alien it had the ability to fly and it's a function just a random function doesn't really matter.
What is a.
Intersection type?
An intersection is essentially the joining of two different types.
So let's say we had some third type hybrid, for example, and this is equal to human ampersand alien.
The ampersand is going to be the intersection keyword.
It's the type literal here.
Hybrid, as you check, is now both a human and an alien.
What this allows us to do is set some variable, let's say, Josh.
And it can be of that type hybrid.
And now what you'll notice is that the value of Josh can have both the name as well as the fly method.
This is possible because this hybrid type will have all of the properties and their respective types
of both human and alien.
If Josh was just a human, then you cannot have the fly method because fly cannot exist and assign on
type human.
Similarly, if Josh was an alien, then you can correspondingly guess that the name does not exist on
type alien.
But if he is both a human and an alien, then he can have both name and fly.
That is essentially an intersection type.
Very simple.
It's kind of like merging two types together.
The other type that I was mentioning is return type.
Let's say, for example, you had some function definition type.
Let's call it my funk, for example.
My funk is just a function that returns you back a string.
If I wanted the return type of my funk, I actually currently don't know how to get it.
The way I get it is I use a return type literal, so it's a very special key word inside of TypeScript
that lets me get the return type from a function and then set it to something.
So let me call it my return.
And this is equal to calling, return type and then passing it some function type.
Now it will reach into this type and then get the return and give that back to me and then set it to
this type.
If I hover over my return, I see it's a string.
If my func instead, the return type of it is a number, then my return is a number.
If we go back and we assumed that type human that we had earlier.
If this is what my func returns, then the return type again will get it and give me that type.
So this is what return type does for us.
And we're going to now use both the intersection as well as this return type to create our maximal type.
Now the manual type is essentially an extension on this action creator.
Remember how I said every function in JavaScript is a object we're going to attach on every action creator
this match property.
And what it does is it's going to reach into this function, get this return type action, and it's
going to get on this action, the type value.
Now the type value is going to be equal to this specific value, and it's going to use that and compare
it against any action we compare it against.
So to do this, what we need to create is first this type.
So I'm going to call this type manageable.
Now, if you're confused, once I write it, just really look at it and really study it and understand
what's happening.
Because right now I understand we're learning so many concepts.
It's definitely overwhelming.
But I guarantee you once you understand it, it will all click and you'll be so much better equipped
as a typescript developer.
So again, we have some type manageable.
It's going to take a generic AKC here stands for Action Creator.
We know that this action creator is going to be some function that returns back any action.
So as you can see here, we imported any action from Redux.
It's literally just any action.
It has some type that can be equivalent to a string or anything else and it has a bunch of other properties.
Could be payload, could be additional meta tags.
We know a saw value add some additional stuff to these action objects.
The key thing here is that any action literally says that it can have any number of fields, as you
can see, any extra props there, string values that point to anything.
That's the any action and extends some action which receive some type which of anything.
Of course for us we use strings or we can use enum values doesn't really matter.
But here this is the definition.
We are saying that we are getting some magical receives a generic action creator which is an object
that returns back any type.
And what we want this magical to be is of course the action creators type and we also want to intersect
it against another type.
And this type is going to have that type value where we're going to get the return type from the action
creator.
So we want to get the action itself.
And off of this value, we want to get the type from the type property which we can access using these
square brackets.
This will reach into the action, get the type value, and then take the type off of that value and
set it to this type.
So I know that seems very confusing, but this will make sense once we start using it.
Once we start using it, all of it will be clear.
Next we have some match method and this match method receives an action because as I mentioned, we're
going to be comparing arm type now against this action.
And what the match does we haven't implemented yet.
But essentially what it will do is it will narrow the tape down.
So this is where I mentioned before that we were using those type predicate functions where we narrow
the scope of the type down.
So as long as whatever match receives that action, once it passes that check, we want to say that
this action is definitely of the return type of our action creator.
So if our action creator is our fetch category start and it passes calling match on the action, if
it passes, then we know for sure it's going to be of the fetch category start action.
That's what this Mashable is trying to define.
So if that's confusing, don't worry.
We're going to now write out the actual modification function that will give us back a manual from an
action creator.
But for now, I want you to absorb the usage of the intersection, the usage of the return types, and
what I talked about that this manual does.
I want you to sit with this, read this and really understand what's happening here.
As long as you understand enough of it, we'll move on to the next video where we will write the actual
function overload that will use this manual type and the past in action creator to create this new object
that I'm talking about.
So again, this is very challenging.
This is rather advanced TypeScript But as I mentioned, with Redux, Redux and TypeScript is challenging
by nature.
So we're really flexing our knowledge on TypeScript.
So let's keep learning.
And in the next video, let's use our new magical type.
I'll see you in the next video.