Hello, everyone, and welcome back.
In this video, we are going to start building out our first reactor application.
The application is going to be this monster's Rolodex project.
What this project is, it's a single page application reactor app, and what it lists is a bunch of
these different monsters.
You can also see the monsters and actually filter them using the search bar.
So let's say, for example, we wanted to filter for Clementine as we start typing.
We will see that we will start filtering out any monster that does not have a name where it matches
what we typed in the string.
It's a very simple application, but it'll teach us a lot about how reax works and how React application
is structured.
Getting started with a React application might seem very complicated because there's a lot of files
that we would typically have to come up with and write from scratch if we wanted to actually write out
an application and react.
However, luckily for us, Facebook has actually created a tool that makes this significantly easier.
And this tool is called Create React App.
Create React app is pretty much just a tool that you can run inside of your command line.
And what it will do for you is it will scaffold out a React project, a very bare bones react project.
And scaffolding just means that it will set up all of the necessary files and folders and then link
them appropriately so that you can get started with a React application.
And that's what we're going to use to really understand how it works here.
Inside of React Jazz's own documentation on Create React app, you'll see that it's very simple.
It says, of course, that it is a comfortable environment for learning react and is the best way to
start building a new single page application.
So we're going to deep dive into what this means all of the different files in the different setups
that it provides for you.
And then we're going to deep dive into how we can do this without create racked up later in the course.
So we're going to fully understand how all of this works under the hood.
But for now, we're going to leverage it so that it makes our lives easier so we can get started with
our first React application.
So here you'll see what it says is that we want to run this command and create React app and then the
name of the application that we want to call.
So what it means is just that when it builds a forest, it will build it into a folder and we want to
give it some kind of name.
So here let's go into our terminal and we're going to type exactly what is said NPCs create React app
and then the name of our folder, which it's going to actually put all of the files into that represents
our projects.
So I'm just going to call it Monster's Rolodex right here.
Now what's happening is that you will see that Inpex is actually downloading the package and the latest
version of Create React app in order to actually help us scaffold out this monster's Rolodex project
scaffold on being actually generating again the files and folders required for our application to actually
work.
So this is really handy, but in this process, you might be wondering what is NPCs, what is Create
React app?
And let's take a little deep dive into all of these things while we're waiting for our project to be
built.
So I'm going to open a new tab, and what I'm also going to do is that I'm going to show you npm versus
NPCs, because that actually be the best way to understand what NPCs does.
And NPCs is actually a tool that gets included with npm version five point two and greater.
So NPCs is actually a tool that lives within npm.
So AMPM, as we know, is node package manager, these packages are just these different node related
libraries or files and folders that get created by different tool developers online that we can use
to help us with our node projects or JavaScript based projects.
What this means is that npm is what we used to coordinate and also leverage these different packages
that we download, create racked up is an example of one of these.
It's just this tool that Facebook built that allows us to quickly and easily build out react applications
so we can do this with 21:00 and not Ampex.
The thing about npm is that npm is a installation as well as a executable environment.
So what this means is that we can install directly, create React app and all of these different packages
onto our local project local.
Being this local folder I have, or we can install it globally on our computer.
So if I do npm install and then the name, let's say, Create React app, what this will do is it will
install and download, create React app locally into this folder.
So that means that anything inside of this folder can leverage, create React app.
However, if I wanted to use, create racked up in multiple projects, but I only wanted one version
of it because create racked up, as we know, is a package created by Facebook and Facebook could be
constantly updating it.
So you might have numerous versions of create racked up in multiple different projects.
But what if we want to always to leverage one version of it across our entire computer?
Well, here it's very easy.
We just say npm install dash, which means global, so install it globally and then create react.
So this is typically how we used to do it before NPCs, meaning that what we have to do is we had to
download down the latest version of Create React app if we wanted to use all of the latest features
in order to build our React applications.
So let me give you an example of what we can do with a very simple library.
And it's called cows.
So cows is a library that just draws out this cow that says whatever we pass it.
So for example, if I wanted it globally again, what I do is npm install or npm AI, which is shorthand
for install Dash G so globally make this available and I want cow say.
So now it's going to download again, as we know, with npm all of the appropriate files and install
it globally.
So what I can do now is I can say, how say hello?
And you'll see that it draws a little cow because I have this cow say Project Global installed, and
it will just say the text that I passed, that which is hello.
So if I wanted to see where I have this house, a project.
I could do npm list, which just lists out the location of a package.
So if I say npm list Kalsi, what I'm saying is that I want you to check the current folder for some
package called causeI.
And when you see this, you'll see that it's empty.
Of course, it is the reason why we install that globally.
So if I wanted to check and p.m. again list Dash Gee and then say now it's going to check the global
location, which is your path location where we save all of our global install packages with npm.
And now we say that, oh, there is a version, of course, here version point point.
So here you can see that we have with npm.
When we installed this library and then wanted to use it, we had to install it somewhere on our disk,
our hard drive, our computer.
This could be in our local project folder or this could be globally on our computer.
So what I'm going to do now is I'm going to delete this housing project from our global list, so I'm
going to say npm uninstall dashi because again, it's global chaos.
So now this is going to get rid of it.
You'll see that it says removed 41 packages.
And again, if we just double check list, how say what we'll see is that it's empty.
So this is exactly what we wanted.
So now that we have this, let's understand what Ampex does start.
So instead, I'm going to say NTPC's cow, say hello.
And now, if we run this, what we'll see is that we're still downloading the package cassette because
we don't have it and it will execute it immediately before when we did it with npm.
Remember, we downloaded it and then we had to run causeI and then call it.
So here what Ampex does is it directly installs all of the required files for this package and it executes
it immediately.
So what this means, though, is that is that all it is just that it download an extra quickly.
No.
In fact, if we check npm list, say locally, we'll see that it's empty.
If we check npm list Dash Gee say.
We'll also see is that it's empty.
So what this means is that NPCs downloads the packages, the latest package for House, so the latest
version of it and executes it immediately and then it deletes it from the disk.
Now you might be wondering, why do we want to do this?
Well, the main advantage is that one you don't have to clog up your environment or your disc with all
of these different packages that you have to make sure that if you're running the latest version of
it, certain things like this you might just want to use when you need it and make sure that when you
use it, you're using the latest version.
So the benefit here is that when you call NPCs, you are going to ask for the latest version.
Now, of course, you can specify with a argument at version, so you can say, Oh, I want this exact
version instead, and NPCs will download that exact version.
But if you don't pass that, what I'll do is it'll just download the latest version and then execute
it and then delete it.
So that's why it's super useful, because this way we don't have to think and manage the different packages
that we're leveraging.
And this is really useful for something like racked up, because chances are you just want to use the
create racked up library to start up a new React project when you need to.
When you don't, you don't want to use it.
And if we go back to our Sierra folder, where we were running our Create React app with NPCs to get
the latest folder here we see that now it's done.
We have our application called Monster's Rolodex and we can see it right here.
So let's see the into it.
And what we're going to do is we are going to talk and break down about what got generated with create
racked up in the next video.
So here once again, let me just go over quickly.
What we did, we used NPCs to download the Create React app package, the latest version of it.
We generated our React application monster's Rolodex and then with NPCs automatically, it deleted Create
React app, so it doesn't take up any space on our computer.
And now we have our monster's Rolodex React project that create React app.
How scaffolded for us and we are going to break down what is inside.
So with that, I'll see you in the next video.