Welcome back, everyone.
In the last lesson, we learned how to use fuel to pull in our markdown files and then use them and
their data to populate out this list of our blogs.
Now we're only displaying the excerpts.
So we're not actually explaining the body of our blogs.
We're going to do that in an individual blog page.
And the way we're going to do that is we're actually going to need to leverage this new concept where
what we're going to do is hijack the build step.
Whenever we built out our Gadsby blog, when we ran, Yorn developed for the first time.
We are going to come in here when it creates those nodes which represent the files that we have written
in the first place.
And we're going to grab the markdown and we're going to build out each individual page at that moment.
In order for us to do this, we actually need to modify our Noad Gadsby file.
So in here you'll see that there's this Gatsby Noguez.
In this file, this is code that will run theoretically on the node server that represents The Gatsby
framework.
Now, two things to note here.
The first is that the code that we're going to write is not reachout.
So it might not be something you recognize if you are only used to writing a react.
There's a little bit of back in node code here that we're writing, but it's not completely node either,
because it has to do with the node API inside of Gatsby.
So you can easily take a look at the documentation here if you follow this link inside of your Gatsby
Noguez.
But let's just get started, because once we actually write this code, I'm certain you'll at least
be able to follow along with what's happening because it is JavaScript.
So let's just get rid of this.
And what we're going to say is exports on create a..
So Gatsby is expecting that if you export this method on note, it is equal to a function and they're
going to pass this function a bunch of properties, one of them being the note itself whenever it's
creating the note.
Now, as you remember, when we did our graphical query for our files, each file had a note, which
was a representation of that file.
So what we're going to do is we're just going to simply console log that node object.
There's a property on there called Internal, which just represents data about the actual node itself,
and we want the type.
So now if we refresh our server.
What we're going to see.
Is when it's building, we see this list of all of these different things that we're logging out now,
these are all the types of note that we have available.
And the main ones that we want are the markdown remarks, because, as you remember, the markdown files
is what we want to use to build out our pages.
So what we're going to say is we're going to say if the no internal DOT type is equal to markdown Remarque.
Then what we're going to do is we are actually going to create this thing called a slug.
A slug inside of Gatsby is the you are l or the link that the browser is able to access from our application
in order to navigate to the page required, now we have to dynamically build out the slug and attach
it to the node as a field because we want to access that field inside of our application so that whenever
we try to route to it or link to it, we are always pathing to the correct path.
So we want to build that path out dynamically.
We actually get access inside of this uncreate node function, this other property called actions,
and these are actions that we will receive from Gatsby.
The one that we want to pluck off is this action called Create Noad Field, create an Oldfield's exactly
as it sounds.
We want to add a new field to our node.
So we want to structure this off of our actions.
And what we're going to do is build the field path to our node.
This path is what we're going to be using inside of our application to navigate to this page.
Now, the only thing to keep in mind is that inside of Gatsby, this thing is called a slug.
And a slug is essentially just some kind of file path or navigation path inside of the application that
allows us to route to it.
We actually get access to this function that we get from Gatsby's source, filesystem, Gatsby, source
filesystem, as you remember, was this plug in that we used to actually get access to our files in
the first place.
So in order to bring it in, we are going to structure off create file path from this Gatsby source.
WAPs.
You'll see here that I use batiks now back Tick's is actually what Gatsby prefers you to use when instantiating
string's.
In fact, you should probably change our markdown remark over to using tactics as well.
And this is simply due to the prettier configuration rules that are set with Gatsby when we loaded it
by default.
Now you can actually find these rules inside of this prettier Arcy file in your bass root folder and
prettier, if you're not sure what that is, is pretty much just the tool that allows you to consistently
enforce certain typos and stylings regarding the way that you write code.
Prettier is really great.
If you have an application with many developers that have different ways that they like to write things
with prettier, whenever you save or whenever you actually type anything, you might get warnings telling
you that you cannot do certain things.
So, for example, if I ever try to make this a single string.
Whenever I say pretty or force that to be double quotes, so if we switch over to using tactics, that's
perfectly fine too.
You'll actually find that when you look through your Glaspie files, any file that gets generated by
Gatsby is using tactics.
So it doesn't hurt, doesn't actually impact performance in any way.
So let's just switch over tactics.
But now that we have our file path function from Gatsby, source filesystem, what we want to do is
we actually want to generate that new slug.
Now, the slug itself, as I mentioned, was the root, now the root.
We're going to use our credit file path method and what not.
This create file path method takes is a object as the argument.
The first thing it takes is a node as the first property.
The node property essentially just points to the actual node that we're trying to convert into a file
path.
So as you saw with our pages, what Gatsby does under the hood is it takes the name of the actual file
and it turns it into the literal name of the roots to that page as well.
So if it's page two as the file name, the actual root to the URL is also page two.
So we're going to pass it the node.
We're also going to pass it, the method that it needs to fetch the node.
Now, this is pretty much in the API docs and you just have to follow along.
What it does is you have to get this get node function that we also get from uncreate note.
And we're going to pass that as the second argument.
That node is just a function that allows you to pull the actual node object representation of a file
or an edge.
Now, you remember when we looked at our actual graph cual, we saw that we had nodes, right?
And then we have these edges get node is just a way to get this little node object.
It just uses it under the hood to actually get the required node that it wants.
Third field is an optional field, which is called base path and based path is something that you add
when you want to add a base path to the URL.
In our case, there's no need for it.
So we can just ignore that property and just pass this in as our slug.
Now we're finally going to actually create the node feel on our node.
So what we're going to do is just call it create node field and we're going to pass this an object where
the first property is the node pointing to the same node.
We're also going to put the name.
So this is the name of the property that we want to add and we want to add it called slug.
And the value is going to be the slug itself that we just created using create file path.
So with this, whenever we actually end up creating all of our nodes, we will end up appending onto
that node a new slug property with the value of our strength.
So now if we actually restart our server and we check out our graph qual, once this is finished, we'll
be able to see it on all of our markdown notes, that new field that we added.
So let's just let this finish building, OK, now if we refresh.
You'll see on this note that there's this new thing called fields and in Fields is Slug, which is our
new property that we just added.
So any field that you add to a node goes under this fields property.
And now if we fetch, we'll see inside of our slug, we have the actual root that we need to use to
navigate to the actual root path that we declared.
Now, what we have to do is actually build the pages dynamically, because now that we've set up our
node, we have to actually set up the actual page that we built.
So we'll do that in the next lesson.