Welcome back, everyone.
In the last video we learned about how to pass this generic monsters array into our own function definition
where we're expecting a generic.
Now, generic is a thing that is very prevalent across all of TypeScript because essentially you're
writing composable types, you're writing parameterized types.
It's a way for you to actually get a lot of extensibility and power out of your typescript and react.
And all these third party libraries utilize generics extensively.
So we were talking about using sets date.
What I want you to see is that once we get our users, let's say I call set monsters and I pass in our
users.
Notice how there throw an error argument of a type monsters array is not assignable to parameter of
type sets the action never array type monster array is not assignable to type never array type monster
is not assignable to type never what is all this mean?
Especially the never never is a very special keyword inside of TypeScript.
It's a very special type.
Essentially, the never type is the opposite of the any type.
It means that nothing can ever get assigned to never.
The reason why it says this is because it needs to make sure that you are defending your code base and
making it strictly tight.
Set state right here.
If you look at you state, notice that right now it's initialized with the never type for the array
as the default value.
The reason why it's getting an array is because we passed it the array, so it's at least knowing we're
getting an array.
But the problem is we did not type this array, so it just automatically applies.
Never.
TypeScript is smart like that because it knows that if you're giving me an empty array, you have not
defined the type for me.
I'm not going to set it to any because that would be extremely not type safe.
I'm forcing you to give me a type in order for me to actually set this value.
So now what we need to do then is pass it as a generic argument or monsters array.
Now what this knows is that U.S. knows we are going to get an initial state of a monsters array.
Our set state is going to expect a monsters array as the actual definition of what gets received as
the argument.
And now we'll notice that Set Monsters works.
Set monsters is equal to some function where the value is a set state action that receives the monsters
array as the actual type.
And now that is how you type you state.
Now you might be wondering, well, why don't we need to type the you state?
So if you hover over it, you should notice that we don't.
And the reason for this is because TypeScript is able to infer the type if it has a type already.
When we passed in you state.
The default initial state that we pass for search field is a empty string.
Now an empty string is explicitly typed because there's no way a string can be any other type.
So here what you see is that you state is already assigned to this string search field.
We'll infer that type and know that it can only be a string.
Because if you're giving you say, an initial value of a string, it's only setting strings.
There's no way that you can set for anything else.
So if you try and call set search field and pass it any other type other than string, you will get
an error.
This also means that we do not need to explicitly type to use state as a result because it can infer
that type.
Similarly, our use state for our filtered monsters takes the monsters from our actual previous use
state as the default initial state.
This is explicitly type to monsters array, which we've already done.
So now this use state is going to also infer that from the initial state.
There is a lot of inference inside of TypeScript so that we don't have to get too explicit about everything.
And this is how we type used it.
There's numerous ways that we can utilize this typing and again, you'll only get more familiar with
practice.
So now that we have this monster type, what we want to do is utilize it in other places that require
it.
Now, chances are we're going to need to actually import this monster type in other components, so
we might as well export it for now.
We can finally get rid of this -- since we now have our own function that will make this async fetch.
And let's make sure to actually call this function as well.
Let's save this now and let's continue typing the rest of this function.
Down here.
We have this on search change event.
This gives us some event that we then use in order to call our set search field.
The problem is that the event here is of an any type because again on search change this function React
does not know what this actual event is.
We know that this is supposed to go to the actual on change handler, but we need to actually type on
search change so that React knows what exactly this event will be.
So here's what we know for sure, is that we're definitely returning void from this function because
there's no explicit returns inside the function itself.
This event is a change event.
So what we can do is from react import in the change event.
This is what we did earlier when we looked at our change event typing.
So essentially we just need to do the same thing.
We know it's a change event.
We know we're getting an H HTML input element and now this event is correct.
Answer Change receives this event change event.
We then pass this into on change handler, which similarly is expecting an event with that exact change
event of a similar input element.
So now this is properly typed.
If we go back to our application, let's close our Jason Placeholder here.
If we start typing, we see that our code still works.
So now that we've typed out our app Dot TSX, we still have two remaining components to type the cardless
component which receives monsters and this card component which receives a monster.
So very simply, in order to type these remaining two files, we just need to import in that monster
type that we are exporting from our app component.
So you go up to your app dot TSX and you import in the monster type.
And then now it's just a matter of typing out card components.
So I'll say type card props is equal to us receiving a monster, which is of the monster type.
Then we can just pass this.
Like so.
And of course, you'll notice that this is saying type aliases can only be used in TypeScript files,
which just means that we did not convert this from G6 over to TSX.
But once we do that, we notice again, everything works.
Carla's component being the last one.
Just like we did with the other component.
Convert it to TSX.
In part in Monster.
From our app component.
And then we type out our cardless props.
Monsters is a monster array.
And then weeks pass.
Carlos, props like this.
And there we go.
We go into our application once again, we notice everything works.
So that's it.
You've learned really pretty much the core parts of typing react.
There are, of course, other additional type structures that we need to get more familiar with.
But generally speaking, this pattern of typing these things out, thinking about what it is that you're
going to type.
This forms the basis of TypeScript.
It's really just getting familiar of when you're going to use generics, when you need to create new
types, where you're going to set some of these values and then allowing the inference to work in the
places where it does, where it's going to infer the types anyways, and typing the places where they're
not just trusting the TypeScript compiler to tell you where things are not being properly typed and
set and then just moving on from there.
Now my challenge to you is to start trying to type whatever you can inside of our actual final project,
crown clothing.
Start working from it.
For now, I want you to avoid the generators or the sagas, because the sagas are actually quite challenging
to type, and we'll cover that together later on.
But for now, just start typing the things that you know inside of your components.
Start thinking about it.
And then in the next video, we'll do it together.
I'll see you in the next video.