Welcome back, everyone.
So in this video, let's actually learn a little bit more about some styling facts with an react.
And also, let's add the image.
So what I want you to do is go into your resource folder.
Get the categories JSON file inside is just an array of JSON, and I want you to paste that in place
of your current categories array.
All that really changes is that you'll notice now we have this image URL field and it points to a special
place where I'm hosting all of the images that we need for our respective different categories.
So once you have this in, I want you to also structure off the image URL because we're going to leverage
this and it's a strength.
What I want you to know is that when you are trying to append, let's say, some additional cases,
that's dynamic.
You can actually do that in react by passing it as a style object.
So on any different component in your GSX, you can actually append custom styles by giving it this
style field.
This Darvill takes an object where the key is the CIUSSS property that you want to modify.
So in our particular case, I want background image.
So with background image, the value that we need to pass, it is going to be a string of Earl and in
the brackets is the actual U R L string value.
So here I'm going to use object restructuring, so I want to use the back picks.
And with the object restructuring, I'm going to pass in image URL.
If you're unfamiliar with restructuring, all this is really doing is it's just allowing us to use a
string variable inside of another string.
And this is essentially what will happen is that we will apply a customs style on to this specific HDMI
element.
So if we save this now?
And we go back to the application.
We'll see that now we have our images loading in.
And that's pretty much it as far as why it's all working stylistically.
Of course, it's because I'm already pre-written the styles for you to keep that in mind, but just
really focus on the fact that all we really did if we now inspect this image.
Is we now have appended this style property and inside, as you remember.
You can actually do this in any demo element.
You can pass it as a strength.
But for us with React React allows us to pass it a JavaScript object, and it will convert it all for
us, both from Camel case, which is how we should rate it inside of the JSON object over to the kabob
case, which is how it actually gets interpreted.
When you're writing rightthere more.
So that's the great thing about React as well, is that it will essentially handle all of this for us.
So now that we have all of this code working.
What we want to do now is really just start moving what is in, it's appropriate one file to its own
separate component.
So what we know is that we are really just using a category item here.
So what we can do is go and create our components folder.
And just like we did before.
I want to make another folder where we have our category item.
Category item is going to be a component, so it needs both a component, Duchess X-File.
And it also needs a style file, so category item dot styles, dot s6's.
So here, let's just go into our staff.
Let's cut out all of the styling that we had, and let's paste it into category item dot styles that
says.
Inside of category item, let's import in our style file.
Let's initialize our category item as a functional component.
And let's just remember to export by default out the category item.
As far as what we're going to receive, we are probably going to receive the entire object as a prop.
So here we can do.
Let's call it a category.
And that'll be the namespace that we do, and in turn, we just want to return all of that HTML that
we had from before.
So let's just close these folders.
Let's go here.
Let's copy this email that we've been using.
Let's paste this in here.
And now we remember that we cannot use the ID here.
We need to put it in the place where we actually call the map.
So will remember to do that when we go back to our app?
Yes.
But we know that we need the image URL.
So here we can restructure here or we can restructure directly in the actual prop.
It's entirely up to you, whatever you prefer.
We need the image URL and we need the title.
So here we've pretty much converted this over into its own component.
Let's save this.
Let's go back to our Angus.
Let's import in the component that we need from our components folder.
In our category item and our category item component.
That's copy the category item.
Let's paste this in.
And now we know that we need to actually pass the entire category.
So here we can do key is equal to category ID.
And category is equal to category.
And now, if we save and let's go back to our application, we see that everything is still working
as we expected to.
Awesome.
So everything still working, and we've pretty much started suffering out of our different components.
What I want you to do is I want you to actually even move this component, which is the entire categories.
Into its own component, so you can make this category menu, you can call it directory.
Call it whatever you want, but essentially it should not all live within an OPG's.
And you also want to move the style that we had here for this categories, so you can move this also
into your own component.
That's my challenge to you.
So do that.
And then in the next video, we'll do it together.