Welcome back, everyone.
In our last video, we created our Mashable type.
Now we need to create the actual with match or utility function that receives some action creator in
order to create a new Mashable type out of that action creator.
So first, we need to define this function with matcher.
So this with matter is going to be exactly that function definition.
So we're going to overload this function with what kinds of action creators will receive.
We might receive an action creator that has no parameters and it returns back and action any action.
And for us, we know that this any actions type value is always going to be a string.
As far as we're concerned, we're using strings.
So we're just going to say, hey, what you're going to give me is going to have type string.
Then what we're going to say is that we.
Are going to receive the action creator function as the literal parameter for this with matcher function.
So essentially if we had this fetch category start, we would be saying with matcher receives fetch
category start and we want to return back this modified version of fetch category star function.
But it has the match method and it has the type on it.
So that's really what we're saying.
So of course, that means that with matter must receive action creator and this action creator is going
to be of that ac generic that we pass into it.
And what we're going to get back is a mashable object of that type a C.
So here, of course, that AC that we passed is also the AC that we're giving to the Mashable type.
And Mashable, of course, will reach in, get the type off of the return type of AC.
And then similarly, we will create a new match function for it with this with match.
But for now we're just overloading this function.
We're defining all the different types of action creators we may receive.
We know we can receive one with no parameters, and we also know we can receive one with parameters.
If you think about our action creator, we have this one that receives a category categories array as
the parameter.
We have this one that receives an error.
In fact, all of our action creators can receive any plethora of arguments.
That's not the purpose of what we care about.
All we care is that we would turn back in action from each of these action creators.
That's their purpose.
So here we need to account for these action creators that could receive any number of arguments.
And the way that you type that is you accumulate all the arguments like so and you say that they are
anything when you accumulate them with the triple ellipses, essentially we're saying, hey, this is
going to be a raid.
I'm going to concatenate them all into an array.
So they can be anything.
I don't really know what they are.
So this is the one place where a casting out as any is actually saying.
It could be anything because it's true.
It can be anything.
We don't know what it might be.
And what we're going to do is we're going to say, okay.
This function still gives us back any action.
And at the same time, we also know that the type is going to be a strength.
So really, that's all we're doing.
We're just essentially saying, hey, I might receive a.
Action created that gets no parameters.
I might receive an action creator that has parameters.
And here again, what we're going to do is that we are going to receive some action creator of type
AC and we return back Mashable.
Of that same AC type.
And that's it.
That's all we're really typing here.
And now what we need to do is write the actual function itself of with matcher.
And what it does now with matcher receive some action creator.
This action creator is a function and we're using a generic function here because we know that our action
creator can be any type of function, any kind of arguments return, any kind of action.
So we're going to use a generic function because we've already got some of our safeguards up here extending
what this function will be.
Remember, this typing is just the implementation of the function in JavaScript.
These others are type overloading for the function that we've already done.
So we don't need to go that intense with this one.
So here I'm going to say, okay, what this with matcher function does is it receives this action creator.
And what it does is it gets the type value off of action creator.
Being invoked.
So we get the action and then we get the type value.
The reason why we know there must be a type value is because these action create our functions, return
back actions.
That's exactly what they do.
They always return back some action, and every action must have a type value.
So we're invoking the creator, we're getting the action object, and then we're getting the type value
on it, and we're setting it to this variable.
And then what we're going to do now is we are going to create the actual map of the object.
So we're going to say object, assign on the action creator.
And what we're going to do is we are going to give it the type value as well as the match function.
So the match function receives an action that can be of any action.
And what it does is it does the check it checks that action type of this past in action is equal or
not to the type itself.
Now, remember this match definition we've already defined up here or received some action.
And what it does is it type narrows down this argument.
If this passes, meaning that this is true, then this action received narrows itself from any action
to the return type of our action creator, which of course is our action create our function type value
that we just got here.
So it's a lot of steps, but what we're doing is we're essentially now creating this generic function
that is overloaded and allows us to receive any kind of action creator, but essentially be able to
check the type against it, which is very powerful.
Now, we've done a lot of this with matcher is not easy to understand.
The main idea, though, is that we are just trying to extract the type off of the action that comes
out of this action creator.
And we're using these to do double duty so that these action creator functions can also match actions
inside of our reducer.
So I want you to look at this, really understand what's happening before we move on.
Actually use this with match or utility function.
Just really absorb what it is that we wrote and all of this type of definition.
Once we move on to the next video, we're going to use them and hopefully it'll all clear up and that's
all we're going to do in the next video.
But before moving on, I just want you to understand the typing here, maybe not necessarily the full
purpose, but at the very least understand what the typescript code is doing.
So once you feel like you have a good handle on it, move on to the next video where we'll utilize this
with Match Your Function.
I'll see you in the next video.