Welcome back, everyone, in this video, what we're going to do is we are going to create our nested
roots.
We have this page already that we want, as our base wrote.
So we need to figure out how to set this up as its own component.
And then we need to set up this nested row while accounting for it in our current routing structure.
So the first thing we need to do in order to make this component of shop investable with its roots is
we need to say OK, when you start matching this path, I know there will be a subsequent you are all
parameter set after shop.
Whatever that set is, I don't care.
That's what this star represents.
It's the wild card.
This just means that I want you to match shop, slash anything.
It doesn't matter.
As long as you match that, I want you to forward them and render this component the shop component,
because now the shop component is going to have its own roots inside.
Now, before we actually start implementing the roots, we need to duplicate this into the appropriate
page component because now this shop component is going to be a collection preview.
So let's make a new route.
Folder, and I want to call this my category's preview, because we're previewing multiple categories,
and similarly, of course, we'll need the categories dot styles, dot SAS and we'll also need a categories
slash preview dot component Dutch sex.
Actually, I misspelled this.
This is not just categories, this is categories.
Slash preview.
There we go.
Now inside of the categories, while I cannot spell categories.
There you go.
Categories.
I'm going to paste in the appropriate code that we have from before.
So all of these are still relative.
So you can double check.
This is going to the correct context.
This is going to the correct preview.
And what we need to do now is we need to modify this.
So instead of importing from shop, this is now category's dash preview.
And this component will now be categories preview.
We no longer need the actually no, we still need the categories map because all of this functionality
is still going to stay the same, except the only difference here is that instead of category preview
container should be the name instead of shop container.
So everything else, though, is the exact same.
We actually already had this component fully finished.
It was just a bunch of updates to the naming and also for preview styles.
We didn't even have any styles.
So actually, since we don't have any styles, we don't even need this file.
Let's get rid of this.
And inside, we don't need this import for the styles anyways if we're not adding styles.
There's really no need.
And if this div isn't doing anything, then we can also replace this div with a fragment which as we
learn about the shorthand of just doing this for fragments.
But again, as I mentioned for consistency sake, let's just import fragments like so.
And let's bring this categories preview now into our shop component, so now our shop component doesn't
need any of this anymore.
Now what it primarily needs is nested routing.
So this means that we need to import in routes and route.
The reason why is because you cannot use a root component unless it's immediate.
Parent is a root soft component from React Root or Dom.
So here we don't need this context.
In fact, we don't need any of this code, let's get rid of all of this and let's start creating our
roots.
So here I'm going to say roots is going to match a root where the index root is going to render the
elements of our new.
Collections preview or categories preview.
So here, let's import this in important categories preview.
From categories preview route.
And then we're going to render the full component.
And now, if I save this and I go back to my application.
There we see it.
Everything is still present, so nothing has broken yet.
It would come back now we need to add an additional route for our new category individually.
But before we do that, let's just quickly go over what we had done.
The main thing with nested routes is that you want to say with React Rotterdam.
Writer Tom takes a look at the path value, and it says, Hey, whenever I match this path inside of
the URL relative to what my parent path is, I am going to render this element that you've given me
for this route.
Now, what we're saying is that, hey, if you match shop, slash any wild card of whatever you are
parameters that follow.
Render the shop because inside of the shop you can expect further routes and these routes are all going
to be relative to the parent route, which was shop slash whatever is rendered inside as the parameter
will be dealt with inside of this route.
So this is the benefit of nesting the code like so.
Now what we can do is we can actually build the next category route, which utilizes a U R L parameter,
and we'll learn about that in the next video.
But really, if you think about nesting roots this way, it becomes much more intuitive as to what's
happening.
Because remember, the whole thing about the path is that the path just matches the URL and then react.
Rotterdam is like, Oh, I'm going to render this element anything afterwards here.
I'm not going to worry about because the fact that you did this means that you have roots set up for
that component that will carry on and figuring it out.
And this is true for any subsequent children roots that get nested.
They're going to follow a similar pattern.
Right now, we just have an index route, but in the next component, we're going to do a dynamic URL
parameter based route.
So let's do that in the next video together.