Welcome back, everyone.
Some of you may have noticed that inside of your deployed application you cannot use the Google sign
it.
The reason for this is because we have not added our new domain as part of the authorized list to use
that authentication service.
So here, just copy the actual URL for your website that you've been given for.
Now, if I go into your authentication tab in Firebase, go to your sign in method and hit edit for
Google.
And then down here inside of authorized domains, click add domain.
Paste in that URL and now this should work.
So now that it's added in, let's go back.
And what we can do is open up our application, go to the sign in, hit sign in with Google.
And there we go.
We can now properly authenticate into our application with Google, sign it.
So that's just one quick thing to note.
Remember, again, if you ever change the domain or actually want more of your subdomains or whatever,
if you choose to end up renaming this website and getting a new actual URL for this, you're going to
want to add that domain here as well.
This is just those things that you have to do for these authentication services.
So remember that keys them.
And with that, let's continue with the course.