OK, async await.
This is one of the most exciting features that developers have been waiting for.
It is a way to write functions that contain promise oriented or asynchronous code that looks synchronous.
So what do I mean by this?
Well, when we think back on our last lesson on promises and fetch.
We know that with our fetch call, if we were to write it with the style of promises that we would fetch
our users.
And then we would get the response, we would call response that Jason, which gives us back a promise
which we then pass to our then which now finally has our array of users.
We would then.
Cast our first use are constant with the first user object in our array.
We blog it out so we see what our first user looks like and then we return Thach to this link, right,
which has posts, except we set your parameter where the user ID is equal to our first user ID.
So we want all of the posts related to our first user and then we get back a response.
We converted to Jason again.
Right, which then we pass through into our next then and then we console log the final posts.
So it's a lot of things happening here.
And what this actually looks like for us, if we copy this, we go back to our browser.
And then we paste this in.
We see that what we get is our first user, which gets logged.
And then we log our final posts, right, so this is pretty much stuff that we're familiar with when
it came down to writing our code.
Now, if we wanted to do this in async, await the way that we would do it is we would cast a function
called my async function, right.
And we make it an async function by writing the async keyword.
And then we essentially write a function anyway after.
Right.
So by saying async and then our function declaration, JavaScript knows that we want to make an async
function.
Now, by using this async keyword within our async function, we're now suddenly allowed to use the
await keyword.
And what a weight does is it pauses the functions execution until what is being awaited is completed
and comes back with a value.
So what do I mean by this?
Well, if we were to say a wait and then we want to fetch this value that we had above here, any code
down here would wait until this fetch comes back with a value.
And the way that we would use that value is we're actually able to cast it to a constant because that's
what a weight does for us.
A weight takes that resolve, promise value, and then sets it to the courts that we declare it equal
to.
So if I say this is my users response.
Right now, I have that same response object cast to this CONSED user, and any code following was waiting
until this FETCH completed.
Now we do this again with our actual users, but we have to wait for our users response to be converted
to JSON because this is also an asynchronous method of converting it to Jason.
So this method returns as a promise, right, which resolves with the final JSON value of our users,
which we cast to our CONSED users, and now we can say CONSED first user equals users at zero.
Right.
Let's console log this first user as well.
Actually, let's just change it up.
And instead of our first user, it will say second user.
Right.
So we'll use our second user.
And then we want our.
Posts response.
Equals to our fetch, right?
Like so.
Except we want to use our new second user.
But our fetch, we want to await for it.
And then we want our posts to be away of our posts response.
Jason.
And now finally, we can't log our posts.
By doing this, this code reads more like Synchronoss code because we see, oh, there's just a variable
declaration, it's just waiting for our asynchronous requests to complete.
And then they cast their values right there, resolve, promise, values to our contests, respectively.
So as we see, this actually looks a lot like normal synchronous code that we were.
Right.
Now, let's see if this works.
So let's copy this.
And then let's just.
Paste it in and let's call my async function.
And we see there's our second user and there's our posts related to our second user.
So this is what a single way allows us to do, so both methods are valid when it comes to tackling this
kind of a problem.
Specifically, what we were trying to solve was that we had code that was dependent on an asynchronous
code above it right to complete before it could actually run.
What do I mean?
Well, we were not able to fetch our second users posts without having a second user in the first place
and getting our second user was dependent on fetching a list of users first.
Right.
This code is asynchronous.
We did not know when that would complete.
This could have taken half a second or could have taken three seconds, depending on multiple factors.
Now, both are valid because this structure of promise chaining is just like a weight.
Each then is waiting for the previous ones, then callback to complete.
So this return of this promise, this whole chain is waiting for this then block to complete and this
fetch to complete resolve or reject.
But with async away, we're able to write it in such a way that it resembles more of the synchronous
code that we're used to writing because we're able to cast these constants.
Right, which are just equal to a weighted values of these function method calls.
So in a way.
You can do both.
It doesn't matter, it's just which one is more readable.
Which one is more reusable.
Now, one thing I have not yet talked about with a single way is error handling.
We know with our promise chain that if we do a catch right here, we are able to handle our errors.
If an error occurs at any of these thens, this catch will catch the error for all of them.
Right.
If any of these reject this catch will be there for it.
How do we do that with an async or wavefunction?
Well, what we have to do is use a JavaScript, try catch block and what that looks like is just this.
We have a try keyword with a block of code and then there's a catch key word with our error and then
the second block.
So we put the code that we want to like we want to run inside of our tribe lock and then in the catch,
if any error occurs in this tribe, block any promises, reject any of the stuff with our fetch that
fails, right.
Then this catch code will run and that error is what will get passed in here.
So if we wanted to console log.
There was an error, we are able to handle our errors this way, so if we were to try this and let's
say we just mistype this string, right?
Now, if I call my function.
We will see that our air got thrown.
So while this code ran, it's because up until this point, this code was all valid.
But the moment that this error occurred at this fetch it through the air, it paused the execution.
It doesn't keep going.
And then it just throws.
So this is how async away it works.
And just like that, you now know the two ways of handling asynchronous events.