Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to leverage the pieces of information that we've just learned, we have
this user document reference and from this user document reference, we got a snapshot.
The snapshot allows us to check whether or not there's an instance of it that exists inside of a database,
and it also allows us to access the data.
So how do we do this?
How are we going to set up our code?
Well, let's write some pseudocode first.
What I want to do is I want to first check if user data exists.
If it does, then I don't want to do anything.
I just want to return back this user document reference.
If the data does not exist, though, so let's say if user data does not exist.
So here this is what happens if user data exists, have user data does not exist.
What I want to do is I want to create a set the document with the data from User Auth in my collection,
and I want to set it using this user snapshot because remember, it's already pointing to a specific
place in the collection for the data that we want.
So to do this, I'm going to say first.
If so, I'm going to use the bhang operator, which means that if the snapshot.
Exists, so remember, it gives us a Boolean.
So if it exists, that it'll return true, if it doesn't exist, it gives us false and with the bang.
I'm reversing it.
So that means that if it doesn't exist, this will return true if it does not exist, because if it
does not exist, then I want to create and set the document.
So to do that, I need to pull off the display name.
And I want the email from art user off object, if you remember those are fields that is on this object
alongside with our unity.
And then what I also want to do is I want to make just a creative that so this is just going to be a
new date object.
This way, we know when these users are signing in.
Then in order to set this document, we need a try catch block.
If you don't know what track fetches, essentially this just means I want you to try something asynchronous.
If whatever you try and here throws an error, then you're going to catch that error and you're going
to do something with it within this block.
So what we're going to try is we are going to try to set the document.
So as we know, if get doc gets us the document, then set doc allows us to set the document.
And similarly, what we're going to pass it is a user doc reference that we just got back using the
doc and then we're going to pass on the data we want to set up with.
So here we want to set a display name.
We want to set a email.
And we want to set a created at date.
And this is pretty much all we need.
Beyond that, what about the air?
Well, what I'm going to do is I'm just going to console log that there was an error creating the user,
and I'm also going to log the error message that comes from the error.
So this is all that's going to happen if our user snapshot does not exist.
But what happens if the user data exists?
So if it exists, then this is not even going to run because this is going to return true, right?
User snapshot exists, which the bang will flip, so it evaluates the false meaning this whole settings
that is going to skip.
So we can just return user doc reference.
Just to be sure.
Let's just save this code and see what happens.
So let's just walk through this again.
We checked to see if this snapshot exists.
If it does not exist, then we want to set it inside of our database.
So we're just saying, Yo, set the doc with this object.
So what we're going to do here is we are just going to also in here cost.
User doc reference, because now we know no matter what happens, we should get back a doc reference.
And I want to await this, because, again, this is an asynchronous step.
In fact, we don't even need to do any of this yet.
We can actually see it directly in our collection if it works.
So let's just test that.
So let me refresh this.
Let me trigger the pop up.
Let me sign into my Google account.
And now again, we see that it's false, of course, because we just wrote the code for our collection
for the first time.
And now if we go into our database and we refresh.
We see we now have a user's collection, and there it is, there is our user created today.
So this is really great because that's all we really need.
We can now authenticate our users allowed them to come in, but also now we can just simply update our
database with all of these authenticated users and their relevant data.
So we have now created a way to create users.
So this is really handy because using this system, we now have authentication as well as storage of
these users inside of our application authentication and users is typically a very complicated feature
to built because it involves servers, back ends and all that.
But here we achieved it using Firebase, and we just had to learn a little bit of firebase along the
way.
So this is it.
We're now creating user documents.
We now have those documents and references.
We can use them for signing in and signing out users.
This is pretty good now.
We can start utilizing this inside of our application.
Before we do any of that, though, let's just make sure that we also commit our changes.
So what we want to do is we want to get ahead.
Let's just get commit our message, which is that we have added our sign in component as well as firebase
utils and brought in Firebase libraries.
And then we can push this up.
And that's it.
So now that we're at the stage, we have in some Firebase utility functions, we brought in Firebase,
we have our sign up component starting out.
Let's move on to the next video.
Well, we'll continue fleshing this out.