Welcome back, everyone.
In the last video, I challenge you to set up the category selector and migrate the category context
code to the appropriate place where we're fetching our categories map.
So what I want to do is I want to walk through this with you when it comes to thinking about where we
want to put this fetching, especially this API external fetching code inside of your code base.
So some of you might have moved this into your app.
J.S. Likely where we had previously our subscription to the Offset Change Listener.
Technically speaking, there's nothing wrong with doing this.
But if you think about it, the app component does not actually need this category's map data.
The first component that actually means this category is MAP is actually.
Inside of our shop page, we have categories, preview and category.
Both of these components, the category preview needs categories map and the category component needs
the category map.
So their nearest ancestor is the shop component.
And the shop page component can actually be the one that matches the code from our categories context,
which is to fetch the Firebase API, get down all those documents, create the categories map.
So we can actually copy over and paste in that use effect that we had before.
Will of course, have to tweak some of these so that they work in the context of Redux instead of in
the context of our context API.
Forgive my use of the word context here.
In order to do that, we need to start bringing in the appropriate methods.
So first, let's bring in our use of Factbook from React.
Let's also bring in our get categories documents from our firebase utils.
Let's go up to r utils file.
Firebase, firebase, utils.
And then we also need our newly created set categories.
Map Action Creator.
So let's bring in set categories map.
Going up to our store folder.
Categories.
Oops.
Categories and then categories.
Action.
So this, of course, is an action creator, which means we still need our dispatch which comes.
From React Redux.
And then it's just a matter of using this hook to get the dispatch.
And then wrapping it and calling it on set categories map.
So there we go.
Now, of course, at this point, we do still have access to our categories context.
So this category component and the shop component are still hooked up to that.
But if you look inside of this state object, we do see that we do have the appropriate categories reducer
with the correct categories map.
So now what we need to do is start using it.
The first thing I want to do is I want to remove references to this categories.
Context inside of index.
Just.
So here what we can do is just delete the categories provider.
And the nice thing about this is once you remove it, your code will stop working because you no longer
have access to the context.
But what you need to do now is figure out where in your code you're still calling categories context.
So clearly here inside of our preview component as well as inside of our categories component.
So first, let's start removing any references to this context because we're no longer using use context.
Instead, what we're doing is we're using.
Our selector, which we have not met.
So inside of our categories selector, let's create a contest select categories map which is equal to
a function that gets state.
And then from the state we pull off categories.
Categories map like so.
Let's make sure to export this.
Import this now into our categories preview component.
Going up to our stuff.
Order categories.
Category selector.
And then from re act we no longer need use context, but instead we need use selector from react redux.
And we'll just say, okay, I want to get categories map by calling you selector.
With Select Categories Map.
There we go.
So here now this category's preview should be properly selecting categories map.
So what we can do is we can go to the shop page and we see that we indeed have our data.
But going into deeper, we notice that we have nothing.
So this is exactly as expected.
We have not migrated over the category component.
So let's do that now as well.
I'm going to copy this because I know this is pretty much a 1 to 1 change of what we need from the category
component.
So instead of this, I'm going to put this in.
I need use selector.
From React Redux.
And of course, I also need select categories map from.
Our store folder.
Our Categories folder.
A category selector.
Let's say this.
And now let's go back.
And there we go.
Our code is now properly migrated over to using category context and we can now delete the categories
contexts such as sex.
And as we see nothing in our application breaks because everything is now properly migrated to Redux.
So I know there is just a lot of this kind of redundancy that we're going through where we're writing
selectors, we're writing reducers, we're writing our action creators, we're bringing in the use dispatch,
the use selector hooks.
But this is all very important because so much of this is indeed boilerplate and set up.
But the main benefit that we get, of course, is going to be still the unit directional data flow,
single source of truth for all of our data.
And here now as you practice and the more you code this, you will naturally just be able to infer all
of the steps that you need and you'll understand why they're necessary.
You need actions that actually create updates in the reducers.
You need selectors to pull that data down and then you have to set it all up inside of the appropriate
store object.
So all of this is just a cyclical flow that you have to get familiar with.
But now that we've set this up, there's a couple of things that I want to talk about, and that has
to do with some of the more optimizations we can make to this set up that we have now that we have two
different reducers, which we'll discuss in the next video.
So join me in the next video and let's talk about optimizing this code.