Welcome back, everyone.
So let's now move the remainder of what we had inside of our objects into its own component.
Inside of the components folder.
When we think about what we want to name this, you want to kind of pick a name that really captures
what this feature will be for us because this feature is not being reused yet.
We don't need to overly optimize what the definition of this component really is right now.
We know at least it's our directory menu.
So I'm just going to call it directory and inside, I'm going to call it directory component dot GSX.
And I'm just going to move over.
This code, some of the say Konst directory is equal to a functional component that returns back.
This to.
We know that off the props, we're going to get categories.
And then we also know that we're going to export default.
We see that we're missing category item.
So let's go to Angus.
And let's scroll up and take this category item.
Because we no longer need it in objects anymore, since we're now putting it up into directory.
So here we just need to make sure that our relative import is correct.
So from here we go up one.
And right now we go from directory up to the components folder and then into category item and the remainder
stays the same.
So here is our directory.
Now what we also need is the styling for this directory, because if you remember, we have a bit of
styling in our categories that sees us.
So let's make a new file called Directory Dot Styles Dot SAS.
And inside, let's just copy over our categories container.
You can call this categories as well just to match the styling.
For me, I'm going to make this a little bit more clear.
I'm going to say directory container.
And I'm going to modify the styling inside of directory component here, this class name, so that it's
more clear as well.
You can easily make these changes on the fly.
As you write your code, honestly, sometimes you might feel like you're naming of a component makes
more sense as you start writing it out.
It's perfectly fine to change these class names and all this stuff when you're in this phase where you're
building out a feature.
As you start to work with other teams, sometimes you may want to talk about this with your teammates
to make sure that everyone understands and agrees that these component names do capture what it is that
you're writing.
Because one key thing to think about when it comes to variable names, you are writing code for people.
Yes, the computer interprets it, but it's developers human people that are reading this code.
So you need to be writing these function names and these component names in a way that is intuitive
for people.
What's intuitive for some may not be intuitive for others.
So feel free to rename this whatever you want as well, whatever makes sense to you about what we're
building.
You can definitely try and name it that way.
That's the beautiful thing.
I want you to try and see.
That's honestly sometimes the best way for you to know whether or not something makes sense or not.
So let's go back to our OPG's, and now let's import in our directory.
So when you go up to our components into our directory folder, grab directory component file and we'll
just replace this whole section here.
With our directory and we're going to pass in categories is equal.
Two categories.
And now let's save this code.
Let's go check.
This was our hot image, but let's check our application.
Let's refresh.
Oh, we didn't actually resolve the category style, so we didn't remove that code right here.
We no longer have categories, styles because we deleted it.
And in our directory, we also did not import it.
We just imported our directory styles file that we moved our styles into into our directory component
and then yes, we've removed the reference to that category styles file that we removed.
And now if we go back.
We have one more cannot resolve category item, category item component inside of our directory component.
So let's go back here.
Let's see what mistake we made here.
Ah, here we see inside we've gone up from our Directory folder to our components folder.
We went into the category item folder and then we went and tried to find another category item folder.
So this is duplicated.
So everyone makes mistakes.
You're going to make a bunch of typos and you're going to make a bunch of errors when you're coding.
Always whenever that happens.
Take a breath and just really focus on where do you think the error is coming from?
We had Stack Trace, which is what we saw when we saw that error message in our browser that told us
where our error was.
And then it's just a matter of process of elimination.
What are the files that we changed?
Where could we most likely expect to see these errors from the stack trace?
And then it's just a matter of going back through all the possible cases and most of the time, honestly,
90 percent of the time.
A lot of our errors are going to be typos.
And now here we come back.
We see that everything is exactly how it was before.
So that's it.
We've moved out and made this major companies major components now and now we can start building out
the rest of our application and thinking about what else to build.
But before we proceed, what I want you to do is I want you to go back to your terminal and now is actually
a great time for us to commit our code.
So commit your code is just to make a save of your code because you really want to think about when
you want to commit.
Oftentimes you want to commit when you've done what feels like a contained block of work.
And for us, we just built out our directory page, which is a great time to commit this work.
So we're just going to say, get, add dash.
Get commit and then are commit message, we'll just say updating our directory page with directory component
and category item component.
And then you can just push this up.
You can do get push for me because I'm using Zetia, which is my preferred.
I have the shorthand Gigi push.
There's a push up, and there we go.
Now in the next video, join me while we build out the next major feature in our application.
I'll see you in the next video.