Welcome back, everyone.
So let's build our category page.
To do that, what we need to do is we need to build a new routes component.
This one will be category because that's really what we're showing is the full category listing.
I'm going to call this inside category act style that says.
And then category act component Dutch asks.
Our component, of course, is going to import in our category as well, and then I'm a concert category
is equal to this functional component, which we export by default.
As for the category itself, what do we need to do?
Well, what we need is actually this value from the URL, because if you remember in the final application,
when we go to hats, we know that we're on the hot route when we're on jackets.
We know where on the jackets.
So there's you are all parameter is actually going to be the thing that tells our category component
what data to get.
And this is a little bit of architecture that we need to think about.
So the first thing we need to do is figure out how to get these parameters.
So let's start at the root level first.
I'm just going to copy this over into my shop component and here I'm just going to duplicate this and
reflect the appropriate placement.
Like so.
And now for the root, it's not an index anymore.
It's going to match a path.
And what this path will match is actually going to be a unique string.
This string only works when you're trying to say, Hey, I want a parameter here, meaning that you
can access it from a component and you say semicolon and then the name of the variable.
So I'm going to call it category.
And what I'm going to render is the category component.
Now inside of the category component, in order to access this new parameter, we need to import in
the use params hook from Rack Rotterdam.
Use params now will allow us to actually get this value, and the way it gives it to us is it actually
gives us to as an object.
So if there are multiple parameters that match, then we'll get multiple.
But for us, because we know there's only category, that's what we call that category, we can structure
this off.
From the return of use, perhaps.
Now what we also need once we get this category value, if you think about it, once we get jackets,
well, we need to call jackets on our categories, map to get the associated products to this category.
So that means that we need to now bring in the context.
So let's bring in use context.
From React.
And let's also bring in.
Are categories context?
So many cities.
So with our categories context, we can get the categories map.
Use context passing in card categories context.
And then with categories context, now we want the actual products from this category.
So typically what you could do at this point, you could just say Konst products is equal to categories
map.
Category, you could do this, there's nothing wrong with doing this.
Essentially, whatever this component renders, these products will be gotten.
But this will happen every time this component renders.
So what we instead want to do is bring in you state and use effect because essentially the only time
that we want to change these is of the category value changes or categories, map changes.
So here we can say we have products and set products which is equal to you, state, which by default
has an empty array.
And then we'll just say use affect.
Whenever category changes and categories map changes.
Then what you can do is call set products where we set the value equal to categories map.
Category.
This way now, if our component renders or anything like that, our products will not update unless
category or categories map has changed, that's the only time we will do that.
And now what we're going to return back is just our div and us mapping our products through.
Using the product card component, which we don't have.
So let's import that in as well.
So here we'll just say use the product card.
And of course, key will be product ID.
And the product.
Is going to be the product.
For this debate, though, we know we need some styling, so I'm going to give it a class name of category
container.
And inside of category styles, we can just directly style category container.
Which is going to be display grid very similar to what you had before.
Great template column rows or columns, sorry for columns.
So we're going to say repeat for one half hour.
I want to call them Gap.
Let's say 20 pixels.
And then I want to a gap of 50 pixels.
You can change these gap values to whatever you want.
But now if we come back to our main application and let's say I navigate to slash hats now.
Now, when we navigate here, we seem to see that something breaks here, if we screw up, we see cannot
read properties of undefined reading map a category.
So when we look inside of our categories map at this point, remember our categories, map is saying,
Hey, you cannot call map method on undefined, so for some reason our products is undefined.
The reason why this is undefined is because we're trying to call category on an empty object when this
app first mounts.
Remember, our categories context fetches this data asynchronously, but when our application mounts
for the first time, it's still trying to actually run this code synchronously.
This is happening before we actually get these categories from our fire store.
So what we need to do is build in a safeguard in order to do that.
What we can do is we can say, Hey, if products is undefined, then don't render it only render products
map if products has a value, which means here.
In fact, what we can say is that instead of calling this by default with an empty array, we can call
categories map at category as the starting value here.
With this now, this will still work because we know categories map by default, is an empty object.
So now, if we save this and we come back here, let's just get rid of this so that we can at least
see now we do see that we are rendering our component without errors.
This styling conflict is actually a separate issue that we'll discuss, but I don't want to move on
from this topic just yet.
Remember, if you have components that rely on asynchronously fetched code, you will need to put in
some kind of safeguard so that you only render your component if the actual data is present.
And that's exactly what we did here.
We defensively programmed against our products being undefined.
So now that we have our products in and we have this check in.
Let's talk about this styling issue.
What I want you to do is actually try and debug it yourself.
This is a good chance to see and think about why some of these errors might be happening.
So what I want you to do is I want you to take a look into these different elements on the side here
and try and identify why we have this issue.
If you can't, don't worry, I have the answer.
I'll give you a little bit of a hint.
If you click on this component right here, you should take to this page and see that this is also broken.
Why is this happening?
Well, take a look into it.
And then in the next video, we'll fix this together.