Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to make our sign out into its own saga.
Now, the reason we have, too, is because even though Firebase is signing out the user, we are not
aware that Firebase has done so because we don't have an officer anymore.
So we need to now make the sign out process part of our actual sign out saga.
So to do this, we need to once again create the sign out trio.
So we'll have our sign out start.
We'll have our sign out.
Success.
And we'll have our sign out Felt.
Using these three, we now need to create the appropriate user actions.
So when you think about it with sign out, we actually don't need anything.
All of signing out is going to just set everything to null.
So as long as we succeed, technically we don't need any payloads.
So we'll say sign out.
Start is just equal to us creating the action of sign out start.
Then our sign out success.
Is just us creating.
Oops.
There we go.
Create action.
User action types.
Sign out.
Success.
And we need the same thing for our failed.
Which is just us saying sign.
Out failed.
Actually, there should be sign out success.
Actually sign out.
Fail.
We need the error.
My apologies.
Failed.
Always has the error payload.
But success doesn't because success.
We're just going to set it to null.
So let's go into our user reducer.
And this is what we're going to say.
We want to say that on.
User action.
Dot sign out failed like.
So this actually allows us to multiple match if you stack them like this.
In fact we even need sign up fail.
That's another failure that we didn't account for like this.
And now we've accounted for all three.
If sign in success.
If sign in fail.
Sign out.
Fail.
Sign up failed.
Now we have our reducer set up.
So we have our actions, we have our reducers now we need our sagas.
So for our sagas, we know that what we need to do is we need to listen for on sign out start.
And also we need a call to our firebase so that we can get the method that signs our user.
So here what we are going to do is we are going to do a.
Entry on sign out start like this yield take latest user action types dot sign out start.
And here what we're going to call is sign out.
Sign out is going to be.
A generator.
And this is just going to received nothing as we know.
What it's really going to try to do, though, is call our sign out, use our method, which we need
to import in.
This is what we've been using.
Inside of our navigation.
So now instead we are going to wrap this inside of our tri catch.
So we're going to call sign out user.
If this is successful, then we will say that sign out.
Success.
Which this should have auto imported.
If you didn't do it, you need to import it for your user action.
And while we're here, actually, let's also bring in sign outfield because we need sign out failed.
As part of our catch block.
Like so.
So that's our saga.
We have our sign out, which is being called by our online out start and then we have to call it inside
of our user sagas.
And then the last thing to do is now to update our navigation component so that sign out user is calling
sign out start.
So we've got to bring in our use dispatch.
And now, instead of calling this Firebase Utils version, we need to bring in the action creator from
store.
Slash user slash user action.
Sign out.
Start like so.
We need to.
Get dispatch from U.S Dispatch.
And then what we can say is contact sign user is a function that dispatches out sign out start like
so.
And now if we go into our application, we see that we are signed in.
If we sign out, there we go that updates.
But we notice that for some reason, even though our sign out success works, our user is still signed
it.
So this is where we need to account for it inside of our user reducer.
We need to say that case user action types sign out success.
We need to return.
State current user goes to?
No.
So oftentimes when you see your code not working the way you expect it to.
Chances are you've missed one of these ten different little nuances inside of Redux that prevented it
from updating.
Honestly, this is a very common thing.
Notice how much we're typing, how much boilerplate we're adding.
This is honestly one of the most annoying things about using Redux in sagas.
It's so much boilerplate.
But the main thing is that if something's not working, you know the flow.
Actions to reducers, to Saga's, it's going to be in there somewhere.
You just have to figure out which one it is that you're missing.
And now if we come back, we refresh.
Let's just make sure we sign in.
We see, we reflecting it.
We sign out.
There we go.
We've signed our successfully user, current user to know.
That's it.
All of our users have now been migrated over to Saga's and this is the last of migrating our code over
to Saugus.
I know it's a lot.
Honestly, it's overwhelming for me, too.
Every time I think about working with sagas again, there is a lot of boilerplate to work through in
order to get it to work.
But sagas are very powerful for this reason because of so much encapsulation inside of these generators.
This coordination is present.
Now, if this is challenging, don't worry.
I'm completely with you.
Sagar's is challenging.
A lot of this are very advanced patterns that honestly, most intermediate React developers might not
even come across with sagas.
So this is just one of those things that it's just part of the path of becoming a very advanced React
user is getting familiar with Redux and all of its ecosystem and figuring out when you need these libraries
at scale.
But you can see how with a lot of this, we're able to now encapsulate and control so much of the flow
of data inside of our redux system.
So that's it.
This is our lesson on Saga's.
This is really the last of the more challenging and most potent parts of Redux.
That takes the hardest part to learn.
So if you made it through, I really want you to pat yourself on the back because this is really challenging
to have all done so soon.
But now you understand.
SAGA'S Let's move on with the rest of the course.