Let's talk about the final type of test automation tests now, you may also hear the term end to end
testing when it comes to automation test.
So keep that in mind.
Automation tests, like I said before, our UI tests that are always running inside a browser or a browser
like environment.
Because they need to simulate user behavior in these environments, such as clicking, typing, scrolling,
and finally they need to make sure that these scenarios actually work from the point of view of an end
user.
It's an important test, right?
If your checkout process has a bug, the best way to probably test it is to actually go through that
checkout flow and make sure that users can purchase whatever you're selling.
Now, in an ideal world, we have automation tests everywhere.
And if any of them fail, we know that our Web app doesn't work.
But it's important to remember that these tests are the hardest to set up, imagine yourself creating
an environment to run a test on different machines because users have different computers, different
devices, different phones, different browser types, different versions.
How can you really test for that?
I mean, you can, but it's really, really hard.
And this is why there's so many services that provide automation testing for you.
Here's an example of a few of them.
Yep, these are just a few of them, such as Nightwatch Web Driver, Eye Test Cafe, Nightmare Cyprus,
the list really goes on.
Automation testing is something you usually only find at bigger companies that have the budget to really
spend money on this because there's so many cases and they're so expensive to implement that some developers
go their whole career without ever writing an automation test.
But I still want to cover it because it is an important topic.
Here's a quick lowdown, though.
If you just want to get started and not worry about cross browser and have all the tools in one, probably
Tesfaye is your best choice.
Or if you want the one that has the best documentation online.
Well, Web driver Eyo is really great.
And if you want really simple ways to automate user actions or do something cool like web scraping,
well, nightmare is pretty good.
Now, the important thing with automation testing is that like the other name suggests, and to enter
testing, you want to test the entire process of your UI.
And you might be thinking, why do we get the machine to do it, why can't we just hire people to test
for us and do automation testing?
And that happens.
Many companies, instead of writing these scripts, simply hire people to do automation testing.
And at some companies, you have people like testers that do this for you and make sure that the app
works as intended.
And there's pros and cons to both of these, and that's something that it really depends on your company
and your work environment.
The main thing I want to suggest, though, is that we want to create two different testing processes,
one for a running unit, tests and integration tests, and a completely separate one to run these tests,
these automation tests.
That's because unit tests take a longer time.
Especially if we worry about different browsers and different devices and they also cost a lot more
money to run them repeatedly, so you would want to run unit tests and integration tests often probably
in your terminal as your saving your changes to your code and your local environment and maybe run UI
tests once a day or a couple of times a week or maybe just before you merge into the master branch,
before you release it to production.
For now, though, that's it for automation testing.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.