Now, before we do reduce, let's do find so what is find?
Well, let's first get our array again, so we'll just copy over what we had from our last experiment.
And find is also exactly as it sounds, we're trying to find an element that correctly returns true
based on the condition that we have.
And the return of our function, very similar to filter, so what we would say is Meyera Dot find.
And we would get our element and let's say I wanted the element that is equal to five well here at what
would get us our element five, right?
Because if one goes in, is it equal to five?
No, three, no.
But five is true.
And the moment that it's correct, this method actually stops and it gives us back the first value in
the array that return true from calling this function on each element so it won't keep going.
So a way we can actually see this is if we say Meyera, fine and we get our aliment.
And let's say we do, as long as the element is greater than four.
So theoretically, five, seven and nine are all true, but because it's applying it from left to right
on each element, the first element that this returns true, it will return and it won't keep going.
And we know that it will be five.
So don't find is a great way for us when world, let's say we have an array of objects, right.
And we want to find a specific object based on some condition.
Right.
You can imagine if we had let's say people are right where we had an array of objects where the I.D.
was one.
The I.D. of four.
And then the idea of seven.
If we wanted to find people Arae right, with the idea for one, then we would say person or person
thought it was equal to four.
And now this will give us our second item where it's our person with our idea for.
So this is the great thing about find is that final give us the reference to whatever element it is
that matches the condition that we pass in the function of our find.
And we will use this as well quite extensively in our coding.