Welcome back, everyone.
So in this video, we are going to finish off our cart drop down.
A lot of the complexity of the actual car maintenance has been achieved through our cart context.
Now, though, let's finish off the actual car items.
So as you can guess, I've already, of course, styled out the car item for you.
So what you need to do, though, is you need to fill in with the appropriate HDMI structure.
So here what we need to do is we need to think about what gets added into the cart.
We know there's name, we know this quantity, but we also know there's an image.
And we also need to know what the quantity is multiplied by the price of the item.
So at this top level, I'm just going to say that this div is of the class name cart item container.
So this is our parent.
Then inside, I'm going to have an image and this image is going to be of the image URL coming from
the cart item.
So all of those fields that we had before the name, the image URL, the price, the quantity, I want
all of these.
And the source is going to be the image URL.
So this is very similar to our product card and the alt text is also going to be the name.
So here inside, I also now need a separate div that will contain all of our item details.
So here when you think about this structure, where inside you have this quantity, when you look at
the actual component.
Notice that this image and this section are two separate sections, but these details are kind of grouped
together.
That's why I want to wrap these in another div and this div, I'm going to call the item details.
And then inside, I'm going to have a span.
And this ban will show the name.
And the class name for this will just be name.
Similarly, this ban is already written, which will be the price, and it will contain the quantity
multiplied by dollar.
And this is it.
This is the entire component.
Now inside of your car item stores, just copy paste in the item style sheet that I provided in your
resources folder.
Now, once you've saved this now, go into your application.
And you should see that right here.
We have everything that we wanted to see from what we had finally.
So here, if I add more, there is another item.
So our car is looking pretty good.
It's pretty much exactly what we have inside of our final application.
There is one feature we are missing left and that is the count inside of the card icon.
I want you to try and figure out using all the things we learned, how to build in that count.
So pause the video and try it out yourself.
You're essentially accumulating all of the quantities, storing it somewhere inside of the car context
and then utilizing it.
So try it out yourself.
And then when you're ready, unpaused the video and let's do it together.
So let's build into our application, the accountability.
So here, let's go into our context.
Inside of our car context, we already have all the car items that has the quantity on them while we
want to be able to do is that whenever car items changes, we want to be able to show a new cart count.
So I'm going to make a new property called car count that by default starts at zero.
Then what I want to do is I want to make a new cart count and set cart count state using you state,
which by default causes zero.
Then what I want to do is I'm going to use the use effect hook because essentially what we're doing
is we are recounting the total quantity every time the car items changes.
There's more ways to do this.
This is just one particular way.
You can also expose a function that will always reduce the car items.
But this way, I think, is just the way that we can think about using use effect and highlight some
of these changes that we can make.
Like so, so remember, with use effect, we pass it a callback and this callback runs every time something
in your dependency array changes.
So for us, I want to change the cart items every time this car items array changes in any way.
We need to recalculate the cart count.
So here I'm going to say new cart count is equal to cart items, reduce some reducing over the cart
items and reduce is going to take two arguments.
The first argument here is the callback.
The second argument is the starting value.
So what goes into the callback?
The callback is going to be the current total.
And then the second volume is going to be the current carte item.
So here what happens is that essentially we are going to say, OK, I want to take the total and I want
to add the item quantity.
So now, whenever these values accumulate, as it traverses through the card items, we'll finally end
up with a new total, which we will then set as the new car count, something I say set card count equal
to new card count.
And now I can just add this cart count to my values.
And then inside of the cart icon component, I just need to pull it in.
And instead of rendering.
Zero.
I just wonder, can't count like so.
And if we go back.
Let's add some items.
And there we see.
We are accurately now keeping track of our car count.
So as you can see, we pretty much now got everything that looks similar to our main Crown clothing
application.
Now, what I want to challenge you to do is I want you to be able to try and figure out how to build
this, go to check out button that takes you to this checkout step.
And then inside of here, there is all of these different checkout items.
You don't necessarily have to build out this visual component.
But what I challenge you to do is try and figure out how to increment the item from this arrow, decrement
the item from this arrow, as well as remove an item entirely with that X button.
This will really flex every single thing you've learned up until this point with the code.
You don't have to do the styling.
The main thing is figuring out the composition of the function, the composition of the functionality,
as well as how to build these additional features into your context and your components and linking
it all together.
This is a great challenge.
And also to comprise the total value as well.
This entire page is actually a great way for you to figure out how to make all of these things that
we've learned into one unique feature.
So my challenge to you is to try that out.
And before you proceed, I also want you to commit your code because we've just added some new functionality.
So I want you to get add and then leave a message that says what you did.
So here we just added in our add to cart feature.
And then push it up and now try and build that checkout page.
Once you're finished.
Come join me and we'll do it together in the next video.