Now we're going to build a pretty simple template, so what we first need to do is import react from
react.
And we're also going to import in fuel from Gatsby because we need to make a request for the actual
markdown.
We're also going to import the layout from our components.
Now, if you're curious why this template is not in our components folder, the reason is because this
template is not a component that we actually use in the application, any application files we keep
inside of our components.
But anything that we use to actually build out our blog posts or any other templates that we dynamically
generate in Our Gatsby note, we're just going to put here instead.
What we're going to export as the default is going to be this new function where we get the data.
Because we know what we're going to want to pluck off is the Makhdoom.
The actual graph fuel that we need.
Is going to be this query.
Now, what we want to query for is the individual markdown remark related to the slug that we get.
We're actually going to get that slug manually by passing in it as a parameter that our graph cool will
use.
So I'm going to show you what the graph looks like.
And then when we go back to Our Gatsby, no, Jess, you're going to see how we pass that it.
So essentially, we're going to have our query and it's going to receive this parameter called sluggard.
That's going to be a string and it's always going to be mandatory.
Now, what we're going to get back is a down Remarque.
Where what we're looking for is we want to match this fields' here to the slug value, right.
And we want it to be equal to the slug parameter that we pass in.
So if you're unfamiliar with GaveKal, this is the syntax of writing a query.
Essentially, we're specifying that I want you to match this field on our markdown remark where the
slug is equivalent to this slug strength that we pass in here.
Now, we can actually test to see if this quarry works first and we can do it inside of our graph cual
playground.
So let's just get rid of our initial query for all markdown remarks.
And what we're going to request for is simply a markdown remark.
And inside here we see that what we did was we checked for the fields, we checked for the slug, and
we checked that it was equal to some string.
So in this case, the string that we're matching will be either ice cream or my first block.
And now whenever this logs, I also want to make sure that I get the ID and I want the fields as well.
And I also want the slug here.
So now if I do this, I see that I'm fetching for exactly the markdown that matched the ice cream slug
to this string, which was our ice cream markdown.
So that's really what we're doing here.
So what we're doing is we are getting that mark down and what we want to plug off of it is the HTML.
We want the front matter.
And we want the title.
So with this, we now have the data that we need and what we're going to do is we are going to set the
post itself equal to data markdown remark.
So now we have access to the marked and remarkable object.
And what we're going to return is our lay out component wrapping around some somdev that holds inside
of it and H2 or an H1.
Let's do another one, actually.
And as you can guess, we're going to do post front matter.
And then for a div, this is where we're actually going to populate the div with our TEMEL, so we're
going to use a react method called dangerously set in our HTML.
This is the preferred way of actually setting this value, so I know it says dangerously set, this
is because in typical reactor you don't want to do this.
But in Gatsby, this is perfectly fine because it's not dynamically generated.
This is statically set.
So underscore, underscore, HTML is the value and we want post HTML, so we want to use the HTML value
here.
And what this will do is this will set all of the HTML value inside of this div.
So with this, we have our blog post template, so let's go back to Our Gatsby, no jazz file and inside
of our Krey pages that we had before, we are going to now pass the component.
Now, this component is expecting a relative path.
So we actually have to build it using the path variable.
That we get.
By default from the Path library that comes with every single no jass file, so we're going to pass
in path and we're going to say path dot resolve.
And what we're going to say is dot slash sauce.
So I want to go from the route down to the source folder into templates using our blogs.
Now, in order for us to pass the actual slug value to this query, we pass it through this context
object.
And here we're going to give the Sloggett equal to our no duff fields dot slug.
So now this will know that when it runs create pages, what it's going to do is it's going to create
the page calling graph QOL using every single markdown remark.
It's going to loop through every single markdown file that we have, and it's going to manually create
a new page for it using that new blog post template.
But now we have our new create pages method.
There's actually a typo here, this actually should be asked.
In fact, let's just double check our blog post to make sure that we're not doing anything wrong.
Oh, it looks like I actually use the wrong parentheses here, so let's just fix that as well.
We want to make sure we're turning with round brackets.
OK, so now let's restart our server.
So let's just wait for our server to finish building.
OK, so now that we're finished building, let's actually see if our pages have generated, so let's
go to localhost eight thousand and let's just navigate to our pages.
So the first is ice cream.
And we see that we have and our second is my first Šamaš.
And here we see that this also works, so we now have our dynamic bill pages using our markdowns if
we write any new markdowns to our pages.
Not only is it going to add to our index, but we're going to generate a new page for it.
So this is awesome because now we've pretty much got a dynamically structured and building blog without
us having to add any more code other than some styling if we want to, or new features.
But as far as it goes, in terms of adding new blog posts, this is pretty much done.
One other thing that we're going to do is we actually probably should reverse the order of this listing,
because right now it's listing the earliest dates first versus listing the latest dates as the newest
things so we can do all this in the next lesson.