Welcome back.
Let's talk about the second point of making a progressive Web app and probably the cutest little icon
that I'm going to have in discourse, the app manifest.
Now, for a progressive Web app to behave like a native app, we need to mimic not just the function
of a native app, but also some of the views that we get with it or the shell.
For example, on your phone, you can download an app and have an app icon on Android devices.
You have things such as splash screens.
The idea is to make the Web app as indistinguishable.
As possible to a real mobile app.
And we can do that with the app manifest before we get into it, though, the one thing I do want to
point.
Is that a lot of people forget to include in their index file this line over here and this comes out
of the box with a react up, you can see that I'm in the public index folder.
And this line, which is the meta tag with viewport, optimises the app for multiple devices.
And this might seem super obvious, but a lot of people forget it.
And this line helps with adjusting the screen size based on the device.
So this is a must and it will warn you if you're missing this line in the Lighthouse report.
So now that we have the screen set up for mobile devices, let's talk about the app manifest file.
And as you can see in our public folder, again, this is something that we get for free from Creative
Reactive.
And this is it, this is the manifest Dodgson file.
It's a simple JSON file that gives the developers the ability to control how the app should appear to
the user in areas where they would expect to see apps such as the mobile device homescreen.
And just define how the app is going to launch and how it's going to look.
So if you remember in my example over here with this Hacker News app, we had the add to home screen
button in the application tab.
And you might have noticed that we actually clicked on this thing called Manifest and the application,
and that's the manifest dot JSON file.
The browser reads this and spits out this little piece of information for us, and if I scroll down,
you see that I have icons here that get downloaded.
Just like I did for when I downloaded it onto my home screen, and this is the icon that you'll see
when you download this app on your mobile phone, and it also gives us this nice little feature to add
to homescreen.
So this is the app manifest fall and what it does.
Now, how do we generate these icons?
We see over here that create react AB has generated a Vatican.
In the public folder.
But we're missing a few things, aren't we?
We don't have all these other sized icons for mobile phones because we still need to generate them for
our app.
And you can see here that they have different sizes.
Based on whichever device this gets downloaded on.
Luckily for us, there's a great tool that does this very nicely and easily.
It's called real.
Taddiken generator.
And this all we need to do is provide an image.
Such as an image of a robot by just clicking on Select Fabricant picture and it will take you through
the steps to download these and all we need to do is include them in our public folder, just like the
fabric on icon laws and reference them in the manifest DOT JSA.
And don't worry, this is exactly where we're going to do in our exercise to turn our robo friends up
into a progressive web app.
Another thing that this website does for us is previewing and customizing the splash screen for our
manifest file.
Now, what is a splash screen?
In older versions of Chrome for Android tapping on the home screen, icon for an app would often take
up to a couple of hundred milliseconds before that screen gets loaded, a user would see a white screen.
Which makes the experience a little bit jarring and it looks like the website is loading really slow,
so Chrome forty seven and above support this idea of a splash screen.
Where you can add a background color when you tap on the app, the progressive Web app, instead of
loading the white screen, it's going to load something called a splash screen.
Where l have the background color, the name and icon of the web, and it will get that all from our
manifest JSON file.
And this is all done simply to make your webapp feel a lot closer to what you see with native apps when
you click on native apps, even if they're loading, they have some sort of a background and icon to
show you that it is loading.
Overall, though, that's it, that's pretty simple, right?
All we need is some icons and add them to manifest that JSA.
That's it for now.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.