Welcome back, everyone here inside of our office dashboard.
What we want to do is access your site and on your site, go to your site settings.
In our actual local development, we're using tight end in order to have environment variables so that
our local server can access them.
Unfortunately not.
Lafite does not have access to Diam because it's reading from the actual repository in GitHub.
And as we remember, we have ignored NW from being posted to the repository because of course this is
not a key we want to reveal to anybody else.
Luckily for us though, we can set these environment variables the same way that we've used them in
end here inside of our site settings.
So inside your site settings, go to build and deploy an inside of build and deploy it.
Scroll down until you see environment variables here when you hit edit variable.
What you're going to do is actually add them by the variable name and then the value.
So as you can see of entertainment before, but for you you're going to do the same thing for both that
react app straight publishable key but also the strip secret key.
You can literally just copy your file variables over into the here.
So for the key you're going to put your react app stripe publishable key.
As for the value, what you want to do is you want to copy the value without the quotations.
Now, of course, I'm not going to show you my environment variables, but that's what I'm saying.
You don't have to post it as a string.
You can just post the characters of the actual key inside here as the value.
So do that for both the React app, straight publishable key and also the Stripe secret key.
And they want to be the exact same key values that you have.
Again, the value not being in the quotes.
So do that.
Come back.
I'm going to assume you've done that and then let's actually deploy our website.
So now that we've done that, you should have react abstract, publishable key as well as Stripe secret
key added into your environment variables and saved.
Now what we're going to do, if you have yet to actually commit this code, if you come in now, everything
should build properly.
But what I'm going to show you is if you want to manually trigger a deployment, so here we can go to
deploys.
And what we can do is just click Trigger Deploy.
And now what will happen is we will manually actually deploy a new build with the latest code.
The reason I'm doing this is because I've already pushed my code up.
So the CLIA has actually already built the website, but I'm just going to show you manually what this
going to look like.
Again, if you haven't committed and you have our new function code in, just deploy that meaning that
you should just push that code up to GitHub.
Let our connection and our ally build the website.
And here now while you're waiting, let's just quickly wait a second, because we can actually see our
functions build inside of these logs.
So I'm just going to fast forward through this section.
So here you can see step two is functions bundling.
So this is actually adding our functions.
And as you can clearly see, this is our create payment intent function.
It was built successfully and now the site, should it properly build script is successful.
If we scroll up, we see that we have published.
So if we preview the deployment now here we can see that I've actually already got a live session and
what I'm going to do is just show you with exactly the flows that we should expect to see.
So I'm going to sign in with my Google account.
And then what I'm going to do if you haven't already added items to your cart, add some value, go
to the checkout, scroll down here to the card payment and just add in the test credit card if you hit
pay now.
What you'll see is that we should see a successful payment.
If we come into our striped dashboard, we see that I have successfully made a payment with equal pay.
So that's it.
We are alive and deployed with our net life functions.
All of our functionality is now in production.
All that's left now is to learn a couple more optimizations that we can make with our React application.
But as far as our Capstone project goes, we are at feature completion.
Congratulations.
You've made it through.
You have learned about all of the different tools that come to help us build features inside of React.
From this point forward, what I'm going to teach you is mainly just additional optimizations and primarily
a lot of the tools that kind of make your process a little bit more efficient, such as performance
and such as TypeScript, etc..
So I want you to take a second, take a breather, patch yourself on the back.
Appreciate what you've built before you learn something new.
Maybe go back and add some more features to the application if you want.
Make it look a little bit more unique to your style.
Again, I have built this website and since the filming of this course, there's actually been a lot
of students who have built this website as well.
So if you want to tweak some of the designs and make it look a little bit more like your own, please
feel free to do so.
You have earned that and it's a great way to practice the skills that you've picked up so far.
I'm very proud of you.
And when you're ready, come join me in the next video.
Well, we'll start a new topic.
I'll see you in the next video.