Oh, Andre, more slides, can we just get to coding and I know what you're thinking.
I know the easiest thing to do is for me to just go to my sublime text and start coding so you can follow
along.
But I really want this course to build the foundation because I can do all the coding in the world.
But if you have these fundamentals and we talk about them first and as you code along with me or you
do the exercises, you truly understand them from the basics, then you're going to retain a lot more
information.
So bear with me.
This is going to help you develop into a better developer.
This is the last slide.
Before we get into some coding, I just want to show you one last part.
And that is our unified picture of testing now that we've talked about everything.
We're going to be writing tests for our Robo Friends app, and if you remember, we have our main file
app.
And the way we're going to write test for it and other subcomponents and maybe even reducers and other
parts of the redox environment.
Well, we're simply going to do the dot test dot js.
Which, with our create react type set up, is going to say that this is a test file.
Let me run it through.
Just keep in mind that tests are meant for development.
You're never going to ship your test libraries or your test code into production.
Most of the time, you're saving these libraries with the flag, dash, dash, save Deve and AMPM because
they're only used for development in development.
As you're writing your tests, as you're writing your code, you have something like just running in
the background that has the scaffolding, the assertion library, the test runner, the spies, Moxon
Stobbs, that we need to read the tests, run the tests, see which tests pass or fail, and also output
a code coverage so that we can work on our project.
And when it's ready, it passes all the tests.
It has all the nice tests that we need.
We can then send it to production without all this stuff that production does need.
And remember that we're running these tests.
We can run them in the dorm, we can run them in a headless browser, or we can just run them in a J-Star,
which we are going to do.
We're going to use Geston because it's the fastest and the simplest to run our tests.
All right.
Time to get to Cotting.
It's going to be a lot of fun.
I'll see you in the next video.