In this video, we are going to build out our checkout page, so here to set up a checkout page.
Let's look at what we need.
We know that we need a new route that will point to a checkout component.
And then inside of this component, we need access to our car items.
So we need to connect this checkout page and our cart context.
Then we need to display the items inside of our cart.
And we want to be able to modify their quantities.
We also want to be able to remove these items and in course, also reflect an accurate total.
So let's build out this connection and the components and then start thinking about how to create the
actual functionality.
So back inside of our application, I am going to build a new folder in the roots and I'm going to call
this checkout.
As for the checkout component itself, I'm going to make the checkout styles that source and also I
want to make checkout dot component Dot GSX.
Here, as we do before, we want to import in our styles page.
So let's bring that in.
Declare checkout is equal to a functional component that for now just returns a div and inside of that
div, I just want to make and one that says I am the checkout page.
I'm going to export this by default.
And then what I'm going to do is go back into our OPG's.
Import in the appropriate file.
And then I'm going to create a new route.
For check out.
And like so.
And then, of course, we need to make some kind of connection between what we have to this page and
as we know, inside of our heart dropdown.
We have this button that takes us to the checkout.
So how do we circumvent this button so that when you click the button, it navigates us to the checkout
route?
Well, there's actually a hook that we get from React Router Dot, and this one is called Use Navigate
from React Router Dom.
Use Navigate is a hook that allows us to get a navigate function.
Like, so when you call it this navigate function will allow us to actually go to checkout.
So here if I say Konst, go to checkout handler.
This is just a function that calls navigate to check out like so.
And now.
If I just attach this to the on click like so and then we go back to our application.
And now if we open our cards and we click Go to checkout, we see our checkout page.
So now what I want to do is I want to get these items into my checkout page.
So how do we do that?
So in order for us to list out our car items, let's think about what we need to do inside of our checkout
component.
The first thing is we probably want to import in the car context as well as the use context hook so
that we can access the values.
So I'm going to first import in used context from React and then I want to import in the cart context.
So let's go up up again.
To our contacts, car contact.
And then.
I'm going to structure off.
Car items.
Which is equal to use context passing in car context.
As for the carte items, let's just make a div that will contain them and we will just map through them.
And we get the car item, and for the item, let's just return an H2 that has the item name.
Actually, no, let's display the quantity as well, because that's what we need to be modifying.
So let's be more explicit.
Let's turn back.
A div.
And inside of the div.
Well, contain the H2 that contains both the name.
As well as the actual.
Quantity.
So we needs these structure, these values off.
From the cart item.
So let's do concert.
I'd name and quantity.
From our car item.
And then for the div, we need to give the key of the ID.
So just a very simple, basic HTML structure that will show us that we are indeed getting the correct
card item now back inside of our application.
We see that we have our car items.
We have a title.
We have our quantity.
And now what we need to do is figure out if we can create some functionality that will allow us to set
the left and right values.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to first come back into our cart drop dropdown.
And into our checkout component from our checkout component.
I want to just create some left button and let's just call it something obvious like decrement.
And let's also add another one called Increment.
So what I want to do is when I click increment, I want to actually increase the quantity.
So how do we do this?
Well, what we know is that we have the cart item currently with the cart item.
I want to be able to increase the quantity of this cart item.
Otherwise, I want to decrease it.
So as we know, we already have that functionality built in, which is our add item to cart.
This ad item, toccata, the way that it works is that it looks inside and it takes a product to add.
But what are we doing with this product?
And we check to see if this ID matches the Item ID?
If it does, then we just increase the quantity on that car item.
Otherwise, we spread it through.
But the thing to keep in mind is that we will never reach this part of the code because we are always
going to make sure that this existing car exists.
Of course it does because it's already in the car item.
It's cyclical.
So for this reason, all we need to do then is just take our ad item to cart and just attach it as an
on click here.
Like so.
And then what we passed to this item to cart is just our cart item.
If we save this and now we come back, we see that it's a little bit unclear.
Let me just add this in a way where we can see it from each other.
I'm just going to add a break.
A break element, which will give us some space between the different spans.
And now if I click increment.
There we go, we see it increasing.
Exactly as it should.
So now what we have to do is do the decrement.
So my challenge to you, if you haven't already tried it out is figure out how to create this decrement
counter.
It's going to be similar to increment, but a couple of things you want to consider is that when you
decrement, you want to decrease this number.
And if you hit zero, you want to remove the item from the cart.
So try that out and let's do it together.