Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to set up our email and password sign up.
We also want to set up our email and password sign in and we're going to style these so that we can
finish off with our authentication page.
So in order for us to work on this, we need to first enable a provider that allows us to provide email
and password to sign in to our application.
Any authentication method that you add is needed as a new provider that you create inside of your authentication.
So here's what I'm going to do is create add a new provider, email and password.
I'm going to enable this email password, one that allows them to sign up using it and also for email
link password list sign.
And this one's a little bit extra.
I don't really need this one, so I only want email.
Password password is sign and you can enable, but there's a lot more configuration required.
Essentially, what happens is when they enter in an email, they submit it.
They get a link inside of an email that they'll receive for that email, which if they verify that they
own it, will take them back to the application and sign them in.
But we don't really need that.
We just want regular email password signing.
So now that we have our email password inside of our application, we need to start building out this
form.
So here's what I'm going to do inside of our components folder.
I'm going to make a new folder and I'm going to call it sign up, because that's what this is.
It's essentially our sign up form.
We can even be more explicit in calling this sign up form.
And then inside, I'm going to make the files required, sign up form dot componente dot GSX.
And then once we're inside, we're just going to create a very basic form just so that we know it works.
So it's going to be a sign up form, which is equal to a functional component that returns back.
And this is where we need to understand a little bit about him all forms.
If you're unfamiliar, we'll go through it pretty briefly, but enough that we understand what's going
on.
So what we need is we need to reflect what this forum will have.
So for our basic needs, let's say there's a divide and in the divide is just an H1 or inside it'll
say, sign up with your email and password.
And then we need a form component.
This HDMI form component is essentially something that allows you to make all these text fields inside,
do what you need them to do as far as form is required.
So this is where you can do things like, let's say with your form, you want certain fields to be required
and you don't want the form to be submitted unless they fill out those fields.
You can do that very easily using this form component because it all essentially do all of that for
you.
So let's talk about what goes into them.
So we know that for our form, we have four different inputs.
So let's create an input and let's make a label.
Inside of this label is going to be some text, and we know that these inputs, all four of them are
required.
So let's copy paste this four times and start filling them out.
The first one is going to be the display name.
The second one is going to be the email, so I'm just putting them in the label.
The third one is going to be password.
And the fourth one is going to be confirmed password.
Now inside of these inputs, because the required what will happen is the formal validate that if these
inputs are empty, then it's invalid.
It's only valid as long as there's actual text inside them and also for display name.
What are the types?
So a type is an attribute that you can give to input.
Text is the most basic one.
It just means that it takes some string.
That's all it is for email, though we can actually use a type called email.
This email type will make sure that the text inside validates in the format of an email.
Meaning that you've got some string and then you've got an add symbol.
You might have more string, you have a dot and then finally, some more string.
So pretty much the format that you always see with an email.
So that's what's great, we get this at the box.
The other great thing, too, is that if a browser does not support email, it will fall back to using
a type text.
For a password, we can also use a type password, and this will just hide all of the characters that
are being typed in.
And similarly, for confirmed password, it's also a type password.
So we have our four input fields or we also need is the ability to submit this form.
So luckily for us, React has bound a event handler called on submit, which runs some callback.
Whenever you submit the form and to submit the form, we can actually add inside the form a button child
with the type submit.
So the form will know that when this button of type submit is clicked, then run this on submit callback
and this on submit callback only runs.
If all of these validations for these inputs are passing, meaning that these four fields that are required
are filled in email is in the valid format that it's in.
And I'm just going to say this is of type.
Sign up.
And for now, let's just export default.
This sign up for.
So I just want to make sure before we actually add in all the functionality of doing all this, that
our form component works.
So I want to import in the sign up form from components.
Sign up form.
Sign up for component.
And I'm just going to put this after this button here.
So now let's save this go on trial application.
And there we go.
So I've got some auto filled auto populating fields here inside of my Chrome browser, but this is our
form.
We see it all here.
What we need to do now is bring in that functionality so that this form is actually valid.
To do that, we need to track the actual input inside of these inputs into our form component.
And if we remember from our monster's Rolodex project, we can do that using use state, which is very
similar to our search bar.
So I'm going to import you state from React.
Now, one way you can do this is you can track all four of these different inputs using four different
use state values.
But personally, I find that a little cumbersome, especially because I know this is all grouped together
anyways as something of a form field so I can actually create an object, and I'm going to call this
like form fields, for example.
So in fact, this is actually going to be our default form fields.
So this is the initialized value for these four values, which should all be empty strings.
I'm just going to show you the shape, though, of this object.
We're going to have a field called display name, which is an empty object email, which is an empty
string, sorry, empty object, empty string emails, also an empty string password, also an empty
string confirm password, as you guessed it, also an empty string.
So using this value now, what we can do is we can say that I want to use state.
And I want that value to be called form fields.
And again, the second value that we get back.
Is a center function.
Now for you state, I'm going to pass it, this default form fields value.
So this object is essentially the value for form fields.
It's not a string.
It's the object of these four exact values.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to structure off these four values.
The reason why is because we're going to use these values somewhere inside of our code.
So I'm going to confirm password and this is equal to form fields.
So what's happening is this object is being passed in as the default state for you.
State form fields is now some kind of object and destruction of the four values that I want, and then
I'm setting them as constants inside this component in case I need them.
And then what I'm going to do next is I am now going to actually figure out what happens whenever these
values change so that I can update my form fields here.
I'm going to create a function called handle change.
And this is going to be a general function that takes that input event whenever the text changes.
However, in order for us to make this function generic, there's a couple of things we need to be able
to do so by generic, I mean that we essentially want to pass this into our input as the on change handler
for every single one of our inputs.
We wanted the same.
In order for us to do this, we need to be able to identify which of these inputs is firing so that
we know which of these form fields to update inside of our state.
In order to do that, we actually need to append some more values.
So on each input, we can give it a name and the name will come through on the event.
So for our display name, we want to name them the same as the name of the actual attribute that we're
trying to update.
So here, because we're just going to be able to structure this off.
As name from the event, we're going to utilize this name to tell our set state which of these fields
to update.
So let's just update all of these different fields with the appropriate name.
Email, of course, will be email password will be password and then confirm password will be confirm
password.
So here, everything matches and lines up with these values.
The next thing that we want to do is we actually want to get the appropriate value, the value that
gets typed in should be the value that in turn we actually display in the input sonar for just do this,
we need to pass in the value here.
So for the value of this specific field, we're going to use the appropriate value that we've pulled
off of our form fields.
So the direction is pretty circular.
When you pass a value, you're actually saying, Hey, the value I want inside of this input should
be the value in passing you.
So if I pass the string ABC, then the value should be ABC.
Let's just save this and we'll see.
Here, let's refresh.
You'll notice that here you actually see display name ABC.
So that's what value represents.
And the reason we do this is so that our changes are circular, meaning that what happens is that the
value from the state is the value that's shown in the input.
But when the user types those values in while are on change, trigger effectively pushes that form field
into our state.
And then again, our state will now actually update the visual here.
So the visual aspect of what the user sees in the form field is not determined by the input, but it's
actually determined by our value.
This way, we can control what those fields are and what we're doing with them through our state itself.
I know that sounds a little confusing, but once you put it in and you follow on track, you'll see
what I'm talking about.
So here I want value to be display name.
Of course, I want this next one for email to be.
Email.
And then I want value for password to be password, and then I want value for confirm password to be
confirmed.
Password.
So in order for us to now appropriately trigger, we can now say, hey, give me the value as well off
the event because these will now come in through the event object.
And then all we need to do now is just, say, set form fields and what we're going to set.
It is an object because we're only going to be updating one input.
All I want to do is I want only to update the appropriate form field.
So all the other fields that were previously on the state, I want them to be spread on.
So this will spread all of the fields and then we're just going to update the appropriate field by using
these square brackets inside of our object notation.
So this says, Oh, take this value and apply it here from this variable of name and the value will
be the value.
Oh, you know what, I also noticed a quick error here.
We need to make sure that we're actually calling events target.
The target is actually going to give us the thing that is emitting the event and the thing in this particular
case is the input.
So the target here will give us all of the things that are attached to this input.
That's what's on the target, not just the event.
So here we have our set form fields called and let's also console.log out form fields.
So let's save this.
Let's go back to our application.
That's refresh.
And here we see this is our initial empty state default state, far form fields.
And as we start typing, we see that our object is updating appropriately.
Let's do password.
Here we see they're hidden, but inside of our password, we see that we are indeed actually storing
it.
And then for email, let's just say they're at Gmail.
There we go.
Everything's working.
So all of this code is working as expected.
I definitely want to apologize for the length of this video.
I know it's rather long.
But as you can see, there was a lot of things that we needed to set up just to get the farm working
as we need to inside of this component.
The key thing here is that we learned a new pattern with you state.
We learned about setting an object, but only when that object is always going to be tied together to
some specific logic.
The main reason for using this object was so that we could generate size.
This handle change and primarily what we're trying to do is that we want to spread in this object and
then modify one value on this object.
And we knew this worked because all of these form fields are essentially duplicated versions of the
same state.
Their only difference is which of these inputs are being targeted inside of this object.
So this pattern only works when you can janiero size and find that common ground between the logic that
you need for these states.
And in this case, with the form, these inputs are the best example of that.
Now that we have learned how to set up this field, let's actually submit it and finish off the authentication
here.
Let's do that in the next video.