All right, it's time to talk about the very last point, the service worker to make our progressive
Web app.
What is a service worker sounds like something useful, doesn't it?
Service worker is a script that your browser runs in the background, separate from the Web page webapp.
It is generally used for features that don't need a Web page or user interaction.
Remember the main thread that I kept talking about, how there's one worker that's trying to work with
a small CSFs in JavaScript?
Well, think of service worker as another worker that you now have in the browser, a background worker.
And it acts as what we call a programmable proxy, allowing us to control what happens on a request
by request basis.
And it's the reason that we can make our apps, our progressive Web apps, work offline.
Hmm.
That sounds pretty interesting, right?
Now, service workers have been recently added into browsers including Safari, and besides offline
experiences, it also helps with background sinks and push notifications.
But we're only going to talk about how service worker allows for offline experiences because that's
its main feature.
And things such as background, sink and push notifications are still fairly new and best practices
are still forming around them.
I'll leave resources for you to explore this further if you're interested in those topics.
But for now, let's get back to the most important part, how do we use a service worker?
Well, if we go back to our career racked up.
You might remember that we created within our Creative React app what we don't really created.
It created it for us this file called Register Service Worker and we go to index jobs.
Were you remember that in our.
Main app that we render, we had our react dom render, but also we had this function register service
worker that I kind of brushed it off up until now.
This register service worker gets imported from, yeah, you guessed it, our register service worker
file and as you go through this file, it can look pretty overwhelming.
But they have great comics to show you what it does.
But let me show you the gist of it and what this entire file is doing, it's a lot simpler than you
think.
Let's open up a new tab here and open up our console.
This is what the register service worker is doing that's a little too big.
Let's see if that works.
It checks for browser support of service worker.
So it's saying, hey, do we actually have a service worker in our navigator or our browser?
And remember, each browser has its own developer teams and each browser can decide to implement this
new feature called Service Worker or Not.
There's actually a really good website called Is Service Worker Ready?
That I'll link to where you can see which versions of the browsers have implemented service workers.
If we go back, we do this check because we want to make sure that when we do navigator a service worker,
we don't get an error saying we don't know about service worker.
What are you talking about?
So we say if there is a service worker, we want to use this service worker property of the Navigator
that is the browser, and we want to do something called register and we want to register it using this
file, the service worker dot js file and registering is just the common way for you to create a service
worker on your webpage.
Now, where is this service worker jobs coming from?
If we go back to our.
This service worker, James, is getting created from this file in our build folder when we run AMPM,
run, build and create react.
We see that we now have a service worker dot js file and it's minified.
So it's really, really hard to read.
But all it's doing is running the default registration of the service worker that you can pretty much
grab anywhere online.
And that's it.
It's literally just one single line, you see that it's a promise that returns the registration and
we can just log out some properties on it.
But there's a successful registration.
And if it fails, well, it fails.
And we can say, oops, service worker registration fails.
With just this statement, we check if the browser has service worker and if it does, we just simply
run the register function.
Fairly simple.
Now, registering the service worker is going to cause the browser to start the service worker install,
step in the background again with the other worker.
And once a service worker is activated and registered this successful case, it's going to be in one
of two states, it's either going to be terminated to save memory or it's going to be running in the
background to fetch messages and events that occurs in the network request.
Now, what does that mean?
Before I get to that, let's go back to our application.
Let me make this smaller, go to the application tab.
And you'll see here that we have below manifest the service worker tab.
And we see that service worker right now, there's nothing here, but if I go to our demo app that is
a progressive Web app and I click on service workers.
We see that, oh, there's something here, it looks like there's a service worker that has been registered
from service worker.
It shows us when it was registered and the status.
And right now, it's stopped because while we're not doing anything with the speech, we can register
on, register the service worker if we want.
But it looks like on this Web page, we have this service worker running, let me show you a diagram
to illustrate to you what this all means and why we care.
You see, without a service worker, our browser is going to send a request to the network, this little
icon, you can think of it as the Internet network.
We send our request, we find the server and the server responds back with some files, let's say a
JavaScript file.
But now that we have a service worker registered, we tell the browser, hey, before you go ahead and
do this, talk to the service worker first.
Maybe he knows something you see in a progressive Web app, the service worker acts as what we call
a network proxy.
It intercepts any requests made first to the network, like I said, step one over here.
And checks to see if you really need to communicate with the network, because maybe he already has
those files, when a user opens a new screen of a progressive Web app, the request for that page first
goes to the service worker, not the network.
The service worker then tries to access something called the Cache API.
And this is something that the browser's gave you again, most browsers have this because they included
this feature with service worker in this cache API is kind of like a box where the browser stores files
such as JavaScript files, CSFs files, any static files.
It could be Imagists.
It could be anything you want.
The worker tries to access check the box and see is whatever I'm requesting inside of this box, if
the content is available, then we'll get the new page through here and the service worker is going
to return the page regardless of the network activity.
We're never requesting to the network.
But if the service worker comes back and says, Mr. Browsr, I don't have the file that you requested,
you're going to have to talk to the network.
Then we go back to talking to the network the old way that we did things and getting those files.
Now, what does this cache storage API again, if we go back to our example.
And scroll down to cash, we have something called cash storage.
And this cash storage is exactly what the service worker checks, if I click over here, we see that,
oh yeah, we have a cash.
Of a few JavaScript files and also some HTML.
If I go to the other one, I see some icons that are also and some lists that are also.
Being cashed.
Very cool.
So we cash the website or the shell of the website, remember, whatever we wanted to.
We want to work offline in this cash storage API via the service worker.
So that on repeat visits, even though the very first time the user browses and goes to a website,
you'll have to go to the network because this cache API will be empty once the network returns.
With those files, we can cache those files.
And on repeat visits, the app Shell can be loaded instantly.
All right, stop talking.
Andre, show me how we can actually do this.
Show me some code.
Well, you're in luck.
In the next few videos, we're going to go through the steps and finally turn our app into a progressive
web app.
Before I do that again, I just want to show you how things work underneath the hood.
If we go back to our Korea reactor, I wanted to show you how this would work before Korea react up
implemented service workers, because right now it's kind of being done behind the scenes for you,
which is really, really nice.
But what if you had to implement it on your own?
It's actually quite easy and you can look at this page that I'm going to link to to show you what you
would have done.
If you go over here, we see that all we needed to do was download something called service worker Prakash.
And in our built step where we say Riak scripts build, we would just run this command, the service
worker Prakash, with config of this file, kind of similar to how Watpac config worked.
So we give it this configuration file in our indexed HTML.
We do the classic if service worker exists and the browser, we're going to register the service worker.
We have our manifest file that we had and then finally with this package that we installed as W Prakash,
well, here all we're doing is setting up the config, telling it that we want to use the built folder.
And I want you to put in the cache any file that's an e-mail file and any JSON files or manifest JSON
file and anything in the static folder.
And we're going to use the service worker, DOT James Forbath.
That's it.
And if you remember in the static folder for a react app.
We have our success, JavaScript and some media files.
How simple is that?
Very, very cool.
Again, remember, we're just using the tools that browsers provide for us to make our websites faster.
That's it for now.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.