Let's talk about reduce.
Now, reduce is probably the trickiest of all array methods, so it's OK if it seems really overwhelming
as we're going through it, but I promise you that once it clicks, it will make total sense.
And it's actually one of the most useful methods that we have in our repertoire as JavaScript developers.
So in order to understand it, let's go into our browser.
Let's say I had some ouray.
Which was equal to one, two, three, four, five.
Let's say I wanted to add all the values inside of my array, how would I do this?
Well, we could write a for loop, right, where we add all the values together and end up with some
final value.
Or this is actually the perfect time to use reduce, reduce is a great array method to use when we want
to do two things.
The first is that we want to end up with one value in the end.
Right.
Not an array, but some value in the end.
The second is when we want to persist, the return or the outcome of iterating over our elements in
each subsequent iteration.
Now, what do I mean by that?
That's a mouthful, right?
Well, let's take a look at how the code actually looks and then maybe it'll be better for us to understand.
Let's say I call or reduce a radar reduce takes two arguments, the last argument we won't focus on
for now, let's just focus on the first argument.
The first argument is a function.
And that function has two parameters, the second parameter is the element itself, so it's the current
element that we're on that we're iterating over.
The first one is what's called the accumulator, right, the accumulator is exactly as it sounds, it's
the accumulated value of calling this function on every element before the one that we're currently
on.
So what we would do if we wanted to add all these numbers together is if we said accumulator plus our
current element.
And what we would pass to our second argument is zero.
Now, you might be wondering, well, what's the first value that accumulator has when we start at the
first element?
Well, that's actually what the second argument is.
And that's why we passed zero, because we want to add all of these values together.
We want to start from zero.
And if we call this.
Oh, I think I have an extra bracket by accident.
We will get 15 now, let's walk through how this works, so the first time this function gets called
accumulator is zero one and one is the current element.
So it'll be zero plus one.
Right.
Which gives us a value of one.
Then it moves on to the next element.
And here Accumulator will get the return of our last function call on this element, which is one.
So accumulator is one current element is two and will get one plus two, which equals three, right.
So three gets passes accumulator in the next element when this function is called.
And we'll get three for accumulator and three for current element.
So we get three plus three, which is six, which then gets passed as the accumulator for the next element,
which is four.
So accumulator of six, current element of four, six plus four equals ten.
And then finally one more time on five or 10 is the accumulator.
The current element is five and that's how we end up with a value of 15.
And this is how the reduced function works.
Now, you don't necessarily have to start with zero, right?
We only did this because the purpose of what we were trying to achieve was to add all the values together
right in our array.
But if we wanted all this second argument symbolizes is the first accumulator value when we get called
on the first element.
So if I said that this was 10.
What happens is that 10 years passes the accumulator when this function first gets called on one, so
it's 10 current element is one ten plus one is 11, which gets then passed as the accumulator, when
we call it on to 11, current element is to eleven plus to 13 and so on and so forth for each subsequent
element until we end up with twenty five.
So this is how we write reduce now, there's a lot more complicated ways that we can use reduce, but
the basics, the fundamentals of how reduce works is in what we just wrote.
It's OK if you don't grab it all right away, it's a lot, and it's always one of the trickier parts
of understanding this specific Ouray method.
Now, we will definitely encounter more opportunities to use reduce throughout our course.
But right now, I want you to just maybe play around with some of this array that we already have.
Right.
Play around with some of the numbers so that you get a familiar feel for it.
But in the future, when we encounter opportunities to use produce, we'll definitely slow down and
take a look at how we're writing our code so we can better understand how to write, reduce and when
it's actually a good solution.
But understanding, reduce and knowing when to use it will be a very powerful tool in our careers as
JavaScript developers.