Welcome back, everyone.
In the last video, we migrated our category store over to using TypeScript.
In this video, we're going to do it for our carts because it is the next simplest set of data to work
with.
To begin with, we're going to start with our car types and as always, we are going to migrate this
file over to its file.
What we now need to do is we need to first convert this over to an inner.
So we're going to replace content with Enum.
Get rid of the equal sign and then every one of these colons is going to be an equal sign.
Now that we have our collection types, we want to think about if there are any other specific heart
types that we need to define.
We can get a good idea of this inside of the cart reducer.
As we can see, we are storing car items in an array.
Car items is a specific set of data in an array.
But what is that data?
Well, if we remember inside of car actions, our car item is the first time where we actually create
this actual car item.
And what it is, is all of the properties of the product that we're adding in, plus a quantity value,
which is a number.
So what is product to add?
What product to add is a category item.
So what we know is that our car item is just a category item with an additional quantity.
And what we can do in order to make our lives easier is we can actually bring in the category item.
From our categories.
So let's go up to categories.
Category types.
Now, if you think about the category item, it has all these properties we want, but it just missing
the quantity.
So here we can make an intersection type of item which is equal to category item, plus this additional
quantity field that we're looking for, which is a number.
And now it's very simple.
If category item ever changes, our item will similarly change as long as quantity is the only field
we want to spend to our items.
The great thing about this is because the way our code is set up as well, we are spreading through
these fields anyways.
So as long as all of these values stay the same, essentially our types of code type is also inferring
the same pattern of spreading through the category item to create the actual cart item.
So now that we have this car item type, what we want to do is we want to start typing the appropriate
actions.
So first we are going to change our cart action from Ajax file to its file and inside.
What we need to do is we need to bring in the appropriate width matcher.
Similarly, we know we need a few types.
We know we need our cart item, but we also need that category item because as you remember right here,
a product to add.
Well, this is a category item.
As for cart items, this is an array.
Of course, items.
And what does the car item give you back?
Well, if you remember, it is going to give us back an array of car items, regardless of which of
these returns it is.
So here we can just say, give us back a car item array.
This is our helper function that we've typed.
This doesn't need the width matcher because it doesn't actually generate an action, but we do use it
inside of our actual action creators.
So let's type these first.
Now, similarly, this remove car item is very similar as well.
It's an array of car items as well as a cart item.
Unlike before remove cart item gets called on only car items.
And now this existing car item.
Here we see check if quantity is equal to one.
But if you hover over it, it could possibly be undefined.
There is a high chance that when we do this find we don't find a matching car item, which is what our
coat checks to do.
Of course, in this particular case, when you check on this quantity value inside of JavaScript, JavaScript
will give you back undefined if there is no existing card item.
But for us this is not good.
We need to actually modify this code so that it works.
And all we can do is just say if there is an existing card item, then check the quantity.
Otherwise, don't run this part.
And now we've resolved our actual type issue.
And in this particular case, it actually helped us, because now our code is less prone to error.
So what we can do now is we can just make sure that we also type the return value for this function
as the cart item array.
Finally we have our clear car item again.
We have an array of car items.
And we have a cart item that is trying to be removed.
Once again, we were turning back an array of items.
So there we go.
We have now typed out all of our utility functions.
What we want to do next is we want to define each of our actions as a type.
So here first, I'm going to say export type set is cart open.
And this is going to be equal to some action with payload.
So actually, first, let's bring that in.
We need to bring in the appropriate action types as well, which we did not bring in.
We need our action as well as action with payload.
So first set card open.
It is an action with payload that receives card action type.
Dot set his car open.
With some boolean value as the payload.
Next we need to think about these three actions.
Add item to cart.
Remove item from cart and clear item from cart.
Each of these, while being a different action creator, actually does in the end create the exact same
set cart items action.
So technically, these three are different functions that manufacture the same type of action.
And here we're just defining the type of action.
And this type of action is our set cart items action.
And this is also an action with payload.
The car action types is set car items, but the actual payload value is going to be an array of cart
items.
So this is what's really useful about typing.
You can actually see some of the optimizations you can make.
So of course set is cart open this we can turn into a matcher first.
We receive a boolean value.
And we output a set is open.
Action object.
As for these other three, we need to first create this set cart items.
Action Creator.
Export const set cart items.
Is equal to with matcher.
We receive cart items which is an array.
I'll cart items.
It's the type.
We output.
Are set cart items.
Action.
And the definition is that we create an action.
With cart action types.
Dot set items.
Passing cart items.
As the actual payload.
As for these other three now, instead, we can simply replace this with set cart items.
Passing in new cart items like soap.
Then we just need to type these card items as part item.
Like so.
And product to add, of course, is a category item, but then cart items to remove is also a cart item.
Just like item two.
Clear.
And there we go.
That is our new updated code.
So now all we need to import in to our reducer is these two matters in order to determine what the new
order is.
So I want you to try that.
I want you to take what we've just made, go into the reducer and update it to the new pattern that
we use with our matches.
So once you've tried that, we'll do it together in the next video.
I'll see you there.