Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to dive into the meat of the actual real code finally.
So what we're going to do as we're looking at the app file.
As I mentioned, the app DXC file, if you think back to our Index Dogs Farm, we were importing app
from this app file.
So app here is actually the App Dogs and what App Dogs is that represents our entire React application.
So we're going to dive deep into how this one file doesn't actually contain the entire application as
we build it.
It's just that right now this is the main bulk of what the application represents because the application
is very simple.
It's really much just this part of the website.
So if you look at it, all it is with react is that we are importing the logo, which is the logo to
SVG, and we are also importing our Abduct CSV file.
So this is also generated for us and it's what makes the logo spin and gives the background color and
then makes these the certain sizes that they are.
That's all the CSS that's listed in here.
So by importing it, we're saying, Oh, I want you to apply this.
Yes.
So that's being applied to this website now.
Here you'll notice that there is this function, and this is very important because in React React is
pretty much just using functions to return the amount.
That's all it is.
This code is just some generic function called app that returns you.
This specific HTML that represents this function of app, and you can see this app function as a component.
So what is a component?
A component is pretty much a self-contained piece of code that returns some visual UI representation
of HTML UI being this thing that we can see and interact with.
Now, as we know with websites, anything we interact with is a combination of HMRC, RSS and JavaScript.
So this is no different here.
It's just that all of this is contained within this function.
So inside of here, if you look at this, this is pretty much just basic HMO.
We have a div, we have a header, we have an image and this image is being passed the source of our
logo.
So our logo as which is just this icon that is spinning.
And this image is being rendered inside of this header HDMI component.
And then there are some p tag here with some text inside, and then there's an anchor tag that points
to learn react very simple HTML and this function is essentially returning this demo.
So that's really all that's happening is that inside of index, Jess React is just saying, Oh, I want
you to render this app, and here this looks like an HDMI tag.
And the reason for that is because using React Dom were saying, Oh OK, this HTML tag is some function
code that will return us more.
Him, which is exactly what app JS is, it's returning us HD marker.
So what we're looking at here is really just the HTML that's being rendered on the page.
And if we update this, let's say I update this tag to say hello, my name is Yehovah.
If I save this now, if I go back here again, create racked up is just rebuilding and it is updating
this text now to say Hello, my name is e.y.
You saw it's pretty automatic, but here what we're just seeing is that that's really all react is really
it's just code, so a function or a class, which we'll learn about later, that returns us back.
HTML.
That's really all react is if you really want to think about the very barebones of React, it's just
these helper functions that help us return HTML.
So it allows us to build websites and these UI in a very efficient componentes way components once again
being the self-contained representations of HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
So this is really all that's happening here.
So with that, you pretty much understand actually all that React app has given us some of the more
nuanced things that go on, such as tests and the progressive web app stuff.
We'll explain later, but as far as the main bulk of what we're going to work on when we start converting
this create racked up application over to the Monster Rolodex project is just going to be around writing
these functions are these classes that return us back each demo, and that's all it is.
So now that you understand what create React app does?
There is one caveat I must mention before moving forward.
So a lot of the videos were done using an older version of Create React app.
Right now, I'm actually speaking to you in the present with the latest version of Create racked up.
So when you go through, you'll notice that some of these files are slightly different, but honestly,
it's so insignificant it's pretty much all the exact same.
It's just that a couple of things have been tweaked and the placements are a little different.
But all the concepts you learn and everything that you see is going to largely remain the same.
So definitely don't get scared if you see it.
Just understand that all the core concepts that you have are already now fully explained as to what
create React app is doing.
The older versions are doing the exact same thing.
It's just that create React app and Facebook like to change the way that they build things every once
in a while.
Not necessarily because it's more optimized, but sometimes just because they want to introduce some
things or remove some things.
But nothing is that significant.
99 percent of everything is largely the exact same.
So now that you understand this, let's start actually building out our monster's Rolodex project and
getting really into the meat of our React application.
So before we start doing that, once again, Andre is going to just quickly dive into why you should
not eject by showing you what happens when you eject.
Once again, this is just a better understanding of what it is that our code is doing.
But here again, you understand that all react is is just functions that return a demo.
That's really all it is.
So with that, let's move to the next video.