Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are trying to build in the decrement, so for decrement, let's go into our to context
as we know if this is where we did our ad item, we're probably going to do a similar remove item here
as well.
So what I want to do is I want to make another method called remove item from cart.
And this is going to be a function that we need to figure out.
So remove item from cart is probably going to be very similar to how we set up our ad item to cart.
So here let's just duplicate our method call it remove item to cart.
And what we're going to receive is the product to remove.
We know that we're most likely going to want to get this product because with this product, will we
actually delete the cart item?
So here, instead of even calling a product to remove, we know that most likely it's going to be a
cart item in the first place, so we can even be more explicit instead of calling a product to remove.
We can't call it cart item to remove.
So now what we need to do is we know we are updating our items.
But instead of calling this add item method, we probably want to create another helper.
So let's think about what we want this to do.
So I'm going to call it remove cart item like so we know that we want to get the original cart items
away because we're going to use this array to create a new array where we've either increased the quantity
of one of these cart items or we've removed an item entirely if the previous quantity was at one.
The next thing that we know we need is the cart item to remove.
And now what we need beyond this is let's think about the functionality.
Inside of our car items, we know that we're removing a car item that already exists, so we need to
find the car item to remove.
We need to find the one that already exists inside of our right.
And then what we need to do is we need to check if quantity is equal to one.
If it is, remove that item from the car.
That much is.
The logic that we've described.
If it isn't, then what we do is return back carte items with matching cart item with reduced quantity.
That much also makes sense.
So let's figure out what we need to do here.
Well, first, we need to find the existing cart item.
So what we can do is we can actually take this method over that does exactly this, except instead of
using the product to add, we're going to use our new cart item to remove.
They're both going to be the same shape and have the same I.D..
Next, what we need to do is we need to now check if the quantity of this item is equal to one.
Now if it is equal to one, then what we need to do is we need to remove this from a new set of cart
items.
So to do that, let's use the filter method.
As we know, Filter gives us back a new array where the array is going to have removed whatever matches.
So here I'm going to say that.
If existing cart item dot quantity is equal to one.
Then just return back carte items don't filter.
And what we're going to do is get a cart item and just say if the cart item ID does not equal cart item
to remove it.
So if this seems a little bit unintuitive, the reason why is because we're saying, Hey, I want you
to filter out anything here that equals false.
So what this means is that if this statement evaluates true, then keep the value.
So we're saying if the Item ID does not equal the one we're trying to remove, keep the value that makes
perfect sense.
We only want to remove the value where the car item ID is equal to the one we try to remove.
So that's how filter kind of works in reverse here.
Or at least it seems a little unintuitive way that we've written it.
But now, once we have removed out when quantity is one, then all that's left to do is pretty much
just duplicate what we had here.
And all we can do is really just copy this over.
And all we need to do differently is instead of incrementing quantity, we decrement the quantity.
And of course, we use car item to remove instead of product to add.
So if you look at it, we're just mapping through all of our car items and we're saying, Hey, if your
I.D. matches the one we're trying to remove.
Give us a new object with the same card item properties, except the quantity has been reduced by one.
Some of you might be wondering, why is it that we're always creating a new object?
Remember that with React, the only way that a React component, which in our case is going to be either
this new checkout item that we haven't made or even the car items that we have made.
What do they receive?
They receive an individual cart item as the actual prop value that they have.
Let's look at it.
Let's look at this component.
We receive a cart item as the object and off this object.
Do we render the UI if we get back the same object with the value mutated?
React doesn't register that this cart item is different, so it's not going to re render the component
where as because we are generating a new object.
When Rick receives that object, it is going to say, Oh, this prop is different, then I can re render
the UI and in turn reflect the new reduced quantity or the new increased quantity.
This all has to do with reacts rendering.
So now all we need to do is, again, just replace our.
Method here inside of remove items of cards and then pass this through as an argument.
We can now include this inside of our appropriate.
Check out component.
And let's just also.
Abstract this off.
And then we can simply add an on click here.
Where we call or remove item with the item.
Let's save this.
Let's come back here.
And because we've rendered we need to re add items to our cart.
Let's come back.
Let's go to the checkout.
Let's make sure it works.
We decrement.
Look, it's working.
We also see it reflected inside of our cart because everything is tied together.
And now if I decrement one more time, I remove the item entirely.
I continued, recommending, I've removed all the items.
There we go.
We've added in our functionality.
So now what I want to do is I want to style out this component so that it looks closer to our actual
final checkout page.
So how do we do this?
Well, let's figure this out in the next video.