Hey, welcome back.
I just want to add a quick note here, I've actually ejected a create react app just to show you what
happens.
You'll see here that it gives me a folder called Scripts and then a folder called Config.
And in here, well, this was everything that the creator racked up was hiding underneath the hood for
us.
You had things like just that was using for tests.
We have our Web configuration.
Remember our module bundler.
You can see over here how long and intense and complicated it looks.
We also have all the scripts that were run, for example, when we ran NPM Rumbold or NPM Run, start
or test, you see over here that it's quite a lot of code.
This is why I recommend not ejecting, because no matter what, no matter how much time you spend with
react, you never going to compete with the developers that are working full time trying to make, create,
react, have the best tool possible developers that are getting paid to make this tool as easy and as
efficient for you.
So I recommend that you never eject out of a reactor unless you absolutely have to, because by using
create react app, we automatically get the best system and project build out of the box.
And any time there are updates or the industry changes and there's new ways of doing things, create
react app is automatically, well, going to have a new version that has those changes implemented by
professionals.
So again, I wanted to show you that this is what's happening underneath the hood, but ninety nine
point nine percent of the time, you don't really need to eject because you lose all the benefits as
a reactor gets more and more updates.
I'll see in the next one, bye bye.