Now, I know that Create React app already comes with just and other testing tools pre-installed.
But I think it's important for us to understand how it works so that we can also build something like
Create React app ourselves.
So I'm going to start from scratch and set up a few testing examples for you.
Now, just here has great documentation once again with any library.
You go through their guide and they provide a lot of info.
So let's get started by installing just or first of all, let's create a project folder.
I'm going to create a project folder called Test, and we'll just go into that folder and run our usual
p.m. in it.
That's why to create an AMPM package.
And we also want to create a script dot just file.
And let's open that up and our favorite text editor.
Looking nice and pretty perfect.
Now let's look at package that Jason, and obviously the first step we want to do is run npm install
just.
And actually, let me cancel this.
Remember, that just is for development purposes.
We don't really need it as a dependency for our app.
So usually when you install just you want to do ampm install.
Dash Dash saved death.
Oops!
Let's try that again, just and remember that with the newer version of p.m..
When you do p.m. installed, just it assumes the Dash Dash save as a dev or as a dependency.
So that's why I didn't do the Dash Dash save here.
Now, while this is loading, let's go into our scripts.
And change this to the test command.
And all we need to do here is run.
Just once it's installed.
Not sure what happened here, it looks like a bit of a narrow let's just close this out and run it again.
Now while that's loading, let's go into our scripts file and think about what exercise we might want
to incorporate.
And I think having us incorporate a simple Google search functionality might be a fun little exercise.
So let's do that.
It looks like everything was added.
So let's just hit clear make this a little bit smaller.
And again, if we go to Pakistan JSON, we see that it's part of the dev dependencies, not the dependencies,
but dev.
Because we did because we did the dash dash that safe or dash safe dev.
And the script I just file, let's say that we're Google and we have a variable.
This is going to be a simplified version of their search algorithm, but the principles are going to
be the same.
So let's say that the Google database has an array of all the websites that they've indexed.
Let's say the first one is cats dot com.
Obviously, it's the internet, after all.
We also have soup recipes dot com.
Everybody loves soup.
We have flowers.
Dot com.
And let's just add one more will say that we also have animals dot com pretty basic web sites, and
these are all the website that Google can search for you.
Obviously, in real life, this list might be a little bit bigger.
All right.
So there is our Google database, and you know what?
While we're at it, just add a few more cat pictures dot.
And.
Maybe my favorite.
Cats.
All right.
And I've added these last two because, hmm, maybe if somebody searches for cats in the Google Chrome
browser, well, we might want to show them these three links.
Again, let's create a function and this will just be the Google search function.
And this function will take the search.
Input.
That the user provides.
So whatever they're searching for.
And from there, it does a few things.
First, we want to say.
It's going to be a very simple algorithm.
Obviously, this can be this is way more complicated on Google, but the idea is we search something
and if there is some sort of a match, we want to return it.
Let's just say that the.
Google database is going to get filtered.
And using the filter function, we'll say that each item in the database is a website that is going
to get filtered.
And all we need to do is return the website.
That includes.
So this is.
Let's say cats rt.com.
If it includes whatever the search input was.
Like I said, very, very nice and basic.
Google search algorithm.
And we also want to return these matches to the user, because while that's what Google does, but let's
say that we want to make sure because hypothetically, this database can get really, really big, we
want to only return the top three results so we can just say, OK, let me make sure I spell that right.
First, we want to say if this dot length.
Is greater than three, if we have more than three matches, then we'll just say matches that slice.
And just returned the first three results.
Otherwise just returned the regular matches.
Let's make this smaller, so we can see.
All right, let's test this out and see if it actually works.
I'm going to run the.
Google search function.
And let's say that the search input that I'm going to put in will be.
Soup.
And let's just canceled our log this to make sure that whatever the output is while we log it into our
terminal.
Let me save.
And again with Node, we can just run this node script dot J.S..
All right.
Look at that.
I have soup recipes.
If this changes to cats.
I get Cars.com and my favorite cat sitcom, but not cat pictures rt.com, because it doesn't match cats.
If we add another website here, let's call it my favorite cats to.
And I only search for Cat.
Oh, and make sure I add a comma.
Always forget the comma, let me clear this and try that again.
All right.
I only get one, two and three results because we're doing this little slice.
We're only returning the top three results.
Awesome.
We've just implemented Google on a simpler scale, but mind you, this is pretty much how Google works.
All right, so that was fun.
But how can we test this?
Let's say we were a Google, and we want to make sure that this Google search function works properly
because it's an important function for our app since we have just installed.
Let's run AMPM test and see what happens.
AMPM test.
Hmm.
It just says no tests found because we haven't written any tests.
But you can see over here that just automatically looks for anything that has either a folder that has
the underscore under score tests and anything inside of it, or it's going to look at any file that
has the spec or the test dot just syntax.
By that logic, I can just create a new file script.
Test dodges or I can put spec in here, which is also common, and I hit enter.
And if I run this again.
I get a feel.
It says your test suite must contain at least one test.
All right.
Let's clear this.
So how can you write a test for our Google search and we'll get to that in the next video?
But just to make sure that our test passes, I'll just show you one quick way that we can write unit
tests and just.
And that is we have now an IT function and the first parameter of the ID function.
And again, this comes with jest.
But if you download other testing libraries, pretty much all of them have this function as well.
Like I said, all these libraries have a very similar syntax.
So if you know one, you can transition into the other quite easily with a few minor changes.
So the first parameter in here is some sort of a string that will appear here.
So let's just say this is a test.
And then the second parameter is a function.
Which is the test that needs to run in our case, we don't really have anything, but let's save this
Enron and PM test.
Whoa, look at that.
We have our very first test.
That was pretty easy, right?
All we did was p.m. installed just and we already have this new ID function and we can run tests and
we see that this is a test passed in one millisecond.
That's a pretty fast test.
Everything is green and nice kind of feels good.
You see a nice boost of dopamine.
All right.
In the next video, we're actually going to start writing some tests for our Google search.
I'll see in the next one.