Welcome back, everyone.
In the last video, I challenge you to utilize our new matcher action creators inside of your cart reducer.
So there is a little bit of difference in how we do it inside of this code and how we do it inside of
our category reducer.
To begin with, we need to import in all of the appropriate files.
So first we need to import in any action from Redux because that is going to be the type that we receive
for our action.
And we also need to import in the respective action creators.
So here, let's just go into cart action and let's bring in our set items as well as set is cart open.
The first thing we want to do is we want to type the actual cart state.
So here we'll say export type cart state, which is equal to is cart open, which is a Boolean value.
And then cart items is an array of cart items.
So we need to bring in our cart item type.
Like so.
And now we can set this initial value over to our current state.
And what we want to do next is we want to also update this action.
So one thing that we were doing before is that we were setting this action equal to an empty object
because sometimes we might get these reducers called and they may not receive the full action.
So we assumed that this might be an empty object by default, so that we can structure something or
attempt to so that we don't get errors.
But in our new patterns, we don't actually use this structuring anymore.
So we actually don't even need this equals we can just go directly.
Action is equal to any action.
And now we know that we will also always return a cart state from our reducer and then we just need
to update our switch cases.
So first we just say if our set cart items.
Well, actually, let's start with his car open.
If this matches the action.
Then we know that we can simply.
Update the is card open.
Actually I copied over the wrong one.
Let's update this like so.
And then just fix up.
Like.
So of course we don't have a payload structure.
But again, because of our type predicate function, well, notice that our action is definitely going
to be set is car open and our payload is definitely going to be a boolean.
The next one that we need is our set items match on the action.
And similarly, we will return.
The appropriate state updates car items, points to action payload and then by default we return the
state.
And that's it.
That's all we need here.
We can just remove our action types, and now our cart reducer is also typed.
It's much simpler now because again, we've already done this before.
The first time we did this with our categories, it took significantly longer because we had to go through
all of the learning of how to make these matters and setting this up for the first time.
But once you get those repetitions in, it just gets much easier.
And here as well, as I mentioned, we no longer need this equals we can just set this equal to any
action.
Now, one more thing to type for our cart is our selector.
So let's update this to teach us.
And as I mentioned before, we can't type the state yet because again, we don't have all of our reducers
typed.
And unless we have them all typed, we actually can't type the reducer which will give us the value
for this state type.
Instead, we just need to type what we can.
So here inside of our select cart, we know that what we're going to get back from select cart reducer
is the cart state.
So all we do is import in cart state and set it to the output it value from here.
And now automatically what we notice is that everything else gives us what we want it to give.
So select cart count, of course, returns a number select is cart open returns a boolean select car
total returns a number.
All of these are now intuitive enough to know based on the inference of the actual top level cart state,
what all of the subsequent values are.
So this is a very, very powerful thing that comes with our selectors as well as TypeScript due to the
natural inference because we've typed what this initial entry reducer gives back, which is the cart
state, all of the subsequent derivations are going to be automatically inferred if you reduce over
cart items and we know that this is a number, then automatically cart item we're using the quantity,
which is a number you can only get back from this, reduce a number.
That's the power of this technology with TypeScript and these inference engines that come with the code
so easy, it makes our lives so much easier.
If you want, you can type them so that it's more explicit and you can see it.
But a lot of times I like referring simply to use the actual inference engine so that it makes my life
easier and I don't have to type as much, but I still get all the benefits of TypeScript.
Now, one thing I do want to mention is that when you switched over from dot jars to dots or even touch
ASX two dot TSX, if you were using a import where you were referencing the path of a value for one
of these files where you explicitly had said Dot Jazz, what will happen is that now you'll notice that
this import will fail because we no longer have car action.
Yes, this is now a car action, dots.
This is why it's important for you not to include the actual end of the file extension when doing these
conversions.
We rely essentially on Webpack and Babel to transport our code down and know the correct endings and
infer the type of file from that.
Again, we'll discuss that later in the Webpack babble section.
But for now, if you're noticing that you're not actually able to finish any of your imports as you
go through this process of migrating your files over to TypeScript, this is an important thing to keep
in mind.
So now that we've finished up with our cart store, let's move on to our user store.
So try that yourself.
You'll probably have to also type the Firebase utils, but just give it a try.
And in the next video, we'll do it together.
I'll see you in the next video.