In order to understand how dynamic programming works, we need to understand what caching means.
Caching is a way to store values so you can use them later on.
Ideally, you can think of caching as a backpack they take to school.
Instead of going all the way home, when you need something like a pencil, you have a small box on
your back that holds items that you need so that when you go to school, you can just reuse them fast
over and over.
Now, that's a bit of a silly example.
Caching is just a way for us to speed up programs and hold some piece of data in an easily accessible
box.
And memorization is a specific form of caching that we're going to be talking about because we use it
a lot in dynamic programming.
But instead of just talking about it, let's actually demonstrate it in code.
The way we can cash things, well, let's imagine we have a function that says we want to add to Haiti
and this function takes a number and all it does is return the value of PN.
That is a parameter we give it and adds Haiti to it.
So that when we run the function, add to 80.
And let's say we put in five, we get 85.
Nice and simple, right, but if I run this function again.
I'll have to go through this step again and add 80 to that answer, and if I do this again, again,
do the same thing.
I've ran the calculation three times.
But what if this operation took a really, really long time?
What if I had a console like here and we can imagine that this operation takes multiple seconds.
It takes a long time.
Every time we run, this function will have to run a long time, three times and go through the step
one by one, even though we've done the exact same calculation three times.
Is there a way that we can optimize this and this is where we can use caching and memorisation?
Let's improve the above function by doing something different?
I'm going to create a new object called cache that's going to hold an empty object.
We're also going to have a function.
That is now going to be called memorized.
Not memorized, memorized.
Add to Katie that takes a number, and inside here, we're going to do something a little bit different
than the above, we're still going to add to Haiti, but we're going to do it in a special way.
I'm going to say that if MN is in cash and this is a way to check if a property exists in an object
in JavaScript, so it's similar to me doing cash dot and to check for the property.
This one just reads better, so I'm going to keep it like that, so if and exists in cash, so if we
cashed it before then simply return the cash dot and.
Or cash in.
So return the cash value, but obviously it's empty the first time around, so this is not going to
work.
If there's nothing in the cash, which is the case the first time around, well, we have an estimate
and in here.
We're going to have our cash.
And.
Which doesn't exist yet and assign it and plus 80.
So that after this, if we do something like.
Minimalized add to eighty five.
It's going to say five plus 80, so.
And here we're going to cash the property five to have a value of eighty five, which is what we're
doing here, so that the next time around we're doing something like this, we go through the if statement,
find the fact that we've already calculated five and just do simple property access, which as we know
is of one time, is super fast with a hash table like this.
Let's complete this example to show you how it works.
I'm just simply going to.
Return.
And.
Since we just filled that up here and let's just have a console log here that does long time to see
that we're doing the calculation, that takes a long time.
The first time I run this function.
I get eighty five and I have the cash prefilled, so it didn't calculate a long time.
Let's try that again, like run.
Long time the first pass through it went through here and did this calculation that hypothetically is
going to take a really long time.
Again, we're using a nice, easy example here, but you can imagine this being a calculation that takes
a long time, many seconds.
What if we do this again, we can console like here?
To make sure that we capture these values.
And we'll label them one.
And to just so we can distinguish them, so the first goal and the second call, if I had run.
Look at that first time around, we call long time and we calculate to eighty five, but the second
time around because this value was in the cash, we didn't have to do this long calculation and we just
returned it immediately.
So what is memorisation exactly?
Well, memorization is a specific form of caching that involves caching the return value.
All of a function that is the return value of this function based on its parameters and if the parameter
of this function doesn't change like it is here, then it's memorised.
That is, it uses the cash because it's calculated the same thing before with the same parameter, and
it will return a cached version of the function it's memorized if the parameter changes.
Well, it's a different.
Parameter that it's never seen before, so it's going to calculate both times.
Different things, and I just noticed here that this shouldn't be five, it should be and over here.
So it's dynamic.
There you go.
That's better.
So remember, this memorization is simply a way to remember a solution to a sore problem, so you don't
have to calculate it again.