Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we want to create the actual checkout component and the checkout items inside.
So when talking about our checkout component, let's take a look at what the final component should
look like.
Really, what we're doing is we're creating some specific kind of ROE that will show what the value
of each column of these checkout items will be.
So coming back here, let's start setting that up.
We know we have our top level do and following typical fashion of these top level containers, we're
going to call this our checkout container inside.
We know we need a device that will hold the header itself.
So the header being those different values that we are adding at that row level.
So I want to call this our class name of checkout header.
Inside of this header, I want to have these different divs that represent the different blocks.
So if you think about these, these are kind of like each of these individual duplicated sections.
I'm going to call these, let's say, something like.
Something like hetero block.
It's pretty clear what these are and then what I'm going to do is I'm going to duplicate this five times
because we have five different blocks.
One two three four five.
Now, inside of the first one, we need a span that will say product.
Then what we need for each subsequent one is going to be what they are.
We have a description.
We have.
Well, let's put description first.
So we have a description and then the next one, we have quantity.
And then after that.
We have our price.
And then finally, we have remove.
For our X button, which we haven't made yet, so here I'm going to get rid of all this other stuff.
And underneath what we're doing is really we are showing the different items so I can either put this
in a div or I'm actually just going to get rid of this div now.
I don't need it anymore.
And what I also want to do is display a total.
So here I'm just going to put a span.
And inside of the span, I'm just going to say Total is equal to zero for now.
We'll figure out how to add the total later.
And I'm going to give this a class name of total.
So what we need to do now is really just add in the style sheet that will allow this code to work.
So once again, inside of checkout styles, just paste in your style sheet from your resource folder.
And now once we've pasted this in, let's go back to our application and let's see how we're looking.
So far, we've got our header.
Of course, our total isn't in the right place, but we'll figure this out later.
So the next thing that we need to do is we need to set up the actual checkout items.
So really, the checkout items are what's going to replace this temporary item that we've created here.
So let's go back into our components and let's make a new checkout item.
Oops, I misspelled that check out.
Item.
And then let's set up our files.
Check out item dot styles access and then check out Item Dot Component Dot GSX.
Now, for the actual check out item, what we need to do is we need to import in our style sheet.
And then, of course, finish scaffolding out our checkout item component.
And then export default check out item.
Now inside, what do we know we get for the checkout item?
What we're going to get is essentially a cart item.
And off the cart item, we need all of the fields.
So let's deal structure off the name the image URL.
The price and the quantity.
And then what we're going to do is return back a div that will contain all of these appropriate values.
So I want to give this class name of check out item container.
And then a div that will contain the image.
So here I'm going to make another class name image container because I want to declare the boundaries
of what this image is going to have.
And here I'm going to say source goes to the image URL and then the alt text, as we've done so far,
is just going to be the name.
And then after this, I want to make a couple spans, so I'm going to make three spans here and then
I'm going to make it do because in the div is where I want to put the remove button.
Now for your remove button, you want to use a special character, and this character can actually be
signified in HTML as ampersand hashtag.
One zero zero five semicolon.
This, in turn, will now create for us that X button, but in a specific type of format and in quite
a large size.
As for these remaining spans, I want to make class name.
Of name.
Class name.
Of quantity.
Here this will be a class name.
Of Price.
And then we need to respectively insert in the correct values.
So here I'm going to put a name, I'm going to put the quantity.
And then I'm going to put the price.
And then it's just a matter of bringing this into our checkout component.
And replacing all of this.
Once we imported it.
Check out item.
Check out item component.
And then let's render our item.
Where the key is going to be, our car item died.
And Cartwright.
Is going to be car item and then we don't need this deal structuring anymore.
And as a result, we can just.
Explicitly, one line return these values.
Now, the last thing that we also need is the check out item styles, so go into your resources folder,
grab the style sheet and then paste it in here as well.
Now, once you've pasted this in, let's come back to our application.
And here we go.
We see that we have our components, although this icon looks like to be incorrect, so let's actually
take a double check into what that check out item component has.
It has Ampersand Hash Tag one zero zero zero five.
I was missing an extra zero.
And now if we come back here.
There we go.
This now looks correct.
So our total is also looking a little weird here.
So let's go into our checkout components and here we see the class name has a capital T..
That's another mistake of mine.
And now there we go.
Accurate Total.
So now all we need to do is we need to attach the quantity arrows as well as build out this remove button.
So the quantity button, that one is pretty easy.
We can do that in the next video.
But before you move on, I want to challenge you now to try and build out this remove feature when you
hit this.
This should in turn, remove this item from the cart.
So this should be pretty intuitive because we've kind of done it already when we talked about our quantity
equals one condition far remove item from cart.
So try and think about that and build that feature to remove the cart item and then I'll see you in
the next video.