Let's talk about Kerrianne.
Now, currying is the technique of translating the evaluation of a function that takes multiple arguments.
Into evaluating a sequence of functions, each with a single argument, that sounds pretty confusing,
doesn't it?
Well, you can think of currying like this.
You take a function that can take multiple parameters and instead using, currying, modify it to a
function that takes one parameter at a time.
Let's have a look at an example, I can create a function, multiply in this, multiply takes A and
B as parameters, and we're just going to multiply A and B, if I do multiply three times four, I should
get 12, nice and easy.
How can we use couriering here?
Well, remember, we want to change the function from taking multiple parameters to taking a parameter
at a time.
We can do something like this.
I can say consed curried.
Multiply.
And we're going to take a parameter which is going to return another function that takes another parameter
and that is going to multiply A times B.
Because of closures, we have access inside of the B function to the variable.
Oh, and make sure I say consed here.
There you go.
Now, how can we use this.
Well I can now say curried.
Multiply four or less, do five times three.
If I run this well, no, that doesn't work, remember, because this is crude, it takes one parameter
at a time.
So instead I'm going to create five.
Which is going to give us the first variable.
And the way that I like to look at Arrow functions is that I can mimic how the function is written in
the way that I call the function.
So I see two brackets here with A and B. So I can call it with A and B. So if I do three here and run,
there you go.
I get 15.
So I'm giving the function one parameter at a time.
But why is this useful?
I can now create multiple utility functions out of this, for example, I can say const covid multiply
by five.
Which is going to equal this could multiply with the parameter of five so that now I've called this
function once and this function for the rest of its time, or at least this function is going to remember
this piece of data five, four well, forever until we finish running the program so that let's say
10 years from now, we finally remember, oh, we have this crude multiplied by five function.
I can use the multiply by five function and multiply anything that we want by five, let's say four.
If I run this I get twenty.
And instead of running this function over and over, I've run it once and now this covid multiply by
five is there for us to use.
So if it's a function that gets called many, many times, we only run this part of the function once,
which is really, really cool.
Encouraging almost reminds you of those methods, right, on prototypes that were shared amongst objects
they're trying to save on memory or at least the amount that our computers has to work.
Now that we have seen occurring, let's go to the next topic that gets often confused with Currey.
I'll see in the next one, Bobby.