Welcome back, everyone.
Let's go through continuing to chat through what we're seeing with our console logs.
Now that we have a clear, accurate example and knowledge of what's happening.
So again, we hit our initial render for our category component.
Our selector fire gets called because we're calling you selector for the first time, the effects,
fires, calling, set products.
And here you might wonder why why is it that are effect fired calling SAP products but then we didn't
re render.
Well the reason why is because our initial state for products is categories map at category categories
map by default gives us a empty object if the array is empty because select categories reduces over
categories, the default value for categories is actually an empty array, if you remember inside of
our category reducer.
So if you reduce over an empty array, you get an empty object.
If you call any value on an empty object, what you're going to get back is undefined.
So our initial state, of course, is going to be undefined.
Similarly with this set products, we're setting it to undefined.
So if you set a previous value of undefined to a new value of undefined, well remember React is smart
enough that when you're calling set state and you're trying to set it to a value that it using a quality
strict a quality determines is true it will not trigger a render.
Why would it do so?
It's realized that what you're trying to set is something that it already has.
That means that it doesn't need to render this component.
There's no re rendering that needs to happen.
So this is why you might see the effect fire.
But again, we're not going to render because set products is not actually re rendering the component.
So moving on from here, we then wait and see.
Oh, at this point actually the synchronous nature of our code has ended.
Our auto listener is actually what's triggering because from our orc listener we are getting from Firebase.
Oh, you have a active session.
This active session then triggers an action to dispatch set current user with the payload of the user.
From here, what happens is that current state of course once again logs inside of our logger we call
next and then our reducers update our reducers update re triggering our selectors.
But notice here that our selector is causing this component to render despite the fact that we know
that only the user object is what has updated from the reducer.
The categories reducer has not changed because our categories reducer does not respond to set current
user.
So here is where you selector.
We have to take a little bit of a deep dive into it.
Use selector, as I mentioned, runs every time that the state object has updated in the root reducer.
However, it only re renders this component if the return of the selector function you passed to it
is different.
So here you might be wondering.
Well.
Ü I don't understand.
Our selector should be always returning the same value, right?
Because the original categories array hasn't changed.
It's an empty array.
This is where it has to do with the way that we composed our logic.
Our logic here, what the produce.
What I want you to realize is that reduce is always returning back a new object.
The reason why is because after running reduce.
What our code says is that I want to build up the accumulator, which is starting with an empty object,
and then you return that back.
Every time, though, we're using a net new object here.
So this is where you need to think a little bit about your code composition.
Now, one of the tradeoffs we made when we created this selecting of our categories map to abstract
the logic into an selector rather than do it so that we store the categories map when we fetch it from
Firebase is that every time the selector runs, we will be rerunning this logic.
Now, as I mentioned, as a result of this logic, we're always getting back a new object, which means
that our use selector will never be able to properly cache that value past the quality check and therefore
not cause any unnecessary renders.
Would it not be great if instead we only ran this selector if the categories object changed that we
get back from our reducer?
Meaning that the only time we should run this logic to derive a new categories map is if our category
reducer returned a new object, and that should only happen if the action corresponds to something in
our reducer that triggered that change.
Well, this is actually where we want to leverage a new library.
It's a very popular library called Re Select inside of the Redux ecosystem that specifically addresses
this exact topic.
And that's what we're going to learn in the next video.
So join me and we'll figure out how to tackle this and learn all about re select.
I'll see you in the next video.