All right, all right, I had to make this quick video to talk about the elephant in the room, if you
know anything about the react world.
Well, this discussion has to happen.
Classes versus Hooke's.
Now, as you learn in the course, there's many ways to build react components and one of the newer
ways to write these components is using Hooke's.
Now, the way we've structured the course is the way that we actually recommend you learn how to write
proper applications.
The thing is, Hooke's are fairly new and they're exciting.
So a lot of people talk about them, but they're also very specific to react.
What you learn about Hooke's, you can't really apply to anywhere else and the programming world because
they're so react specific versus classes.
Well, that's part of JavaScript.
Learning classes is an important concept, not only in JavaScript, but a lot of other programming languages
also because Hooke's are fairly new.
A lot of code bases, in fact, still use classes because there's nothing wrong with classes.
So the way we've structured the course is that we're going to teach you react starting with classes.
So you know how those works so that you can apply that knowledge to any of your future projects.
Or if you land on a project at a job that still uses classes.
And then we're going to convert the app using hooks.
So you get to learn both ways.
And we also started with classes because there's been a little bit of move lately in the industry where
people are shying away from hooks because of the added complexity.
It adds to react.
Now, this is a hot topic of discussion.
It doesn't really matter whichever one you prefer.
Our goal is to teach you both and then you can decide for yourself what is best.
The way we structure the course is what we think is the best way to learn, react.
That is starting with classes as they were intended, and then learning hooks afterwards to show what
problems Hooke's solves that maybe we had with classes.
So hang in there.
We're going to cover both of these.
I'll see you in the next one.