Welcome back, everyone.
And the last video I issued a challenge to try and create this handle submit method yourself.
Hopefully it worked out and you now are able to sign up users using email and password.
It's really cool if you did.
If not, let's do this together.
No worries at all.
So here are what we know is that for signing up a user, the first step we need to confirm is whether
or not their passwords match.
So here I want to say that if password does not equal, confirm password.
Then what I want to do is I want to alert them that your passwords do not match.
And then I just want to exit because I don't want to proceed any further.
I've already told them they need to now update their passwords.
There's actually another way that you can add additional checks to this password and confirm password
by adding additional length checks inside of the input fields themselves.
I'm going to link for you the input documentation for this HDMI element, so if you wanted to add more
functionality yourself, such as adding requirements of length and such.
You can do that yourself.
I'm not going to add any of that just because for me, this is enough for me to get the idea of what
I'm trying to build with this form.
And the other thing I want to do now is once I've made sure that passwords and confirm password match,
I need to continue and actually attempt to create this user.
So as we did before, we're going to try and catch because when we try and call our Firebase server,
we might fail.
And if we fail, we want to be able to catch that error here inside of the try.
What I'm going to do is I am going to make sure to call this method that we just created, which is
create a user with email and password.
And here's what I'm going to do is I'm going to pass it the email value and the password value.
These are the two values that we've structured off from our form fields.
Then what I'm going to do is I'm going to make sure that I know what it is, that this response is first
before I start working with anything else.
So in this particular case, let's say we get an error as well.
Let's just catch the error and let's just console error the error.
We can also console log the error.
Maybe that's a little bit more clear for us right now, and we can just say user created encountered
an error.
Or user creation?
Let's be more grammatically correct.
User creation encountered an error and will log their.
And this is enough for us to at least get started and see what's happening.
So let's pass our handle, submit into our on submit handler here.
And now let's save this.
And let's go back to our application.
And let's actually try it out.
So here I'm going to say that my display name is Mike.
My email is Mike at Gmail and my password is one two three four one two three four one two three four
one two three four.
So I know I'm logging this.
Typically you don't want to do this, but I'm just logging it for our own benefit right now.
And if I had sign up, let's see what happens.
We get back a user credential and inside we see we get a user object.
And here we get an access token.
We didn't pass a display name because we have not actually done this inside of our code.
So this is a very key point that I want you to notice.
The display name here is not coming back to us inside of this user.
But how could it?
We just created this user.
So of course, there's no display name, but the reason why this user object is the same is because
Firebase is making sure that across all of its different ways that you can authenticate, you're expecting
the same shape, whether or not there's a value or not, that's entirely up to the authentication method
itself.
The reason why for Google there's a display name is because in Google, when you set up your user,
you have to tell Google what your name is.
In our particular case, we did not do that in the actual authentication method.
We did it in our form, but we don't actually do it in our authentication with it, and there's no real
need to in this particular case.
What we're going to do, though, is we are going to use this and store inside of our database since
that.
So this is an important distinction is that now display name is not coming from this user object display
name is going to be coming from, ah, sign up form instead.
So how are we going to do this?
So here, let's go back into our application as we saw we are getting back this user, which is good
because we want that user.
But what we're going to do with this user is we are now going to have to pass this value that we have,
which is the email and password confirmation.
Into the actual final.
Document that we're trying to generate, but let's look at this method right now.
Our method infers from this user off the display name, the email and the creative that these were just
assuming comes off of that user object because it did when we signed up before here.
We're not going to be able to do that anymore.
So in order for us to extend this functionality, we may sometimes get this value.
We may, sometimes not.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to say that, OK, in the cases where there's not, let's
say we get some additional information and this additional information I'm just going to say is an object.
And what I'll do is I will spread this object in at the end, after all of these fields have been filled
from any previous variable setting that we've done.
So if display name exists on use or off, then it will get spread through and we're not going to pass
any additional information, meaning that this will probably by default, be just an empty object,
for example.
But let's say in our current example, display name, there's no value here.
It was null, as we saw.
So what's going to happen is display name is going to get set to null.
But then because what we're going to do is we are going to add the additional information ourselves,
then what will happen is that this is instead going to be passed in like this where we will have a string
ourselves.
So it'll be Mike, for example.
And then this is going to overwrite that null value so that we do actually have a final display name
inside of our user document.
And now what we can do is we can just say that after we get back this user off object, I want to now
call in that method that generates this create user.
So I'm going to say, what is the method name again?
Create user document from off.
And down here, after we get back, I'm going to await.
Create document from off, I'm going to pass it the user off, but I'm also going to pass it this object
with the display name value that we have expected them to fill out inside of their form.
And then after this, if it's succeeded, we'll figure out what to do to confirm to them that they've
successfully signed up, but for now, this is enough for our form field.
The only other thing we need to do is make sure that we clear out the sign up field.
But before we do that, let's just make sure this is working.
Let's take this one step at a time.
So here I have all the same code in, and now I'm going to refresh.
And let's just keep typing.
Mike Mike at gmail.com one two three four one two three four one two three four one two three four.
And if we hit, sign up now.
Oh, we see we get an error, we see that we get the air Firebase Air off email already in use.
So this is actually very helpful because earlier when we logged out the sign up for the first time,
it actually already created a user for us for this email and Firebase won't allow you to make the same
email for multiple users.
So this is really great for us because now what we can do is we can capture this error and we can alert
to the user even more specificity on why the error failed.
So here what we can do is we can actually leverage the error code and this particular error code was
the off email already in use, Erica.
So we can say if error code.
Is equal to this.
Then what we can do is we can cancel or actually let's alert to them instead that they failed because
they have the same email, cannot create user email already in use.
And now if we save this.
And we can do else console.log this error.
And now, if we clear out the console and we sign up again, we see that we get the proper alert.
So this is great.
We've added more functionality in now and there's more ways that we can make this look prettier, but
we'll talk about that after.
For now, what we want to do is we want to properly create this user, though.
So what we can do is we can delete this user.
From our authentication and if we go back now and we try this sign up again, what will happen?
Is now if we come back in here.
Let's refresh.
We didn't get the air.
We see that we have this user and inside of our fire stored database, we see that we have our new user
great.
So everything is working as expected.
The only last thing we need to do is after we successfully actually fire off this successful creation.
We want to clear out these fields and that we can just do by creating a another method called reset
form fields, which is just going to be a function that calls set form fields with our default form
fields, which are the empty states.
And then let's just append this to the end of after we've successfully created the user document from
the off.
And now, if we save this in order to properly do this will have to delete the user again.
So here, let me just go in here.
Let me delete both these users.
So I'm going to delete both the documents as well as the authentication because we're going to have
to go through this step again.
In fact, I could have just created another user.
I don't even know why I'm doing this.
This is really just a bit of hindsight in my end.
But let's refresh.
And let's just make sure that everything works like like gmail.com one two three four one two three
four one two three four one two three four.
Hit the sign up.
We see that our field successfully cleared out, which means that we probably successfully created our
user, so if we refresh, we see our user and inside of our database, we also see that we've generated
the user successfully.
So everything here is working.
So our code is working as we expect.
We've now properly integrated in sign up using this email password.
So now that we have this, let's finish styling up our sign up and then what we can do is we can figure
out whether or not we can successfully sign in with this newly authenticated email password user.
So I'll see you in the next video.