Welcome back.
Let's start to actually write a test for the Google search function.
The first thing we want to do is obviously have access to this Google search function, but in our test
file.
And that's simple, this is simply just JavaScript, we can just export this function and import it
in here now because this is node and we're not running and the browser or using Bable or Watpac, we
don't have the import and export statements yet.
Node is working on that.
But for now, they're still using common G.S., which, as you might know, has the syntax module that
exports equals.
And we'll just do the Google search.
We're going to explore this and then finally, we can import this at the very top of this test by saying
Consed Google search.
He calls.
Require.
From the script for.
Let's save that and just to test it, Liz, just console log this.
And do a Google search, safe run and test.
All right, so we have our consul log of Google Search that's on script, but also in the test we see
that we're logging out function Google search, which is great.
I'm going to.
Comment, that's all for now, because we know it's working.
We don't want to cancel long, but you might have also noticed that it's kind of annoying running AMPM
test over and over and over.
And luckily for us with Jess, we can do a nice, easy command.
Dash, dash, watch, and then we give it what to watch for, in our case, all JavaScript files, so
any time we make changes to any JavaScript files.
Just is going to watch out for those and have the test running constantly.
Let's see what I mean.
I'm going to save this.
And run npm.
Test.
And if you're wondering why I can run AMPM test and not ampm run test, that's just the default of AMPM.
If you do ampm start or ampm test, you can run those two commands without the wrong word.
But if you do anything that you created yourself like ampm bake a cake you have to do npm run bake a
cake.
All right, so now it's running, if I change anything in here to let's just have save it.
You see that it's now changing.
If I change this, it's constantly updating with the new test, but nothing is happening in here yet.
So let's write an actual test that we can use.
Now that we have the Google search function, we want to test it.
We want to say Google search, give us some sort of a dummy input, let's say test test and somehow
say whatever this returns should match whatever.
And remember, that's an assertion library.
What we want to make an assertion and you may notice one issue here.
What about the database?
Well, we'll have to export this database as well.
Right.
And we totally can.
We could do a Google database and added to the module exports.
But is that realistic?
You see, in real life, you're not going to just export the database and imported into a test and have
the test to actually go through the database.
That's really expensive, really slow and a huge headache.
Ideally, you want to market, you want to pretend that we have a database in here so that it makes
tests run faster.
Let me show you how we can do that, we can just say, Debe, mock a database moch and this mock will
have some dummy database, which isn't actually our real database, just something that we can test
on.
So let's say this one has dog dotcom.
It has.
Cheese, puff, dotcom.
It has, let's say, Disney, dotcom, and it has dog pictures, dotcom.
So completely different from our real database.
All right, so we have this now, but the problem is, well, Google search up until this point was
using the Google database.
And if we run this function and script, that test that goes well, we don't have access to that database.
We'd have to manually change the function and make sure that it filters through the DB mark.
And a good way of solving this issue and the way you want to write your functions is, again, you want
them to be pure and you also want to add things to them, like a database through something called dependency
injection.
That is in order for us to make this reusable and use it in other parts of our code base, have the
database injected into Google search so that anybody using it can, like I am in the test, can inject
this Dimmock instead of the real database.
And that's really easy to do, all we need to do is pass it a parameter of, let's say, DB and I'm
going to change this into DB and now this Google search is more extensible.
We can add whatever database we want to filter.
Now, all we need to do is in our when we call the function is to add a single parameter of.
Google database.
If we comment that out.
And go back to our test file, we can enter the.
DB Moch database.
Let's save now and see what happens.
All right, test is passing, but we're not really testing anything right now, we're just returning
things and running this function, but that's not where we want to test.
It's not very meaningful that we run this function.
We want to assert that this does what we expect it to do.
And again, just like we had the IT keyboard just gives us a nice little function for us to use.
If you go to using matchers, we see that in their documentation, they have the expect and to be and
they have a few other things that you can use to be define to be defined, to be falsey, truthy, and
they have a ton.
For now, let's comment this out and say that we expect.
Hello to be.
Hello, hello to you.
Hello.
All right, let's save that, all right.
Everything is passing.
But if I change just to know and save, oh, I get a failed test, it says it expected the no value
but received hello and it's got pretty nice output.
It shows you which line failed and what the test failed that using that logic.
Let's change now the Google search to have expect.
And you know what, let's keep this test, because I like this test will do.
Hello.
And calls this it.
Is a silly test.
And create another test again, we can just have as many as we want, and this one will say it is searching
Google.
And in here will have the function.
Let's outerspace here because.
That looks nicer and we'll say that we expect.
Google search, and we can just copy this.
We expect Google search and we're running that function with test test DB Mark, and here we can use
instead of to B, we can also do two equal.
And within the two eagle, now let me just create a new line just so you can see it, it's going to
say we expected to equal an empty array because there's no test test here.
Let's save.
Oh, and I forgot a little bracket here, we want the expect to have the result of this, so we need
an extra bracket over here.
So make sure you get that right, a save.
Oh, and you don't need that now, perfect again, maybe not having it on two lines is better so we
can see.
So we have the exact function that runs this.
And to equal to test that, this equals an empty array.
We can now add another line and let's say that now we want to expect Google to test dog and if dog exists,
we wanted to include these two websites so we can add.
Dog come to this area and also dog pictures dotcom to this day.
And let's save.
All right, this is running and passing, we still have to test because, well, the it there's only
two of them.
But if I change this to let's say that just.
I'll get in there because we got something.
Different than what we expected, we expected a different array.
There you go.
We have our very first test.
I'll see you in the next video.
Bye bye.