Welcome back, everyone.
So let's build out our final actually clearing out the item from this cart, so to do that, what we're
going to do is go into our car context, such as and inside of here.
I am going to add yet another function called clear item from cart.
And this is going to be a function that is just going to be very similar to our remove item from cart.
And here I'm going to call it clear item from cart.
Of course, it's going to be including the item to remove.
And similarly, we're going to call it clear cut item.
So let's talk about how to do this.
Let's make a third helper function called Claire Cart item.
That is going to receive the car items because as we know, we need to probably utilize this card item
to give us back the new card.
And then there is the cart item to remove.
In fact, we can even be a little bit more explicit, we can call this car item to clear.
Because we already did carte items removed here this way, at the very least, it's a lot more visually
clear for whoever is reading our code.
So what we now need to do is think about what we did before here, if the quantity matched to one for
some existing cart item, then we filtered it.
So really, this is all we need.
This portion of the coat, because all we're doing is we're saying, Hey, if the item you're trying
to clear out from the carts is equal to the crime that's already there, then just filter it out completely.
So this alone is actually all the code we really need.
Let's test this out.
So let me just make this a one line return once again and then.
Down here, we're calling it.
We can just add this to our value.
And let's import this into our check out item component.
And inside of our check out item, we need to attach it to this.
So in order for us to do that, we need to import in.
Use context from React, and we also need to import in our context.
And then inside here, I want you to pull in clear item from cart.
Equals use context, cart context.
And then if I just add this as a on click.
You know what, let's do our typical pattern where we create a separate handler and we'll call it our
clear item handler, which is equal to a callback that will call this passing in the cart item like
so.
Then here we can now do.
On the click.
Which is equal to clear item handler.
And now if we go back to our code.
Again, we need to include it in some items.
Go back to the checkout.
And now, if we hit this, there we go.
We got rid of all the quantity of that great brim hat, and as we can see, we've reflected it everywhere
possible.
So what we need to do left is also attach on the increment and decrement that we previously kept inside
of our checkout component.
So here we can actually just cut this because we're going to need it anyways.
Come over back to our checkout item component.
And add this on right here.
And then what we need to do beside the quantity for these spans is also include the arrows.
So what I'm going to do is I'm actually going to add to dips into this span.
And what I'll do is that for each div, I want to give it a class name.
Of Arrow.
So let's duplicate this on both sides.
And then what I'm going to do is I am going to.
Actually, add a left and right arrow inside of this.
So the way that this works is that you're going to use another similar symbol this time it's going to
be Amerson hashtag one zero zero nine four semicolon.
This one is for the left work facing Arrow and then for the right word facing Arrow, you're going to
use five.
As for this quantity, we're going to want to make sure to wrap this in a span because we're going to
need to style this quantity now so that it accurately shows what we need to show.
So here I'm going to give it a class name.
And what I'm also going to do is now just add the on click for our arrows.
So I'm going to say on click is equal to let's create our handler's contest ad item handler.
And this will just be a callback that calls add item to cart.
Passing in our car item.
And we'll do the same for the remove item.
There we go.
Now, if you're wondering, why are we creating these outside handlers rather than just putting these
anonymous functions directly into these on click areas?
This actually has two purposes.
The first one is that if these methods ever change, we have a very clear idea of where these definitions
are rather than being inside of our assets.
They're in a place where we know we instantiate and initialize all of our helper functions and anything
like that.
It's just for code clarity.
So it's easier to update these if need be.
The other reason is because by doing this, we're actually going to be able to optimize this code later.
But I'm going to talk about that later when we get to the optimization step.
For now, we're still in just the building functionality step of this code.
So let's add these on to the appropriate places.
And oops, sorry.
The top one is actually going to be the remove item handler and then the bottom one is going to be.
The ad item handler.
So now if we save this.
Let's just double check in our check out item styles in here inside of our quantity and all of these
other values, we are indeed adding in the appropriate styles.
But let's think a little bit about whether or not we need to update our styles, especially on quantity.
So in the quantity we added in this additional arrowe div that contains the left and the right arrow,
we want to make sure that whenever somebody hovers over them, we do a cursor pointer and ask for the
value in the middle.
The reason why we added the value is just so that we can say, Oh, give me a left and right margin
of ten pixels.
So now if we save this coat, we come back.
We see that we have a little bit of wonkiness here.
So what we need to do here is we need to modify this quantity to have display flex so that now.
There we go.
We have everything looking like how we need it to, and we can increment this quantity and we see it
reflect appropriately in our cart.
And that's it.
Everything is working, as we expect now before we move on.
One last thing to do is to figure out how to correctly display the total.
We need to be able to iterate through all of our card items and figure out what the price is versus
the quantity of all of those card items.
So that's my challenge to you.
Figure that out, and let's do this last thing together in the next video.