Welcome back.
Let's finish up testing our Google search functionality, because with tests, the more you have, the
better it is in most cases anyway, because these are never going to go into production is just for
development purposes.
It never hurts to have a lot of tests that cover a lot of scenarios because that way we just cover our
bases even more.
And don't worry too much about repeating yourself or the do not repeat yourself rule and programming
with when it comes to tests, it's OK to repeat yourself every once, every once in a while, especially
if it makes the tests really readable for other people.
Reading your code once again, these are never going into production, so it's always better to have
more tests than less tests.
So let's test a few more cases with our Google search function.
Let's say that we also want it to work with undefined.
And no input and that we want to make sure that this function.
Is going to work and let me just copy this expect.
Assertion and within here in the Google search, I'm just going to say undefined.
And we want that to equal an empty array if we somehow get a weird entry on an undefined input from
the user, we still want to return an empty array because maybe on the front end we're still displaying
an empty list.
Let's save.
And that passes, we now have three tests and let's also test for the null case.
Again, we'll copy this.
And we'll test for null as well.
All right, our tests are passing perfect and you can see how nicely outlined they're in just for us.
Finally, we also want to check if we look at our script, that we return no more than three matches.
That's an important feature of our app.
Once again, let's say it.
Does not return more than three matches.
And let make more space for this so we can see.
And once again, you can see a lot of repeating here, but it's good we're writing tests.
Let's say that again, I'm just going to copy this because I am lazy to type and we'll say that we want
the.
When we searched dotcom, which all of these have, we want this to equal well, to equal.
An era with three items, how can we do that again?
This is just simple JavaScript.
We can just do a dot length in the expect bracket, which will return hopefully three, even though
we're doing dotcom and has four items because of our function is should return.
The length of three, so let's just set.
Look at that, our test pass and another advice here, just because your test passes doesn't mean it's
always correct.
It's always good to start off by making your tests fail and then trying to make them work.
Let's just make it fail by adding four in here and it's safe.
And all right.
We see that we expected a value to equal four, but we received three.
That's good.
If we change that to three.
Everything is good.
And you can play around with the inputs a little bit more.
I think you're starting to get this right.
It's not that bad.
It doesn't look that intimidating.
And yet when you look at other people's tests, there might be a few more methods that they add other
than to be and to equal.
But the basic principles are the same.
We just have a function that we run tests and that's it.
One final thing, we can group all of these because remember, with our thinking things can get bigger
and bigger and bigger, we can group tests that are similar, especially in this case, the ones that
are doing a Google search with another function called the describe and describe will say describes
the.
Google search.
And this is the exact same way that the Eppalock was described, the first parameter is a string that
will be displayed on the test and then the second one is a function and we can enter all of these tests
inside of this block.
So now if I say this.
I see that the tests are grouped together, and I know that all these tests that we're running are under
the Google search function so that when we have hundreds of tests, we can see which ones are failing
and where we want to target to fix our tests.
All right, more exciting things in the next video I'll see in that one by.