Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, let's finish styling our sign up form.
So here I want to give this div a class name.
And the class name is going to be signed up container.
As for this one that contains the sign up with their email and password, I'm going to make this into
a span because technically speaking, our title, which I'm going to use an H2 instead of an H1, just
so that in terms of the HTML, it's a little bit more clear to web scrapers that this isn't something
as high ranking of a title as an H1.
Someone needs an H2 here.
I'm going to say something like Don't have an account.
Like so because this is a pretty common format for a sign up.
And then what I'm going to do is I'm going to make a sign up form stylesheet, so I'm going to say sign
up form dot styles dot SAS.
And inside, I am going to say that the styles will target our sign up for container.
And I'm going to give it display Flex.
Flex direction.
Column.
I'm going to set the width to three hundred eighty pixels and then I'm just going to target the H2.
And for the two, I'm just going to say that I want to give it a margin on the top.
And also, no margins on the side.
So just margin, top bottom know, left right.
And then here inside of our sign up form component, I just need to make sure to also import in.
That stylesheet.
And I'll save this.
We go back to our application.
And there we go.
We see that we have what we need inside of this for.
That's what we need to do is we need to now create this button component.
So here we see that we have this button component.
Let's recreate this button.
So let's actually think about what this button entails.
We notice that this button has some custom styling, but we also know that there is this sign in with
Google button.
So this button and this button look the same other than the fact that there is a couple stylistic differences
in how they perform.
So there might be some consideration here for us to already think about making a general button component
that can adapt to the styling required for where it's used.
Let's check around and see if there's any other buttons anywhere here.
We see that we're still using a regular black button, and inside we notice that this button is a pain
now button, but this one is actually not as required for us inside of the application.
We also notice that there is this same button that we had before, but it's inverted.
So if we check, we know that we have our black button.
But inside of here, we also notice we have a default white button that when you hover, turns black.
So it looks like there are three types of buttons.
There's this default block button.
There's the inverted button.
And then there is this sign in with Google button.
So now that we have these three different buttons, let's start coding out the button component itself.
So the first thing that we want to do is we want to make a general button component.
So inside of components, let's make a new button component.
So I'll make a button folder and we'll do button component dot GSX.
Now, for those of you wondering what this button component?
Shouldn't we name it something else, since there's already a button html element?
Well, for us, our button is actually always going to be capitalized because as we know, we can't
write different components that start with a lowercase letter.
So our button is just a capitalized button, and that's enough for us to know that that is indeed our
button.
So here I can say Const Button is equal to a functional component that will return a button that has
some specific styling.
So it's still a button at the end of the day.
The only thing is just that we know we need some class name that we can target for this button to apply
our styling to it.
And what we're going to apply to this is, let's call it a button container.
And then inside of our button, we want to use this button the way that you would use any button.
Meaning that whatever inside text or ones or P tags or spam tags you put in the button.
We want to do the same inside of our button and that will just, of course, be the children.
So we'll just render the children inside of this button component.
Let's export this out by default.
And let's do a little thinking here.
We know that we have three types of buttons.
So here what I'm going to say is that we know inside there's three buttons.
We have our inverted button.
We have our default button.
And then we have our Google sign in button.
So how do we leverage this button type in order to show styling for three different kinds of buttons?
Well, what we can do is we know that we're really just modifying this one button styling.
So really, perhaps we can control the styling by a class so we can have default styling for a button,
inverted styling as well as Google sign in styling.
And how we can do that is we can create some kind of variable, let's call it our button types, for
example.
And here we know that what we're telling it to apply is classes so we can even do button type classes
as the name of this object.
And inside we know that, for example, if we get past some value like button type, if the value is
the string of Google, then we want to render this the class name Google sign in.
And if we got inverted, then we'll show inverted.
And what this does is this allows us to use a more readable and legible kind of input four button type,
but render whatever it is internally that we need in order to properly display this button type.
So through this one value that we're getting as a prop, we can now control how we want to render this
button.
It's just that right now we're only doing it by class name.
So let's just restructure or not restructure, but let's string interpolate button type classes like
so.
And in fact, in order for interpolation, this needs to be JavaScript, and I need to change my regular
quotes over to back decks.
But I'm going to say button type classes and then I'm going to call button type off of button type classes.
So button type here is expected to be a string.
And remember, with our button, we pass it all those other values that we were seeing inside of our
sign up form.
We had a type of summit.
So here in order for that to go through, we can do our other props and then we'll just spread this
in after the class name.
So now let's save this, so now that we have this class name set up.
How do we actually get the styling?
Well, as you guessed it, I've already done the styling for you, so create a button dot styles dot
SAS file.
And then inside paste in the button style sheet that I provide it for you.
So once you've pasted it in, you can see inside we have our button container, which is our class name
that adds all of these different stylings and hover effects.
But you'll notice that I have the Google sign in class name styling and the inverted styling that will
overwrite some of the styling that applies by default.
So now we just need to make sure that we import this in.
And then inside of our sign up form, let's import in the button itself.
And then all we need to do now is come down to our button.
And paste this in.
And now if we save this and we go back to our application.
We see we have our button, in fact, now just to confirm.
Let me add a button type which is equal to.
Let's say Google.
We come back.
We see it becomes a Google button.
And then if we changes to inverted.
We see we have an inverted button, so there we go.
We have our button component.
I'm going to switch it back to the default, and it's the default.
Awesome.
So we've styled our sign up component as well as our button.
So now that we have all this set up, let's actually work on our sign up page and then we can finish
up this overall page for sign in and sign up.
Now there's two things left that we need to do before moving on.
The first is that we need to actually commit our code.
So let's go back to our terminal.
Let's add all the things that we did.
So here I want to say that I created the sign up component, the form input component, as well as the
button component.
And then let's push this up.
And the second thing that I want you to do is I actually want you to attempt to create this sign in
component here, all the signing component does is it takes an email and a password and it tries to
verify otherwise.
You can sign in with Google.
It looks very similar to our sign up component.
But what the sign in portion?
You may have to look inside of the Firestorm box a little bit to figure out the method.
But I want you to at least try and figure out how to replicate pretty much what we have here, but inside
of sign in and just trigger a callback for sign that you don't necessarily need to actually call the
method.
But at the very least, I want you to try and recreate what we did for sign up.
But here, create it for sign in because we ready have all the components we already know of the logic.
So this is a good chance just to practice everything that we've learned for building the most complex
component that we've built so far.
So good luck and I'll see you in the next video.