Welcome back.
Let's talk about inheritance, a core aspect of object oriented programming is inheritance, which means
passing knowledge down.
Remember, at the start of this journey, we decided that we want to create this game, this fairy tale
game that had all these characters.
And we started with else, just a couple of ETFs.
But as you can see, our goal is to have many things we want to have maybe a dragon, a night, a king
and queen, maybe some magicians.
Yes, even Dracula.
So using this object oriented programming principle of inheritance, how can we accomplish this with
the work that we've already done?
Let's have a look.
We have our class here.
Yes, we've seen it before, and it shouldn't be anything new, but let's say that I wanted to have
a new player and this player is actually an ogre called Shrek.
How would I go about creating this ogre?
The one thing I could do is to copy and paste this code and create an ogre class.
I mean, that's copying pasting dry code that eventually we want to avoid.
Because as we keep copying, pasting, copying and pasting, we just have repeated code which gets messy.
So one option that we might have here is, well, let's just copy the elf, and maybe we can extend
it.
So for example, if I want to copy Fiona, let's say Fiona over here.
If I click Run, I have this elf class.
For instance, with all these properties.
Now, in order to copy while you already have.
We can just do something like this.
We can say Konst Ogre and ogre is going to equal.
Well, let's clone Fiona.
And as I've shown you before, we can do dot dot dot spread.
Operator and then just do Fiona.
If I do this, let's remove the spaces, and I look at what Olga is now.
And I click Run.
Look, that I've copied Fiona into the ogre variable.
And the interesting thing here is, if I do yoga dot underscore, underscore, Prato underscore, underscore,
what do I get?
I get an empty object.
What if I do, Fiona?
I have health.
So I've cloned the object, but OGA no longer has Elf as the class, the base class.
So that if I do hear console dialogue, Fiona.
Equals.
Olga Clone.
And I click run.
Oh, and I don't need a clone here, it should just be OGA.
I get false.
These objects are not referencing the same place in memory.
They're completely different things, but I've also lost this chain, this prototype or inheritance
chain.
I can't even do ogre dot attack.
No, I don't have a tech.
So that's a problem.
How can we extend this, this work that we've currently had?
And this is where inheritance comes in, and it used to be really difficult to do with JavaScript.
Before we had this class syntax, it involved a lot of ugly prototype code that, luckily for us, is
now a lot cleaner.
So let's have a look.
To start off to make naming a lot better, I'm going to change the class here to character because all
characters in this game are going to have name and a weapon and they can attack.
That's great.
And now from this character, I'm going to create a class elf that extends, which is a key word.
This character class.
This is something called subclasses and object oriented programming that is we have a base class or
a super class and a subclass that is we want to inherit from the character class.
All these properties and methods and create something new out of it, extend it with health.
Let's have a look.
If I just do this and I click Run.
All right, I get undefined.
Let's see what Fiona is right now.
If I do Fiona and click Run.
All right.
Look at that.
Everything is still working.
I have Elf.
Name Fiona Weapons, Ninja.
All right.
Great.
But you know what?
Let's make this a little bit more interesting.
Let's say that the Elf characters in this game, they also have an extra property that they can have.
Maybe it's a type property.
As to what type of health they are, so let's build, but how would we go about doing that?
Well, in here, let's add the type property if I do a constructor here.
And I do this that name or this type.
Equals type, and let's say that we receive a type parameter in here.
Hmm.
How is this going to work?
We have to instantiate the elf class and we give it the name and the weapon, but we also want to have
the type.
So maybe we'll do this.
We'll say name and.
Weapon.
And the third parameter will be type, so I'll say that type of a self.
I'm going to change the name from Fiona to Dobie.
The name is going to be Dobey and the attack is going to be well.
Or the weapon is just going to be a cloth and the type of elf, it's going to be a house elf.
Right.
If I do this, let's see what happens.
I'm going to click run.
Hmm.
Reference here must call Super Constructor and draft class before accessing this or returning from derived
constructor.
Does that make sense?
Not really, right?
I mean, that's a pretty confusing error message.
What is it saying?
In order for us to have our constructor and be able to use this and know what this is referring to,
which is Elf and not the character, because remember we have both name and weapon.
We have this special keyword called Super for superclass and the superclass we call like this.
And by doing inside of the constructor, the super call it says, Hey, call the superclass, what's
the superclass of Elf?
Well, that's character.
It extends character, so it goes up and calls the constructor so that we create the same name and this
dot weapon.
So in here, we have to pass it name and weapon.
Now I know this is a little bit confusing.
This whole super thing is just a standard, especially with classic class based languages where Super
is referring to the superclass.
Let's have a look here if I click Run.
Look at that.
I got off.
That is Doby weapon is a cloth and has a type.
Well, it's a house off.
And if I you Dalby dot attack.
Attack with cloth.
Not very effective, but it's working.
Now, let's go over this one more time when we do Class Alpha extends character.
It means, hey, extend and set the prototype.
That is the underscore underscore prototype to point to character.
So L'f now has a prototype chain up to character.
It's saying, Hey, any time you run an instance of alpha like Dobie and uses a property or a method
that I don't have.
Well, then look up to character and tell me if character has.
The constructor is our own constructor, just for the ALF class.
This is something that only gets run with an elf, not with a character.
And in here.
We can't leave it as is.
But if we want to set any sort of property that is used that this keyword, we have to call super and
say, Hey, call the constructor of our superclass.
And then after that, I'll know what to do with this keyword.
Let me show you if I do console dot, log here and do this and I run.
That gives an air.
Because in order for us to use that, this keyword inside of the constructor, when we extend something
we have to call super first so that if I move the console dialog to under the super call and I run.
Look at that.
I have Elf that has name and weapon attached to it.
So this because we call the super runs the constructor.
We now have a instance.
Of character with these properties, and then we can use this Scott type two ad type to it so that by
the very end.
Of our construction process of Elf.
We have all our properties set.
Very, very cool.
And remember, the this keyword simply says, who am I?
Who's calling me?
In this case, we use the new keyword.
So this is going to be set to health.
All right, but we started this video with us wanting to create an ogre.
So let's do that.
Let's continue on.
Let's create another class that's going to be an ogre class that extends the character.
We do the same thing now, let's say that our OGA has a constructor.
And we want to pass in a few things, such as name, weapon and you know what, ogres have different
colors.
So let's do that.
Let's add a color property.
And what do we do here?
Well, we're going to call the super class, which is character with name and weapon, so that now we
can use this keyword to attach new properties to the yoga class.
I'm going to add a color that equals whatever color we give it.
And you know what, ogres, they have special powers.
Let's say that ogres can also make forts, so we have a make for it because, you know, they're very
powerful, obviously, and they'll just return, let's say strongest fought in the world, made nice
and easy, just like that.
Let's see if this works.
If I create, let's say, Shrek and Shrek is a new ogre.
With the name of Shrek, the weapon is going to be a club.
And then finally, the color.
Obviously green.
If I do Shrek duct attack or lizards, do Shrek here to see what we get.
Look at that, I have a new ogre that was just created for me.
How awesome is that?
And if I do make Ford here and run this, look at that.
I'm able to use make Ford function or method on track.
But if I go and do make fought to Dobie.
No, Dobie can make for it.
He's very, very weak.
There's not much that he can do.
He's just the house off.
So let's go back to attack here.
How cool was that we were able to keep our code nice and organized and extend our base class character
to create all these different characters in our game?
Elf, we have ogre.
We can keep creating different things like night magicians, princesses, kings, queens and we can
reuse code that we've written before, but also extend these classes to have their own individual unique
things like properties like type or even methods like make fort.
This is a simple example, but you can imagine the power of this as we get more and more properties
and methods and bigger and bigger objects.
Now let's take a break here and revisit this code in the next video.
But by.