Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, let's learn about the resell like library.
So first we need to add the select library into our application.
While this is fetching, what I'm also going to do is I am going to restart the server because once
this is installed, we need to make sure that our server has the latest libraries.
This is most likely the most common time when you want to restart your development server is when you
know you have new libraries.
So I'm just going to rerun your and start here and then I'm going to go back to my application and I'm
going to explain to you how re select works.
Now the basis of re select is that it creates for us this concept of a memorised selector.
So let's talk about what a memorize selector is.
Memorization is the process in which you cache the previous value of something so that if the input
has not changed, then you just return back the same output.
This works when you have a pure function.
For example, if we had some function called AD, which takes some value A and B and it returns you
A plus B, we know that because this function is pure, if we call ad of three and six, this gives
us back a value of nine.
If you call, add three and six.
Does this mean that you need to run A plus B every single time?
No, of course not.
You know that if you receive the same input because of the function as pure, you should always get
back the same output.
So why waste the extra resources to recalculate something that you already have calculated before?
Memorization is that extra step inside that does that for you.
So create selector does that with selectors.
It memorizes them, assuming that as long as the inputs have not changed, then your output should always
be the same.
Now how do we extend that into selectors?
The way it works is that we have to create what are known as input selectors and output selectors.
Inputs selectors are selectors that give us the parameters that we need in order to determine what our
output should be.
If that sounds confusing, I know it absolutely is.
Let's write some examples so we get an idea of what we're doing.
First, what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a initial selector that gives us back just that
slice of the reducer that we need, which is the category reducer.
So here I'm going to say select category.
Reducer is equal to some function that receives the state.
It's a selector function.
It gets the entire read of state.
And then from this, we just want the category's slice of the Redux store.
Next.
What we're going to do is we're going to use this inside of a memoir selector.
So in order to create a memoir selector, we need to first declare what it is.
So this is select categories.
Select categories gives us back the categories array that lives on the category slice of our redux state.
So here, in order to select this, we have to say, hey, I want to use the create selector method.
This method creates a memoir selector and it takes two arguments.
The first is an array of input selectors, and the second is going to be the output selector.
The input selector is going to be What do I want as part of the parameters that I'm going to use to
produce what the selector should return back?
So what are the slices that I want from Redux so that I can use them to produce something new outside?
Here, I want to get the category's slice because off of the category's slice, which we will receive
as the arguments inside of the output array.
So whatever this is, whatever the output of this will be the argument that is in the same place inside
of the output array.
So if, for example, we had another selector, let's say it was select current user, this output is
going to now be the second argument of our output.
But we only need, of course, the one for this.
So now we're going to take categories.
And we're going to say, okay, you know what?
Actually, let me rename this category reducer so that it's more clear.
Or category slice.
I like that more.
I want to take Calgary Slice and I want to get off the category value.
Now this selector is a memoir selector.
The only time where this will run is if this category slice object that we get back from this selector
is different.
Because if this input value of categories is different, only then does re select determine.
Oh, we need to rerun this method.
If this category's value is always the same again with the strict equality triple equal, then I know
that the previously cash competitive value is going to be enough because these functions are pure.
So as long as this categories object is always the same in memory, which it will be as long as categories
reducer has not updated.
Then that means now, suddenly this value will always be the same one.
Now, this becomes extremely powerful when you think about what we were trying to do with our categories
map because we didn't want to run this reduce if categories had never changed.
So in order for us to memorize this, all we need to say is that, hey, I'm going to create a selector
here and this selector is going to receive select categories.
You can notice they're composable.
If we pass this structure selector in as the input, it will in turn memorize here already and then
memoirs here again.
So now we know that we're getting the categories.
Which is the categories array with this categories array.
I want to of course, reduce over it.
So I'm going to copy this over.
And now I can get rid of this code.
Fix this typing here.
And now a pretty memorise selector for this mapping that I've made.
What's happening here is that we're saying, Hey, as long as the categories array does not change,
do not rerun this method.
Of course you want to reduce once, but after that, as long as it has not changed, don't even bother
rerunning it.
Just give me back the previously calculated value.
And because the previous he calculated value was the previous return of reduce, which is an object
in memory.
What you'll notice is that use selector now works, that triple equals is going to see hey that previously
cash value is actually the same value the same categories map.
Now unless the categories array value is different.
Then what will always happen is we'll just get back the previously generated object.
In fact, to prove it to you, I'm just going to add an additional console.log here so that we can see
what happens when we relook at our flow.
I'm going to say selector fired so we know that we're firing our selector.
If I go back to the application, I want to clear this out.
I don't want to talk about the initial mounting step yet.
I just want to show you what happens.
If you remember previously, what happened is that we would sign out this trigger set current user,
set current user updates our Redux store.
And of course, because our Redux story is rendering our selectors get called from the use selector
hook of React Redux.
This in turn will do the equality check and see if there's anything.
Before we were noticing that our components were getting rendered because we were not being able to
properly do the check due to the reduced call.
But now if we sign out, what do we see?
We see that current user gets called, we see that our payload gets called, we see that our current
state is getting updated, but this is all within our logger.
We're not actually even seeing this component getting trigger.
Now, why is it that our selector didn't even fire?
This is because we didn't even make it this far into this select categories map this select categories
call here didn't even run it.
Just return what was already cached, which is an output.
And the reason for this is because of course, once again, this is all memorized.
If we even go up here and we say, hey, is this even getting called?
So I'm actually going to be more specific selector one here.
This is selector to if I save this and I come back here and I refresh.
Let's re trigger our flow.
Sign in.
Clear out.
If I had the sign out still you notice I'm still not even getting our selectors.
The reason once again is because this is also a memoir selector.
This selector is actually the only one getting run.
And this one is in itself.
What is being cached at this input level?
So now if I move this console.log up here, set this one to selector two and then this one to selector
three.
If I save.
Let's reset up our application.
Clear this out.
Refresh.
Let's.
Now we see selector one fired.
That's as far as it got.
So inside of our category component when current user got updated and our user selector updated.
Of course all use selectors are getting fired.
Select Categories Map.
As far as that went, was it determined?
Hey, what's the current value of categories?
Now categories is output from our category reducer.
This object, of course, has not updated only the user reducer has updated.
Therefore, it doesn't even determine the need to fire this logic, let alone this logic.
It's just going to take what was returned from the last calculation of this entire compose chain, which
was the previously calculated, reduced down categories map.
And it just returns that as the value.
And that value, of course, is the same value that this use selector had previously.
Therefore, this category component does not render.
Now, if that is confusing, I understand we learn a lot today, but really this is one of the most
powerful aspects and why the Redux ecosystem is so fleshed out.
Because React is constantly going through this render battle.
All of these elements, all of these steps that we're taking are just all of the ways that we scale
out a redux application.
Every single step that we're doing here is a different way that all of the different tool makers and
this redux ecosystem has developed because of this separation of the logic.
We want to make sure that in our selectors we have all of our business logic, but at the same time
we want to make sure that we're not messing with any of its own render cycles.
So there's all of these tools that were really thought out and very careful and intentional about how
this all works together.
But hopefully here now through this flow, you saw what we were doing.
We now have memoir selectors which are very intelligent in being able to determine, hey, if nothing's
changed, just don't even bother re rendering.
So let me get rid of all of those console logs because now we have.
A working example.
Of our memoir selected.
There we go.
So hopefully you learned a lot through this process of migrating away from the categories context into
category reducer.
There was a shifting of the logic, the architecture and a lot of these additional pieces that we learned
in order to fully flesh out our understanding of how all of these different pieces and Redux play together
and how we can optimize it.
So if this was challenging and confusing, redo this yourself because only through that process and
just console.log every step of the way in order for you to really understand what's happening in these
interactions.
I know it's really, really challenging.
Redux has a very notorious reputation, as I've mentioned, for having a very steep learning curve for
this exact reason.
There's so much boilerplate to set up.
There's all of these additional libraries in the ecosystem that help us to understand what's happening.
But the benefit, of course, is the unit directional data flow that we get with this type of architecture.
So now that we've done this, my challenge to you is to migrate over the remaining context to Redux.
And that context, of course, is the CART context.
So do that.
And then in the next video, we'll do it together and I'll see you in the next video.