Welcome back, everyone.
In the last few lessons, we watched Andre explain to us all of the key things required in order for
our application to be considered a progressive Web app.
Now, luckily for us, our application is built with Create React app.
And as Andre explained, it's incredibly easy because Create React app has pretty much given us all
of the tools required in order to adhere to those principles that make an application a P a.
Now, in order for us to actually do this, there's a couple things we have to first tweak about our
application a little bit beyond what Andre explained.
The reason for this is because we're also running an express server, but we'll get to that.
The first thing that we do need to do inside of our index is bring back that service worker.
What we're going to do is we're just going to say import and then we'll use that wildcard, the star
symbol, to say everything.
I want to import everything as the content service worker from the service worker file.
So now that we have a service worker code, we're just going to say service worker register at the bottom,
which will register the service worker inside of our application, and that completely verifies the
service worker requirement for a.
The other thing to remember, though, is that because we're using an express server, whenever a application
tries to load the service worker, it's going to be looking for a service worker file.
So what we have to do in our server is that whenever and the app makes a get request for service worker,
yes, we will give them that service worker file.
So inside of our server jass, we're going to do one thing.
We're going to add inside of here a new app to get call and we're going to say if they're ever requesting
service worker James.
Then with the request and the response as the function.
We are going to say that with the response, we're going to send the file path resolve.
Our directory name.
Combined with this dot dot, meaning that we want to go up one because we were inside of our clients.
We want to go to our build folder.
And then we want to pass it, the service worker.
So that's all we're trying to do, we're just saying whenever an application requests our application
to provide something from this route, we're just going to go into our build folder, get the service
worker, Jaspal, and that's what we'll render and return.
So that's all we need in order to add our service worker into our application.
The next thing that we have to do is we have to ensure that our applications manifest is up to date
with the icons that are required.
We also can change some of the names here because our application is going to actually render this name
or the short name in a mobile browser when we try and open it, after we've downloaded it into our mobile
device as a progressive Web application.
So how we'll do that is we can just name this whatever we want.
I'm just going to call this one Crown Clothing.
With a capital S. and the long name, maybe I'll say something like Crown Clothing by Baiba.
So luckily for us, create react that generates us this Phalcon and it gives us the sizes that we need.
And if you remember, I did give you a Fabricant Ekko.
This babakhan is good enough to replace all of these image sizes inside of our manifest.
So this one is fine.
The only other thing we need to add is two more pages that are the sizes for the Android's splash,
as well as a one nine Chubais one nine two version that Android also needs.
So what we can do is just import them in from the resources folder because I will provide both of those
for you.
So simply just drag them into your public folder.
And what we'll do is create two new objects inside of our icons array.
The first one is going to just point to the source exactly like the same format we see with our Phalcon
Icko above, there was a crown five, 12 times, five, 12 Panji, which is the name of this file.
Four sizes, well, just say five, 12 by five, 12.
And for type, we just got to say it is image.
You can actually copy this text pasted in here and just change the instances of five 12 to one ninety
to.
And that's all we need for our manifest, we have to the names and we updated the icons, the last thing
we have to do is https.
As you remember, we're hosting on Heroku and Hiroku by default does give us.
The only thing to note is that we do need to redirect any HTP request over to meaning that if anybody
requests our application using HTTP, we should automatically redirect them over to https.
Typically when you have a server, you do do this on the hosting server.
Now, Hiroku does not have this option for us.
They have us do it inside of the application, but they do provide us with some links about what the
best libraries to use are.
I'm going to provide you with the one that I think is best.
The one that I like to use is called Express Alfy.
So that's what we're going to do.
So in order to add it into our application, what we're going to do is we are just going to install
that.
And so I'm going to use yarn.
And if you're using NPM, of course just use NPM, but I'll say yarn and express dash ssl i f y asus
alphie.
Once this is finished installing, we're just going to go back into our server jass.
And add this new line, so first of all, we're going to bring in is inforce.
Which is what we're going to call what we get back from Xpress SS Elfy.
In order for us to use it, we just simply call use where we do all of our use statements.
So down here we can just say Apte use.
Inforce.
TB's.
And then we're also going to pass at this object that says Trust Proteau Heter.
Gosta, true.
The reason we need to do this is because with Heroku, Hiroku runs what's called a reverse proxy.
Now a reverse proxy is something that allows us to forward unencrypted HTP traffic to the website.
So this is really difficult because inside of Hiroku, it's going to hide away the headers that originally
would tell our application whether or not it's coming from an IP request.
But luckily for us, there is this Proteau header property that they append on it as well.
So as you can actually read right here, I'm actually realizing that what I explained was inside of
this block of text here, it's just something we've got to do with Hiroku.
So with that, we're now able to enforce our https.
So these are all the changes we need.
So what we're going to do is just simply get at everything in.
Get commit updating our code to be a compliant, let's say, added service worker.
HTTPS.
As well as updated manifest.
And then we're just going to run get push Hiroku M..
And in case your application is out of sync with any of the get repos that you've got so far with your
Hiroku because maybe you closed down my project or something, you can just force your existing Heroku
application to switch over.
OK, now that we finished building, let's actually see our application.
So we're just going to run Hiroku open.
Now, your application may take a little longer because the dynamite need to be spun up, but mine is
already life.
So what we're going to do now is we are going to run an audit to make sure that our application is progressively
compliant.
So to check this, just go to your audits tab if you're in Chrome, because by default, LightHouse's
is actually brought into it.
And here you're going to select the desktop.
Let's actually pop this up just because we want to look at everything.
So we want to choose desktop, we want to audit performance, progressive web app and best practices
accessibility.
Nescio is not important because that's not the focus of this course we're going to set no throttling
and clear storage is perfectly fine.
So we're just going to run the audit itself.
And this might take a couple of seconds.
And there we go, we got our scores, so we'll see that we have one performance, we have ninety three
for best practices and we are progressive Web app compliant.
So if we scroll down here, we see that we have gotten a checkmark for every single one of our sections
and we're now a optimize.
You can actually check this application inside of your phone.
Now, unfortunately, since the making of this course that adds a home page button is no longer available
inside of your Chrome browser on your desktop.
But if you have a mobile device, simply go to the link that is your Heroku app, or you can go to mine
and you will get a little tap at the bottom that asks you to add it to your home page.
If you click that, you'll add our application using our Fabricant to your home page and you can open
it and browse it like you would a native application, which is what's really, really cool.
So that's one great thing about create react app.
And the way that we've set up our project is that we're able to get progressive web application level
compliancy so quickly and so easily.
Hopefully you enjoyed the section on converting our application over to a PWI a check it out on your
mobile device because it's really cool to see for the first time with that.
That ends our section on progressive web apps.
And I'll see you in the next lesson.