Welcome back.
We got our tests to work and Google search right now is working pretty nicely.
I'm pretty happy with it and I think we can move on.
Let's create another script and have perhaps a more realistic or a harder function than this to test.
So I'm going to just add a new file and call it script to James.
And we definitely want to write some tests for it, but for now, let's just write our function and
what it's going to do.
Now, one of the harder tests to write and something that you might be thinking of is a Synchronoss
test.
I mean, right now you can see that with Google search, we can copy this with pretty much any function.
And you might see why pure functions are so good to test.
I mean, you're just testing function.
You're just adding some random inputs and making sure that the outputs are what they're expected.
Very nice and simple.
And they're all just synchronous, nice tests.
But in real life, we most likely have fetch calls or API calls that are asynchronous.
How do we test for those?
Well, in this video, let's tackle that for this exercise.
I'm going to use an API that I really, really like called Swaby.
And yeah, that stands for the Star Wars API.
It's free and it's awesome.
I recommend it in the other course as well.
So some people might be familiar with it.
But yeah, it's great.
You can see here that you can request planets, you can request people, you can request starships all
from Star Wars.
Yeah, pretty awesome.
Using the Star Wars API, you can see that this is the end point that we can hit to get the JSON response.
Let's create a nice little function for us to use that we can test now fetch in node one work, because
if you remember, fetch is something that's implemented by the browser.
And it's on the window object, but a. there's no such thing as a window object, so there's no window
fetch for that.
We need to install something called.
Noad Fach.
And there's a few other libraries that you can use so you can do fish calls from note, but let's just
stick with this one for now.
This way, we can now have such a..
And again, we import it with the common way because imports and exports are not available yet in note
and then just import noad fetch.
All right, and in here, let's do a contest, get people from Star Wars and let's say this is going
to receive the fetch.
Remember, we're doing a bit of dependency injection here so that we can test and we can keep this nice
and easy to test as possible.
And here we can say that we're going to return.
Futch and I know I know this is a little bit.
Redundant because we could just not have an input and have fetched, but it's just it shows, I think,
dependency injection really well, and this isn't something that you necessarily always need to do.
But for this purposes, I think it's a good way for you to get familiar with dependency injection.
And here we're going to have the Star Wars episode.
Let's go back to what they had.
And let's copy this.
And say that we want to request the people API, and if you remember, we always need to do our classic
then.
Response and then run the JSON method on the response.
And then finally, we have our data, which will be the people that it returns.
So let's say in here we're just going to return an object that has a count, because if we go to people
over here.
Because we want to get all the characters, we get a count variable of all the characters in the API.
So let's do that and we'll say count.
And actually, it should be DataDot count.
And then we'll do results that will just have the data that results, which will have all the people
in an array and each person in an object.
All right, let's save that and I want to make sure this works, so we'll just do console dialogue,
get people and pass in the first function to it, going to save.
And let's just run node.
Let me clear this for now, and actually, just because this is a Synchronoss, a nicer way of doing
this is just in here console logging the data.
The save and run AMPM script to James.
And we have to wait a bit, but you see over here that, all right, we got all the characters with
count to eighty seven and we got Luke Skywalker.
What else we got C three.
Po are two, D two.
All the main cat's awesome.
This is working.
And you know what, while we're at it just for fun.
Since this is using a promise, let's also add the async weight version of the code.
And let's just remove the call and just call say that get people.
Is going to use the async await, so that means in front of the function, we're going to do async.
And not we can use the wait keyboard so we can just say consed get request equals await the first call.
And now we can say that the.
Const Detta again equals 08.
The.
Get request.
Dodgson and now we can remove the dog then.
And keep everything the way we had it.
Let me add the semicolons.
And let's just make this smaller so you can see better.
And we can move this.
On this line, you can decide for yourself what looks cleaner, but let's test out to this as well to
make sure that it works.
So get people and we'll add fetch.
Going to save Amron NPM, oops, not there, run it here, ampm run no and Noad scripted as we wait
a bit and there you go.
Everything is working.
I don't know why I decided to show that in the test video, but I'm sure somebody out there is going
to find this useful to compare promises and async a little bit of a tangent.
But let's get back on track here.
Let's actually start writing tests for our async code again.
The first thing we're going to do and I'm going to remove the get people and cancel log from here.
Let's save.
And I'm going to create a new file.
Call it script 2.0 test.
Dr. James.
And within here, we want to do a few things first, we want to use the fetch function, so we need
the require.
Noad Fetch.
Again, because we have used dependency injection and we need the parameter fetch for the get people.
And then we also need the function.
From the the API that returns the get people for now, let's just say require.
Script.
To James, We don't need the James.
But remember, because this isn't no package, we need to actually give it the path.
All right, so let's export the function, let's just export both of these for now, we'll say module
dot exports.
And we export them in an object, we'll say get people and instead of doing get people, get people.
Again, shorthand with ethics is to just to get people and get people promise, which which is the same
thing as get people semicolon, get people property and value property in value.
All right.
So now within here will have the will have access to our functions, both of them.
Let's take a break, and in the next video, we're going to finish up this test, I'll see in that one
by.