Welcome back, everyone.
Now, before we continue with our car context, let's just make sure we've cleaned up everything up
until this point so far.
In the last video, we added a few console logs that I want you to remove as well.
If you have, then that's great.
If not, please do that now and inside of your context.
If you have not deleted your user context and your category context, please delete those as well.
So with our car context, there are a lot of little micro functions, utility functions, as well as
a lot of the separation of logic that we did so far.
There are a couple things that we need to think about when it comes to how we migrate this code over
into Redux.
It's everything we've already learned, but there are just a few more steps.
One key thing is that so far we've been storing our cart count and cart total actually on the reducer
itself.
So here what we've learned so far is that with these selectors we can actually extrapolate out that
data and we can also make it relatively performance as long as we make sure to memorize them using SELECT.
So that's what we're going to do.
Beyond that, a couple other things we want to do is just make sure that we capture all of the logic
in the right places when coding this out.
So to begin, what we're going to do is let's go into our store and let's set up and scaffold all of
the things we need in order to get this redux up and running.
So I'm gonna take the cart folder.
I'm going to make the action jazz.
I'm going to make, of course, the reducer J.S..
I'm going to make the selector jazz, and I'm going to make the types jazz, all the things that we
need.
And then what we'll do is we will slowly migrate over into each of these files, the different things
that we've already created.
For example, we know that we already have the reducer and the initial state.
We, of course, have to tweak some of these in order for this to work and fit our current model.
So initial state.
And then the next thing we need to do, of course, we need to set our state equal to cart initial state
and our action equal to a empty object if no action is passed.
Then by default we just also return the state.
The next thing we need is car action types.
So here, let's go to our car context.
Let's grab our car action types.
Put them into our cart types.
And let's also add cards in front of each of these strings, because now every single reducer gets every
single action.
So we want to be very clear and explicit about which one should be receiving it.
And then what we need now.
Is we need to actually create and move in the types so we're going to import in our car action types.
Export out this producer and put this producer inside of our producer.
So here we have our cart reducer.
We just attach it to cart like so.
And now for our first sanity check.
Let's just make sure our reducers actually inside of our application.
So here, when we initialized, what we see is our next data object.
And on the next day we see on cart we indeed have all of our initial values.
So there we go.
Have set up our reducer.
Now we need to think about the hard parts, which is the actions as well as the selectors.
So as I mentioned, our selectors should be what actually extrapolates out the logic that we had before
that we were doing when we were pushing the values into our reducer in context, because now instead
of doing it before it goes into context, we're no longer storing car count and cart total.
We want to extract that into selectors.
So to do that, what we need to do is just make sure that based on the cart items, we want to move
this over.
So let's copy this into our selectors first.
Let's also make sure to import in our create selector
from re select.
As far as the electoral logic goes, the key thing that we know that we need to extract off is the cart
items.
So currently, though, we are storing cart total as cart quantity.
So what we can do is we can get rid of these values.
And we need to make sure as well that when we set, all we're setting now is just cart items so we can
just pass it as the payload, which will be our card items.
I think I'm realizing that when we look at our car context, I did not make a new set or a function
that uses reducer.
Instead, we're still using use date.
So this is an oversight on my part, but this is a very quick, simple setter that if you want it to
set, you can make it yourself.
Maybe some of you have noticed that I missed that, but it's no worries.
We'll do it now inside of our car reducer.
So all we need to do is just switch the case.
I believe, in fact, we even have a set.
Is car open?
Yes, we do.
Is just an oversight on my part.
We just need is heart open to point to the payload which will pass as a boolean.
So for us let's create the actions that will do this here.
Inside, we want to import in our cart types.
And then what we'll do is we'll export content set is cart open which will receive a boolean and we
also need to import in create action.
Because what we'll do is we'll create an action with the cart action types set is cart open and pass
the bullion as the value for the payload.
Now for the remaining actions, this is going to be a little different when you think about the car
context.
The way we had a before is we had these helper functions that we exposed and what they did is they were
update the reducer, but we would also generate what the new car items would be here and do this as
these functions, this you can kind of see as your action creators.
All you need to do with the action is the action needs to figure out what to update inside of our final
reducer.
So what we'll do is we will make sure that our actions are the ones that do so in order to do this.
We will probably need all of these different helper functions that we've created.
So I'm going to copy these over first.
Move these at the bottom and each of them rely on some utility function that helps us actually derive
the new car items.
So I'm going to copy these over as well.
And there should be one more for clear cart down here.
I should.
We should have moved this right here for more clarity.
But no worries.
We have it now.
And now it's just a matter of modifying these new action creators so that they actually do what we need
it to do.
So what I want you to do is I want you to try and take a stab at this.
If you have already, that's great.
If not.
Just try and figure out, okay, now that we're inside of the Land of Redux, these actions now no longer
have access to items in the scope of the context.
We'll probably have to pass it in.
But before you do that, just think about when you're writing these actions anyways.
Understand the context under which they'll be used and what you might have to do in order to get it
to work.
So try that out yourself and then join me in the next video where we will code this together as well
as finishing up the rest of the set up for this cart.