Welcome back, everyone.
In the last video, we learn about initializing some local state inside of this component, which is
a object that has key value pairs in it.
And then how do we access that state object or any JavaScript able really inside of our GSX code?
In this lesson, we're going to learn more about extending some JavaScript functionality into these
components to do something much more dynamic and much more useful when it comes to building applications.
So what we want to do is, let's say, I just wanted to click this button change name and then have
it change from Yehovah to Andre.
How do I do that?
So inside of your Jazz X, React actually allows you to bind event handlers onto any HTML element.
So what is an event handler?
Event handler is really just something that I want to happen whenever an event happens.
So what this means for our button, for say, is every time this button is clicked, I want something
to happen.
So to do that, I have access to this on and then the name of the event in this particular case, I
want on.
Click.
So whenever this gets clicked, I want some functionality to happen and the way that I can tell it,
what functionality are to happen when I click it is, I say on Click is a property which is equal to
a block of JavaScript, and we'll remember whenever I want to access JavaScript, whether it be a variable
or even hardcoded in JavaScript, I use these curly braces.
So here I'm saying Hey on click equals and then inside of here, what on click is expecting is a function.
You may hear the word function or callback function used pretty interchangeably, a callback is just
a function.
You pass to some kind of handler that you wanted to call during some process.
In this particular case, of course, I want it to be called whenever it gets clicked.
So I'm passing it right now, this empty function, so nothing will happen.
But what I want to do whenever this button is clicked again is change the name value to Andre instead
of EÜ.
Now you might think, Oh, let me just do this dot state dot name is equal to Andre.
But this is actually not going to behave the way that we're expecting it to.
In fact, let's also console log this start state just so that we're very clear about what's happening
once we save this.
So if we go back to our application, we hit this button change name no matter how many times we hit
it.
We see the EUA here is not updating to Andre, even though the object that gets logged out is the correct
value we're expecting.
We see that our object here name is now Andre.
But why is it that inside our application, it's still using the previous value of EUA?
Now this actually has to do with the way that react determines when a component needs to re, render
and re rendering.
In this case, as I mentioned, is when React decides, Oh, I need to update the DOM or repaint the
UI.
So let's break down why exactly it is that here this is not working the way that we want it to.
This actually has to do with the fact that we're not actually changing the object in a way that react
recognizes that the state object is different.
Now you might be wondering, well, Yehuda, the object is different.
It used to say name equals equal.
Now it's his name equals Andre.
But for React, it's not leveraging that change in the values in the object as a actual change.
The way that react to text it that there's a change is that uses JavaScript underlying reference by
memory for an object.
What that means is that in memory, whenever we instantiate a variable, let's say const object one,
and let me say that this object is equal to the same object that we have as our state.
So name is equal to EÜ.
This object one is just pointing to this object when it gets instantiated.
So what happens is that under the hood, JavaScript goes, Oh, there's this object I want to create
in memory, which has this shape name equals EÜ And then I'm going to create some variable called object
one, and it's going to point to this object that is just made.
An easy way to see this is if I say Object two is equal to object one.
What's happening here is that JavaScript like, OK, this object one, what's it pointing to?
It's pointing to this object in memory.
So I'm just to make object to a pointer that points to the same object in memory.
And now if I say object to strict equality, which is three equal signs equals two object one, it'll
say that it's true.
Strict equality just says, are these two pointers pointing to the same thing in memory?
Yes, they are.
This is object equality when you do triple equals with objects.
The reason why this is actually not working for react and updating the DOM has to do with this concept.
Let's say we say object one name is equal to Andre.
When I update this object, one now has that new updated value object to also has an updated value.
And this makes sense.
They're both pointing to the same thing in memory.
But again, this object in memory is not different.
It's the same object in memory.
So even though the value has changed, it's still the same thing in memory.
So for React, React actually says the only way I'm going to update a component when I know that the
state is different is if there is a completely different object in memory.
And how does that happen?
Well, let me give you an example, let's say we make another object object three.
And in here we use object dot assign.
Object assign is a method that allows us to create a different object using another object as a template.
So let's say first, what I'm saying is the first argument is a new object, a brand new object.
So this is the first argument.
It's like, what do I want to make or assign a new object from?
The first one is a brand new object right here.
The second one, I want to use object one.
Now, if I look object three, it has the same signature or it has the same shape as object one.
It's still named because Andre.
But now if I do, object one equals against strict equality with object three.
I see that it's false.
And the reason for this is because this object, even though it's the same one as object one when we
change it.
These are two different objects in memory.
An even easier way to do this is if I say Konst Object four is equal to an object with the name Andre.
Here you'll see that I'm typing out a brand new object.
So this is a completely different object.
Even though it looks the exact same as Object one and Object 2's pointing object in memory, even object
three.
They all look the same.
But when we do strict equality with Object four, we see that different.
Object three.
An object for completely different.
Not the same object and memory.
So this is when react will determine that it needs to re render.
Your component is when state is a completely different object in memory.
The moment it's a different object and memory react will be like, OK, it's time to update this object.
So let's do that quickly, actually.
How do we do this?
Well, an easy way that we can do this react actually gives us a method, and it's called set state.
Now, Sets State is an interesting method because there's actually many ways to use it.
But I'm going to show you the very basic, simple way, which is that you give it an object that you
want to shallow merge with your current state object.
What's shallow merge?
A shallow merge just means that whatever values that you pass to me inside of this object, I am going
to update and check through the state object to see if there are the same keys.
If there are the same keys, I'm going to update your state keys with the new value.
Give me.
So here I'm going to say name is equal to Andre.
So what's going to happen is that when we call this?
React is going to be like, OK, you want to call sets state.
So you want to update the state value, what do you want to do?
You want to take this object and you want to say, Oh, I want to find any name on this object and I
want to update it to the new value.
So now this, I'm just going to say name because Iowa, instead, it's going to update to name equals
Andre.
So now if we go back, we clear we had changed name.
We see that it's updated.
And the reason for this, again, is because what sets state does under the hood is that it's actually
updating state to a different object and react once it detects, Oh, state is now a different object
in memory.
Let me re render this component and in turn, update the applications UI.
So now that we understand a bit more offset state as well as object and reference, which is how React
determines when a component updates, let's go more in-depth into said state, which I will do in the
next video.
So I'll see you there.