In the last video, we learned about how a class component decides that it needs to render when the
state is different, the way that it determines that the state is different is when it sees that the
state object is now a different object in memory.
And the way that we can best use this is to utilize the class components set state method that React
has given us.
As I mentioned in the last video, that state can take an object and it will in fact shallow merge this
object into your current state and give you a new state object.
But there's actually other things you can pass the said state, but we'll talk about that a little later.
For now, I want to focus on the shall emerge, so we really understand what it does and then what the
best practices for it are.
So when you pass it, an object, as we saw with shallow merging, it will look for any keys that exist
in the current state object, and we'll update them to the new one that we have in our case.
We're updating name to Andre so we can actually see this if instead we do another value.
Let's say company is equal to XDR-TB.
And just to be clear, let's also render this to our UI, and I'll say hi.
I work at.
And then this Scott state company.
So I haven't modified said state.
We're still just updating the name.
And if we go back to our application, if I hit change name, it says, Hi Andre.
I work at XHTML.
And just to be clear, let's also console.log this start state.
And if I save this.
Now, if I click this again, you'll see the first time that we click console.log our state objects
skills as one company, but I'll break this down a little later as to why that's happening.
And it's not what you expect, which is why is it not saying Andre if I click it again?
Now it's Andre.
So don't worry about this.
For now, I'm going to talk about why this is happening a little later.
But for now, what I want you to focus on is the fact that what happened with that shallow merge is
that name did get updated to Andre.
You'll see.
Name is now Andre, but the company stays the same.
So this again is a shall emerge.
It only updates the keys for the values that are being passed to it.
Anything else it keeps and it retains the same way.
Now, one important consideration to make about the shallow merge is that there's actually a thing that
yields a best practice when we do this, because with a shallow merge rack doesn't care what the value
was before.
All it cares about is that I see that the keys match.
I'm going to update the value regardless of how complex the previous value was.
What do I mean by this?
Well, let's update names so that instead of a string, it says that it's an object that has a first
name value as well as a last name value.
And now inside of my string, let's also update this Star State name, first name, so that it's now
referencing the new value that we have, which is an object.
And I want to point to the first name as well as the last name.
So now, if I save this and I go back to my application, we'll see that now it says, Hi Juzang, I
work at XDR-TB.
When I click change name again, we see that this was the previous value, so let's ignore this again.
I'll talk about this in the next video.
But let's say it again, you'll see what happens is that our state object got updated.
So that name is Andre.
But here we see that our app is not working, that we expect it to.
It's not displaying Andre anymore.
And this makes actually total sense because name is now just a string.
It's not that object that we had before the first name, last name, complex object.
And the reason why that this is not rendering is because when we look at our code, our code is looking
for this dot state dot named Dot first name and this dot state dot named Dot last name.
But of course, as we know, a string doesn't have a dot first name or a dot last name property.
So now our code is breaking.
But again, with a shallow merge rate doesn't care that this is a completely different shape or even
in fact type, then what it was before, because now we got a string before as an object.
RAC doesn't care.
Let's say, Oh, you just want me to shallow merge this key of name value to replace the old one.
I'm just going to do that.
So this actually extends into a best practice so that our code doesn't behave in this weird way where
it breaks.
We want to make sure that when we update our state, we're always using the same types of values for
our object properties.
So if your name is going to be an object, make sure that you update it appropriately, like so.
So that here first name is still Andre.
And last name is Niagara.
I hope I spot that right.
So here now when I click change, name now works the way we expect it to.
So this is an important thing to understand about using such state when you pass it and object.
So now that we understand that state with an object, I'm actually going to in the next lesson, break
down what the different way you can use that state is where you don't pass it an object, but instead
you pass it a function.
And with this function, it's actually the preferred way to do so.
Not all the time, because you will see a lot of projects use such state where they pass it and object
still.
But as far as reax own suggestion goes, you should use the function and there are certain parts to
it which I'll explain in the next video.
Similarly, it's also going to explain why whenever we were logging our state object in our experiments,
we see that the first time I do so, despite the fact that the value in the UI has updated, my console.log
seems to be behind because the object still says firstname lastname of the previous value.
So we're going to break that down in the next video, and I'll see you there.