Welcome back, everyone.
So let's finish setting up our action creators here inside of an item to cart.
What I want to do is I want to make sure that I pass in the current state of what these cart items will
be.
Similarly, I want to do the same for remove items, a cart as well as clear item from cart.
These are all necessary because I need to actually generate the new cart items through which I will
instead of calling update.
Now what we'll do is we will dispatch the action itself.
But the dispatch is going to be from the action, and the action is what we need to generate.
So to generate the action, we need our create action because that's what we're going to return back
from this function.
And our create action is going to receive the new cart items as the payload.
But we're also going to receive cart action types, set cart items as the actual action type.
So here, because each of these are called new car actions, we can just move it over like so.
Then lastly, we just need to make sure that we export out each of these action creators.
And this will be the action creator that we use in order to replicate our previous behavior inside of
context.
So now that we have our action creators, we can, of course, further tweak them once we have everything
set up.
Now it's time to think about the selectors.
So with our selectors, as we know now, what we want to do is we want to work off of the car items
inside of the reducer in order to generate the car total as well as the car count.
So here what I'm going to do is I am going to create the basic input selectors that I know we always
need.
The first one, of course, is to extract off just this slice of state.
So here I'm going to say select cart reducer is equal to us receiving state and then us getting state
scorecard.
So this will give us just this cart slice that is governed by this slice of the reducer.
So nothing here, much different.
The next thing that I want to do, which is going to be probably something we want to memorize, is
getting the actual cart items off of this slice of our state.
So here I'm going to say export const select cart.
Items.
Is equal to create selector where we receive select cart reducer.
And then off of this, we get the cart.
We want to return carts, dock cart items.
We probably want something similar for our is open.
So I'm going to say select is carte open.
Which is equal to create selector receiving select cart reducer.
Once we get the cart along, carport is cart open.
Now, as far as new counts and the cart total goes, we want these as the logic in our new selector
logic.
So here I'm going to make contact select.
Can't count.
And this is again a create selector that receives select cart items because off of these cart items
is where we're going to actually get the total value of all of these items.
So I'm going to take this reduce I'm going to put it here.
Similarly, I need a new.
Select cart total.
Which is create selector passing in select car items again as the basis and then from the car items.
Now will reduce over these card items for the total.
So I'm just going to copy this over.
And get rid of the semicolon.
But that's it.
We know that we need to extrapolate out the logic that we had before we just moved it into our new normal
selectors that we get from Pre-select.
And the key thing here is that no longer are we storing cart total and cart quantity inside of our reducer.
Instead, now everything is based off of card items which we know it will be.
And through using memoir selectors, unless those cards change, we won't be running any extra renders.
So now comes the long and arduous process of making sure everything works as we expect it to by replacing
everything that calls our old car context.
So to begin, what we know we need to do is we need to gut out the car provider from our index chase
because we are no longer utilizing the car provider.
The next thing that we need to do is figure out where car context is being called inside of the application
and slowly migrate over using these new methods that we've created the creators, the actual selectors.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to leave this to you, try it out.
And in the next video I'm going to show you how we do this.
But I want you to get some practice first to really figure out where you need to import, what you need
to remove, what you need to call from what hooks.
It's always good practice and we have quite a few of them to do inside of our application.
So try it out.
And then in next video you'll see how I do it.
I'll see you in the next video.