Welcome back.
Let's start writing some tests that are for asynchronous code, if we go back to our script to test
our jobs, we can start off our first test by saying it.
Calls.
Swaby Star Wars API to get people.
And again, same syntax as we've seen before in our first test, what can we do?
Well, we can say swapping dot.
Get.
People.
We'll give it the fetch API or the fetch function.
And then do it then.
And like I said, you could pass down you earles here and we could do something called mocking, which
we'll talk about later.
For now, we're just sticking with this method.
But let's see what we can test.
We have the API that we're calling again, it's going to return us a ton of data.
So again, we do the DOT, then just simple JavaScript and this dot then is going to return us.
Some data.
Remember, it's going to return our data or it's going to return our count and results.
So in here inside of the dog then block, we can do our assertions expect.
Data does count.
Two equal.
A seven.
Because remember, if we go back to the website, the count is 87, so hopefully data count matches
87.
Let's see if that's the case, I'm going to save and go back to running our tests.
Let me clear this and run AMPM test.
And we all need to press a to run all tests.
All right, so, hmmm, that worked, that wasn't too hard.
We don't do anything too crazy.
What if we add another test?
I'm going to add another test here and it's going to say it's called Swaby to get people with a promise.
Now, this time around, we'll use get people.
Promise.
Let's save.
Right.
Is that actually working?
It looks to be working.
I mean, we get the tests, six of them that have passed.
But remember what I said, we always want to make sure that we fail our tests and check that the tests
actually are checking what we're what we want to check.
One tool that we can use with.
Jest is something called expect dot.
Assertions and assertions are remember assertion library.
Are these things?
These are assertions, so using the expected assertions, we can say within this block, we expect one
assertion if we had to, then we should say we expect to.
And this is a good way to test that.
These things are actually running, especially with asynchronous code.
Let me do one here.
I'm going to save.
Whoa, what just happened?
Are expect Dott assertions one failed.
There were zero assertion calls, so something's happening here where this test is passing, but this
is never being called.
And this is a little gotcha with asynchronous tests.
You see, when this happens during tests, it's really, really hard to debug because it's easy to not
check that they work properly.
The problem is that the tests are actually completing as soon as the get people gets called and remember,
a promise returns a pending state.
So this is going to get returned before we actually receive the data.
How do we get around this?
How can we tell the test, hey, don't just pass this test because nothing happened and we just returned
a promise with a pending state.
Wait until this is actually done and then keep going.
There's a few ways to do this, the first way to do it.
Is to use a single argument called Done So instead of having an empty parameter here for the function,
we can have done that.
That gets automatically passed to a test.
And this says.
Hey, just just wait until the done callback is called before you actually say this test is finished
and you usually put it right after the call.
So let's say this is now done.
So let me save that.
All right, it passed now we're saying, hey, don't pass this test until this is done.
Just to test, if I change this to zero.
This is failing because we have one assertion call awesome.
Now, this is one way of doing it, and the neat thing with this is that if for some reason this if
this festival fails, let's say that in the script to James, this is actually.
And incorrect, your URL parameter that we're sending, maybe we misspelled people if I save this.
You see that I get an air call Sorbi to get people and I get an air here so that the test waits until
I'm actually done, very nice.
Now, let's fix this, bring this back to one and talk about the other way that you can do this, and
this is really easy, if your code uses promises like we have, there's a simpler way that's probably
less confusing for most people to handle asynchronous tests.
And this is another thing that I really like about just we can simply instead of doing this.
Just.
Return the promise and justice smart enough to say, oh, because we're returning this, I'm going to
wait until this promise returns and if the promise is rejected, the test will automatically fail,
which is very nice.
Again, let's say this.
Everything's passing if I misspell the Aperol again.
You see that the test automatically gets failed.
Now, this is a little tricky, you have to always make sure that you return the promise if you omit
this return estimate statement, as you saw, your test will complete before the promise actually gets
resolved or rejected.
So here's a tip.
When running a Synchronoss tests always do this, always do the expect assertions always test out that
your assertions are being tested.
So let's finish this off.
Let's add a few more lines.
We'll say that in here.
We're going to add to assertions and again, we want to return here.
And we'll add another assertion that says that we expect data.
Dot.
Results.
To have a length.
And what can we use here?
We want to check maybe that the results we get at least five people or that the length is greater than,
let's say, five.
Luckily for us, there's they just cheat sheet and this just cheat sheet.
Well, try to say that fast five times.
That's pretty hard actually has all these things that you can use for the test right in here.
Super, super useful.
These are pretty much all you need to write the perfect test.
And we see here that we have the to be greater than method.
So let's use that.
I'm going to say to be greater then.
And again, this is why I love Jast and most assertion libraries.
They just make everything very nicely in English.
So you understand exactly what's going on.
So I'm going to say to be greater than five, let's save.
All right, we get a few hours, so let's fix this test to assertions to be called, but we only got
one.
Why is that?
And I get an error length of undefined.
And let's log out data to see what we're getting here.
So let's do console dialog.
DataDot results.
And I'm getting on to find so it looks like over here.
Oh, there you go.
I've noticed Meyer, I misspelled results here.
You're probably laughing at me right now, but this happens a lot more than you think.
All right.
So let's see that.
That's good.
We're getting some response.
Let's remove the council log.
It's safe and again, this is another good reason to retest, right, because I wouldn't have caught
that mistake until I've actually run the app.
So I see here that I just have a simple.
Type air.
To be greater, then again, terrible at English.
This is an.
All right, everything is passing, and what you just witnessed is how tests usually work, they're
constantly breaking, they constantly breaking, and you try to get to this green state.
And when you get to this green state, it's like, hallelujah, this is so nice.
It feels so good to have everything green and things are working awesome.
All right, I think that's good for now in the next video, I want to talk to you a little bit about
mocking.
I'll see in that one by.