Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we're going to migrate over all of these different references to context inside of our
components that we found over so that we can now use the bindings in Redux because we've migrated the
cart over.
There's actually a strategy you can use to approach which of these to change first based on which components
are able to have references that will open it up for us to we can access further ones.
An example for this is that we know that everything now that references car context is no longer working
because we've removed the car provider that we had before from our index.
Yes.
So the first thing that we should probably hook up is any places that have the most high level access
that will then unveil for us the remainder of the code.
For example, we can't really see the CART dropdown unless we can open the cart dropdown.
So what this means is that inside of our navigation, we probably want to do this first so that we can
actually set is open or is not open.
So to begin, let's get rid of any references to use context as well as the car context.
And then what we'll do is we will import in what we need from our appropriate store folder so we know
we need is cart open.
This is going to be a selector that we have inside of our cart selectors.
So let's go up into the appropriate file for cart selector and here we'll say select is cart.
Open.
We also need use selector, which we already have when we did our current user.
So here I'm going to say is car open is equal to use selector.
Passing in select is cart open.
Now let's save our code.
And what we know now is that we can see the cart drop down as long as his car open is true or false.
So the binding there works.
But the next thing we need to do is actually make it so that we can set that value is car open.
So to do that, more have to do is go into our car icon and we'll have to remove our reference to car
context, use context and import in our dispatch.
So here we know we have his card open as well as reading his car open and cart count.
So that means we also will need use selector because we have to select off the car count value and is
car open.
What we need now next is we have to impart in the appropriate selectors as well as action traders.
So let's first go up to the appropriate folder.
Of store.
And then carte.
And then we need one for our card selector and we need one for our cards.
Actions.
So let's think about which ones we need here.
We need cart count.
So let's get select cart count.
And also we need select is cart open.
As for our action creators, we just need our set is carte open.
And here.
Now, we don't need this anymore.
We can just make sure that we get, first off, the cart count value, which is equal to use selector
passing in select cart count.
And then we also need our dispatch, because we will be dispatching our action creators.
And we can now say, hey, this toggle method right here that we already have.
What it will do is it will say set is open is a.
Action creator.
So we know we have to dispatch this.
So let's just wrap this inside of our dispatch.
As for is car open we can get this value using our selector for select is car open.
And there we go.
That's all we need.
So now what we should be able to do is at least open and close the cart dropdown.
So if we go back to our application.
We see, that's exactly what we get.
Next step, we need to set up our cart dropdown so that it can actually show the values.
So inside of our card drop down component, I'm going to get rid of cart context again as well as use
context.
And here we see that we just need cart items.
So I'm going to import in use selector from React Redux.
And then as far as the actual selector goes, I need to select cart items.
From the card selector.
And here I'm just going to say, I get my car items.
From U selector passing in.
Select card items.
But in order for us to actually get car items into this car dropdown, we need to make sure our product
card is able to actually dispatch the add items cart.
So here once again, let's get rid of our cart contexts.
And what we know we need is pretty much just the add item to cart action.
So I'm going to import in use dispatch because as we know, every single one of our actions needs to
be dispatched.
And then I'm going to import in our add item to cart method.
Which comes from the appropriate folder inside of our store once again.
So let's go to store cart.
Action.
And let's just make sure that this is the right method.
So here I'm going to go into this file.
And down here we see that it is at items a cart.
So this is indeed the correct name.
And then all I need to do.
Is get rid of this context.
Bring in dispatch using the used dispatch hook and then just making sure that we dispatch out our action
creator that had the same name as our old function.
So now I should be able to do is add items.
But here we see items that find is not a function.
So something we've done is a little off.
Let's go back and check.
Inside of here we call add item to cart and as we notice, we need to pass and cart items into our actual
action creator.
So we were not doing that, but we knew that we had to do this when we set up the actual action creator.
So in order to get this value, what we'll have to do is get in the car items that is currently inside
of a retail store.
So we'll need to bring in use selector and also import in.
The appropriate car item selector.
Select cart items like soap.
And now I can just say contact cart items is equal to use selector.
Calling select card items.
And then I'll just pass cart items into add item to cart like so because the first argument is the current
card items.
This is the one that we need to add.
And now if I go back to the application and let's refresh.
There we see we got the appropriate actions firing and here we see that we are indeed getting our correct
values.
So at this point now we've migrated everything we need inside of the main application except for the
actual checkout components.
So you've seen me do it.
If you haven't done it, try it out yourself.
If any of this seems confusing, again, we practice and implement it and got it out and then move it
over again, as I mentioned.
You want to think about the migration strategy.
You want to pick the components that you need to unlock through the first surface level of the migration.
And then as you go deeper, you're able to actually access those and modify them as well.
So fix up the checkout and then join me in the next video where we'll do it together.