Welcome back, everyone.
So I know we're spending a lot of time with such day, and you might be wondering if let's just build
Monster's Rolodex.
But I really think this forms a great, solid foundation moving forward of really understanding the
code that you're writing and how reacts engine works at a high level.
If we build the solid foundation of just understanding how through set state and state and this class
component that react determines when to render or render a component, we really can very quickly understand
all of the other nuances of components and react, as well as why something is working or not working
and just the general flow of everything.
Because as I mentioned with React, it's really just all about components and how and when they render
or we render with such state.
I showed you earlier that when we just passed the object, we do a shallow merge, which in turn React
does do an update.
But inside of this same function, so the same callback that we gave to on click.
We also did a console.log dot this dot state.
And yet, for some reason, once this console.log ran, we were seeing our old state object and not
the new one.
So just to clarify, when we refresh here, what we should begin with is high.
Using this should be the initial state, which it is, as we see demonstrated in the UI.
But I click change name UI updates to Andre Aniagwu.
But for some reason, the console.log still shows the previous Why is this?
So this again actually has to do with the way that React does its re render, which is where Re rendered
our component.
However, with this set state call, what's happening here with the shallow merge is that this is actually
happening asynchronously.
So typically what JavaScript code code happens in asynchronous manner, meaning that it runs one by
one by one by one.
In this particular case, we're expecting that within our callback that we update the states and then
we console.log this start state.
But clearly, as we see this is getting run first.
However, the state is not being updated when this console.log runs, meaning that the state at this
point is still the previous one.
Why is this is because React batches these different sets state calls so that it can determine what
the most optimal strategy for re rendering the website is going to be.
What do I mean by this?
Well, let's say you imagine that you have an application where you have a lot of different components
and perhaps through one interaction, one button click, you're actually updating the state in multiple
components, not just this one, because inside of here, we have one component right now with one state,
but you can imagine how in a more complex app, one interaction might update the state of multiple different
components.
In that case, React doesn't want to just completely isolate and do all those different updates independently.
RAC wants to figure out if it can stack these together, or maybe there's a more optimal way of updating
these components so that it is more performance.
That's all what React is doing under the hood for us.
So as a result, set state as a call is a non synchronous call.
It's an asynchronous call, meaning that when consort log, which is asynchronous call, gets called
at this point, the state might not be updated.
It may or it may not be.
Chances are it's not.
So you might be wondering then?
Well, with such state, then what if I want to use the latest state after I've updated it inside of
my code?
Somehow, like in our case, I want to console.log and make sure that my state is up to date.
Now we can achieve this where instead of passing this object to such state, we can pass it a function.
So in this format, there's actually a different way.
So as I mentioned, we can pass it a function.
And what we can also pass, it is a callback, so these are two different arguments that you can pass
to set date.
If you pass it like this, you'll actually be able to get a more consistent synchronous behavior.
Not really, but just at least one where we anticipate what's going to happen.
So let me break this down, so I'm going to comment this up.
So this first function is a updater function.
The first function that you passed a set state here is going to be some function where you return an
object that it will then use to shallow merge against state.
So this is kind of very similar to what we did before.
When we just passed the object that we wanted to shall emerge again state as the argument to set state.
But now instead, we're passing a function that returns.
This object that we want to again shall emerge.
So you might be wondering, what's the point of doing this additional function?
Well, the reason why we do this is because within this function, we get access to state as well as
props, props I'm going to cover later.
But state at this current moment, this state variable that we have access to is equal to the current
state.
And the reason why we want to use this is because sometimes we want to maybe update our state based
on the previous value of the state.
Props, on the other hand, is something that does with components.
It's different values that you can pass to your component, and we're going to do a whole separate lesson
on that and deeper understand it.
For now, just understand that you don't really need it right now.
But if you wanted to utilize props somehow inside of your state, you can do so.
But again, don't worry about it.
These are both optional, as you can see right here.
I'm not even going to use it.
I'm just going to use the return where I passed the object that I want to have.
So let's just save this and see if it still works.
So if we go back here, we see using a head change name.
It's updated to Andre Nagwa.
So just like we saw earlier, this is doing that same state update as we had before reactor's registering.
Oh, it's a different object in memory.
I can now re render, which we saw, but I mentioned earlier that we want to see the console.log show
the correct value.
Well, that's actually what this second argument is.
This function that we wrote this callback.
Again, as I mentioned, a callback is just a function that my code says, Oh, once I'm finished,
I want you to run this callback.
So here inside of this function, we can write whatever we want, and I'm just going to console.log
the new states of the Star State and what happens here is that this console.log inside of this function,
this function is going to run only after all of the state changes have been applied, meaning that only
one react has determined in its asynchronous manner.
Oh, I've updated shall emerge the state and now the state is the new object, then I'm going to run
this callback function.
So now if we save this and we go back now, if I hit change name, what we'll see is that we have the
correct newly updated state.
And this format is actually the ideal optimal way that you should be writing your set state code in
class components.
The reason for this is just because by doing this, it's much more clear what's happening.
You don't have to use the previous state or the props values.
As I mentioned, we're definitely not doing that here.
But in this way, anyone looking at it just anticipates and understands what's going to happen.
It's going to understand that, oh, this object, just like before, is just going to be the thing
that gets shallow merged, but also that this follow up callback, if there is one, is going to run
only after the state is fully updated, which makes it much easier to think about what's going to happen.
You don't have to consider, Oh my God, at this current moment, is my code actually updated or not?
You know for sure that React is handling that.
The moment that the state is up to date is only when this callback is going to get run.
Now again, this callback is also entirely optional.
You don't have to pass it.
You can just pass it this function if you don't want to run a callback after state updates.
There's nothing wrong with that.
If we refresh and we clear out our console, we change name.
Our code still just works.
So this is just a very key thing to understand, except state and how react determines when to update,
when to batch things, to make it more performant.
And also when to run after it's updated the state.
And this is really all it is.
I know there's a lot that we learned about such state and we're going to get a lot of practice.
So don't worry, we're going to practice with it.
We're going to get familiar with it so that as we build out Monster's Rolodex, it'll become like second
nature to you about using set state.
I know I talked a lot about that state and it's really boring and really technical, but now we can
start using that state to actually build our monster's Rolodex application.
And as promised, I'm also going to talk about props and how that gets involved as well.
So in the next video, let's start building out our application.