Welcome back.
Now, one thing you may have noticed, if you're really paying attention, is that these tests are fine
for now because the swab API is fairly fast and we're getting the data back fairly soon.
But imagine if we had many of these tests.
Imagine if we had APIs that return lots of data that takes a long time to actually get to.
You can imagine this growing bigger and bigger until it takes forever for our test to run.
I mean, it only took two point five five seven seconds, but with more and more tests worth more and
more asynchronous tests that we wait to actually get a data response, it's going to take longer and
longer.
And if we're developers and working and saving our work constantly, if we have to wait a couple of
minutes for our tests every time, that's really going to slow us down.
How can we improve this so that we're not always doing this fiscal.
Well, we can use something called Mock's with a mock.
We can fake a function and just pretend to have it running.
So that we can use this mock to let us spy on the behavior of a function that is called indirectly by
some other code, rather than just testing the output and waiting for the asynchronous code to complete.
And you can create mosques and just really, really easily so let's do that, let's create a mosque
here to speed up our asynchronous test.
The first thing we're going to do, let's create more space here, I'm going to again create a new test.
We'll just call this get.
People.
Returns count and results.
And in here, we'll do the same thing, second parameters, a function.
Now we're going to create something interesting, we're going to mock this fetch because.
First of all, note fetch is a third party library, and if we've really tested out the library code
and we checked the GitHub repo and they have tests, we don't need to test that it works.
We can assume that the fetch function works as intended.
So let's just do a mock fetch.
And Mark Fitch, and this is going to be a variable, so let's just say cost, we can mark the fetch
and the way we can do that in just again, if you remember, this is something that Cosworth just mock
spies and stuffs.
Otherwise, if you're using something like Moka, you'd use Sinon.
But with just so we can just do just dot.
Then for function.
And we can do something called again, this is all in their documentation, we can do something called
mock return value and we can just return something as if this fish function was called.
So what does a fetch function usually return?
Well, we know that it returns a promise, and let's just for now say that it's always going to resolve.
So that is a resolved promise.
And inside of this resolve, let me make this on a new line just so we can see it better.
That's better and here, man, let's make this a little bit smaller.
We want to resolve to an object that is Jason.
Because if you remember, we always have to do the dot then response dot, Jason, so we can just mock
this whole thing out.
We can say that, Jason, so the object that we return is going to be a promise, so we're going to
resolve a promise with the Jason method.
And this method, again, is a.
Promise, so, again, promise and resolve and this promise, again, this part we're doing this the
Jason.
And then we get the data so we can say that within the resolve we'll have.
Count equals eighty seven, and the results will be let's just create an array that says zero one,
two, three, four or five.
Let's say this and.
Get a bit of a syntax error, let's fix that.
We have an unexpected token, and I forgot to come over here.
Classic commas, they always get me.
All right, so now we just mocked the festival instead of calling this get people promise and wait for
the data and get the data account data, the results, we're actually just doing that automatically,
assuming that the API works so we can just test our other parts of the function again.
Because this is still asynchronous, we're returning a promise to remember.
Well, want to do a return?
Swaby don't get people.
Now, let's you get people promise, and in here we can, instead of the fish, do the mock fetch,
we're mocking the function that is fetch.
And this is how when we test, we can use dependency injection to make sure that we're testing different
functionality and you might remember this from integration tests, but without actually using up all
these resources, we're trying to be as smart as possible.
Now we can have the dot then and we're going to receive the data just like we did up above over here.
Now, within here, let's do a few tests we want to expect.
The mock fetch, that's right, because we use just fine, we now have an ability to listen in because
in jest, this is also a spy.
We can spy on this and see what this function did inside of this function.
So what did Moch fetch do inside of get people promise.
I can say expect Moskvitch Dock Mock again.
This is in the documentation to have a calls.
So how many times has this been called.
I'm going to say lenth, so the number of times it's been called.
To be one.
Let's save.
And this is passing, but remember, with asynchronous tests, we want to always do the expect.
Dot.
Assertions to make sure that they're being called so in this case, we only have one.
Everything works if I change this to zero.
That fails because we actually did call the Mark Fish this function called the mock fish once a very
cool.
What else can we do?
Well, another thing we can do now.
Let me just copy this.
We can expect Mark fetch.
Have another method called to be called with.
And we can test to see what this was called with in our case, it should be called with this you URL.
So, again, let's put it in here.
Let's test this out.
I'm going to save.
Oh, and I actually did make a mistake and we want to do expect.
Again, Dimmock fetch to have been called with the euro, the safe o and remove the bracket.
All right, it's actually passing by, remember, our associates is now expecting two things, so I'm
going to save.
Do you see how it took a little bit more time this time, again, because we're repeatedly calling this
API, it's taking a little bit more time this time, three point ninety one seconds.
But with the mark, because we're returning, we're doing promised that resolve right away, it's a
lot faster and that's passing.
If for some reason I change this to and I call we expected to call planets instead.
We see that it fails because we expect to get people to actually get the people, not the planets.
Very cool.
All right, let's do a few more.
Well, let's just add again, copy and pasting and testing is not bad.
Let's just copy and paste this and expect that things work the exact same as they did in the above with
the regular fetch, but this time with our mock so we can save go back.
And I have a test feeling because now our assertion number is four.
We're who everything is passing, and if I change this count to eighty nine.
And I changed this to eighty nine, but let's say to be greater than 10, it should fail.
Because our results only have six items.
There you go.
But if I change this to greater than five.
Our tests are passing.
Very, very cool.
And there you have it.
Other than learning a few methods.
Such as to be greater than or to equal, which you can always check, and the documentation when you
write a test, everything is pretty simple, right?
Once you get the hang of it.
We have a synchronous tests that are very, very easy and we just have and expect assertion.
And then we have a Synchronoss test that we just have to remember to return and make sure that we have
access to the promise, whatever it returns, and then we can also to avoid long running asynchronous
code such as API calls or maybe even a database call to mock and mock functions also known as spies.
And just because they let you spy on the behavior of the function.
Is called by our test, and it's going to spy on what is happening and you saw that get people promise
actually runs this mock fish that we created.
And all you need is this syntax.
And here we just added extra things because we wanted a certain behavior, but even just doing this,
we could have seen that mock fetch would have been called with this URL.
Just as an awesome, awesome tool, if you work with other libraries, you'll see a lot of the similarities.
Like I said, Mock's Stobbs and spies can also be seen and sign on, especially if you work with Moka.
But overall, the principles are the same.
And you can see that tests can be fun because we're just testing logic and nothing feels better than
getting all these green passes.
All right, that's it for now.
I think it's time for us to get into some riak testing and testing our robo friends up.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.