Welcome back, everyone, in this video, we're going to break down this warning, which says that each
child in a list should have a unique key property.
What does this mean?
A key property is just a property on the actual.
You can see it as a template or you can see it as the element HTML that we're returning from our map.
In this particular case, it's the one rack just saying, Hey, I want you to give me a key property,
which is some unique string value, or it could be an integer.
It doesn't matter.
React is going to turn into a string either way.
So here, if we know that, let's say, for example, our names are currently unique, then we could
pass it a name value.
This will work in our current context, but you can imagine that there might be a case where if we had
a thousand people, one of these names might overlap, we might have two different monsters named Frank.
If that's the case, well, then this is no longer unique.
So what we need to do is actually use a unique value, and most of the time a unique value is going
to be an ID.
So when most projects in most APIs and almost everything where you're getting some kind of data, they'll
have an ID value, which is some kind of string that's like very complicated.
And usually it's extremely complicated in a way that no two of these strings is identical, making them
completely unique.
And this is what we're going to use inside of our key value.
So instead of monserrat name, we're going to say monstered ID.
So you might be wondering, well, you are.
Why do we need this key value?
This again goes back to react and re rendering.
This key value is actually something that REAC uses in order to make it more optimized when it comes
to updating and re rendering components on your page.
On this page, we now have one app component, yes, but we have four different ones that React has
rendered onto the page for us if we inspect.
What we see is that inside of our app, which is the div, which is our component, we have these four
ones.
But React won't actually update this dom directly, as we've seen before, when we, let's say, add
more to our components.
In this particular case, how does react actually differentiate Linda from Frank, from Jackie, from
Andre, these different ones?
The only way it can do it is by using the key value.
And why is that important?
You might be asking.
Well, let's say, for example, what we did is we updated the name of Jackie to something else like
Yehuda, for example.
When react, does that, does that mean that reaction now re render every single one in this entire
list?
Or should it just re render Jackie so that now it says Iowa?
In order for Iraq to do that, it needs to be able to properly differentiate these different components
from each other because as I mentioned, these components are all using the same template.
So how does react actually differentiate them and know that when Jackie got updated to what only Jackie
needs to be up to date?
Well, it uses that key value, that unique key value that associates that component to that bit of
data.
That is the purpose of the key.
So we'll talk more about this when we start building a more verbose website.
But for now, that's why whenever you use Dot Map and you map out a list of HDMI html elements, you
want to make sure that the top level the very highest one.
So let's say if this one.
Actually, let's make this a div.
And inside of this div, we have an H1.
We want to make sure that at the highest level of this element, which is the death that we add this
key.
And I we go back.
We'll see that each of these are divs with the ones you might be wondering, well, I added the key,
but is it not showing up inside of the elements?
Well, this is actually something unique for React.
React is going to be the only thing that needs that key value.
The regular HTML when it actually gets you built doesn't need the keyboard, so ract takes it off.
But it knows under the hood it's keeping track of this key.
And using this key again is able to be much more performant and efficient when it comes to differentiating
these components from each other and then figuring out which ones to render appropriately when their
values update.
That's the whole point of the key.
So now that we understand this key, let's now move our application towards something that's much more
typical of what we would expect instead of hard coding this array of monsters.
Let's fetch it from an API somewhere in the next video before we talk about that.
I'm going to talk about some of the higher concept of why that's important when it comes to react and
single page applications.
So I'll see you in the next video.