Welcome back, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to talk about how to get arrays of information from somewhere that is not
just hardcoded on our website.
So let's think about applications for a second.
Right now, this array is hardcoded on our React application.
The only way that this code can be updated is if we update this directly using some JavaScript code
as we saw or if we manually update it through typing.
Almost all applications don't do this when it comes to any kind of dynamic information.
This is dynamic because these values can change.
We could get new users, we could get less users.
You can imagine on Facebook they get millions of new users or users changing their data every single
day.
It would be completely unrealistic to have that all hardcoded inside of their recode.
In fact, what they have to do is they have all of that user data living in a database somewhere and
then whenever their application needs it, they will then ask that database for that information and
then use it to populate their website.
Right now, what we're doing is we are hard coding in the website.
We're not actually calling it from any database.
And that's what we want to change.
But before we go into that, we need to talk a little bit about single page applications and why it
is that a react application as a single page application makes this whole process way easier.
So let's break down a little bit of how websites work before and after SBA's SBA stand for single page
applications and use frameworks kind of like react and angular and view to help build them.
So what we're building is a spa.
Whenever we work with React now, there are, of course, some nuances.
Once you start doing things like server side rendering or even static page rendering when you do things
like Gatsby, which is a react framework for static pages.
But as far as our application goes and this course with React, we're just focused on building our space.
But before we understand space, we need to talk a little bit about the world before us space.
So let's say you have a website.
In this particular case, let's imagine you are navigating to zero to Mastery I o, which is our website,
when you navigate there, what happens is that you actually need some code and in a non spa environment,
your browser doesn't actually know how to build this website.
So what it has to do, it has to ask for the code from some kind of server.
Now the server is going to host all of the HTML, CSS and JavaScript required to build your entire website.
So your browser is going to go, Oh, I need to access zero to mastery.
I o what do I need?
I need the home page.
So you're going to make a request to the server and say, Can you give me the code for the home page?
So the server is going to say, OK, send you back the required HMRC s s and JavaScript needed to build
the home page and then your browser takes that and actually creates the UI and the page that the user
is trying to access.
Similarly, what happens if you try to navigate now to zero to mastery IO slash react?
Well, this is a different page entirely.
So the code that we had before for the home page, not all of it is relevant.
So what again, what's going to happen is the browser is going to make another request to the same server
and say, Hey, someone's trying to access the React page, can you give me the code for that?
And the server says OK, and it will give off the required HTML, CSS and JavaScript files for the React
page, which your browser then uses and builds that page.
This is very familiar if you were using websites pre 2010.
Nowadays, there's very few websites that kind of have this interaction, but you might remember before
that there was a brief white page when you are navigating between pages on a website, which was when
your browser was actually making a request on the network to a server and getting that code, which
is why there was that white page, because essentially that's the time it takes for the network request
to ask and then receive and then build the web page.
Now, in an s.p.a environment, this is completely different.
Similarly, you're still going to ask the browser, Hey, I want to access zero to mastery dial, so
for the very first time, there will still be a request to the XHTML server because at this point,
your browser doesn't have the code for XHTML.
Oh, so it's going to make that request.
The server and the server is going to send back the same thing, some html, some yes, and some JavaScript.
But now remember, our web site is an ISP, meaning that it was built with react.
So this JavaScript code actually contains the React code, as well as the React library and all the
stuff that we wrote in order to build the website.
So now what's going to happen is that our web site, our browser, is going to take that code, build
out that home page.
And now, just like before, everything here is the same.
You have your home page, everything is built with the code that we got from the server.
But now, when you navigate to XHTML, I'll slash react.
We still have all of that JavaScript and REAC code and now react isn't need to go and ask the server
for more code.
Instead, using this real code, it itself is going to build the CFSAN HTML pages required for the React
page.
And this is the big difference.
We no longer need to go to the server for the code whenever we navigate and change pages.
Anything that you see on a web site that is an spa or built in react, what's happening is that components
are getting stripped off.
They're getting put on.
They're getting created.
They're getting destroyed.
All those processes are happening live on the browser.
Once we get that initial bundle of code that contains our React code and this is what makes react so
powerful, because now we no longer have any more of those white pages and there's no more additional
requests the server for page related code.
This is not entirely true in the future once we start doing really, really customize optimizations.
But for now and the majority of space, that's the main difference you need to think about.
Any of those optimizations are further down the line way further down the line.
You don't have to worry about that right now.
Right now, all you need to know is that through nzrpa, we're able to get the entire bundle of our
React code and our website code in one shot.
So let's talk about what we are trying to do with our monstrous Rolodex.
As I mentioned, we already are writing some of this code required to build the monster's Rolodex website.
We don't really have any pages at this point.
We have our home page, which is going to display all those monsters.
And then we're going to really just sift through them using a search bar.
But right now, we don't actually have all those monsters because we're just hard coding them.
So what we need to do is we need to access those users from some kind of user API.
We're going to ask an external API, which is going to give us back a list of those users that we will
then use in order to build out the list so that code that we have hardcoded instead, we want to get
that from an API somewhere.
Not only do we have to get it from an API somewhere, we have to learn how to actually bring it into
our React application so that we can use it.
So that's what we're going to cover in the next video, and I'll see you there.