Welcome back, everyone.
So here is the website that we want to use in order to get our list of users.
The website will display all of this as JSON, which is pretty much just objects of users with certain
attributes on them.
So there's an idea, there's a name, there's a username, there's email, there's address, and then
there's some other extra information.
Well, we really care about for now is just that.
There's a name and there's an ID.
We need the name to display and we need the I.D. because it is the key I fully remember.
So what we're going to do is we are going to make a request to this website, which will give us back
this array of JSON objects so very easy.
If you want this, it's actually going to be in your Reasons folder, so it's very easy to access.
And what I want you to do is I want you to copy this and then what we need to do now is figure out how
to bring this array into our React application.
So let's go back to our application and let's think about a couple of things that we need to do before
we even start coding it.
First off, what we need to do is think about where we're going to leverage the actual array once we
get it inside component.
We've actually already thought about this with our monsters array.
So what we want to do is we want to update the state of monsters to the array of users.
Once we get them from the API, here we have some hardcoded values.
But in reality, I actually don't want that because when you think about it, why would I want to use
any hardcoded values at all?
I just want to use what values come from the API.
My application should not have to worry about what that data looks like or not what it looks like,
but whether or not I get how much data, that's not something our application should be largely concerned
with.
Of course, there are certain things like there are edge cases where if it's empty, do you want to
display some kind of message that tells the user that there are no users that have been fetched?
Perhaps.
But that's not what I'm talking about here.
I'm talking about the initial state of this monster's array.
If you think about it, if you have an application that makes a request for a bunch of users, if you,
let's say, fail in the middle of that API request, let's say your network cuts off or there some corrupted
data or something that is not related to our application.
What would you want to do?
What would it matter for a user to see?
The user should not see anything that they should just see the fact that there is an empty array, meaning
that nothing should display them because nothing was properly fetched.
That is the typical behavior of most applications.
So in this case with our states, we want to think about what's known as the empty case or the null
case.
So what happens when you have an initialized state or when you have a state that has nothing in it?
So I'm told about these state variables.
Of course, a monster's here is a list of users.
So what's an empty version of that?
Well, it's an empty list or an empty array.
So we want to initialize these values as empty.
Once this is empty, now, what I want to do is I want to actually get that list of users.
And the way I'm going to do that is I need to think, when do I get the list?
How do I get the list?
Where do I put the list?
We already talked about where it's going to be in our state.
But how do I get the lists?
This is actually where React is going to give us these things known as lifecycle methods.
So when you think about a component, I've always mentioned that a components key thing and react is
just figuring out when it renders and when it re-enters.
So if our monster's array is empty, when we get the new list of array from our API, we want to update
the state object and therefore we want to re render this component.
But when do we want to get that information we want to get at the moment the app is actually mounted
or the moment it's rendered by React because we want to display the users as soon as possible in order
to do that.
We leverage lifecycle methods on this component class that reactor's given us, and these different
methods are listed here, you'll see in my dropdown.
There's a bunch of them, but the most important one is really component did Mount and component did
update and probably also come on at will on Mount, but we'll talk about these a little later.
We'll focus on component did Mount.
So component amount is a method that you have access to and inside, you want to write your coat and
whatever you right here will get run whenever the component mounts.
Mounting is the first time a component gets placed onto the top.
So the first time React renders a component onto the page that is mounting.
It only happens once through a components life.
The only time when a component might reach mount is if it's been on Mount it, meaning it's been completely
removed from the dome, and you could almost argue that it's a different component.
It might be the same app component or the same component we're using, but it's a new instance of it.
So we'll talk more about that as well as we start building out a more complex application.
But for now, just understand that the moment your component gets placed onto the DOM is when you want
to make an API request for something like users, because that's when you want to get that information
so we can display it as soon as possible.
So remember, if you need to make an API request so that your component can have the appropriate data
it needs in order to render the appropriate things.
That's when you want to put it in component that mount.
So instead of component that mounts.
How do we actually fetch from that API?
Well, we're going to use the native fetch and native fetch.
What we do is we give it the URL that we need in order to get that JSON.
So here I'm going to paste that in again.
You'll find that in your resources folder.
Once we fetch this, this is going to be a promise, and a promise is something that is asynchronous
in JavaScript.
It's essentially a promise that eventually I'm going to have a value.
We can talk more about promises in a video in the appendix, where if you're not really familiar with
it, it's a good time to watch that after this video so that you can get a deeper understanding.
But all you need to know is that what's going to happen is JavaScript is going to fetch what data it
can from here.
If it succeeds, it's going to come back and then we can call then on that value, meaning that now
we have a response back from that API request and this we want to pass a callback where the argument
is the response itself.
So the response that they give us.
Let's take a quick look at it.
So I want you to see what we're going to get.
We're going to go to our application.
We're going to open up our console.
And again, it's empty because you remember I took out all the monsters, so there's nothing in our
natural state.
But here we got a response back and inside you see, it's just this object and it has a lot of stuff
in it.
There's headers and there's like the status of whether or not it was successful, which it was.
There's the URL in which we fetched it from.
But primarily what we want is we want this in JSON format.
So what we're going to say is that, OK, I want you to return from this dot then.
This response, Dodgson, some converting this over into Jason, and this is what is being returned
from the start that.
Every day then that returns, a value is going to return another promise that has been resolved.
So here I can actually say then again.
And what I have now is the users.
And let's just quickly console.log this as well.
So remember, whatever got returned from response that Jason is going to get passed to this users as
the argument of our call back.
So if I save this, I come here.
There we see it.
If I just refresh just so you're familiar.
You'll see that this is the array of the users that we got from Jason Placeholder.
It's exactly what we're expecting.
So now that we have this, let's actually get this in our state, which we can do using said state as
we've done before.
So let's get rid of this console.log.
And instead, what we're going to say is this starts at state and here you can either pass at the object
where monsters points to users or you can use the function method.
So I'm going to use the function method and I'm going to return back an object where monsters now points
to users.
And the reason why I want to use this function method is just so that I can also pass it.
The callback when this set state is finished, just so that I can make sure that my state has the correct
value.
So now, if we go back to our code, what we see is that we do indeed have all of our users in here.
Let me refresh.
And we also see that we are logging out our new state with the appropriate monsters, with the appropriate
values.
So everything here is working.
And the key thing I want you to focus on and what we learned was that whenever we have a component,
a class component specifically, that needs to leverage some kind of API call in order to get data that
it needs in order to display the appropriate UI, you want to put that inside of your component.
Did Mount lifecycle method.
Now there are definitely more lifecycle methods that will cover in later lessons.
For now, though, I just want you to focus on component at Mount and mounting of the component in the
next video.
I'm going to go a little deeper into these three methods that we've seen, which is the constructor
component and mount and the render method because there is an order here that is important when it comes
to how this component is getting added and react, determining when to run the code inside each of these.
So in the next video, we'll cover that so that you can understand deeper how a class component works.
See in the next video.