Welcome back.
If you remember our talk about testing, I mentioned that React has these two special features that
you often see in their tests.
One is the enzyme library, which allows us to render our components in a test environment, which we
saw.
And then we can use whatever expect methods that we want from just to actually test whatever is render,
but there's also another thing called the snapshot testing.
And again, this is another really good tool that comes with just that really, really helps us test
our react components.
So let's talk about that in this video.
If we go back to our app, you might be asking yourself, All right, I can keep going with this car
component and just use the regular just syntax to make sure that the car component has everything that
I need, including maybe in an image tag, a diff tag, some names and emails.
But here's the thing, we worked really, really hard to keep these components, what we call stateless
components, they are not using the class syntax to extend Riak component.
They don't have any state.
They're just pure functions that we've created.
So if we're actually writing tests.
I bet we're going to repeat a lot of code here, we're always going to just be testing if this guy render
if this guy rendered.
And that's a lot of repeated work for a developer.
Well, just realize that this would be a lot of redundant, wasted time, wouldn't it be great if we
can just take a snapshot of whatever this card component renders and any time while we're writing our
car component, anything changes and the component doesn't look as we expected it to as the snapshot
that we took a picture of.
Well, if it looks any different, then we fail the test.
That's what snapshot testing is and it's really easy.
Let me demonstrate and you'll see how simple it is.
Let's go back to our car test here.
Instead of doing the length to equal one and many other tests that we can right here, let's do something
different here.
I'm going to right.
Expect we're going to shallow card.
And since we're not using render and mount here, let's just remove that from our imports.
Now, we've rendered the card component in just we can use snapshot testing to say to match.
Snapshot.
That's it.
So what does this do?
Well, let's save here.
And see what just happened.
We have a snapshot summary that showed up, it says One snapshot written in one in one test suite.
And we see that it passed.
That's good, but one thing you may have noticed is that we now have a folder.
A snapshot folder that magically appear just by running this method.
If I open this up.
I see that just took a snapshot.
And you can read out more about it here, but it looks like a text file, a plain text file that has
all these things, you see these shallow wrapper object here that has of length one.
It has the class name that we have in our d'Hiv, if I keep scrolling down.
We see that we have a ton of information.
Such as the type of div, we also have a type of P, a paragraph.
Now, what does this actually mean?
This took a picture of this component when we shallow rendered it so that now I can keep saving.
Let's say I'm working on my app, working on the card component and I keep saving, keep saving.
But I decide to remove this tech center tachyons glass that it has.
I'm going to change that and save that.
Now, my tests fail and it says one snapshot test failed.
Because we've just changed what the snapshot expected, the car component to render.
How cool is that magically detects any changes.
And if, let's say, a developer comes in and messes up our car component, the test will immediately
fail.
We see that expect to rent your car component is failing.
That's very, very cool, and it even tells you where the changes have made.
This is the same with, let's say we're by mistake, not rendering our component our email of the robot.
If I save this, we see that we're missing a few things.
Very cool.
Now, let's go back to having the email here.
Let's save it.
OK, everything is passing, but let's say that well, I actually do not want the tax to be centered.
I do.
This was intentional.
I did want to move the class name.
And make a change to it.
Well, with snapshot testing, if I save this.
We see that we have pressed W to show more.
I'm going to press the WC.
And here we see that we have the option of pressing you to update the failing snapshots, if I press
you here, it's going to take another snapshot and it's going to say, yes, I made this intentionally,
take another snapshot and use that as a reference.
So I'm going to say you and there you go.
My snapshot is now updated.
And if I go back to the way I had it before.
It's not going to fail because it's expecting a different snapshot, the snapshot was just updated in
here.
Now, how simple is that?
It's very, very nice and as a matter of fact, because we've made this card component so simple, is
just a function, a pure function that takes an input and always produces the same output by just using
the snapshot testing.
We don't really need to test anymore.
We're testing exactly what it needs to do, which is make sure that the car component renders whatever
we tell it to render.
And that's the beauty of snapshot testing and creating these small stainless components.
We can have really, really nice tests that are one liners to just run a snapshot test and we've pretty
much covered our bases for the car.
Now, one thing I haven't shown you and let me.
Go back to updating our snapshot here, I want to press you.
Is code coverage.
How do we know that the map snapshot or the.
To match snapshot is actually.
Fully testing the car component.
Well, I can run NPM.
Test, dash, dash space, dash, dash coverage, and it's going to show media coverage report.
And let me make this a little bit bigger so we can see.
Look at that, we have absolutely zero tests other than perhaps the set up test.
But that's because we're not doing anything in that file.
So there's not much to test here.
But if we look at card component, even though all the other components have just zero percent, zero
percent test coverage card component now has a 100 percent code coverage.
How cool is that one simple line and we've covered our bases with the card component.
Again, I'm going to keep saying this throughout these videos, but writing tests shouldn't be complicated.
Try to structure your application in a way that writing tests are really, really simple.
And the way you do that is by writing these pure functions that keep things simple.
And you don't have these massive functions that do a ton of things that become harder and harder to
test with more lines of code.
All right, that's it for now, let's keep running some more tests and the next video by.