Welcome back.
Let's use snapshot testing to test some of these other simple presentational components that are completely
stateless since we saw how easy that is.
So let me make this a little bit smaller.
And make sure we run AMPM test to have it running in the background.
We see that our test or our car component is being tested now, so let's create another one.
Let's create a test for the Carlist component.
I'm going to remove the console log here because we don't need it and let's create a Carlist test file.
So a card list, dot test dojos.
And again, it's failing because we need to make sure we have at least a single test.
We can actually go back to card that test us and just copy and paste this, go to Carlist component,
copy and paste.
Whatever we had and just change our component to Cardless.
So let's just do that quickly, we can just select all this and say card list, let me save.
And we have some fails here, let's see why.
We see that we get a type Air Canada property map of undefined, and that is because card list, you
see card component is just rendering name and email, but it's not doing anything to it.
So if it doesn't get name in email, I'll just render undefined.
When we go to card list, we see that we're actually receiving the robots and we need to map over them.
But in our test we're rendering card or let's go to Carlist.
I'm going to close this so we don't get confused.
We're not passing down robots.
So in this test, when we try and render Carlist, it's going to fail because.
There's no robots to map over, so let's fix that.
All we need to do here is just mock our robots so we can just say const.
Robots or leisure say mock robots is going to equal an array of some dummy data that we can create.
So let's say that this is going to have an ID of one.
And we'll have the name of John Snow.
Let's say username.
Is going to be.
John, John, and let's say that email, I don't think we're using your username, but I wanted to give
that username anyway is going to be John at Gmail dot com.
Now we can just pass our mock robots.
As the.
Robots.
So let's see if that works.
I'm going to save.
All right, and we have our tests passing.
And if we go to our snapshot, we see that we have a card list snapshot as well.
That's good, our test failed because we weren't passing robots and, well, we want to make sure that
we actually pass those properties and you can imagine you can probably do the same thing with Card as
well, or maybe have a default in this component where if you don't receive name, email and ID, that
it has some sort of an error boundary or an output that it does for the user.
We now see the power of snapshot testing, we see how we can mock some of our properties, and you might
want to just go ahead and do snapshot testing for some of these other cases that are quite simple to
do to increase our test coverage.
And I'm going to leave that up to you because, well, just to give you a bit of extra practice.
So let's move on to the next video where we do some things that are a little bit more difficult.
But just to check, let's do our coverage to make sure that our coverage for the Carlist is now looking
good.
I want to make this a little bit bigger.
And we see that, yeah, look at that feels good getting 100 percent, doesn't it?
Kahless component is not well tested as well.
I'll see in the next one, bye bye.