Welcome back, everyone.
Just so that we can keep track of all these things we're learning when it comes to our lifecycle methods
and our class component methods, as well as rendering and rendering.
I know it's a lot of new concepts that we're learning at once, which can be confusing.
So just so that we're aware of the order, as I mentioned before, its can structure, then render then
component did mount and have component did mount updates the state another render?
We're just going to update this console.log text so that it shows us the method so that as we build
out this application, we can see very clearly what's happening, and it's really just for your own
familiarity in case you get confused.
So instead of console.log one, we put constructor instead of console.log.
Three, we put component at Mount and instead of console.log.
Two we put render.
So now that we have this, we go back to our application.
We see that when we refresh.
We'll see that our constructor runs than our render runs component, didn't mount runs, then render
runs and then of course, our monsters array gets logged from our callback in our sets, they call.
So everything here is just to recap now moving forward.
Let's talk about how we're actually going to build out this application, and in order to do that,
we've got to talk a little bit about what we're looking to do.
So as I mentioned before, we have these different ones that represent different monsters.
Now, before we actually start styling these h ones to look more like the final product, what we want
to do instead is actually work on functionality.
You always want to work on functionality of your application before you work on the CSS, because once
you have the functionality and it's easier to start afterwards, at least that's the way that I prefer
to do things.
So in order for us to think about the functionality, let's actually take a look at our final product.
What are we trying to work towards?
So here we have these different monster cards, which represent the different monsters in our H1.
So instead of ones, we have cards.
But as I mentioned, that's the styling.
We're not going to work on that.
Instead, we want to add in this search functionality.
So what does the search functionality do?
Well, let's say that you want to find Clementine Bausch as you type it in.
It will filter out the monsters that do not match in name to what we've typed in here for our strengths.
So seemingly only matches two cards Clementine and Clementina.
In fact, if I type out Clementine, it should get rid of Clementina, but as I remove it, it will
bring back anything that does match.
So this is the functionality that we want to add into our monster's Rolodex project.
Another thing to include is also the fact that if we hit this X, it will also clear the search field
and in turn also bring back all the different monsters that were loaded.
So this is the feature that we want to build in.
Now, before we start coding this right away with any feature we're building, we want to think about
what it is that we need to do, because only then do we get a better clear idea of the requirements
of this feature.
And from there, it's the best way to start moving forward and actually comes the planning out, the
code that we want to write.
So what we need and what we're missing is we need an input field, and with this input field, we need
to be able to insert text, so allow the user to type into it and filter out our monsters.
So let's just think about that.
Given what we have, we clearly don't have the input field, so we know we need an input field somewhere.
So let's start with that.
Inside of this app, I'm going to use an input field, and this is just the same input field that you
have inside of HTML.
But one thing I want to mention is that all of these different HTML like GSX tags that we're writing,
the divs, the ones, the inputs or any single HTML tag that you can typically write inside of Iraq
in this GSX.
It looks like HTML.
But it's a little bit more advanced in that what it is really is that it's pretty much a component that
React has already included into the jazz acts.
So just like the components that we're writing, all of these are also components.
An easy way to think about this is that when you look at this app, this class app we know is a class
component.
We've been writing it and we export this out.
But when you look inside of index tags, what's happening is we are importing this app from Dot app,
so we're importing this whole class component that we're writing.
And what we're doing is we are rendering it right here.
But if you look at this, do you notice that this looks like HMO?
Well, this does.
But again, we're still inside of GSX, and the important thing to notice here is that what is happening
is that this app is being written in GSX like an HTML tag, the exact same way that these divs and this
one and these inputs are as well.
And the reason for this, of course, is the fact that React has created these HTML looking components
for us.
For every HTML tag, there is an equal React component.
And the reason why React does this is because it allows us to bind once again functionality to the UI.
So if you think about this input, what do we want to do with this input?
Because with all of these inputs, we typically have a bunch of HTML properties we can provide it.
In fact, any small property you can think of is equally available on these React HTML components.
One thing, though, that I want you to notice is that some of them are named a little differently.
And we can see this explicitly up here in this div.
We notice that instead of class, it's class name.
And the reason why its class name instead of class is because this is written in Joe's X and J X is
a syntax extension of JavaScript, meaning that all of the rules of JavaScript apply to GSX because
you're really just writing JavaScript with some additional functionality and class.
Being a protected keyword in JavaScript means that classes also protect protected keyword inside of
GSX.
When you think about classes, we use it up here, and what it does is it allows us in JavaScript to
create classes as well as class components.
So for this reason, riot cannot just allow us to use class freely inside of our JavaScript because
there's a very key functionality of JavaScript that's tied to class whenever it appears inside of JavaScript
and equally inside of GSX.
So keeping that in mind, that's why its class name.
So if we wanted to give our input a class, then we have to use class name.
And that's exactly how I'm going to do.
So here I'm going to say the class name is equal to search box.
And what other input properties do we want?
Well, we want to give it a type, so we want to say that the type of this input is going to be search.
We also want a placeholder.
So placeholder is going to be the text that shows up inside of an empty search box.
So before the user types in anything, what do we want to put there?
Usually what this text, you want to put some kind of text that explains what it's going to do.
So I'm just going to say that it's going to be search monsters and that text search monsters is going
to show up in that empty input box when users haven't typed in anything yet.
Finally, now what we want to do is we want to actually code in the functionality in order to filter
down this list.
So how do we do this?
Well, typically with inputs, what happens is that you have a change handler that you can bind to an
input.
So this is an event handler very similar to our button.
If you think back to our button, you remember that earlier we had a button that would change the name
inside of our search field, from Yehovah to Andre, and we used the on click handler.
So here instead, we have a similar handler, but every time the value inside of the search box updates
or changes.
And this is the on change handler.
And just like with on click, you get to pass it a callback and this callback runs whenever the value
inside of this input changes.
So what we want to do is we just want to say, OK, what's going to happen every time it changes?
Well, we want to start filtering out the different monsters that we have available.
And luckily for us, just like with this event handler inside of regular HTML JavaScript with Jeff Sachs,
this is pretty much the same event handler.
So what we're going to get back is we are going to get back an event.
So for those of you unfamiliar, let's just quickly console.log this event.
So we see what we receive.
So coming back into our application, we see that we have our input field.
We see we have our placeholder text search monsters.
And now if we start typing in, if I type L, we see we get this synthetic base event.
This event, if you look closely at one of these properties, has an underscore react name.
So this tells us it's a reactive it because React is in here.
In typical any other events that are generated by your browser or your DOM, you would not see underscore
react name.
And the reason for this is because React is generating these events for us with these different methods
that it provides us in those JavaScript HTML components.
The reason for that is just that it makes it easier for us to do this kind of event handling like this
on change handler.
And the reason why there's an underscore is because these are typically the kinds of properties that
react as these events, but they're not for us to access.
We shouldn't be accessing anything with an underscore.
Generally, everything else, though we do want.
And the main thing that we want is target, because inside of Target, other than all of these other
keys and values that you could use, these are going to be mainly valuable because of this value instead
of value.
Here you see, is the string L, which is what we have typed.
Now, if I continue to type.
E!
In the next event, if I check in the target, what we see is that the value is Ali.
And similarly, if I type another A, we see that we're going to get inside of target and value LGA.
So we know that with this, we're now able to actually get the value.
Now this is going to be my challenge to you.
Knowing that we need to use the event, don't target dot value.
I want you to take this and actually try and filter down this list of monsters.
We've done something very similar already.
We know that we need to use this handler to update our state object or our state array for monsters.
What you have to do is figure out how to use this in order to filter it down and to give you a hint,
there's actually an array method called filter that you can leverage for this.
I'm going to include in the resources folder a link to the filter so that you can take a look at it.
But I want you to try and implement it yourself.
Implement a way where as you type, you will filter out these monsters.
So good luck and we'll do it together in the next video.