Welcome back.
Let's do some tests that are a little bit more difficult to do.
We make this a little bit smaller.
Let's just have NPM run test just to have a running in the background, that's always nice.
And let's go into our cards or account or button, because this is a little bit more unique, right?
It's not a stateless component anymore.
We actually have a state with the count.
And, yeah, we have a little bit more logic.
We also have this.
Set state that is happening where we increment our state count and I think in the previous video, I
had this as a separate method that you can call in here for now we can just leave it the way it is.
The idea is that we want to test this state function that it actually increments.
Because that's what you expect from a.
So how are we going to test that?
As we know, the very first step is to actually create a test file, so let's say.
Carnavon.
That test, James.
And the first thing we want to do, well, again, we've already kind of done this before, so I'm going
to copy from the Kahless test.
Let's close some of this just to clean things up.
And copy and paste this.
Now, instead of Cardless were testing the counter button.
And we also don't really need our mock robots anymore.
And this counterman doesn't have any props that it receives.
Well, it has the color prop, actually, so let's just do a const mock color and we'll say that this
mock color would just be red and we'll give it a.
This is an actual component we'll give it a color of.
McCulloh.
Now, here's the thing, even though it's a stateful component, we can still do match snapshot testing
to it.
I mean, it's still a component, so let's save.
And now we have a new snapshot.
Perfect.
So if we ever modify contraband, it's going to erupt.
That's good.
Let's make this a little bit smaller.
All right, let's create a another test in here, and by the way, if you want, you could use the describe
and then group all the tests together, but I've already shown you how to do that.
You can do that on your own if you want to have more organization for your test.
Let's have another test this time that we'll say we want to make sure that a correctly.
Increments the counter.
And again, our usual syntax, and in here we can write tests.
So what can we do?
Well, first, thanks, let's just do a const.
Rapper and this is just going to be the shallow.
Rendering of our component.
And we'll just have a mock color as well that we're going to use, all right, so now that we have this,
instead of just always typing expect and then doing this shallow, we can just say expect wrapper and
we can write more tests that way.
And here, let's say that we want to have rapper DOT find another thing that we get with the enzyme
package, so on the wrapper, just like we would in Jaquie or Querrey, select all we can do something
like find where we find, let's say, the I.D. and this has to be square brackets, actually.
Where we have Edek of.
Counter.
By doing this, I can now go into my Carnavon and just give it an ID of.
Connor.
And we'll make sure that we make the.
Snapshot pass.
And now we can find this ID counter, which is the button now.
And we can do something called simulate.
And we can simulate an event such as a click event, which our economy has an unclick event, so we've
just simulated a click.
On this counterman.
So if we've simulated a click on the counterbattery and the state or the count in the state is zero,
we expect the count now to be one.
So all we would need to do is say expect.
Wrapper, we can use something called state.
So this is going to grab the state and we expect that state to equal.
Count of one.
Let's see if that actually works.
Let me add some semicolons here.
All right, everything is passing, but again, we want to make sure that it's actually testing while
you want let's say this is zero now.
Oh, it's failed, and let's go back again just to make sure our thing passes, I'm going to simulate
a click again.
So if I go, nope, now it's expecting a count of two, so I changed it to.
And our tests are passing, that's pretty cool.
Now, if I remove this.
Counter.
And I have two failed tests now because on top of running the snapshot, which fails now because we've
changed the look of the component, we've also removed the way for us to grab that component by ID.
And you can see that method simulate is only meant to be run on a single note, zero found because we
weren't able to find the ID of counter and you can do many things here to grab an object.
I usually like having an ID because, well, just raise nicely.
But that's pretty cool, right?
We just in a very simple way, tested our state.
And once again, don't get overwhelmed by all this wording with the just cheat sheet and the enzyme
documentation, you can pick this up in a day fairly easy.
And I don't remember all of these.
I usually go to their documentation and say, oh, yeah, they have a simulate method.
Oh, yeah, they have the state method to grab the state.
And that's how you work as a developer.
You don't have an encyclopedia all in your head of all the methods.
You just know that this is what enzyme and just do let me go check out their documentation and see how
I can grab state.
Oh, and by the way, if I add again, remember, this is JavaScript.
We're just going one by one.
If I add here another click and at the bottom here I.
Ron, another expect I'm going to expect that it's now a three.
And you see that all my tests still pass because everything happens sequentially.
And if I add a another click here, then I can.
Or let's say this one is going to be a key press.
Even if there's a key press on there, because there's no key press event, I still expect the state
of Canticle three.
There you go.
Now, when you're testing, there are so many things that you can test for.
You can just keep going and keep going and keep going.
But you want to use your time wisely.
Does this test is it enough to move on to other tests?
And it's always a trade off on how your project is doing, how much other tests your project have,
and how much time and resources you have to write tests.
Let's do one last one.
I'm going to expect that the.
Rapper DOT.
Props.
To, let's say, to equal.
The same color.
Read.
Let's see if that works.
All right, I got a felt test, and that's because I was just kind of guessing based on state, whether
it has the props and to equal.
So let's scroll up and we see that we expected color red, but instead we got a ton of other props because,
well, we have color red, but we also get children and we also have ID as well as well as the UNCLICK
event.
Another thing we can do here is perhaps just do color, let's save.
And now we get red, which is good.
So we want to say to equal.
Read.
And there you go, our test pass, we do have a console log here, which is kind of annoying, so let's
remove that from the counter bun and there you go.
Our tests are passing and looking very, very nice.
I hope that you got a general idea of how to test components and by the way, this snapshot folder,
you're going to actually include that in your GitHub or whatever source control you have, you're going
to push that and committed to your project because any new developer that comes onto the project is
going to download the latest master.
And you also want to make sure that they have these snapshots of when they run the tests and they modify
a component.
These snapshots are going to check against the old version and make sure that this new new developer
doesn't change anything.
So, again, these things are also going to go into your source control or version control.
All right, I'll see you in the next video.
Bye bye.