Welcome back.
I wanted to take a second here before we keep going with testing our robo friends up to just go over
what we've learned from our slides and how it all makes sense now.
We learned that now we have just that we can install that provides for us a test framework, something
that we can run tests in, and this just also comes with an assertion library where we can use expect
DOT to be equal or to have or all these things that we can do that we saw in our cheat sheet to assert
something to make sure that this equals this.
And then we also saw that just comes with a test runner, something that we're able to run the tests
in.
And you saw that in my terminal.
I always have those tests running and checking and making sure that things are always passing.
We also saw that we have mocking functions that we can use.
We saw that in our example where we built our Star Wars API, where we got all those people that we
could mock the fetch function and make sure that it was called, again, something that comes with just.
Sinon is another popular one that it works very, very similar that you're going to see as well.
And then finally we saw that we can do code coverage by running NPM test, dash, dash, dash, dash
coverage.
And it gives us a coverage of where we have tests and where we don't so that we can improve our app.
I told you this is going to make sense and we're not even done yet.
We saw that we can test our app programmatically, but if we need any time to use some dumb APIs, we
have those three options.
We can use the actual DOM.
We can use something like puppeteer for a headless browser or something like just dump, which if we're
using the mount, rendering an enzyme, we can set up as well.
Again, there's this set up is fairly simple and you can check it out on the enzyme documentation.
Oh, yeah, and we also learned that in React, we can use enzyme and snapshot testing to make our tests
super, super easy again.
Another reason that I love using, just especially with Riak projects.
That was a quick break, back decoding, we go in the next video seen on that one by.