Welcome back, everyone.
In the last video, I issued a challenge to you in order to figure out how to use this event, we're
getting back from our on change handler inside of our input in order to filter out the list of monsters
that we have stored inside of our state.
Here, what we're going to do is do this together.
So we know that event, our target date value gives us the string that is typed into the search bar
so far.
So what we need to do is we need to filter down this list of monsters into a list of monsters that have
names that match this event, our target value.
So here what I'm going to say is I'm going to initialize some kind of variable called filtered monsters
just so that we know exactly what it is that we're creating.
And I'm going to say this dots state dot monsters.
Dot filter and dot filter is very similar to Dot Map in the sense that it gives us back a new array.
And what that array will contain is going to be a list of elements where it's run this callback on every
element in that array.
So here we know that monsters is an array of these different values that have a name on them.
So let's just say, for example, we have Liane, and we also have equal just as an example.
So, of course, our array is bigger about I'm going to use these two, for example, what's going to
happen when you call it filter is that dot filter is going to receive a callback that you give to it
and it's going to pass and call this callback on each element the same way it left to right.
And based on what the return of this callback is, whether it's true or false.
So it's expecting a Boolean, it's expecting true or false.
If it's true, then it will keep that element, if it's false, then it will take it out.
So what will happen is once Filter runs this call back on all of these different elements inside of
the array that you're calling it on, it will give you back a new array.
So here, let's say that with that filter, what we know is that the first argument, just like we saw
before when we called don't map, the first argument is going to be the element itself, and I'm just
going to call it monster just for my own sanity.
And here we're going to say that monster dot name, so give me the name.
And what we want to do is we want to think about how we're going to actually check whether or not the
tax we have is included in this name.
Luckily for us, with all strings, we have eight includes method.
And I want to say that if it includes events that target value, meaning that if the name includes the
string, then what I want you to do is I want you to return.
True.
So luckily for us, includes is a method that returns a Boolean as well don't include returns.
True if this string includes the string you passed to it, meaning that if the name includes the search
string, then return true.
If it doesn't, then return false.
And what we're saying is that when you filter over these monsters.
If this monster's name includes the search string, then keep it, if it doesn't include it, then get
rid of it.
And here filter monsters will give us back a new array.
And the reason we want a new array is because similarly, with our previous example and we're looking
at react with those objects and our state objects, you remember with our object, if we modify the
object, react can't actually register that it's a different object.
Similarly, with arrays, it's the same if you increase or decrease the number of elements inside of
an array, meaning you add more or you remove to it.
This is still the same array in memory.
It behaves very similarly.
Now, React doesn't really care about this as much, because it's really just what the state object
that it checks.
But as a general best practice, you always want to use non modifying methods, meaning that if you're
going to modify an array, you want to generate a new one.
Chances are you don't want to modify the same one.
And this is a concept called immutability, and it's a general best practice.
So most of the time, remember, if you're going to modify an array, create a new array with that modification,
and there's a series of these different methods on arrays that are helpful map as one that filters one
and there's another one we're going to learn later called dark reduce.
So here we filter out this massive array, and now what we need to do is we actually need to set the
monsters to this new filter at monsters.
So here we can just say this Scott set state.
Is equal again.
To this.
Function and we're going to return back and object where monsters is filtered.
Monsters.
And here, very explicitly, this is exactly what's happening.
And if we save and we check back here.
Now, if we type in L e A, we see that we're filtering out now, you might be wondering why is it that
this first name, Monster of Leon is not here?
Sorry.
Let me refresh.
You notice that as we typed in a.
We expected the capital, Liane.
Well, the reason for this is because it includes is not case sensitive.
In order for us to make this case sensitive, we actually need to lowercase all of the text that we're
typing in.
So here what we can do in order to actually make this handier for us is let's actually cast this into
a variable.
So let's say a search string is equal to event dot target value dot to lowercase.
So two lowercase is a method on all strings.
That lowercase is them all.
So no matter where there is a capital, it will get lowercase.
So if you have a string that's like AAA, a like this, this when you run to lowercase on it will give
you back a string that's like this.
So that's really handy for us when it comes to any kind of search ability.
We just want a lower case, everything because most of the time people don't search with the idea that
it's case sensitive.
So now that we have our search string, we want to do the same thing to dot name.
We want a lowercase the name.
And then on that lowercase string, we want to check to see if it includes our new lowercase search
string.
And now, if we save this and we go back to our application and I type L e A, we see that it works.
So this is the beautiful thing now.
Everything is working for us.
But what you'll notice again is as you.
Remove characters.
Why is it that this array of monsters is still what we had filter?
I want to give you a second to think about it, really think about what's happening here and in the
next video, we'll cover it together and how to remove it.
If you want to take the challenge, in fact, and you figure out why, it is that even as we removed
the different strings, we didn't get back the original list of monsters and you want to try and solve
it yourself.
Please try and take a stab at it, because that's the best way to learn is to really try and figure
it out yourself first.
But once you've hit a point where you ever figured it out or you want to see the answer, join me in
the next video and we will implement this together.