All right, we're starting to see more and more tests, but up until now, we've only worked with some
simple components.
What if we want to work with something like a container that says we have all this map state to props?
It's also a connected component.
How do we test with that?
Let's give it a try.
I'm going to create a new file and call it dot test dojos.
And this test suggests, again, we can just go through the motions and copy one of the.
Last tests, let's just do this.
And this time, instead of contraband, it's going to be up.
And again, we won't receive any colors, let's just run this and see what happens.
No, actually, let me delete this as well.
Save.
All right, I'm getting some errors, it says expect to render app component, which is over here,
but I'm getting an error saying that invariant violation could not find a store in either the context
or props of Connect app.
All right.
So let's just mock a store.
We can say const lock store equals.
Say an empty object for now or let's just do the robots of an empty array and let's do.
Sarshar.
Or a search field that is an empty string.
And we'll just pass this mock store.
As the storm.
Let's save.
And Hellboy, I'm getting stalked, get state is not a function, and that makes sense, right?
If you remember, our store isn't just an empty object or a dummy object.
I mean, it is an redox terms.
But it also came with all these other things that we didn't really think about when we installed Redox.
We had get state subscribe and all these other methods that came with it.
So that means we have to mock this entire list of store methods that redux comes up with.
And if redux updates and add something new in the future, we're going to have to update that as well.
And luckily for us, there's tools that already do this for you.
For example, there is a package called Redox Lock.
Store that you can use to actually mock this store and have these proper methods on it, and that's
an NPM package that we can install.
But I want to take a different route.
I want to take a route of simplicity, because right now, looking at this app, dot JS file, we're
doing a lot of things.
And I like simple test tests that test simple things.
And this app is frankly a little bit complicated because we have this Kinect.
So it's technically not even rendering the app.
It's rendering Canet.
And then that is wrap by app, let me show you what I mean.
If I go back to our app and open up our react developer tools, you might have to download this plug
in if you don't have it already.
I see that my app is a provider and then a connect to app.
So this app, what we're actually testing is this Kinect component that is wrapping the app and only
inside of it we have the app and then header search box scroll and so on and so forth.
Let's simplify this, why not just test our app instead of testing our connected component, and this
is what I like to do when I test things instead of trying to.
Test a really complicated component, I asked myself, is this component as simple as it can be?
Is there better things that I can do with code to make it more testable, which usually results in better
code overall?
So looking at this, this app component does two main things, one, it connects to the Redock store
through all this map, say, to props and map dispatch to props, but it also renders a ton of these
things.
So let's separate this out.
I'm going to create a new component file and call it main page, Gorgias, so you can think of this
as the homepage of our robo friends up.
And now this main page will also have a test file, so I'm going to move the app test, James, to actually
be renamed to Main Page and put it into the components folder.
All right, our tests are failing, but that's because we have our names all off.
So let's go about this step by step.
Let's make Jess be worried about just connecting and receiving just receiving props from the store and
make our main page be concerned with rendering all this homepage stuff.
So how can we do this?
Well, the very first step is I'm going to copy the entire file, go to our main page, copy and paste
it and right off the bat, remove all the redox things because I don't need anything redux.
This is going to be a simple component that's not connected to a reduc story.
So I'm going to remove the Kinect.
I'm going to remove any of the actions and just leave our components.
I'm going to remove the map state to props, map dispatched to props.
And I'm going to rename this to.
Main page.
Component and you don't have access file for it.
Or maybe we should move this apgar's to our main page, so for now, I'm just going to create something
quickly.
I'm going to say new file.
Main page dot success.
And by the way, you're starting to see why we might want to have a better folder structure than just
files, files, files.
We might want to have components and a component folder for each one of these components.
And I'm just going to copy and paste here.
And going back to our main page, we now have the success, we have the.
Constructor and I don't know why we have our.
Count in here, I don't think we need the count, it's not using it at all, so let's just remove that
so we don't need a constructor.
And in our main page, again, there's no constructor we have the component did mount because while
we want to request robots and we have our regular render, but we also don't have our connect anymore.
We're just simply rendering our.
Main page.
All right, so we've removed this and made this into a simple app that still has the component did mount,
but that's just props that we received from the store.
All right, so let's go into Abduh and now remove the up part, because we don't really need that anymore
or we don't need the render part, we just need the connected component.
So again, in here now for our render.
All we really need to do is, well, remove all of this feels nice, removing stuff and making files
smaller and all we need is the main page component to render, right.
So we can remove all these component imports.
And just import the main page component.
Again, another reason I love reactivates everything is just so nice and simple to move component's
around, but look what we've just done really, really quickly.
Oh, and we definitely don't need component did mount.
Because we're doing that in the main page, so look how small that component just got.
How nice is that?
And now this app component just turned into a super simple container component, and this is an architectural
decision that I really, really like because we don't really need to even test this, do we?
Because all we're doing is just using the connect function to grab the state and dispatch events from
our Redock store, so even writing test for this, although we could do it, we're just simply testing
the functionality of redux.
And that's something that Redux Library already does.
It already has tests and people working to make sure that it works properly.
This component now becomes something so simple that we might not even need to test and we've moved all
our logic that we can test to the main page component, and that's something really important to think
about, to always try and make your tests easy.
If they're not, then perhaps there's something in your code that you can simplify and you can see how
elegant of a solution this is.
The last thing we really want to do is just pass down these props down to the main page.
To do that, we can just use some de structuring.
Or object spread to say this dot props.
Let's save and actually haven't tested this Scotsdale, make sure it still works, let's run and start.
Sure.
There's something that we may have missed.
Let's close this.
All right, we have your render method, should have a return statement.
And yeah, we need to actually return from this render statement that's silly of us, let's return.
And we have a bit of an issue with the access, and that is because they can't find the sycophant,
so that's a simple fix.
We just go to the euro and do because the sycophant is in the containers.
We can just simply do.
Containers for now, even though we probably want to move this around for now, for demonstration purposes,
that's fine.
Everything is passing.
If I go back, I see that there's a few other areas we have the count of.
No.
And we're passing the count state in here in the header component, but if you remember our header component.
Has the.
Counterbattery that actually has its own state, so looks like we're doing this for no reason, so let's
just remove that from the.
Where is it from the main page so we can just remove that save?
Go back.
All right.
Everything is working.
Make sure our searching works.
Yeah, everything is working.
Count is working if I open up my react developer tools.
No, not redox, we won't react.
We have the provider, we have the connected app, but check this out.
We now have the main page that we can test.
And this main page now is more accessible for us using enzyme and just.
So let's try some tests here.
We're going to go into the main page that tests.
All right, let's first change the name to Main Page, which is what we're testing now.
And because I feel like we're going to be doing this a lot and passing down some props, there's a neat
little trick that we can do.
Let's say we're going to have a little rapper and I'm going to.
Remove this for now.
And we can use something called before each again comes with jest and other testing frameworks, and
this makes sure that it runs before each one of our tests.
Now in here, we simply give it a function.
And inside of this function, we can say what should run before each one of our tests.
In our case, we want to mock props.
And these mock props, well, why are we going to have we're going to have the on request robots.
Which if you remember.
Let's close this and close this, so it's a little bit cleaner.
If you remember, Main Page has the request robot's function, so we can just do the just.
Function here, which we've seen before with mocking, so we're just saying that this is just this simple
function, don't worry about actually doing the API call.
We'll say that robots is an empty array.
That search field.
Is going to be an empty string.
And that is pending will be set to force.
And then finally, because we have this for each or before each, we're going to say that the rapper
is going to equal the shallow.
Rendered.
Main page and this main page, again, just like we did in our Apgar's, can just receive the.
Props, that is the.
Mock props.
So this is going to receive all these properties just like we did, and see that over here.
All right, so let's say here, I'm going to go back to running and test.
And we have a few areas because, well, that's not semicolon, that's comma, my arch nemesis, the
comma.
And we get an air saying that our test, we must contain one test because we haven't ridden one yet,
we just wrote the before each.
Now, let's start off with the basics.
The it renders main page without crashing.
And we'll say that.
Well, we can use our favorite testable snapshot testing, we can just say expect rapper, because now
we have access to this rapper that is shallow rendered because before each is going to run before this
test and I'll say to match.
Snapshot.
I love how easy this is.
Let's save.
And what did I mess up here?
Wow, I am terrible writing, Comis.
All right, there you go.
You must be just laughing at me right now with all the comments that I miss while I code.
But, hey, we're all human here.
We all make mistakes.
I don't think there's ever a perfect developer that doesn't make mistakes while coding.
If there are, well, I'm very jealous of them.
All right.
Let's test another thing.
Let's say that I wanted to make sure that it filters the robots correctly.
So I'll say it filters robots correctly.
And I'm just going to say that in here we expect the rapper.
And hmm, how do we do this if we go to Main Page, James?
We have filter robots in here, but that's happening in the render function, so let's just clean this
up and say that we have the filter robots.
And this filter, robots will receive the.
Robots, and it's going to make it a narrow function.
And we can just grab this.
And just return.
Are filtered robots, we're going to need the search field here, so I'm going to say this dot props,
dot search field.
To lower case.
And now within here, we can just say that filtered robots is coming from this dot filter robots, let's
just make sure this runs.
I'm going to go back and run and start.
And it looks like I made a mistake somewhere here.
We need to actually pass down the robot, so let's just say it's going to receive the robots or we can
even do this up over here for now.
Let's just leave it like that and make sure we have our name incorrect here.
Felter robots.
Let's go back.
All right, it's still working, so now that I've made this a little bit cleaner in our render function
and let's just remove the search field from here.
There you go.
How can I actually test this, we can now just simply test this method on the main page class.
Well, we can just now use the instance property that comes with enzyme, and now this instance is going
to give us access to all the methods that Main Page has, including Felda robots.
So let's say in our test, I'm going to move this around.
I'm going to say.
Dot filter.
Robots, it's going to run filter robots with, let's say, an empty array.
And we expect that to equal.
An empty array.
So let's save and run, npm start or ampm test.
We have a failed test.
And I made a bit of a bit of a mistake here, the expect should be around this entire thing.
We want to expect that the filter robots runs and we want it to equal the empty array.
Let's save.
All right, everything is passing, but let's test other cases, because while this is most likely not
going to be the case.
Let's say that this time around, in this statement, only even though we're getting these before each
and we have access to the rapper this time around, we want to have a special case where the mock props
is going to have a search field of a and in here we have a robot.
That is to say, I'd.
Three with a name of John and email, Wolf, leave your username out of it for now, John at Gmail dot
com.
Let's save this.
And create a new expect statement now.
And just for this test, we're going to use a different wrapper, so let's just a.
A rapper with and I know this is not the cleanest, but trying to illustrate a point here, so bear
with me.
So let's do mock props.
To mock props, too, and this is going to be rapper two, so let's save rapper to save.
And it says filters robots correctly, and you know what, I just realized, I think a better way for
us to do filter robots for now at least, is we can forget about the props and we can just do this dot
oops.
This dot props dot robots.
So going back here, we can now remove these arrays, so just looks a little bit cleaner.
And let's make this test pass, we get a bit of an error here because we need to do CONSED rapper too,
because rapper is not defined.
Remember, we have to define it and our test pass because our search field is a and we only have robots
with John and John.
A good outcome.
But if I change this through John.
Oh, it fails because we expected to equal the actual robots with John and.
For now, we can just say that we expect this array to be returned.
And I'm going to remove the first one, let's save.
Oh, and I have extra brackets here again, this is good, our tests are failing and we're working towards
passing them.
All right.
And now we know that filters robots correctly is working.