Welcome back, everyone.
In the last video, we learned how to implement a search bar into our application, and we learned how
to filter out these different monsters that we have based on what gets typed in.
However, what we noticed is that while we did implement a case insensitive filtering system, the problem
is that as we get rid of the characters, we are left with this filtered list.
We cannot get back a new list based on the characters that are actually in the search bar.
Why is that?
So let's go back to our application when we look at the code.
What will notice is that we are directly modifying this monster's array.
However, whenever this change event happens, we are just using the current monster's array, meaning
that every time we're filtering, we're not filtering off the original list of monsters while filtering
off of the currently filtered list of monsters.
In case that is a little confusing.
Let's make this clear by console logging this out.
So here I'm going to console dot log.
I'm going to say that this is the starting array, actually.
Let's let's make this more clear.
I'm going to make an object and I'm going to say starting array.
Goes to this dot state dot monsters, because this is the monsters array in our state that we have when
this event first fires.
And then what happens is we modify it.
So following set state, I am going to pass it a callback once the state is updated.
And here, instead of calling it starting array, I'm going to call it ending array.
And this is just easy for me, because using this object, we see these keys.
So if we go to our code.
What we see when we start typing.
L e a, we noticed that when we went in the first time for the L.
We saw that there was a certain area of 10 and then an ending array of nine.
And then when we tied the E, there was a starting area of nine and then an ending array of five.
And then finally, when we type the A, we had the stunning array of five and the ending array of one.
So this is expected because we're filtering down the list to one.
But now, as we remove what we notice is that our starting array is one.
Every single time the starting array is the same array as are filtered list.
So no wonder we're not getting back all of our monsters from before.
We don't have that stored anywhere anymore.
That list is completely gone.
So this actually brings us to a very important best practice.
If you are going to modify any kind of data inside of your state.
Such as filtering it out based on user input or whatever.
If you're going to go back to it and most of the time you want to go back to it and at least keep some
kind of reference to that original list.
What you want to do is you want to actually keep your state equal to the original list of whatever it
is that you're keeping track of.
So for us, it's the users.
We want to keep that original list of users.
We don't actually want to modify the states and use that value.
Instead, we want to filter that value and then pass it into wherever we need it to be.
So how do we do this?
How do we modify our code to do so?
So here, what I'm going to do is get rid of these console.log.
And what we're going to do is we're going to keep this search string because this is still useful and
we're going to keep this filtered monster's list because essentially this is a new array.
Remember what I told you?
Dot filter gives you back a new array.
That means that this starts.
State dot monsters is untouched because any filtering happens in the new array we get back.
The original array is completely unmodified.
And this is exactly what we want.
The question now is with this filtered monsters, how do we actually use it inside of our rendering
because we now want to render this filtered monster's list?
We want the same functionality we had before, except instead of acting on the state, we want to access
it where we filtered it.
Well, this is actually where we should move some of this code out into the render, and maybe this
will make it more helpful for us.
We can either move it out of the render or we can move it out into a method, and there is a little
bit of optimization here that we're going to have to talk about.
But first, what I want to do is let's just move it out into this render because it's the easiest way.
So what we're going to do is we are going to create.
This filtered monster's list.
Out here inside of the render, but outside of the return.
So here I have access to filtered monsters.
But the problem is, I don't have access to search string.
And in order for me to get access to search string, I need access to this event.
So what we should do is we should actually stop this search string value inside of our state because
then we have access to it anywhere in our component right now.
This search string is only available inside of this callback, but not actually inside of our component.
So in order for us to get access to it in our component, we need to move it into our component.
And the best way to do that is to put it into state.
So inside of state here, I'm going to say there is a search field.
And this to start, as I mentioned before, is equal to the null case or the empty case of what this
will be.
And this is going to be a string.
So the empty case of that is an empty string.
Then what we're going to do is we are now going to get access to this search string value.
So what we want to do is we actually want to update this in our state.
So instead, in our on change of settings state of Monsters, we're going to update this search field.
So here I'm going to change this to search field instead of search string.
And by doing this now, I can get rid of that code.
And this is just a quick shorthand when you're writing objects.
If you use a variable as the only field, then what JavaScript is going to do and he asks, is it's
going to say, OK, you know, the key is going to be the name of this variable and the value is going
to be the value of this variable.
And by doing this now we are updating this search field value.
And here I'm going to do is I'm going to change this now to our newly stored this dot state dot search
field.
So now filtered monsters should be.
Using this state search field because we're updating it in the same way, so you'll notice that we're
just moving some things around.
And instead of mapping over this dot state dot monsters, let me just map over filtered monsters.
So if I save this now?
Here you'll notice that we have our original list of monsters, and then I'm going to say Ali A.
So this filters out as we saw before, but now as we type back, we get back our original list.
So everything now works the way we want it to.
Now I know we covered a couple bigger concepts in this video, so some of this might be a little confusing,
and that's perfectly fine.
Let's just quickly go over what we did.
What we knew was that as we were filtering monsters, we needed the original list of monsters to display
because any future filters that we wanted to make should be made on the full list of monsters.
It shouldn't be made on the filter list of monsters, especially when we start removing characters.
And we want to get back to that state of our original full list of monsters.
So remember, whenever you're filtering down a list, you always want a filter from the full list.
And if that's the case, what you want to do is you want to keep track of that somewhere, and the best
place for that is in the state.
So after you've updated state with the full original list, don't modify that.
Modify that somewhere else inside of our input because we want to access that input value.
We want to store that somewhere where the rest of the component has access to it, not just in the callback,
because remember, with JavaScript, all of our variables are locally scoped.
So with that in mind, what we need to do in order to make that more accessible to the rest of the component
is we have to move it to something where the rest of the component is access to, and that is the state.
So what we did is that we stored the value that we wanted, so we don't store the event, we store the
actual thing that matters for us, which is just the string.
And we want to modify it in a way where it's useful for the rest of the application, which is where
it's lowercase.
So here what we're doing is we're storing that inside of our state.
So once we have this search field now inside of the render, we are able to filter it down from the
original list of monsters using the search field.
There's a couple little optimizations that I'm going to show you in the next video, and we're going
to deep dive into that so that you can learn a little bit more about the render cycles about React and
these glass components.
Join me in the next video or we'll talk about that.