And you can already start to see some things that we can clean up here, we can just copy and paste
this, let's just create one more instance and says filters robot correctly to.
We'll say that the will say three for now just to keep this clean.
I will say that the concert filter or filtered robots.
Should equal an empty array, and this time we're searching for the letter, which doesn't exist in
name, and we expect the filtered robots to.
He called the.
Dummy filtered robots that we gave it.
Let's save.
And we see that something is failing.
Because Mark, props to is not defined, we need to give it three.
And there you have it, we've now tested our main page, at least the main page method of filtered robots.
And we also have some snapshot testing as well, so let's just look at our code coverage for now.
Let's just run NPM run test dash, dash.
Dash dash coverage.
And again, this is always with testing, there's always many more things they can do.
We see that main page has a hundred percent, but there is a branch percentage.
We're only testing 50 percent of the branch.
And you see that the uncovered line is on 28 if we go back.
We can go to main page and see that we have a is pending on line twenty eight.
How cool is that?
The test says, all right, we're testing that the card list is rendering because we're always testing
with spending is true.
As you can see here in our.
In our mock props, we always have is pending default, so we might want to test is pending to true
as well.
And I'm going to leave that up to you to add the important concept here is that there are so many ways
to test.
You can always use the covers you report as a reference, but try to be smart about your tests and make
sure that you spend your time wisely because you're just going to have infinite things that you can
do.
But you only have limited time.
That's it for now, I hope you have a better understanding of how container and components testing can
be enhanced with enzyme and snapshot testing.
And obviously the tools that come with just the rest of the test is something I'm leaving up to you
to complete four components and containers.
But let's get to actions, constants and reducers.
We're going to want to test those as well.
So in the next video, we're going to do just that.
I'll see in that one.
Bye bye.