Welcome back.
We have a good idea of how to test react components, but what about redux and some of the reducers,
actions and concerns that we have?
Let's start off with reducers, and you're going to absolutely love this section because remember,
our producers are pure functions and pure functions are a Testa's dream.
They're the easiest to test.
So let's do that.
I'm going to create a new file.
Call it reducers test dachas.
And then in here, I'm going to.
Import while we need the constants.
So I'm going to import the constants and obviously our reduce or so import, we'll do import star as
a new syntax, as reducers.
From.
Reducers.
With this syntax, we can just do reducers, dot, whatever we do here, that we've exported it.
So in our case reducers that's are showboats reducers, dot request robots, which reads nicely.
All right, let's group these reducers this time around by using a described celesta describe.
Search robots, we're going to do our first reducer here and within here.
Oops, that's not what I wanted to do within here.
We're going to have a test, the first test that says should return the initial state.
Now, the initial state in the search, robots reducer can be tested like this, so we can do expect.
Reducers Dott.
Search robots.
So that's our reducer and remember, our reducer takes two things a state and an action.
And because if state doesn't exist or is undefined, we give it the initial state search, let's do
that.
I'm going to say that the reducer does search robots gets undefined.
So no state at the beginning and it's going to get no action.
But let's just give it an empty action for now.
We want to test for those cases where, well, we we have an undefined state, what happens?
Well, we wanted to equal.
Our ideal state.
And our state in this case is to have search field.
To be an empty string.
So let me save that.
Open up our testing suite.
And all right, everything is passing, if I press to see that everything is logged out nicely, including
our reducers dot test, if we we put in a in the search field, it's going to fail.
All right.
So that's great.
That was super, super easy.
What else can we do?
Well, we expected that this reducer when we see our.
Change search field event that it returns a new state.
So once again, we can say that it should handle the change search field event and we can say reducers
that search robots.
Let's make this a little bit smaller.
Is going to get the state of, let's say.
An empty state or you know what, let's add a const initial state search here and say that this initial
state search is.
Search field.
He calls this.
All right, so we can just use initial search, so this is going to be the initial state, which equals
to the empty string and it's going to receive an action.
And what kind of action is it going to receive?
I'm going to remove this for now.
Well, if you remember, our actions are going to have a type.
And in this case, we'll say that type is going to be changed.
Search field that comes from our Konstanz file.
And we can make up the payload that it's going to send.
So let's just say for now that the payload is going to be ABC.
Now, what do we expect from that output, we expect that once it goes through this reducer, that the
search field is going to equal.
ABC.
So we can say Sarsfield should be AVC again, we have our initial state search, which is an empty string,
it goes through this reducer with this action and we now need the state because remember this reducers
just going to return the state.
We want the state to be A.B.C..
Let's save.
And we have a bit of a fail here.
Let's see what kind of an error we get and it looks like just the unexpected token.
Oh, and we need an extra bracket here.
And we had an air saying that type is not defined because because, well, you don't need to type here.
That's just a typo on my part.
All right, so that's passing, how simple is that with reducers, all we need to do is just give us
some sort of an input and expect an output and could just keep going like this forever.
Make your tests better and better.
Let's do the next reducer now, let's say that we want to and let's make more space here.
We want to describe the.
Request.
Robots reducer.
In that case, we can just say that we have well, let's create an initial state, so I'm going to again
say consed initial state for the robot's.
And if you remember, we have the this as the initial state, so I'm just going to actually copy this.
So this is our initial state for the.
Test.
And we want to do the same thing as above, it should return the initial state, so let's just copy
and paste the above and just change the search robust to request robots.
And we want that to equal the initial state.
Let's save.
And we have a failed test, let's see what we failed here.
Initial state robots.
Is not defined.
Because I need to add a cost in here, let's save.
All right, everything is passing, we're getting our initial state as expected, that's good, but
let's do another test and say that we want.
The three cases over here to be tested.
So let's do an initial it.
Should handle.
Requests Roberts lists two pending first action.
And it's going to.
Have something similar to hear.
So, again, we're going to use the expect statement.
It's going to have the reducers dot this time request.
Robots.
It's going to receive the initial state of the robots.
And then we'll give it an action of type.
Request robot spending and a payload of.
Let's give it.
Is pending, too, true, so we expect that.
When this happens, actually, if we take a look at the reducer, we see that it automatically sends
the spending to true and there's no payload.
So we don't need to set that.
We don't need to send a payload, but we expect that payload to change from is pending all us to.
False here, because his spending, when we start off, is always false.
And in here, we want this to equal.
The state of robots.
With an empty array.
Is spending set to true, so let's save.
All right, everything is passing, but I just noticed here that we don't actually want.
The default is spending to be true.
We wanted to be false because when we first have the initial state, well, we haven't sent the promise
yet.
We haven't requested anything from the API.
If we go into our reducers file, we see that we have the initial state here by true by mistake.
We can just change that to false.
Let's save.
And in here, let's save here.
Perfect, everything is working, and the request of robots pending is changing our is pending state
to true.
All right, let's keep going, we have the second case, which is the success, so I'm just going to
copy and paste here and this time say request robots spending.
Success.
And this success.
Should have well, what should it have what we need some sort of payload, because, again, in our
reducers we have the robot's action payload.
That we return or add to the state upon success, so let's just create that in our type, we're going
to say payload.
And I'm going to return let's just grab.
Let's just create a dummy.
Idea of one, two, three.
Let's say name of test and then finally email of test at Gmail dot com.
You see over here that this is a string instead of a number, I believe, in our component, we're actually
not distinguishing between a number and a string.
So that's something we might want to fix in the future.
But for now, we expect that if the payload is that the state now gets updated with that payload, so
let's copy that.
And we also expect the spending to be false again, if we remember our reducer.
We're also changing our spending to false on success.
So let's save.
And we have a bit of an air here.
That is a simple arch nemesis, comma.
If we save, there it is, it passes.
One final test you can see can get pretty repetitive with tests, but this is a good thing with reducers.
They're so simple to test that you just copy and paste a lot of the code, which again, is fine for
testing because this code was never going to go into production.
So let's do the the fail case here.
That is the failed.
And in this case, we want the payload, if we go back to our function, we want the payload to just
have an air.
So again, back here we can just say no super upset that we got an error and we expect the state to
now have an error that is of.
Nephew and a spending of false.
Although I see here that we're actually not turning the spending to force, which we should be, so
if we save.
But we also expect the robot's array to be returned.
Remember, so the robot's arrays should be empty.
And now we have this passing.
Very cool.
All right, that's enough for reducers, you see how simple they are to test simply checking the input
against the output, and that's why you want to have these reducers everywhere and why redux is so amazing.
It's super easy to test.
And if you think about it all our logic is in our reducers.
So if we have really, really good tests for our reducers, we cover a lot of the logic of our applications
because reducers are the thing that taken actions and spit out the state.
They're pretty much the controller or the brain of our app.
Redox allows us to have really, really nice tests and keeping things simple on the back side by just
doing snapshot testing or simple enzyme tests and testing out pure functions, which again is very useful.
But for now, that's it for me.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.