Welcome back.
We've written quite a few tests now and, well, 13 tests.
That's not bad for a small app.
There's definitely more that we can do.
But I want to cover the last part now that I think is important and that is testing our actions.
Now, you might be asking yourself, what about Constance, are we not testing the constants file?
But you can see here that constants are just simply, well, just assigning string constants to a variable.
And when you're testing, you really want to decide for yourself what you need to test and why you don't.
With testing, you can really get into a rabbit hole.
That is, you just keep working on test, keep working on tests.
And next thing you know, you haven't really done anything on the production side of things.
And tests are important, but you really want to avoid the idea that, oh, I just need to have one
hundred pass tests or one hundred snapshots or I need my code coverage to be 100 percent.
It's actually not a good idea to have 100 percent code coverage because it means that you're running
tests that most likely don't need to be run and your time could have been spent wisely in other areas
of your app.
Remember, there's infinite things that we can do to refactor and make our code prettier, write more
tests, but we have limited time.
So as a senior developer, you have to decide for yourself where the tradeoffs are.
All right, so Constance File, we don't really need tests for that, but actions, I think we do need
some tests for our actions.
Let's create an action or actions that test file.
And within here, let's once again import star as actions.
From our actions file.
And.
With the first action that we have, which is the set search field, that's a pretty simple one.
We just want to make sure that this function returns, this object.
So we can just use basic just functionality here, we can just have the IT.
And I know I should be using that described to to separate out the.
To actions that we have, but I think you get the idea you can do that on your own.
I want to get you to board here, but let's have it should create an action to search robots.
And this is going to have.
A simple, very simple tax, let's have a constant text that's going to equal our search term through.
And the consulates have the expected action.
And the expected action is going to be our object of.
Type.
And let's import our constants here as well.
So we can use them.
It's going to have a type of change Sarsfield and a payload, and this is the expected action.
So we expect that the action is going to include the RUU text or we don't need the strong characters
here.
There you go.
So we can simply just say expect.
Actions.
Dot.
Search, what was it?
It was set search field, Skype, that search field.
To have the text.
And to have two equal so we want to set the search field with that text and we needed to have the expected
output of the action, so expected action, let's save.
And what did I miss here?
Let's see.
No, no comma here now over using the commas, this test section has been hard on me with the commas.
All right, so there you go.
We have new tests now in the actions that is passing.
Very, very nice.
And that's simple.
We should know how to do that.
But here's the challenging part.
Now we have this action request robots that, oh, boy, does a dispatch and I have an API call here.
And this is something that you might not have seen.
I've created an API folder here that simply extracts out our fetch call.
So we give it a neutral.
And does the response response that Jason.
So that it simplifies things for things for us so we don't have to constantly do fetch.
But then response.
Response that Jason.
But you've seen this before, the where is it?
The actions just have the dispatch of request robots pending and then finally it's going to have either
success or failed.
Hmm.
So how do we do this?
Because looking at this action, we need to dispatch.
Because this is an asynchronous action and remember, we need thunk for it, we need a thunk middleware.
Let's start writing the test and see what we can improve on.
I'm going to close some of these tabs just to clean things out.
There you go.
And we're going to create a new blog.
And in this block, we want to say handle's.
Changing, changing or handles requesting robots API.
And we'll say here that.
Well, the very first thing we want to do, we need to pass the dispatch to our function.
Again, remember the dispatch here?
Well, if we do it without this, so let's just test it out.
If I run the expect actions dot request.
Robots action, I believe that's what's called the request robots, and we leave it at this and let's
just say that we expect the type of the action.
To have the, let's say, request robots pending and payload, if we look at our actions, we're not
sending any payloads.
So we can just go ahead and leave that as it is if I save.
Yet one failed.
Request robots.
And there you go, I get an error type error dispatch is not a function because remember, with asynchronous
code, we need to pass this dispatch function to actually run this.
And we used a thunk middleware in order for us to do this.
If you remember, index suggests we have the thunk middleware in here.
How do we do this?
Well, there is a special package that we can use here.
Let me exit out of this.
Make this a little bit bigger.
Let's clear.
We can install a package called the Redox.
Mark.
Store.
And remember that this gives us access to a fake store that we can use for testing, so let's do.
NPM.
Install, dash, dash, save def.
And now we have access to this fake store and the way we can use it is if I go up here and I say import.
Configure store, and once again, this is all in their documentation for the package, we want to use
the redox lock store.
And we also want to import the.
Thank.
Middleware.
From the.
Redux.
Funk package, which, if you remember, we already have in our index does jazz file.
And the last thing we need to do.
Let me make sure it's lined up properly, is to configure and create this store so we can simply just
say const.
Mark store.
Equals.
Configure, lock store, and we can figure it by giving it some properties, of which one of them is
the middleware that we're going to use, which is going to be the thunk middleware.
So sometimes you're most likely going to add this into a setup test file.
For now, I'm going to keep it in here because we only have one actions file, but you can usually export
it.
So this store is available to all your tests.
So now we can.
Create the store.
He goes to the mock store and we run it.
And I can now say store dot dispatch and store dot dispatch takes actions, dot requests for robots.
So we're going to dispatch this action.
Remember, that's.
This action over here.
And once we dispatched that, we can do something like constant action equals to store DOT get actions.
And now this action is going to contain what we need.
Let me just I get to show you, so console dialogue.
Action, it's going to contain the action.
Let's save and run test.
Scroll up and I have a bit of a console log area here, the Configure MOX store should be Configure
Mok's store here.
All right, so we see that dispatch is not a function.
Now, why is that?
And this is something that you may have noticed while we're looking at the action dot JS file.
Do you remember that Redox Thunk expects a function to be returned?
And although our program works the way it is now, you ideally want to let's go back to the top dogs.
You see here that and this is something we talked about before, the redox section you see here, that
we're just giving the dispatch to our request robots.
But the way it works is we want to make sure that we dispatch like this.
Run the function inside of it so that we can run the dispatch dispatch function, just like we have
in our tests over here and the actions request robots and we want to dispatch that.
Otherwise, we would have to do store dispatch in here, which is kind of ugly.
Once again, to fix that or we need to do is in the actions, because if you remember Apgar's, we have
dispatch now and request robots needs to run.
So we're just going to have a function inside of a function.
And we want to make sure that this works as well.
So I'm going to go back and do not start.
Right, and everything still works, but now we're able to hopefully run the tests better.
So AMPM test.
Go back to our tests and we see that we have one failed fun.
We have a type request, robots pending that we expected, but we got a function instead.
And if we log actions, we see that we have a action type of request, robots pending, which we're
getting.
And that's because you can see that the action is returning an array and we want the object.
All of the action in the expect because we no longer need to run this action, it's all being run up
here and we can get the actions, we can just say expect action.
The first item in the array.
To be run and look at that, everything works, and I know this can get a little bit confusing, and
any time you're testing asynchronous things, it can get pretty difficult.
But all we did was really create a fake store that had the thunk middleware.
So it awaits for any functions that are returned from an action, in which case we did with our actions
request robots.
Because you see here that every turns and action.
That takes the dispatch and.
Now this dispatch gets automatically sent into request robots, it's going to receive the actions,
and because if we go to our action dogs, the very first thing we dispatch is the pending action.
We receive.
Action zero to equal the expected action of robots pending.
All right, so how do we test the request, robot success and request robots failed, and that's a little
challenge that I'm going to leave for you to decide what to do based on what we've learned about asynchronous
tests and also what we've learned about mocking our reduc store.
And this is a tough, challenging problem, so use whatever resources you have at hand, Internet,
Google Stack, overflow, anything you can to try and figure this out, because that's what testing
is all about.
Testing is sometimes very simple when you have pure functional components or functions, or it could
be really difficult when you have all these dependencies that your tests run on.
But every situation is different.
And luckily for us, with all these resources online, you can figure it out as long as you understand
how things work and what the errors mean, which as a senior developer is the most important thing.
They don't know every single syntax in a library and know all the documentation.
They just understand how things work underneath the hood so that when the problem arises, they can
solve it.
Finally, I wanted to show you two things that may help you or I think are great whenever you are doing
asynchronous tests.
The first one is a library called knock and knock, simply as an MP and package that you can install
and you can see over here that we can pretend that we're doing a Eurail call, we can do a get request
to an end point, and we can automatically reply with whatever we want.
We can say that this reply had a status of two hundred and it gave us username and email.
And this sets you up really nicely for asynchronous test.
Once you get deep into testing as well, especially when you start working with APIs, Super Test is
one of my favorite tools simply by importing super test, just like here.
And we have the request you can request, let's say, an express app and you can do all these things
like running get and expecting a content type and a status and a ton of things.
Now, this is beyond the scope of this course and is something that you can take a look at as you get
more and more into testing.
But just realize that there's tons of tools out there for you to use to write clean, nice, beautiful
tests.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.