Welcome back, everyone.
So let's actually start moving this cardless section of our code into this cardless folder.
So let's talk about the file.
What we need to make is we need to make a component file.
So here I'm going to say card list dot component.
Dodgy sex.
Now, depending on your project or depending on the files you look at when you are out there reading
other React projects, you may see that this file is called instead indexed.
Yes, inside of a cardless folder.
You may also just see card list.
Dodgy assets.
All of these are valid ways of naming a file.
It's just how you decide to do it for your project or how your senior architect decides to do it for
your project so that it's easy to navigate.
Personally, I like cardless stock component because it's very clear to me when I'm searching through
files using the global search function.
What I'm looking for, I can just say I want the card list and I know it's a component.
Now you might be wondering, well, isn't it inside of the component folder, as long as you find the
Karlis file inside of the component folder, isn't that going to be the file?
The problem with this is that there may be numerous files inside of the card list that are all related
to the component.
This might include styling files.
This might include test files.
This might include a plethora of other things.
Again, depending on how you architecture applications, folder structure, for me personally, this
is the way that I prefer to do it.
And it's really easy for me to search and this is what I prefer.
So this is my justification for why I named my files this way.
This actually, I picked this up when I was coding on angular projects of Angular has this type of naming
convention, and I thought this was a really great way of navigating through files, and I've just kept
it and moved it into my rack project.
So here inside of our cardless component file, what we need to do is we need to bring in the relevant
component, which is again our class component that we get from React.
So we're still writing our class components even for our cardless component.
You might be wondering, well, you well, what about functional components?
We'll learn about functional components and how to convert this whole master's Rolodex application over
to functional components once we finish with our class components.
Right now, I still think class components is the best way to really learn about them to begin with
because you will see them in projects.
And also, it's easier to understand how React does rendering and the concept of rendering overall class
components to me are just the most clear again because of those lifecycle methods.
So here what we want to do is we want to initialize this card list component, as we did with our app
and as we saw, we want to extend our component.
And then once we have this, what we want to do now is just render something just so that we can make
sure that our component is working.
So what I'm going to return is a div.
And inside of this do.
I wanted to say hello.
I'm the cardless component.
So let's just save this.
And what we need to do is we need to export this.
So I want a default export this.
And what exporting does is it allows other files to import the code that you write inside of it outside.
So this way, what I'm saying is that, hey, I've got this class card list and I want you to export
it by default, meaning that if they don't try to disk structure from the file in order to access other
things by default, give them whatever this is, which is our cardless class component.
So then what I'm going to do, I'm going to go into OPG's and I'm now, I'm going to import it like
so.
So I'm going to import cardless from.
I'm going to go up to the components file, into the cardless folder, into the cardless component file,
and now we have access to this component.
And as I mentioned, we can use these components the same way that we use any other of these components
input device, they're all components, except now we have card list.
So one quick thing to note, all of the components that you write, unlike these other components that
react has given us that resemble the HDMI tax.
Ours must always be cables as the first letter.
So it's camel case in the sense that every subsequent word needs to also be capitalized.
But the very first letter also needs to be capitalized.
This is how REAC can see, Oh, this is a component that is made by the actual developer.
So now that we have our cardless, let's just save and see what we see.
So inside we see this is our component.
Hello, I'm the cardless component, so we know our car list is working and it's rendering onto the
page.
Now, before we proceed any further, I want to highlight one thing about components inside of our components.
So far, we have returned one element.
And what I mean by one element is the sense that even though our components might have a lot of similar
inside of them, this component is just one div.
But you can imagine that if inside of this div, we had perhaps an H1 and.
Maybe as a sibling to this one, we had another div, let me just structure this, so it's more clear.
And maybe inside of this div, we have a p tag that has some text and there may be beside this.
We have some other components.
This is all perfectly valid.
But the thing to remember is that technically this is all encapsulated in one parental component or
parental HTML tag.
This is an important thing to remember because all components must be just the one component or the
one the parent level holder html tag.
If you have siblings, this is actually going to give you an error.
You'll see that here.
All this is highlighted and I turned off highlighting because it gets annoying when I'm teaching and
you see all of the different text file.
But this is a very important thing to note.
You cannot have multiple different components at the same level returned from a component.
You must have one parent level component.
Now there are some ways around this which I'll show you in a later lesson when we talk about more,
I guess, complicated ways of rendering different components.
But for now, this is a very good rule of thumb is that when you return a component, make sure that
there's only one top level component that you're returning.
So now again.
We understand that our cardless component is rendering.
We've put it into its own file.
What we need to do now is get the monsters that we had before into this component, and we're going
to do that using props, which is going to be a new topic with our components.
And that's what we'll cover in the next lesson.