Welcome back, everyone.
So in this video, let's talk about actually getting these monsters that we want to pass in to our cardless
that it renders into the card list.
As I mentioned in the last video, you're going to do it with props.
So what?
Our props?
Props are pretty much shorthand for properties, which is identical to these different properties that
we've already used inside of our other components class, name, type, place, holder on change.
These are all props of input and input, as I mentioned, is a react component that simulates and generates
a input HTML tag when you actually render it to the page.
So similarly, we can pass these monsters into our card list as a prop.
Now you might be wondering what is the name of the prop?
Because all these other props that we see are props that have been predefined for us.
As I mentioned on change is one that React has actually already placed onto this input component so
that we can trigger on search change or any other callback that we want to pass to whenever there's
a change event on this property.
The difference with other props inside of our components that we write is that we can name them technically
whatever we want, but we have to make sure that what we pass in is the same thing as what the component
is expecting.
So what I mean by this?
Well, technically, you can pass whatever you want.
Let's say, for example, I want to pass these monsters through and I want to call it monsters.
This monsters will actually pass, and the way that we can check what I'm going to do first is I'm just
going to pass into monsters a string for now, and it's just going to say I am the monsters.
I'm not going actually past the array there because I want to show you what's going to happen now inside
of Carla's component.
We can actually access this as a protected keyword on this.
So remember, this references the actual class component itself.
And here on this react has given us this special keyword.
Props and props will log out all of the props that you have passed this component inside of an object
where the key is the name of the prop and the value is the value of the prop that we passed to it.
So I'm going to save here, but I'm also going to remove all these other console.log.
So we're really clear about what it is that we're seeing.
And just in case I'm also going to remove, I think there's one more right here.
I'm also going to remove the additional callback that we passed or such state.
So now we should just see what happens inside of our component.
So here you notice that what we logged out was an object where the key is the name of the prop and the
value is the string that we pass to it.
For now, I want you to ignore the fact that it's logged twice.
We'll talk about why that's happening a little bit later.
But for now, just look at this object.
So any props that you pass into this component, you will see it inside of this object.
So let's just quickly test this theory up down here.
I'm going to make another value and I'm just going to call it anything just so that I can prove to you,
you can pass in anything you want.
And I'm going to pass it and array where inside is a string a.
NZ.
If I save this, I go back.
Here we see.
That there is our new prop that we passed in anything with an array that contains a NZ.
So this is how you can access props and pass props from one component into another.
One important thing to note here now is that because we can pass anything into our props, we can now
pass in our monsters.
So we want to take a second and we want to think, what do we want to pass into this list of monsters?
Well, this is where it's interesting to think do we pass in the filter monsters or do we pass in the
full list of monsters?
Well, as we know, this cardless component should only display the monsters, the cardless itself shouldn't
really have to think about how it's going to filter, because that's really actually up to the search
box.
The search box is the one that actually modifies the monsters that are being passed into this.
For this reason, there's no reason for us to hide that responsibility together.
Instead, all our cardless cares about is what am I going to have to display?
And what that is is going to be the array of filtered monsters.
Now let's save and go back to our project.
Clear out all of this and refresh.
And what we see or getting in is our monsters array, and as we type, we should see that this will
continue to update and give us the correct list of monsters.
So even though we can't see it visually as we type in our letters, we do see that the only monster
we're receiving is the one that matches the LDI strength.
So everything here is still working as expected.
In fact, as IRS, we're getting back our full array of monsters.
So here again, everything works.
Now, what I want to do is we actually want to render these monsters.
So what we're going to do is let's go into this component.
And let's actually just do the same thing we did before, so we know that what we're getting back is
the monsters.
So I'm going to say Konst.
Monsters, some destruction structuring off of this stuff, props.
And the reason we do structure is because if we need to use this in more places than one, it's just
easier to do so.
And now I can just say monsters dot map.
The monster.
And just render back.
And one.
Where the text is monster dot name.
And if I save this, we go back, we see here we have it again.
We have that warning with a unique key prop, so let's go back and make sure we have it.
And here we're going to say Monster ID, which we remember was what we used before to keep track of
the unique keys on these H1 tags.
And if we care and refresh.
We see that it's gone.
And again, if I type in, everything works as expected.
So just like that, we now have a cardless component that replicates the same behavior we had before.
One quick thing to note.
What I want to do is I want to console log here.
Render.
And I want to go back to what we were talking about before.
Where what we noticed is that when we refresh.
We see that the render is called twice.
And here it actually has to do with the way that react renders components.
I want to talk about this in the next video, but I want you to take a second to think about it.
If you can come up with an answer, that's at least pretty good because it's really important here that
you think and try and piece these things about how Iraq renders together.
While we're learning this topic this way, you really get to think and really try and understand based
on the way that React does things that we've learned so far about why it might be doing these things.
So once you have an answer or once you've thought about a little bit, join me in the next video and
let's break down why.
In our component, we see render twice.