Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we're going to talk about re rendering inside of components.
And we're also going to understand how it extends into this new component structure that we have because
now we have two components.
So when we first looked at our component before this was saying console log render.
I've updated this to say console dot log render from card.
And I did this just so that we can be clear that the render log is coming from the cardless component.
Hear what I'm going to do is I'm actually going to comment this out for now.
We're going to use this later, but outside of that comes it out comes a lot.
There's no more console.log.
So going back to our application, if we refresh, what we see is that we see that we're calling render
from cardless twice.
Now, at this point, I want you to pause and think about why this might be happening.
Really think about the flow of all your components.
Once you've thought about that, let's explain why this is happening.
Render is going called twice inside of our cardless component.
Before when we looked at Angus, when do we see that render gets called render gets called when we initialize
the application because constructor gets called first and then render gets called.
And then when we called component did Mount and we actually did the fetch we call a set stay and remember
whenever set stick, it's called render gets called again.
So we can predict that.
If I just comment out that and we just look at this render from Angus and I refresh.
We saw that we initialize the app we call render from Afghans jazz and then component did Mount happens?
And then we do the fetch we call the set state again.
Renderer map just happens.
So we know that sets state will trigger a render from calling.
However, components will also render when prompts change.
And this is a very important thing because it's just like said state, whenever props is different or
components will also re render.
So how does the props change inside of cardless?
Well, that's console.log this stop props.
And then let's just console.log our actual value inside of props so that we see.
Let's refresh.
When we first render our card list, we are getting past an empty array.
This is the initial state value inside of A.j.'s.
Of are monsters.
It's an empty array that is being passed into cardless initially.
So Carlos is getting rendered and it's getting rendered with an empty array.
And then what happens is that we call set state with the full list of users in our component did mount
and here.
That's why we see the second time that this array is now a full array.
Well, how does react?
Actually, no.
Oh, I've gotten new values.
I need to probably re render in case the UI is based on our props, which is exactly what's happening.
This is why all of these are now updated because React is saying, Oh, I have new props, let me re
render the component with the new props are props.
As we know from our code directly actually gives us the new monsters we map over the monsters, which
is our props, and that's how we see the UI update with all of these monsters.
This is an important thing about components, components we render based on two conditions.
When set state gets called and when props are updated, this is how primarily react determines that
you want to re render because only when those things happen does react.
Actually update the DOM and try and see, Oh, what are these components and what are the new things
that we need to return from them?
That's why you see render from cardless get called twice.
And this goes into a deeper thing when we think about this new componentry.
When I see a componentry, what I mean is that you have these parent components and inside there are
child components.
If we think about it, react always renders from the top down.
So what I mean by Top-Down, if you look at index chess index chess shows us the very top level component,
which is our app component.
So what it's going to do is it's going to attempt to render the app component first, meaning it goes
to the constructor and then it calls the render call of our app.
Yes.
When it's going through a render as it goes line by line runs all of our code and then it goes into
this return.
And inside here it now sees card list.
Once it sees cardless as a component, then it's going to try and run this card list components different
lifecycle methods.
So from the cardless component, it's going to call the constructor, which even though we haven't written
it, it's running it under the hood.
And then it's going to run the render and actually render out what's inside.
If we had another component here, imagine we have a third component and we call it third component.
At this point, after running through the render and the constructor, then it's going to go into another
component and it's going to do the same thing, it's going to run this components constructor.
This components render and any subsequent children are going to do the same thing.
So it's going from top down.
And this is the idea of a component tree where the top of the tree is your parent component and then
each level down is any children that there are and subsequent children and subsequent children and et
cetera, et cetera.
Well, definitely talk about this more, but this is the way that react renders things so very important
thing.
Remember, react renders on mounts and re renders whenever props change and set state gets called.
And here we've seen two examples.
Now we've seen set state where we're calling it, and we saw the render get called.
And we're seeing one new props come in.
Render gets called.
So that's a very important thing to think about.
When you're looking at your components and thinking about, how do I update my components one, that's
how you do it.
You either have to make sure that that state is getting cold and you're updating the states or your
props are changing.
Those are the main ways that you want your components to update.
If your component is not updating, then you're probably not either updating props or using set state.
So we'll talk about how to leverage this when we want our UI to update, when we make changes and we
build complex applications.
But this is a very important groundwork to understand about how React determines when it needs to re
render the application and it needs to re render components.
So hopefully now you understand at least the basis of how these components render and render.
This will get us through the majority of a lot of the rest of building this application and future applications.
We just really need to understand this about React and these components rendering and rendering.
So now that we understand this, let's build out the rest of our application.