Welcome back, everyone.
So in this video, let's apply some of our styles and have a better understanding of the way that react
handles regular access.
So right here, when we initialized our application and create reactor, we knew that we had also generated
this app Dot CIUSSS file.
Inside of this app that Sears has filed, there are, of course, a bunch of styling that was related
to that original spinning logo that create reactor scaffold it for us.
Now we don't need any of this anymore.
So what we want to do is we want to start styling our application to look much more similar to what
we had in the final output.
So let's go here and see what we have is, of course, we have this title.
But then we also have this background and we have these different cards that are styled in place of
what we see now, which is just once.
So let's start styling, and that way we can get an understanding of how this application works.
So here, let's talk a little about structure inside of us.
Ijaz represents the entry point to our entire application.
There's a reason why in most applications, A.j.'s does not live inside of your components folder.
And the reason for this is because App J.S. is not necessarily the same category of component as these
other components.
These other components represent reusable components in our application, whereas OPG's there is only
ever one.
You will not have multiple agassiz because again, OPG's is the entry point represented as a component
into our entire application.
Similarly, then, we also have an app that says this is going to be styling that should apply to your
entire application.
You can keep it in app Nazi SS or if you don't like App XYZ, you can make a index that CSC violence,
that an import that instead into objects.
It's really just up to how you want a name.
This idea of a styling file that reflects styling that should be present across your entire application.
So for us, what should go in there?
Well, for now, let's look at this application.
We know that this background is ever present, so let's actually add this into our application.
So she has us inside of React is like CSI anywhere.
I don't want to spend too much time on CSI because generally speaking, there's so much JavaScript and
react that we have to learn throughout this course.
So what I'm going to do is give you all of the CSI that you are going to apply.
I'm going to, of course, talk about how CSI actually operates inside of React and all of the considerations
you have to make for it.
But if we just talk about CSI, I'm going to spend hours on hours teaching CSI.
So there's no real point to that when really the purpose is to learn, react and JavaScript.
So here, just look inside your resources folder and get that ceasefire and just paste it into your
app that sees us.
Once you've passed that rent, save and go back to your application and you will see that you now have
this gradient background.
So one thing to note about the way that CSC works inside of React.
Is that no matter where you import it?
As long as it's a general ceasefire, react will build it all into one big ceasefire so that no matter
what, that cease is always present in your application.
Now why is this an important thing to think about?
OK.
Let's discuss and represent how we should structure our system knowing that, and we'll better understand
what I mean when I say this.
Inside of your search box component.
What you want to do is you want to write XSS that's relevant to the component.
So I'm going to make a search box dot styles dot ceasefire.
This is just going to hold cost that is only applicable to our search box and of course, our search
box component here.
Right now, we are appending some classes on here, but let's say, for example, by using string interpolation.
We can do this, so we have to wrap our string interpolation because interpolation is JavaScript inside
of these squiggly brackets.
And here what this interpolation I'm saying, OK, I'm going to use some JavaScript in the string.
I want you to take this variable and apply it, and we know class name is going to be a string.
But let's also just say for our sake, we say this is a search box.
So I'm adding the class name search box right now.
The property that we're passing into apparatus is also search box, and I'm just going to call this
monster's search box.
So when I save this.
And I say this, if I go here and I look at this component.
I will see that there are now two classes on here.
There is search box and monster search box segments.
The search box tells me, Oh, this is a search box for monsters, but then search box is general.
Style it.
And this is important because inside of my search box styles, I can now target this search box.
Class that I have by default in the component.
If I wanted to overwrite some of these styles or add additional styles for the monster search box,
which is a specific instance, or I'm using the search box component for a specific purpose, then I
can apply styling on that class and that is dictated by whatever is passing it, and it makes a flexible
like that.
But I do want all my search boxes to have some general styling.
So here inside of here, you can just again look inside your resources folder.
Find that, yes, that's code for search box and paste it in.
Now we save.
And what we need to do is we need to import this ceasefire into our search box component.
So I'm going to say input, and then I'm going to go up in the same folder and just import search box
styles that SS.
Once I look inside of my code, I will see that this search box now has the styling, it's thicker now,
it's bigger now.
That was all we did for updating this.
But one thing I want you to know when I mentioned earlier that no matter where you import CCS, it will
be present on the entire page.
The important thing I want to say there is that this list does not mean it only applies to your search
box component.
So our car getting inside.
Of course, only applies to this class, but I mean that this file is not in isolation from the rest
of our application because styles CSF style specifically apply to the entire website, the file is present
across the entire website.
That means that other components are not protected from the styling that you write, even though here
when you see this import, it makes it seem like I'm importing styling that's only relevant to search
box.
That does not mean that only within the context of this file is this applied once ISIS is actually bundled
and then put onto a website that's just as is applicable to every single components, every single HTML
that's on that website.
And a quick way that we can test this is if we look inside of our car component for this div that reflects
our cardless component, I'm just going to put a quick class name here.
And I'm going to say cardless.
And I want to do this just to demonstrate to you that we can target this from our search box styles.
Let's say here I say Doc Cardless.
And let's do something really bold.
Let's set the background color to red.
If I save this and I go back here, you see that this cardless components background is affected.
And this is because again, when you import a ceasefire, that ceasefire is going to be applicable to
the entire website.
The only reason why we put these imports at the component level is more so for us when we are looking
for our styling that is related to the search box, you want to put it where that component lives.
And of course, you want to target your access.
So that's only relevant to the components code inside.
But this is just a designation for us as the actual developers.
As far as the underlying technology is concerned, if you write CSI that will overlap with components
outside of your component, it will still happen exactly as we saw here.
This doc cardless code in CSI is still going to affect other code.
So that's an important thing to remember.
Now you might be wondering, is there a way that I can isolate my code so that the CSIS doesn't overlap
with CSIS in other files?
There is, and that involves learning some CSC in Jeff's libraries, which will do in a later project.
Not this one that is going to help us do the isolation.
And we're going to definitely dive into why the differences with that one exist between this one, which
is CSC in React.
Now, let's delete the style.
And in the next lesson, let's star the rest of our application, including styling out our different
users slash monsters into their own respective cards, so I'll see you in the next lesson.