Welcome back, everyone.
In my last video, I asked you to move this into its own component, this card.
So what we can do in this one is do that now.
So let's create a component call card.
So we'll initialize the folder and we'll say card talk component Duchess X as well as card dot styles.
Dozier says.
Inside of card component, let's do all of our setup, so we know we need to import the component class
from React.
We also might as well import our style file because we know we're going to need the styles.
Finally, let's initialize the class, so we'll say a class card extends component.
And also, we need to make sure we export default the card, so I like doing all of this up front,
the setup for a new component just so that I remember it's easy sometimes for us to write our code and
then for things not to work.
And we think that it's a bug when in reality, we're just missing some of the crucial steps that are
necessary in order for these cards and these multiple files to all work together.
So by doing this stuff upfront, you're making sure that you get around that.
We also need to make sure that we render something and in that render we return something.
So what I'm going to do is I come over, I'm a copy this code over.
So this is the HTML.
And when we look at this HMO, what do we see that we're missing?
Well, we actually don't have all of the required variables.
We don't because we have an intern.
And I think so here.
What I want to do is I want to make sure that I structure off the ID, the name and the email, which
are the values that my component is expecting to use.
And obviously, this is going to come in as a prop.
What I want to do is I want to pass the entire object through by doing that.
I know that what I'm getting off of this props is going to be exactly that whole object and the object
should have these values.
There are ways that we can enforce this that we'll talk about later.
For now, we are making a pretty small application where the only people coding on it, so we know what
it is that we're coming in, which is this monster.
At this point, if we save this.
And what we are going to do is replace the cardless component with this component.
So here I'm going to say card.
And instead of doing the restructuring here, I'm just going to pass Monster.
Like so as a prop that we set up.
And then I'm going to import in.
Card from.
Hard Dash card component.
And let me save this.
And just to make sure.
Our code is still working.
The other thing that we're missing now is moving the styles.
We have card related styling inside of card list, and as I mentioned, yes, as is relevant everywhere,
which is why our stores still work.
But again, for the proper separation of concerns, we want to move this into card styles.
We've already done the import.
If we go back, we see that our code is still working.
The last thing that we need to add is going to be the title.
So here I'm going to leave it up to you to put whatever title you want into your application.
What I'm going to do is just go into the app.
And I'm just going to put an h one above the search box.
And here I'm probably going to want to move it a little or put some padding around it, so I'm also
going to give a class name.
Of app title.
And inside, I'm just going to say Monster's Rolodex.
I'm going to save this, go into apps, assess and Target app title.
Once we're inside, what I want is a margin top, oh, let's just say seventy five pixels.
I want a margin bottom.
Of, let's say, 50 pixels.
I want a font size of seventy six pixels.
And I also want a font, color or just color in this particular case of hash zero c c a c for.
Which is a light blue.
At this point, you can also actually include a new font.
And if you're unfamiliar or if you are familiar with adding fonts into applications, typically what
you might do is might go on to Google Fonts and inside of Google Fonts.
You'll just find a font that you like and then you'll install the script into your HTML file.
So I'll show you how to do that.
You can pick whatever font you want.
I'm going to pick Bigalow rules.
Which is this one, because it looks kind of like monster ish kind of reminds me of Addams Family.
So here I'm just going to hit this plus to add the style.
And then all you do is you take this link, you copy this.
You go back into your application.
And let's just close all these other unneeded files.
In order for us to actually include it in our application, typically you put it inside of your indexed
HMO.
And for us, it's the exact same.
We have it here inside of our public folder and we're just going to paste this somewhere.
So I'm going to paste this right here and this will install in our Google Fonts.
So once I have the fonts, then what I'm going to do is I'm going to go back into my apps to assess.
And I'm just going to say that font family is going to be Bigelow.
Rules.
Because this is the one that we just installed.
You see the name right here.
And then if we go back to our application, we'll see that everything matches now.
So this application looks pretty similar to this application.
I've got a little bit more padding or margin at the top.
It's up to you.
If you want to add less, add more.
You can tweak this however you want, but this is it.
This is our application.
Everything works as we expect it to.
You can clear the search bar and everything works.
And there you go.
This is your first project of as Rolodex, if any of this was confusing.
Please rewatch this series of videos because from here, we're really going to build a top the foundation
of everything we've learned.
And just to quickly go over.
A lot of the main focus of what we wanted to understand about this project and react was primarily components
how they render, how they re render.
And the basic composition patterns that we need for react.
So now that we understand this, I'm going to go deeper with what we've just learned and you're going
to get a lot of practice with a lot of these concepts again.
We just work with class components and in the next video, what I'm going to do is I'm going to talk
about converting these into functional components and some of the differences between class and functional
components.
So if you're unfamiliar with class components, just quickly go over them.
You'll get a good understanding of generally how they work.
And then in the next video, let's dive deeper into functional components and hooks.