Welcome back, everyone.
Before we move on to functional components, I want to quickly go over our class component rendering
and re rendering because we're relying on a lot of life cycles right now inside of our class components
that we need to now understand how a functional component replaces them.
So in order to understand that, we need to properly understand all of our life cycles.
Once again, we've gone over it a couple of times, but there's actually this great diagram here by
a white Ma who I will link inside of your resources folder that has shown this diagram where you can
see the breakdown of class components and the rendering and re rendering alongside lifecycles.
So let's go through the three most important phases.
Mounting, updating and mounting.
So when a component mounts, as we saw with a class component, we know it runs the constructor and
then it runs the render method.
At this point, after these have been called React, we'll update the DOM and in our particular case
with mounting it is updating the DOM by mounting our components for the first time.
And after that has mounted, then you will see component did mount as the lifecycle method that got
calls after.
This is all of our code inside of our current app class component.
Nothing new here.
What happened subsequently is with updating, as we see here, whenever new props come in or whenever
set state gets called, render gets called again.
This still aligns with what we know.
We remember logging out, render and whenever new props came in or sets take, it's called the render
method.
Get called.
Similarly, React will then update the DOM with the new UI.
And then there is actually another lifecycle method that you can hook into called component did update
so you can run some code inside of this after a re render happens.
Meaning when new prompts comes in sets, it gets called react as updated the DOM.
Then this method runs just like component did.
Mount runs after the Mount update.
There's also this force update method where you force the component to re render.
This is oftentimes not something you should be calling.
It's provided if you have to force your component to update.
But typically speaking, you want to rely on react and its component structure understanding when updates
are supposed to happen.
You should not necessarily always force an update.
This more so only happens when you're integrating with third party libraries that don't necessarily
have a React based library that hooks in and follows along with the typical update cycles.
Then you want to use force update if you have to.
But most of the time you just want to rely on what's provided.
Finally, there is un mounting, I'm mounting is just when you are taking a component off the page.
What this means is sometimes you're navigating to different pages or you're changing your UI where you
don't need a component on the page anymore.
React will be the one that takes that off the page.
And once it takes it off the page, it is now on mountain, so there's no longer existing on the page.
And before that happens, there is a component will unmount lifecycle method that runs before the component
is finally stripped off.
This is typically done when you need to clean up certain things when you think about this, for those
of you familiar.
This is where you might want to remove any listeners or anything that consumes memory by relying on
the component actually being alive.
This will run before you actually pull that off so you don't get any memory leaks.
We'll definitely talk about this because we will utilize some listeners.
If you're unfamiliar with the idea of an event listener or subscriptions, that's another way to think
about them.
If those you aren't familiar with, don't worry, we'll do them later in the capstone project.
But for now, this is mainly where you will do these types of things.
This is where you will utilize this lifecycle method on an unmount.
Now, this is unique to class components component in mount component IT update and component will unmount.
Functional components don't have these lifecycle methods, but they do still follow this same three
phases of components.
There is a mounting phase, there is an updating phase and there is a UN mounting phase.
The only difference is that you don't interact with these three phases the way that we do with the class
component where we override the constructor method, the render method component and mount component
and update component will unmount methods.
Those are what we were doing inside of our class component when whenever we wrote into our constructor
or our render or our component did mount lifecycle methods, functional components do not do this.
They are completely different, but they follow the exact same structure and that I want to make very
clear.
It's just that you have to think about how a functional component moves through these three phases based
on the concept of a function, and that is what we're going to cover when we dive into our functional
components.
So go over this chart whenever you need to really understand what's happening.
And once you do join me in the next video and let's dive into functional components.