Welcome back, everyone.
So let's continue with creating our app functional component.
So here what I'm going to do is I'm going to move search box back into the return of our demo, so I'm
going to uncomment to.
And let's think about what we need in order to pass this on such change that we had before into search
box.
As we know, with a function, a function is supposed to iterate from top to bottom, meaning that JavaScript
runs from top to bottom.
So of course, we need to actually create this on search change function inside of our app.
So I'm just going to create this function right here on search of change.
And this is going to be equal to a function.
And this will be the exact same search change handler that we had before, so scrolling down here.
Let's copy what's inside of here.
In fact, let's take the whole entire function because we need the event.
We're going to have to fix it up a little bit because it is common set out below.
So if I paste this here, I will need to uncomment that out.
And fix the tapping here.
So here what we do.
We get the event.
And then what we do with lowercase it and following up we do this sets date.
So this not such date, as I mentioned, is a method unique to class components, but we're not using
that anymore.
In fact, let me remove it because we don't need our class component anymore.
How are we going to set state?
This is actually where we need to use a hook.
So let me explain what hooks are and more specifically, the most simplest hook that's available to
us, which is the use state hook.
You state essentially gives us a ability to encapsulate local state in a functional component.
So let's talk about how we actually use it.
What we're going to do is we are going to use Array D structuring from use state because use state gives
us back an array of two values.
So if you're unfamiliar with array restructuring, essentially what it does is it allows us to assign
variables to values inside of an array.
So as a quick example, let me just quickly show you.
Let's say that we had some aura and it contained the values two and four like this.
If I do contest A, B equals A.
So I'm saying, Hey, I want you to assign a variable a to the first value, add a vowel B to the second
value.
Now, a as we see as equals A to B is equal to four.
So this is exactly what we're doing here.
You state gives us back an array of two values.
The first value is going to be the value that we want to store.
And the second value is going to be a set or function.
So what do I mean by this?
You state, unlike the set state that you're familiar with, inside of class components is a object
in the class component, but in the functional component, it's individual values.
We are not trying to store entire objects.
So here what we want to do when we say, Oh this u state value, we are going to encapsulate a singular
value from that state.
So if you have multiple values in a state, well, then you need multiple use state calls.
Each hook only hooks into one value.
So here we want to do search field.
So search field, you want to pass into the you state the initial value that it should be.
And for us before.
Inside of our object, our search fields, initial value was an empty string.
So we want to do the same thing here.
We're going to initialize it as an empty string.
And what we'll get back again is the value and asset value.
So here I'm going to call it the search field.
Value and then I'm going to call this set search field.
So what these two values now we're able to actually replicate the sets state for just search field.
So we don't need this anymore.
Here are these two names clash what really this search field is, is really the target value that's
been lowercase.
So I'm just going to say this is the search field string, because that's what it is.
It's the string value we're getting back from our search field.
And what I want to do is I want to call that sets search field center function that we get back from,
you state.
And then I'm going to pass this in.
So far, this is all we're really doing.
And with this search field.
What this should do now simply is just log the value, because right now nothing is actually happening.
We haven't used this search field string in the state for anything yet before we were filtering monsters
with it.
But so far, we haven't done anything.
And the reason why is because I just want to show you what these values will be.
So here I'm going to console don't log search field.
And I just want you to see what's happening.
So let's say let's go to our application.
Let's clear this out.
So when we initialized our search field is an empty string, that's the first time it logs.
So remember, we're logging this after our you state gets called.
So at this point, search field is an empty string because that's the default empty string value.
We have this on search change function, and what it does is it receives the event a lowercase is it?
And then it calls that search field and then we pass that into our search box component.
So our search bar component runs it every time we type into the search box.
Now, if we start typing, what we see is that our search field is indeed updating the value inside
of the local state with this string value.
Now, one quick thing I want to mention is that when we're logging this, this isn't an object because
I am logging out an object right here, I'm just using object shorthand in order to make it more clear
to us what it is we're logging.
But set state is really not in an object anymore.
It's whatever value it is inside of the state itself.
So in our particular case, this used state is a string.
And whenever we set the value, we're setting a string.
So search field value itself is actually a string.
So if I instead remove those curly braces and here instead, you'll see it mounts, it's empty.
And then as you type, you log out a string.
It's still just whatever value type it is, it doesn't get converted into an object the way that set
state had it before where our entire state object was an object in here.
It's whatever type it is when you pass it to the state hook.
So this is an important difference.
So now that we understand how to utilize the used state hook in the next video, let's dive into the
way that we can understand how these components are re rendering in the context of this hook.
See you in the next video.