Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to talk about rendering and re rendering inside of our functional components
and specifically we're going to talk about how hooks and more specifically the use state hook fits inside
all of this.
To begin with, I have console logged out the string render online eight at the very top of our functional
component, and we're still continuing to log out our search field value.
What I want you to think about is whenever right now inside of our application, let's clear this.
When I refresh, we see render and then we see the empty string.
Whenever I type anything, you'll notice that render is getting called first and then the string value
is being called.
What this means is that React is running this entire function every single time it needs to re render
a component that is a functional component.
This is a very important thing.
Previously, inside of our class components, whenever there were mounting and update cycles render
would get run and update cycles ran whenever props changed or whenever state updated.
The only thing that ran, though, was whatever code was inside of the render method with functional
components, we don't have a render method.
This entire functional component, you can kind of see as the same thing as the render method.
Essentially, whenever React has determined that a functional component needs to render or re render,
it will just run the entire function top to bottom.
The way that it determines whether or not a functional component needs to update is the same as a class
component whenever the props change, which is the arguments inside of a function that we have not worked
with yet.
But we will soon.
But just remember that whatever prompts change, the whole function gets run.
So Rack is determining, Oh, I need to re render the component.
Let me run the entire functional component.
Similarly, whenever state changes, it will also rerun this entire functional component.
That is the only way reac knows there's probably new UI.
How do I determine what that new UI is going to be?
Let me just rerun the entire function so that whatever gets returned from this function is going to
have the latest variables, latest props to state values so that I know what the new UI will look like
based on the returned GSX from this function.
This is the thing to remember about functional components.
You cannot just run part of this function.
This whole function needs to rerun every single time.
So what about you, state and this hook?
The thing about you state, is that you are getting back this state value and under the hood, what
react does is React will actually check whether or not this state value is different.
Only went through that hard a quality, it notices that there are different values.
Only then will react actually rerun this value.
So currently, every time our event changes, the state value is updating because we're either typing
new characters into the string or removing characters from the string.
We saw that.
However, if I were to copy search field and just call set search field instead and save this every
time we type into this search box, I don't care about what the string you're giving me back is.
I just want you to set the value of search field to the current search field value.
If we do this and we refresh, we'll see.
Is that despite the fact that I'm typing in these characters, we're not seeing any of the console.log,
the fire.
And the reason for that is because React is calling our set, our function, our set search field,
but it's just not giving it a different value.
So React is smart enough to know, oh, as this state value is the same value, then don't rerun this
function.
And what this tells us, it's not actually set a search field that triggers a rendering of a component.
It's actually when the state value changes.
In the context of our current you state, if the current string value of our state is the same as the
new string value coming in, literally the string values are the exact same.
Then we will not render meaning that we will not run this function from top to bottom again.
We can easily test this.
Let's say I initialized the initial state value as a string that contains the letter A.
Let's update so that instead of passing the search field and we're passing back in the string value
that we're getting from the events of our search box.
Remember are search boxes, internal string state is completely separate from our you state, meaning
that whatever the state value is does not actually affect the value that a search box has inside of
it.
The way that we can easily see this is that with that initialization, the initial string value is a.
But our search box is an empty string.
Of course it is because we're not actually taking our state value and putting it into the search box.
It's the other way we're taking out whatever value is being typed into the search box and we're trying
to remedy it against what we have in our app.
So here what should happen is that when I type the letter A..
We should see no consul logs because our current state value is a.
So if I type a, we're going to get the letter a string and it's going to say, Oh, the value of the
string you typed in is the same value as what I have inside of my state.
So our function is not going to rerun and that's what we see.
We just type in.
Nothing happened.
But if I keep typing it in, then we see we're now rerunning the component because of the string value
is now different than what we have inside of our internal state.
And now everything works as expected.
So that's the thing to understand about the way that react determines using state inside of your functional
component, whether or not it needs to re render.
We'll talk more about this as we build out our application with the different hooks and some more complex
cases when putting this kind of stuff together.
But this is really the most important difference about functional components and class components.
You need to stop thinking about functional components and life cycles and start seeing it instead,
as when does react determined that I need to rerun my entire functional component.
That's really the difference.
So with that, let's move on to completely changing the remainder of our class app into this functional
component.