Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, let's actually migrate out what we have left inside of this component, which is the
card list.
So let's uncomment out that part of our code and put this in.
And here what we need is filtered monsters.
In order to get the filter monsters, let's think about what we need inside of this part of the code,
which was our old class component that actually returned us the filter and monsters.
What we need here is we need a monsters to filter from.
And this monsters before.
What's inside of our state, which was initialized as an empty array, so let's do that first.
Let's first initialize a new state, so konst monsters and then set monsters.
Remember, it's the value and then the center value, and I'm going to say you state and I'm going to
pass it.
The initial value, which is an empty array.
Now that we have this, what we need now is to figure out how to actually get the values from Jason
placeholder into this app component.
What we had before is that we had this component did Mount call component did mount is some lifecycle
method as we know that fires only when the component mounts, that's the only time we need to fetch
this initial data.
After that, we don't need to ever fetch it again.
But this might pose a problem for us because let's just look at if we copy this fetch and let's comment
this out back again.
And let's just say put this inside of our application.
If we just made this call and what we did is right here instead of such state, we said monsters.
And instead of passing it a function, we can just pass in the value that we want the monsters to be
set to.
So which is our users?
Now before I save this and before you save this, what I want you to do is I want you to also add a
console dot log render.
Remember, I'm trying to show you that this is not the way that you want it actually fetch.
There are a couple weird things that are going to happen, and we're going to dive deep into why that
happens.
So if you save this fetch now and you go to your application, let's refresh.
What are we going to see?
We see the render call.
We do see our content, but lotus, how this render is constantly firing over and over and over and
over and over again.
Why does it keep doing this?
Well, this actually has to do with the way that functional components work.
So what?
You don't have to do an art to break this is you're going to have to go into your windows and go down.
It's your task manager.
Open this, find your application right here and end this process.
Only by doing that, you prevent the stack from continually recalling.
So why did that happen?
What do we know about our functional components?
Whenever the state updates, if there's a different value for the state value as there was in the previous
state, then it will re render and to re render, we need to run this entire functional component.
Top to bottom again.
Fetch is fetching from some foreign API, some specific value in our particular case, it is the user's
array.
This array, because it comes from outside of our browser, is going to give us an array that is different
in memory than the one that we have stored.
Even if the values inside of this array is the exact same because we know we get the same 10 user objects
back in this array every time we call this API URL.
But because it comes from outside of our browser, it is a different array in memory.
Every time this check happens.
Or set monsters is seeing that this users array is a different one, a memory, so the a quality check
fails, meaning that React thinks it's going to be a different array, which it is.
It's a different array, even if the values inside of the same.
Remember, it's not about the values in the array, it's about whether or not that array points to the
same reference in memory.
And every time this happens, it is a different array in memory.
So as a result, what happens is that every single time this set monsters is getting called, it is
re rendering this entire function.
And this function, as I told you with all JavaScript functions, will run through every single line.
It cannot just isolate one part of this function.
It has to run every line in the function.
So it's going to refresh every single time, which puts us in a circular loop.
We are going to re render in turn, we are going to fetch again, get a new set of users and then update.
The state state is updated React Re renders.
This function fetches again, gets different users, sets monsters and then reruns.
And now we're stuck in this loop where we're just constantly refreshing over and over and over and over
again.
And that is why this is happening.
As a result, what we need to do is we need to stop fudging somehow inside of this functional component
every time and the way we do that is actually using side effects.
Side effects can be generated from functional components using the use effect hook.
If you remember, a side effect is some behavior that we trigger from our functions that affects something
that exists outside of the scope of the function.
It's either that we modify or we rely on some value that exists outside of what's within scope of our
function or component in this particular case.
Any such call is a side effect.
So we need to use the use of that took and this hook is a little complicated.
But right now, before we move on to utilizing this use effect, I want you to really understand this
specific thing that happened in our functional component.
It's incredibly important because through this, will you actually understand how functional components
really work and how React determines using functional components that it needs to render?
So remember.
Functional components, any time it renders or re renders, runs the code inside of this function.
Top to bottom every single time.
So if you have some weird bug, whenever you're coding out react components and you notice that you're
stuck in a random loop, think about what's happening.
Think about all the steps that to three rendering.
Think about the fact that this function runs top to bottom.
Look at the variables in your states.
Are they different variables or are they the same variables?
These are very important things to really know about when it comes to react and coding at this level
with React, React has come a long way, and as a result, you have to really have solid foundational
understanding of JavaScript in order to properly code react components and understand how to optimize
your React code.
But now that we understand what's happening inside of app and why we were stuck in that infinite render
loop.
Let's move on to utilizing use a fact hook to get around this issue.
I'll see you in the next video.