Welcome back, everyone.
So in the last video, we learned about why adding fetch calls that might cost that state can trigger
these infinite re render cycles.
And how do we simulate this behavior that we know we need inside of our component without causing ourselves
to get stuck in that loop?
I mentioned that we want to trigger side effects, and we do that using the use effect hook.
The use effect hook takes two arguments.
The first is going to be a callback function.
And the second is going to be an array of dependencies.
So let's break down what each of these are.
What is going to be this first argument, this callback?
Well, this callback is going to be the code or the fact that we want to happen inside of our functional
component.
What about this second array?
Well, the second array contains different dependencies and by dependencies, these are most likely
going to be state of values, so either search field or monster in the context of this application or
prop values, which will be arguments that get passed in as props to our functional component.
What this array says is that whenever any of the values inside of this dependency era change is when
I'm going to run this function, this callback function.
It's going to run this callback function the very first time this app mounts, because it's the very
first time this entire code is going to get run.
And then any subsequent re render of this component, I will only run this callback function if the
values inside of the dependency ray have changed.
So by doing that, we're now able to generate these side effects, which are again effects that come
out of our function.
In our particular case, a side effect is this fetch call.
So by moving this inside of our use effect hook here, we're just saying, hey, there's a callback
that creates a fetch call that then sets the monsters.
And I only want you to make this call if the values inside of this are a change.
Well, let's think about that.
When do we want to make a fetch call when this app mounts the first time?
And then after eight minutes, do we ever want to fetch from Jason placeholder again?
We don't.
We only want it to happen once.
So what needs to go inside of this array?
Well, nothing.
We don't ever want to trigger this callback ever again other than the very first time the app mounts.
So for that reason, we pass it an empty array as the dependency array.
We're essentially saying to this use effect Hey, the only time you should ever call this function is
on Mount, because if any of the dependencies change, use effect is going to call this function.
But I'm passing, you know, dependencies, which means that nothing is ever going to change.
So nothing should ever trigger you to recall this function ever again.
Other than the very first time when the function mounts.
So now, if we save this and we go back to our application and let's just refresh.
We see that we get one render call when we had our empty array and then we have one render call after
our fetch request comes back with all of our users.
But now what we'll notice is that even as we re render, we are not recreating that fetch call.
And just to be clear, let's add a console dot log in here, just so that we're sure that our effect
is not firing more than once.
I'm just going to say effect fired, and here we come back.
We see that we have our initial avec fire, and now as we type, the effect never fires again.
And this is exactly what we want out of our use of fact.
So here we have an example of what it's like to pass an empty array to our use factbook.
Let's take a look at a way that we can actually leverage this function's array so that we can get a
better understanding of some more complex use cases of this dependency array.
Another thing that we know that we need to do is we need to update the filter monsters.
Here is something that is interesting about filtered monsters to those of you that are savvy and have
understood what we've talked about when it comes to these functions rendering top to bottom.
What we know is that every time this function runs, this filter and monsters array is getting rebuilt.
Even if the monster's array has not changed.
This is OK, though, because we want to do this essentially whenever monsters change or one of a search
for real change.
But let's say just for an example that we wanted to trigger some changes as well in this application
that also modifies the state.
So I'm just going to give you a very quick example.
Let's say that I have some Stringfield.
This is another field and I just do set Stringfield.
And this also stars.
And let's just create another search box.
And inside, I'm going to generate content on string change.
And it's going to be very similar, it gets an event.
And all we're going to do is that we are just going to set the Stringfield value.
Whenever this event fires target value.
And I'm going to pass this into.
This second search box, I'm going to call this, in fact, I'm going to get rid of this class name
just so that we can visually see something different, and I'm going to set this placeholder as set
straight.
What I'm also going to do is I'm going to console dot log filtered monsters.
And now if I save this.
Here we have our search monsters and then we have our set string.
What you'll notice is that every time I type this.
Even though this searching hasn't changed and this monsters or hasn't changed.
I am really filtering through all of these monsters every single time, which is why you see this log
of the filter monsters every single time.
Even though this Stringfield doesn't do anything to our monsters, our search filters over here, this
Stringfield is just a different secondary input.
And yet for some reason, as we know, our function is going to re filter through these monsters.
This seems like a very inefficient thing, because to filter through these monsters, it costs our application,
our JavaScript some time to do this.
And over time, this could lead to a lot of inefficiencies.
So what we want to do is we only want to filter these monsters whenever the things relevant to filtering
monsters has changed, meaning that if the monsters array has changed or if the search field value has
changed, both of which live in our state.
So what we can do in order to fix this is that we can make another effect.
And order to do that.
What I'm going to say is that I'm going to initialize a filtered monster's state.
And set filter monsters.
And this is initial state is going to be the monsters value.
So by default, I'm just going to take whatever value was used here.
We do this because in case this initial value, as ever something else, we know that the filter on
monsters is always based off monsters.
So I'm just going to use this value.
So to initialize it will be the same empty array.
And then what I'm going to do is I am going to call another use effect, I'm going to say use effect.
Our callback.
And we know that in this callback, what we want to do is we just want to run.
This filtered monsters call.
And here I'm going to say this is new filtered monsters.
And once we filter through and we have that new monster, then we are going to say sets filter monsters
to the new filter and monsters.
And now filter monsters here is always going to contain the values we want.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to say I want you to filter through these monsters when other
either the monsters are changes or whenever the search field changes.
And just so that we can see, let's also just add a console.log inside of this effect.
To make sure that we're not firing this effect whenever this Stringfield value is being updated.
Not a search field, but a string field.
So here I'm going to console.log.
Effect is firing.
I'm going to get rid of this, actually, no, let's keep the render.
Let's save this and now let's go back.
Let's clear this.
Let's refresh.
So we see our initial calls.
Of course, we see effect is firing twice because we initialize with the empty and then we initialize
with the empty string.
Remember, there's two fields now.
And what we're going to do is let's just validate that everything works with the normal search field.
So if I say, hey, we see that our code is working, we fire for each character like a three effect
test firing, which is exactly what we want and then three more when we clear out the field.
Now, when I type into this Stringfield value, we notice that again, this side effect is now not firing
anymore, which is perfect.
It's exactly what we want.
This Stringfield value is being updated.
So this set Stringfield is getting cold, but our side effect here doesn't need to run because monsters
and search field are two values that have not changed.
And now we know we're not needlessly running additional filters in our cycles whenever that happens.
So that's exactly what we want to do, and this is how you want to do the majority of writing your effects.
Now let's get rid of all this code that we don't need anymore because it was really just needed to prove
this example.
And let's get rid of these council logs.
And here we've pretty much converted the main class component inside of our application over into one
that uses a functional component and hooks, the hardest and most complicated thing is really going
to be understanding use effects and composing your code into these effects.
But don't worry, we're going to get a lot of practice with that throughout this course.
And the next video, we're going to convert the remaining components over into functional components.
So I'll see you in the next video.