Welcome back, everyone.
In this video, we are going to convert our cardless component card component and search box component
over from a class component to a functional component.
So to start, let's get rid of our class import because we won't need it anymore.
And what we're going to do is we're going to say Konst card list is equal to a functional component
and then what we'll do is get rid of this render statement so that we can have it like this so that
we are now returning the actual GSX.
We also need to get rid of this stop props.
So how is it inside of our parameters that we get our props?
Well, react.
Functional components actually only get two arguments.
You get the prop and you get something called the Forward ID.
Ref.
The Florida ref is something that you are honestly only going to use maybe two, three, four percent
of the time max.
It's something that we'll explore later because it's honestly a little bit more complicated, given
that we haven't really seen it in context.
Most of the time he was using use props, and those props is the exact same as this props.
It's an object that has all of the different parameters and properties essentially that are being passed
into this component.
It's just that instead of this is not props, it's going to be the first parameter that gets passed
into this functional component.
Similarly, because we know that this will always be the first parameter, we actually don't need to
do the restructuring structuring here.
We can do the structuring right inside of the parameter itself, like so and now instead of doing this
return because we have nothing else to return, we can switch this to a implicit return.
And there we have our card list component.
So let's go back to our application, and we see that everything still works as we expected to.
So let's do this now.
Same thing for our card and our search box.
If you want, you can do this yourself.
Just take some time and convert these.
Pause the video and then once you're done, come back.
OK, so if you've done this, you can skip the section.
If not, let's just do this together.
So what we're going to do is, again, say Konst Card is equal to this functional component.
We don't need this component.
Class anymore, we get rid of the render.
And then let's just fix our indents.
And now we know we're getting this stop, props that monster.
So I'm going to structure off the monster and instead of doing this further destruction like so I'm
going to do structure like this.
And here we see code still works.
And let's do our final one, which is our search box.
So I'm going to get rid of the render.
Cornstarch box equals a functional component.
And similarly, here, let's get rid of this component.
Get rid of the return.
Since we're probably just going to do a implicit return right here.
And now, as far as what we need off of our props, we need class name.
We need placeholder and we need on change handler.
And then let's just get rid of this, not props.
Let's save this.
Let's go back to our application.
Make sure that our search box still has all of those fields.
We have the class name, which is massive search box 10:18.
We have our placeholder and are on chain handler works.
So that's the most complicated thing that difference between a class and a functional component is really
just doing the deal, structuring off of the actual argument itself rather than doing it off of this
props inside of the component.
But you'll notice in the card we did it like, so we can theoretically also go one step deeper, which
is an even further version of restructuring like so if you want to do this instead of doing the deal,
structuring within the code.
You'll notice that if we do this, our code still works.
But personally, I think this is a little bit harder to read.
I would personally just prefer to say, OK, we've restructured off this specific parameter and then
further, the structuring happens within the functional component.
But this is really a preference.
But there you have it.
We've converted all of our class components over to functional components.
And if you're a little confused about functional components, don't worry, we'll get a lot of practice
using functional components and hooks throughout this course and definitely throughout the capstone
project.
But for now, I just really want you to think about the core lessons we had on functional components
rendering and rendering, as well as class components and rendering and rendering with lifecycle methods.
This is going to be probably some of the most challenging parts of understanding react.
But other than that, react is generally pretty simple.
Once you have those concepts down in the next few videos, we're going to dive even deeper into how
React actually works under the hood in order to help us determine what it's going to render and render
and why it does it the way it does.
So join me in the next video and we'll get a really good understanding of how react and react Dom works
under the hood.