Welcome back, everyone.
So in the last few videos, I keep talking about rendering and re rendering with react and how react
does it and why React is doing it the way it's doing it, but we haven't really talked about what it
is about re rendering with react that makes react such a good solution.
So let's dive deep into this in this lesson.
So inside of our application, if I open up our inspect.
And instead, what we want to do is look at our elements.
What I want you to see is that inside of here we have our HDMI layout.
What this represents is actually a tree of elements or a dom tree.
So the Dom Tree is essentially our document object model and primarily what it encapsulates is all of
the different elements that compose our application or website.
It's represented as a tree because inside of these different elements right now, as you can see, we're
sitting inside of our component app.
This app is reflected as a div.
What the class app and inside are three children.
There is the H1 class, there is our search box input, and then there is our card list.
These three elements are actually siblings to each other because they are live at the same level inside
of cardless, though this is actually.
Apparent to all of the inside different containers and then inside these card containers, of course,
are images which are therefore then children of the card.
All of these are represented more as a tree.
You can see it as if siblings are branches on the same level.
And then children of these different components are further branches down.
So let's take a look at a visual representation of this, and what I want you to do is really think
about what we've talked about.
There's a top level app inside being H one search box and then the card list and then in the card list
are the different cards because this is what we're going to reflect as a tree.
So here I've drawn out a diagram that reflects this Dom tree that we've been talking about.
Right here at the top, you can see that this is representing the app component, which is that big
div with the class name app inside of it, there are three children which are three different siblings
of each other.
We have the H1, we have the search box and we have the card list component inside of the card list.
We have the children, which are the cards.
I know we have about 10 different cards from our JSON placeholder, which represents the 10 different
users that we have.
But here I'm just going to show the five to make it easier for us to visualize.
But this pretty much reflects a real dom.
This is a true representation of our entire application right now.
The thing about the real Dom is that it's actually really expensive in order to make changes.
What I mean by make changes is something known as reflow.
And what that is is essentially, if you were to remove nodes or pieces of the DOM or if you were to
update pieces of the DOM, it's very computationally expensive in order to make those changes.
It's actually really quick in order to figure out if things need to be changed.
But the actual changing process, the process of pulling things off the dom or putting things on the
dom or changing things on the Dom.
That's pretty expensive.
So we don't want to needlessly do that if we don't have to.
What react does is that in this case, React makes a duplicate copy of the real Dom, but it does it
in JavaScript.
So this is a dom tree.
But instead of using the real dom elements, it reflects all of these elements in JavaScript.
JavaScript is significantly quicker to actually create and reflect these changes.
So that process where I was saying call reflow, that's like really easy to do on JavaScript.
The only thing is that we need a real dom to actually display to the user.
So of course, we can't use a JavaScript tree in order to do that, but we can use this tree to determine
what's changed.
And this tree is called the virtual dom.
So you hear a lot about a virtual dom.
That's what it is.
It's a JavaScript representation of the real dom tree whenever we were to make some changes.
So let's say, for example, a user started typing into our search box, Ellia, as we know what happens
is that we will start filtering through our monsters in our application in order to pass those filtered
monsters to our cardless component.
So what does that look like using these virtual dom and real dom trees?
So let's talk about how to react under the hood is going to trigger through this process that we've
done numerous times already in order to actually make the changes we want to see in the real DOM.
So first, what's going to happen is it's actually going to make another copy of the virtual DOM.
And the reason why it does this is because it's going to use that first copy of the virtual Dom as a
snapshot.
So this is the latest snapshot of what the real Dom looks like before it needs to start actually making
these changes.
What react is going to do is use this newest virtual dom copy as the actual dom tree that it's going
to make these changes against.
So remember, what's happening is we're typing into our search box, Leah.
So as we remember, this search box is triggering an event for each character being typed in the URL
and then the E and then the A.
These changes are in turn going to call set state inside of our app, which is represented as that blue
note up at the very top.
If you remember, I said that that top note is our app component inside of Here Reacts sees Oh, I'm
getting set state called three different times.
What's happening is that React is actually going to bash these calls together.
If they're slow enough or if they're fast enough, it really differs.
React has a bunch of different optimizations that it does under the hood by bashing some of these calls
together in order to make this process more efficient.
Because even though it's in JavaScript, it still wants to be as optimal as possible and reduce the
total number of changes it has to do.
So what's happening here, either way, is that the earlier string is getting called into our sets date.
So this is what's happening.
React is saying, Oh, I want to set the state of this note and remember whenever a state is being updated,
it is re rendering.
So what this does is it's going to re render the app and react is smart enough to say, Oh, I'm going
to re render all of the HTML and the GSX that are the children of this component.
But it's also going to be smart enough to know that the only components that need to be updated is the
card list because the H one is not changing and the search box is not changing.
So the cardless needs to update because y what we're doing with that string is we're modifying that
monsters array, we're filtering it, which in turn means that we're passing new props into the card
list.
And remember, whenever new props get past, react is also going to re render that component.
So Cardless says, Oh, I've got new props, I need to re render.
So what it's going to do is it's going to look inside of its HD html and it's going to render new cards.
Maybe in these new cards, there are lesser cards, which we know with our users.
That's exactly what's happening because we're filtering out all cards of monsters that don't have Leia
in the name.
So React sees, Oh, there are these three cards that no longer are necessary because they are no longer
matching the filter monsters that I'm receiving.
So React is going to say, OK, these needs to be removed.
I'm going to literally remove them from my virtual dom tree, so I'm grayed them out, meaning that
they've been unmount it.
Remember, I'm mounting as that phase where you're pulling things off of the Dom.
That's literally what's happening.
So they're getting removed from the page or this virtual dom representation of the page.
Now what react does the CS?
OK, have I updated everything from these changes?
Yes, I have.
This is the new virtual dom.
So this reflects what the Dom should be.
After all, these changes have happened.
What it's then going to do is it's going to compare this virtual dom copy against the virtual Dom snapshot,
and it's going to highlight where things are different once it figures out where those differences are.
It's going to actually make those changes onto the real dom because that virtual dom snapshot is a copy
of the real Dom.
And because what it needs to do in the end, in order for the user actually see these final changes
is apply those changes to the real DOM.
Now it knows what it has to do.
It's already gone through the most complicated process of doing the thing and doing the patching so
that this final process, React thinks, is the optimal and fastest final solution of what the current
page should look like.
So the real Dom is then going to go through the reflow and it's going to remove those components or
those different elements on the Dom tree and now are real.
Dom is going to take the form of what it finally should be.
And this is how we finally see those changes reflected on the page.
So it's a pretty lengthy process, but that's really all the virtual Dom is doing.
It's just an optimal way for react to figure out what the real Dom needs to look like.
And the reason it does this is because pulling off and changing these different nodes on a real dom
is expensive.
It's easier to do it in JavaScript and save when React is absolutely sure that what is finally supposed
to be reflected onto the real Dom.
It will then actually make those changes.
That's the whole process of using the virtual DOM and react in order to optimize the.
Process of figuring out what your dorm should look like.