Welcome back, everyone.
In the last video, we learned about how react and rapped on work as base libraries.
In this video, we're going to push it a little further before we move on to actually building our application.
Back in the world of beautiful jazz sex.
But here, I just really want you to become familiar with React as a library of works so that you understand
what jazz sex is doing compared to what you would have to do if you didn't have jazz sex.
So as we saw we were initialized, are at component, and I typically want to actually make components
that are a little bit more interesting.
So let's keep this H1, let's say underneath.
We wanted to create a few elements that were a little bit more complicated.
So what I'm actually going to do is I'm going to create a new component and I'm going to call it person.
This person component is a functional component.
So here React is smart enough to say, Oh, you're still personally functional components.
It's going to behave the exact same.
Remember, create element really just replaces GSX.
Everything else about our components is still the same.
So what I'm going to do is I'm still going to write a functional component that gets props as an object,
and instead, I'm just going to return back what I want for this person.
And let's say that we know for sure we need a parent level container, so I'm going to use a div.
It's going to say React, create elements and it's going to be active and I'm not going to pass it any
attributes in this particular case.
And inside, I want it to have children and these children that I want.
I'm going to say React, create element.
Again, the first child should be an H1, and the value inside should be props daughter name.
So again, no attributes, but the children and side is just the text note, which is the string strings
automatically get converted to text notes, which is really what you see when you look at strings that
are wrapped in like a paragraph or inside of a span.
Whenever you see those, those are text notes.
So I'm saying props on them because I know it'll be a string.
And then underneath that, let's just say that for this person, it's both a name that we're going to
pass, but also another string, let's say, occupation.
It's going to say, React, OK, create element here.
And this one, I want to be in a paragraph text again.
No more attributes I'm seeing as a prop star occupation.
And with this, we have our person component.
So what I want to do now is I want to, let's say, create more.
So I'm going to do react to create elements and here I'm going to pass it the person.
Again, remember, the attributes are the props, that's how you pass props into this component.
So here we know that we want to give it a name.
So the first one, let's say it's Iowa.
As for the occupation?
I am an instructor and then inside, I want to pass no children, so you can pass a all or you don't
have to pass anything, but I'm going to pass and so we're really explicit about it.
Next, let's make two more.
So here I'm also going to do Andre, and he is a lead instructor.
And he's also going to have no children.
And then finally, let's just say there's Emily.
And her occupation is a teacher.
And now, if we save our application and we go back.
And we refresh.
We see that we have our three instructors or three people.
And here we really saw a little bit more of a verbose example of how we've created two different components
both our app component and our person component and how we can leverage react to actually put these
elements on the page.
With this, you pretty much just seen what it is that GSX does.
GSX just simplifies this entire process, but we're still writing functional components.
Everything else about these components is the exact same.
It's really just the fact that what GSX it looks a lot more like readable HTML as far as dictating what
UI we want to render reading, react, create element.
This is a lot more difficult on our eyes as developers in order to actually write this code, but it's
really simple.
It's pretty much just what kind of component are you trying to make?
What are the attributes prompt you want to give me?
And then what are the children inside?
That's it.
That's really all it's doing under the hood.
In fact, in order to make this easier, what we can do is we can actually copy all of this code.
And what we can do is create another file court, AP us and inside our app tags.
We can just paste this code that we have.
And then what we can do.
Is we can just leverage this code inside of our script tag, so here I'm going to save it all.
Get rid of this and then this script source is just going to point to the code inside of our relative
folder.
So I'm going to go dot slash OPG's.
And now if I save and I look back and I refresh.
My code still works.
This is really just a very bare bones.
None of the benefits that we get from utilizing web pack that helps build our code.
We just wrote all of our code and right now in writes HTML and raw JavaScript.
But really, with all these tooling that create racked up gives us and with GSX and all of these bells
and whistles, it just makes it.
So it's a lot more of a pleasant developer experience.
In order for us to write our real code.
But I really just want to peel back away, what is GSX, what is really doing?
What is Dom doing so that you have a better understanding of how these libraries function so that when
you're actually writing code, you have a solid foundation to stand on.
But now that we understand what react and react Dom do for us as libraries, it's much easier now moving
forward for us to just leverage assets to write our code.
So hopefully you understand what we just went through with react and react on.
So let's move on with building our application.