All right, so for this first challenge, I'm going to show you how to debug this issue now, as you
can see here, we're typing in some text.
We get this invalid password message and we type some we backspace and it goes away.
So what can we do to figure out how to get the right password?
Well, first thing we're going to do is we're going to want to find the code that's causing this issue.
Right.
So we want to find that code and we want to read that code so that we can understand what's going on
in the browser and then after knowing that we can debug the issue.
So the first thing we want to do is we're going to open up this chrome dev tools here.
So this is going to be so useful throughout all of these challenges because we can read the code through
this.
We could put breakpoints and inspect certain data and all this is going to be super useful.
So as you could see here, first we go into the console and we see not much.
Right.
We refresh the page again and we don't see much here in the console.
So there's not going to be any errors here that are going to help us to find what's going on.
But what we can do is we can go here and we could just try and find the files that are causing this
issue.
Right.
Or that are preventing us from entering in to the app and see what's going on there.
And now there's a lot of ways to do this.
So I'm going to show you a couple different ways to do this.
First, if you go to the more tools section here, if we go up here and we go here to the bottom.
Now, if I do this, this is probably what you're seeing.
So you see we have this console here right now.
If you do control shift F, you can also go in here and find the search option.
So now what this is doing is it allows us to search the files for certain text or elements or anything,
write certain code that is going to appear in our app.
So we have here some text that says, what's the password?
So I'm going to use that.
That's going to be my clue.
So I'm going to search the code base for that text.
So I say, what's the password question mark?
And I hit enter.
Now, this is going to bring up just like that, the files that have that code.
So as you can see here, we have an app that James and we have an app that Jass with a source map.
So if I click on the first one, this is going to be the minified code.
So this isn't going to be super helpful to debug because it's minified code.
But if we go here, we see that source map, we click on that and then now we could see we have the
React JSA source map here to that code.
And as you could see here we have what's the password right there?
Now, if I go back, because you could see if I click on it, it it highlights that line for me.
So that's really useful because it just drills down exactly into where that element is.
Now, obviously, if you have some more vague text, like if I type in submit, maybe that'll show up
in a bunch of other files.
And this might not be exactly how to get that file or that element.
So there's other things you can do, for example, in the react dev tools.
If I go here to my reactive tools, which will show, we'll talk about more in detail.
You could see here that we have an app element, we have an app component.
So we click on that.
And then what you could do, which is really cool, is you can actually see the source of that file.
So you could see the source where that file's coming from or where that code is coming from, that component
is rendered.
And then if you go here to this view source for this element, you click on that and you could see just
like that the exact component that's being rendered.
So this is our app right here.
So it allows you to see the elements, the react components on the page, and then it allows you to
drill down into exactly where that component was being rendered here.
So this is really cool.
So that was how we were able to find where that issue is happening in our app.
Now, let's actually go in and find why this issue is happening.
So as you can see here, the issue happens really when we click submit.
Right.
So what I like to do is find the event handlers for that.
So as you can see here, we have a submit button.
It's pretty obvious, right, to submit.
And then we have an on click here and that's a submit.
So we say, well, what's simit, we could double click on that and it'll show us the function right
here.
So we double click on that text and it's going to highlight that up for us right here.
You can also search for submit if we want to.
We could search for submit and enter a few times and then that'll show us where that is defined.
Now, if we click or we go up here, we could see this is where the submit function is defined.
So now what we're going to do is we're going to actually start to debug more into this function.
So we have this kind of function here that's going to this is going to be our focal point.
Right.
So as you can see here, we have that invalid password message.
So we were reading this.
We see it looks like there's some kind of comparison for the password and then we have a error that's
being set.
And then we have a wind condition after that, so we've read the submit function, we're understanding
what's going on, but that doesn't really help us to figure out how to get past it.
Right, because we have this secret password right here.
So in order to figure this out, what we can do is we can.
So now we have this here.
Once you read this line, you should be able to if you've gotten this far, hopefully you were able
to figure out what to do from here.
If you haven't, there's a couple of ways we could do that.
So, you know, you could read this, you could see, OK, this data is coming from data data just so
we can find that file or what we could do is even quicker.
We could just put a breakpoint here and then we can hit our submit button.
And then just like that, we can hover over data and see what the secret password is, a secret password,
says Coconut's.
So that is the secret password.
So we've debug this issue.
Now, if we go here to password, you could see that we have no text in there.
So this is a currently typed in string.
And so there we go.
So we we've read the expression here.
We say if the password is not equal to the secret password, do this so it returns out of this function.
Or else it will set the wind condition so based on this, I've been able to debug this issue, I can
continue here to continue along on the code.
Now I know what the password is.
If I go and I type that password in and then I had simit.
I win, so just like that, we were able to debug an issue, the future challenges will be doing more
in terms of actually fixing code and writing code.
But this is a fun challenge just to get you to start using the chrome dev tools and inspecting code.
Now, what we're going to talk about more is our strategy guide here.
So our strategy guide is going to help us to debug issues like this in the future.
And as you could see, I did use this strategy guide quite frequently throughout this specific solution
as well.
So you could see I made sure I confirmed that issue.
I gathered some clues about where that code was.
So I found where the code was.
And then I isolated what files and code are causing that issue, using the reactive tools as well as
the search in the Chrome Dev Tools console.
I did not see any error thrown, but I did inspect some DOM elements and I searched for some files.
So we found that where it was happening and then we determined why it was happening by setting breakpoints
and examining state.
So like I said, we're going to be using this throughout the course and I hope that was helpful for
our first challenge.
So that's going to be it for this first challenge.
Thanks.