I'd like to now share the purpose of this course or the purpose of why you should learn debugging within
the react world and the tagline here, it's about the journey, not destination.
This kind of sounds pretty cheesy, but actually this is really appropriate for debugging because a
lot of people were taking my courses.
And if you've taken them, you know that it's sort of this big application that you kind of build up
to.
And a lot of people would be posting these kind of basic bugs out of nowhere.
And that is just something that I feel like beginners really get stuck on, which is they get blocked
at these at these Jurnee, are these stepping stones.
And when you're in the professional environment, you can't go to your supervisor and say that you're
stuck on this bug, especially if they're an engineer, because they're going to expect you to know
how to do that already.
So it's almost like debugging is kind of like a set of hiking boots or a set of tools that you can use
to climb that mountain easier.
And this is why this course is really about the journey.
It's not about client, you know, getting to the top of the mountain and looking at this big application
that you built when a lot of the times it was just you kind of copying maybe a coding tutorial or something.
I feel like those tutorials can be a little lacking in basic skills or equipment or tools that you need.
Right.
And so this is really about the journey.
It's about getting equipped and getting stronger and debugging so that when you hit those bugs and you're
when you're building the next big project, you're not stuck and you can easily power through those.
So really, it's about changing your mindset on debugging.
I want you to actually start to expect and love bugs in the apps that you're going to be building.
Not only should you expect the bugs, right, you want to love them and be excited about them.
And I'm going to the last lecture of this is really going to go into that more.
But basically, you need to start expecting bugs because, you know, I think a lot of beginners will
see the bug that they hit and they'll think that they did something wrong or they're like, what's going
on?
And that makes sense, right?
They're totally new and they don't really understand the error that's being thrown at them.
But you have to start getting used to that, get comfortable to that error and move on, move forward
with that error by troubleshooting and debugging it.
Right.
And you have to understand that they occur.
Bugs occur for everyone and all the time without any exception.
So any programmer, they're going to be hitting bugs.
The difference is, though, is that the professionals are going to know immediately what's what's going
wrong with an error most of the time.
Right.
Unless it's a library specific error.
And then they'll kind of even know what to do about that.
They'll know how to research that library.
And we'll talk more about that in this course.
It's more of a strategy guide.
I'm going to walk you through different ways of troubleshooting, different types of errors.
But the point is that the pros are going to expect this already, that they're going to have bugs and
they're going to know how to fix them very quickly, because when you're a professional building an
app on your own, you you don't have time to spend a day or two or hours or waiting for an instructor
or somebody to get back to you about a bug that wouldn't be very productive.
Right.
The Web development world set up to where the bugs are there to be or the error messages are there to
help you.
And that's why the next bullet is there.
And I'm so happy to really explain this, this bullet for you, which is why error messages are actually
good.
Error messages are a good thing because they explain where the bug is coming from.
May or may not be obvious, but they explain where it's coming from via the stack trace.
And then they also tell you are human readable explanation.
Right.
A lot of people may not realize that a human wrote that bug description, a human wrote the error that
you're reading a lot of the times or most of the time.
Right.
You know, it's very rare that you'll get an error.
That's just a bunch of, you know, gibberish and you can't read it right.
You know, an unknown error occurred.
That would be that's like every developer's nightmare.
That's like what how do we do, you know, how do you move forward from that?
And that's why errors are written by developers in a way that make it easy to debug.
And I'm going to show you about show you how to read errors in this course to to help you move forward
with that.
So that's why you should look forward to errors, because if you see an error, that's going to be a
great clue that you can move forward with fixing it.
And so the next bullet.
So that's why you should love error messages.
Next, I want to just talk about why debugging is actually more than just fixing bugs.
So not only is debugging good for fixing bugs, but also they helps you understand your app.
And it's almost like popping the hood of your car and looking at the engine.
The chrome dev tools is open, should be open all the time when you're building an app because you can
quickly put a breakpoint and inspect how things are working.
Right.
You can just check things and you could.
Research things to just validate that your code is working, and I think that you may be unfamiliar
with chrome dev tools if you're a beginner, and that's this is really what this course is all about,
using the chrome dev tools to inspect your app in addition to fixing it.
So once you get good at chrome dev tools, you'll be able to easily understand your app.
And that's what I really hope that you can get out of this course.
So, yeah, with this course, you succeed by debugging, not building, so other courses, you know,
students build, they race to build this big app and this course doesn't have a giant application.
And that should be a relief to you, because a lot of times you're you're typing out what I'm saying.
And it's not really a great engaging thing for you this course.
It's really focusing you on.
This, of course, is really just about explaining how apps work.
And the goal is to build an understanding of how to research and fix broken applications.
So goal of the app isn't to build an awesome.
The goal of the course isn't to build an awesome app.
It's to just gain an understanding of how apps work and how to fix them.
OK, and so next, seriously, actually try and debug the challenges in this course, there are 25 opportunities
for you to fix bugs.
Some of them might be really easy for you that you're going to roll your eyes and say, this is so easy.
Why is this here?
And others, you know, you might want to just give up entirely, but either way, just watch the solution
videos.
To understand my perspective, I try to show you honestly how I would fix them if I knew nothing about
bugs, even nothing about react, you know, from a complete beginners perspective.
And I truly think that these types of research investigations and chrome debug debugging tools can be
used for any app that you use.
Right.
Any type of front end project you could use these skills in.
And just understanding my perspective, I hope that you learn something new that you didn't learn before.
And so that's why I say, you know, don't just get to the end and just look at the solution of the
challenge.
That's really not the point.
The point is to like it's to understand the process of getting to there and to see what I do, what
I try, what I what kind of searches that I Google for.
And and then the next one, you know, pretend your job is on the line.
Like if in like I said in the before, if if you're if you're on the job and you don't fix the bugs,
you know, your customers are going to suffer from a bad experience.
Your coworkers are going to be asking you for help.
And this is really encourage you to just put yourself in that situation and just say, you know, how
can I learn or how can I fix this bug if, you know, my job is on the line.
Right.
And that's really why that first section's there, to just help you absorb all of those strategies before
you go into the second section of the challenges.
So the first section just really trying to absorb as much of that as you can.
I promise that everything that I use to debug apps in the real world is there.
There's no tool that I did not discuss in the first section that you wouldn't that that's missing that
would help you debug faster.
And.
Yeah.
So the next one.
So the prompts that you're going to read on these challenges, they're intentionally vague, so the
the problems that you're going to read or something like the dropdown doesn't work, please fix.
So in the real world, you'll be contacted by a non-technical user telling you about your broken app
and they will rarely tell you about a JavaScript error or even how to reproduce.
They will just say something like, it's broken.
And so I kind of wanted that experience for you so you could read that error, that you could read that
form of contact and you could internalize that and work through that yourself to try and understand
how to.
What are they even mean, you know, translating that in English and then, you know, putting that
into a diagnosis.
That's the root cause.
So that's that's why, you know, it's part of the career, really, to understand when people say things
are broken, that you have to do a lot of work there.
And like I said, they're not going to tell you about a JavaScript error or any of that stuff.
So I'm not going to tell you about any of that either for the prompts.
I'm not going to give you any hints about what's going on.
That's entirely up to you to debug.
And with the videos and the solutions, you should be able to learn how to do that.
OK, so why is this important, you know, everything that was created in this course is material I
would consider like vitally important to your career as a reactor developer, because if you if you
know this stuff, if you don't know this stuff, you're going to be you're definitely going to be blocked.
And I want to make that really clear.
You will get stuck if you don't know how to debug.
And that's why a lot of the questions that I get are people just kind of they stop their app process
or some of them don't.
Some of them keep going.
But, you know, maybe some of them here and there will just say, like, hey, this is an error that
I got.
Please help me.
You know, my reaction to that is, well, you know, I don't want to just solve the bug for you.
I want to show you how to debug better.
And so that's why I created this course.
Really, it's because I want to just create a course that helps people debug and fix apps.
I don't want to just fix bugs for people because you don't learn anything if I tell you what's wrong.
Right.
And yeah.
So, you know, I and you might quit entirely.
And that's what I really don't want to happen, because when I was first starting out, I almost quit
because I couldn't really get a lot of help.
But I was in an environment that I constantly had people that I could ask for help.
And it was allowed me to work with people to show me and to get me through the different types of issues
that I would run into.
OK, so the next one is the reality of opensource, and I want you to just know, like when you when
you look at react and when you read forums and everything, you see people talking about react and all
these different things like these are these just happy tools that just work all the time.
And that's really it just could not be further from the truth, like with the exception of like react
and material UI, like a lot of the other libraries out there are just going to be broken sometimes
and or they won't have any documentation, you know, meta material UI and react or the exceptions.
They have great documentation and great, you know, examples even react.
I would say, you know, they could even have better documentation.
Right.
So even like the big libraries, like react, they may not be able to give you the clues or whatever
that you need to, you know, the examples that you want to use in your app.
And so the industry is moving too quickly to have an easy path for beginners.
Right.
Like, if you look at the bridge picture on the right, you can kind of see this is like there's these
awesome tools out there.
There's awesome libraries.
But at some point it just kind of falls off.
And at that point you'll get stuck.
And and I want to help you to just build on these tools yourself by learning how they work and learning
where you can really go inside of the tools themselves.
So go inside of those libraries and learn how they work.
Like I said, documentation generally isn't good for a lot of these libraries that you're going to find.
And so that's really where you need to be that resourceful of where you're going and you're reading
that code.
So never assume things will just work.
Right.
You know, it's good to it's good to assume that things will work.
But when you when you do that, you might get frustrated.
So you want to assume that if you run into a bug, you want to be prepared for that by being able to
debug and having those issues that those issues set up, you know, the GitHub issues set up.
In other words, you're looking through those GitHub issues right away.
You know, one of the things that I do when I'm looking at libraries is even, you know, if there's
a library that doesn't have any GitHub stars or something, even though that might seem like a superficial,
like metric of how many people are using that library, that's a really important thing, because if
there's no one who's use this library for three years or five years, that's a good sign.
It might not work for your react app.
So in general, I like to stick to really popular projects that are complete in terms of like developers
have used them a lot and there's a lot of history there where developers have run into all the bugs
already because if you're using a library that no one else uses and you run into a bug with it, that's
going to be a lot harder to fix than a common library like react, because we've run into bugs with
react all the time.
And that's that's still hard for beginners to or anyone professionals to even fix.
Right when you run into a bug in a library like that.
So imagine how hard that would be to to troubleshoot that in another library that only a couple of people
are using.
So be careful what libraries you pick up.
And if you pick up a you know, if you use a library like reactor material, you are going to be in
a lot better shape.
But just know that use the use the communities that are available to look up what's going on in those
communities and and debug the source code when you have two or frequently.
Okay, so the last one, this is kind of a positive thing that we're leaving on here.
You will be a hero.
There's no question that when you get on the job and somebody sends you a broken app, it's something
that people are frustrated with.
And nobody wants to figure the, you know, the bugs out like non-technical people.
Forget it.
They can't fix the bugs.
Even engineers on your team, they're going to they're not going to be the first person usually to jump
onto a bug.
They're working on their own projects.
And so when I say love bugs, like I mean, like you should love them in the sense that you can take
that on and figure that out yourself, you'll be a hero.
You'll be praised.
People will will love it.
They'll be so happy that you fixed that issue for them.
And that's one great way to to succeed on the job and keep your job charging headfirst into a bug,
you know, shows bravery.
So even if you can't figure out a bug, it's great to just drop that information for your other developers
on your team, like, hey, I took steps X, Y and Z and I learned this, but I didn't go this further,
so I didn't get this far right.
I got stuck at this point.
So even just doing that for other developers is really helpful to other developers can help you to continue
troubleshooting.
It's almost like you're a detective and you or your Indiana Jones.
Right.
Like, imagine if Indiana Jones was like, you know, I can't get to the temple.
How do you get to the temple?
Right.
No, he's going to go all the way up to the temple and he's going to get all the way up there and figure
it out himself.
Right.
So, you know, you're not you're not Indiana Jones yet, but you're going to you're going to be the
the person who's going to try.
Right, like at least go as far as you can and when you when you finally do get stuck and you've exhausted
all of your options, that's when you can really contact other developers or file a GitHub issue or
ask a question on stack overflow or read it and who knows?
You know, maybe you might be the person that ask that question and figure out a bug in reactor, another
library.
So do as much as you can on your own.
And, you know, you'll you'll go along.
You'll go really far.
So that's it.
Good luck.
And that's all I wanted to say about this.
Thanks.