All right, hello.
And this one, we're going to talk about the mobile debugging right here so you could toggle the device
on right here.
So when you click on this, you'll see that your sight kind of turns into this phone shaped, basically.
So if you go back to my site here, you could see that I am.
Basically showing the iPhone, so if you go up to the top here, you'll see the device that you're running.
So you could see you could choose from a couple of different types of phones or tablets.
So here I could choose an iPad if I want to, and it'll render it like an iPad, which is cool.
And then I could click around like I'm in like I'm on an iPad.
And here you'll see the zoom here.
So the zoom is 50 percent.
I could change that to 100 percent.
So this would be more life size.
And then I can also zoom in more if I want to make it zoomed in more.
But you'll see up here, this is very useful, the pixel count.
So if you're doing media queries, so you actually want to target specific access, you could actually
set that up here.
So where you can you just know exactly what size devices these are.
So if I do an iPhone ten, I know that this is going to be a maximum width of 375 pixels.
So that's really useful.
And here you could throttle mobile speed also if you want to see how slow or fast your website is.
So I did low end mobile, so my site's going to load really slow.
So there you go and then I do online, so here, if I do responsive, this is another more free form
way to check responsiveness.
So here as I change this now, you could.
Now, if you do in a normal browser window, what you're going to get, you get stuck right here at
about 500 pixels, I think.
So usually it tells you if I undo this.
So see up here this top.
Right, you're going to see that here where it's going to tell you exactly how wide your browser is
and that's going to go away.
So I believe this is about 500 pixels.
It see, it locks you at 500 pixels.
It can't go further than that.
So if you want to actually debug your iPhone, believe it or not, you can only do that by going in
here and clicking this phone and then you can go in a responsive and then you can see how your device
looks on a phone that's as wide as you want.
So I recommend keeping this on iPhone and then just doing iPad as well.
Just getting a couple good breakpoints in.
And that's how I would debug a mobile responsive website.
So that's all I do with this device toolbar here.
I just toggle it on and then I check my breakpoints and I check different things on your phone.
This is only going to do certain things.
It's not going to actually render native functionality like native iPhone controls or native iPhone
widgets or anything like that.
It's not going to emulate everything on an iPhone.
It's just to see your width.
And that's pretty much it.
And there's probably other stuff that does, too.
But don't fully rely on this.
Always go and actually test on a real device.
So that's the best advice I can give you there.
So when you're done, you can just untangle it and then you're in dev tools again and you're good.
So that's mobile, responsive testing.