All right, so four, challenge 10, you could see that we have this issue here that says cannot fetch
Cat, please see if you could fix.
So for we continue this, we're going to open this up in the code sandbox up here.
All right.
So inside of the code sandbox here, I'm just going to just review the code here.
So and as you could see here, we already have a syntax error on load of this.
So we've already reproduced the issue.
And as you can see, the the error is occurring in the console.
And you could see it's a syntax error.
So syntax error means there's sort of an issue with the code structure itself.
And we'll review that now.
So as you can see here, this is the error that's happening and it's happening on this line, which
is line 19 inside of this function.
And it says, can I use keyword a wait outside in async function?
So there's two approaches that you could take here if you're not familiar with this error.
First would be to just Google the error itself, and second would be to actually research the terminology
inside of that error.
So the first thing that we did, let's say we researched this, I found this GitHub issue when I searched
for this error, which says cannot use keyword a wait outside and async function.
And as you can see here, the there are just people talking about this issue.
And as you can see here, someone at the end of the day, it's usually the end of the issue, somebody
you're looking for a resolution or a summary of the issue.
And this person says it's not about this library.
So this is a library that this issue occurred in.
And it says, I recommend you take a look on ESX async, await spec and promises.
So as you could see here, this person is not familiar with this, you know, await async function terminology.
And so that's how you could research this.
And then if you research async functions, you'll get this doc from Mozilla, which would tell you all
about async functions, which is basically just shorthand for promise based behavior.
So instead of this functionality here for promises, you would or rather instead of resolving for promises
or, you know, passing in callbacks for promises, you would instead call use the await an async function
terminology.
So.
What this does is it pauses the code execution and waits for this promise to resolve.
And so in our code base, we are doing that here.
But as you can see here, we're not using the async function.
So it requires an instance of an async function.
So you need so the async, so you need the async keyword around the function.
So basically you need to define async with the function like this.
And as you can see here, there's this is the syntax, so does the actual spec for the syntax here.
And as you can see, we have the async.
Parameter before the function name, and then you have the name of an argument.
So these are just regular function.
So it's a regular function except that the return value must be resolved.
So a promise which will be resolved with the value returned by the async function or rejected with an
exception, thrown or uncaught within the async function.
Let's keep reading the description.
Async functions contain zero or more await expressions.
So and like I was saying before, a great expression suspend progress through an async function.
The resolved value of the promise is treated as a return value of the expression.
So basically, we have an asynchronous callback, the code is going to wait for that actual promise
to resolve and then it'll pass it in through here.
So that's the general idea of asynchronous functions.
The async await terminology.
Now that we know that we we could see plenty of examples here where we are using the async keyword in
front of the function.
And you could read all about this year regarding, you know, more details about what exactly is going
on.
So as you could see here, this is returning the.
The regular terminology of what you would do before async wait, so before async away, you would wait
for it to resolve and then you would essentially then do your callback here.
So instead of async went away, you would do this.
And now we we can shorthand that to just wait within that function.
So now that we know about async await functions, we can go ahead and type in the word async here in
front of the arrow function to fix the the issue.
So as you can see now, we are not getting that error anymore and we are getting a nice cat rendered
here, so.
As you could see, though, all is not well, we do have a problem.
So what is a problem?
This is a lente, so we actually are running Esslin in here and yes, it's sort of a helper that will
help you write better code, writes Lintz.
Your code points out problems that are in your code that won't necessarily cause issues, right?
So it's absol functioning.
This is not going to be a syntax error.
This is just going to be a limiting problem that's going to sort of like you have prettier.
It's like a file formatter.
Lintang is sort of pointing out things that sort of a preprocessing tool that you'd use to write better
code.
So Esslin is telling us about this, which is if we read this and we can also read it by hovering over
the error itself, affect callbacks are synchronous to prevent race conditions, put the async function
inside the use effect handler like this.
So if you got this far and you noticed this and you were able to fix this, that's extra bonus points.
So this is basically saying that you can't pass in a async function in here.
You're not supposed to do that.
React can tell you that you're not supposed to do that, but they can't force you to stop doing that.
So they can't you know, this is where reactance gets kind of hairy, where you actually need the react
hooks glinting in here to actually help you write better code and to not encounter bugs with reactance.
Other react hooks like, you know, other react lintang errors would be, you know, actually conditionally
calling you state Hoke's.
So like if you said, you know, if true and then you said const F set F equals use state.
This would also throw an excellent error here because this is called conditionally.
So you're not allowed to call you state conditionally.
So to learn more about this, you really should.
I'll point you to a resource shortly after this.
But you should know that you know the rules of Hucks, right?
It's just called Rules of road, rules of Hooke's.
So if we search for rules of Hooke's comes up right here, here, all the list of hooks and excellent
plug in that you should add to make sure that you're calling these hooks appropriately so they don't
even have that async issue right here.
But, you know, that's one of those things that you just are going to have to Google if you want to
read more about it.
So.
So what was the fix?
The fix was actually to just call that function here.
So instead of actually putting that as the use effect took, you're just going to call that function
inside of it.
So if we do this so we just pass in a regular function like this and then we use our async function
inside of this, but we call it something like async function, fetch cat, fetch cat async.
Then we do this and then we call it like this.
We are getting another syntax error, which is because we need to do this.
We're going to get rid of this code as well.
And then we make sure that we we refresh the page right here and we get that cat again and we have no
issues, so great.
If you are debugging this, you might try and debug or look more up information about this, the actual
call, we didn't really talk about this at all, but this is just this thing that I found that returns
a random cat and.
Yeah, so that's it.
So then what did we learn?
We learned all about rules of react hooks and we learned about async and await functions.
So cool.