All right, challenge 11, so this says names are set at the same time, please see if you can fix.
So I open up my code sandbox here and I start typing in one hand.
As you can see, I've confirmed that that is true.
I am typing and the text is appearing in both inputs at the same time.
So let's actually look into this.
As you can see, we have a simple app this time and you could see we have our inputs here.
So we found the code that's causing the issue.
If you look at the change handler, we see that we are referencing the same on change handler.
So that makes sense, right?
We have one state variable here and we are changing with the same handler calling the same set state
handler.
And we're changing the inputs.
The same inputs are being referenced here in the value prop for the input.
So if you're not familiar with inputs, you could look up inputs on Mozilla, you know, developer tools
or any of the other documentation for HTML.
And that would get you information on if you're not that familiar with inputs.
You could also look at our website over here.
We have some inputs, examples that you could look into.
And here we have just, you know, basic react inputs.
And that's where you would just kind of confirm, if you wanted to, the various inputs, perhaps,
but really just go to Mozilla, go to Mozilla input to learn more about inputs.
But we probably had a few challenges about this already.
But as you could see here, they're passing in a couple of different props.
They're passing a name in here.
And name is very useful because it's available on that element.
So if I go here and I search for name, maybe wondered what is actually name do.
And it's the name of the input form control.
It's submitted with the form as part of the name value pair.
So this is designed to be used inside of form HTML elements.
So when you actually submit a form behind the scenes HTML, you can automatically submit that input,
name and value.
So actually putting a name on the inputs, good practice in general, what does that have to do with
our change?
Well we can actually put some names on these inputs.
So if we say name equals first name and then we go down here and we say name equals last name.
You could see now if we save this, you might notice that we could actually go here and we could.
Now, this is going to just kind of give us access to this name inside of our synthetic event.
Right.
So if we go here and we just say console, log, dot, target, dot name.
See, we already have the value referenced here.
Now, let's see if the name actually works.
So if we go here to console, if we save this, we go here.
See, now we have first name.
I'm typing in the first name endpoint and then I click over here and now I'm typing in the last name
input.
So what did we just do?
We just figured out a fork to actually set different values of this or actually figure out which input
I'm in.
So we don't have to actually copy the same exact handler if we want to reuse this functionality.
Right.
So what we'll do is we'll save const input name equals Yeeda Target name.
Now we could say something like if input name equals first name.
And then we go down here and we say set first name or else set last name.
Right.
Eat target value, and then we could also just get input value, right, input.
Input value, he target, not value or even more advanced than that, you could just d structure this.
This is already so now this is Target and then also what else is there inside of Target?
There's name and value.
So you could structure it just like that.
I me the same thing.
And then now we don't even have to use these.
We could just say just like this name in value, we could just say name and value which is this so value.
Value.
And then now we're just going to duplicate react hooks, so another thing that I forgot to do is I can
actually Google this, which if you just Google, I Googled search over here, input's are set at the
same time, react like I just took the scenario that I was in and I Googled it just to show you that
if you're very lazy and you don't feel like figuring this out on your own, you could theoretically
actually find people who've already done this and look at their examples.
So once again, I this is pretty much exactly what we're doing.
Right.
I mean, it's almost like this example, you know, is the same thing that we're doing.
So as you can see here, what they're doing is.
They're setting the state to the name, they're setting the object, so usually you have an object as
a state.
So they're doing they're they're setting that dynamic key to be that that value.
So they're just blanket, you know, setting that key on the state and then setting it to be the value.
So.
Always good to be resourceful, if you're not sure.
But anyway, let's continue in our path.
This is just one solution, right, where we're just saying we're going to break this out into two different
react hooks, which is not even the most dry or do not repeat yourself.
Right?
It's not it's not the least repetitive solution to this.
But we're just showing you one option.
So to say first name.
Last name.
And then we have set last name.
OK, and now.
Name equals first name.
We're going to say set first name and then down here we are saying value is the first name and value
over here is the last name.
All right.
And that's it now we have figured this out, we are now typing in both inputs and they are behaving
independently.
We have split the shared functionality of that out into two separate state variables here.
And we use the same on change handler.
Except we added a fork cleaning solution would be to have done something with this person's doing,
but we will just move on since we've fixed the error for now.
So that's this challenge.