All right, in this one, we are going to talk about Dom breakpoints, so this is a concept that is
not really used that often in my experience anymore.
It used to be really useful when you were writing query code with React, React, kind of figures out
the DOM for you.
And so putting a breakpoint on the DOM isn't as important with react because you're going to want to
be debugging more state stuff rather than the actual DOM breakpoints itself.
The dominant population itself, I should say.
But I've included an example in this in this talk where we are going to actually modify the DOM ourself
and you'll see where that this could be useful.
So anyway, let's get let's get into it.
What exactly is a Dom breakpoint?
So Dom Breakpoint, if you're on the web, get inspector here.
You could say I'm hovering over different elements.
And when you want to, you can basically just right.
Click and you'll see that this will allow you to see some options.
So let me go ahead and I'm going to actually just expand the the app that I'm in here.
So if I go over here and I write click and I say inspect.
So that'll get me to exactly what element I want to break point on.
And so looking at my app, this is an app that I just set up here to do a couple of things.
So this is just going to swap a font size class out.
So this is an example of let's say something in your app is happening and you want to see, well, what's
exactly the cause of this class change.
So this is doing in the code.
It's changing out of class.
So let's just say that you you want to.
So basically you we first took that step of.
Right.
Clicking and inspecting that element.
So we found that element in the DOM.
That's step one.
Once you do that, you could do a whole bunch of things which will show.
So right here you could see this.
So I know that when I click this button, that class is changing.
So if we do this, you could see that you saw this flash, right.
So if you go over here and you do that again, so we saw this flash.
So that's our first clue that this element is changing.
And we saw the parts of that that are changing, which is this class section here.
Now, if we zoom on in, could see that we actually have this class here called Big.
And when we click that button, that big class goes away.
So we know that when we click the button, the class goes away and then when we click it again, it
comes back.
So that that's an assumption that we we just learned some information.
We learn that this component is being modified and now the next thing.
So we've determined that.
Right.
So one thing that you could do is we could.
Click on this.
And right click and we're just going to say.
Brake on.
So this brake on here, this is going to give you three options, subtree modifications, attribute
modifications and no removal.
Now, the classes are part of the attributes.
So that will that's going to be a brake point.
That will change when we click that button.
Subtree modification, that's when anything in the subtree changes.
So if component gets removed or added, that will get triggered then and then a node removals on this
element gets removed altogether.
I want to show all these examples.
So first, we're going to show what happens when we click this attribute attribute modification.
You see now we have that breakpoint set here and when we click this button.
You could see now that we have some JavaScript that's actually been paused, so this is the raw attribute
that's actually or this is the raw code that's actually going to be modifying that, Dom.
So you can see here and react.
Dom, at this point, this is not our code anymore.
This is really code.
If we go over here to the call stack, you could see it's going all the way down into React Dom development
code.
So basically REACT has delegated this all the way to the react Dom.
And we can't see any of our react code in here.
So this is unfortunately why this is really not that useful for react right now.
Maybe there's something in the to bugger that we can find that will trace it back to our react hook
function.
But in the meantime, this is why this is really not that useful for debugging that exact function.
So let's go back to our code, though, because.
All right.
So anyway, so you can see here, we could just continue to resume this execution and then we're going
to go back to our code again.
So go over here now.
I'm going to show you what our code does here.
So basically, this is it's running this function here, which is called swap class.
So it's setting the big class and it's we have a react hook up here.
And when this hook is set, we have this big class else we have no class.
So that's added onto that element.
Now, I want to show you another example here.
This is called Add Class Vanilla.
So this is going to be using vanilla JavaScript to add that class, which means we're going to be using
the document.
We're going to use this native JavaScript function called Get Elements by class name.
We're going to access the class list and we're going to add a new class.
Now, this actually took me some Googling to remember this because I was so used to using react.
I haven't manually added stuff to the DOM in a while.
So this is a good thing that you can research.
So basically you have.
So let's let's go back to our DOM point, though, so we have that DOM breakpoint set.
Now, what I'm going to show you this time is instead of clicking that first button, we're going to
click on that ad class, Menella, which is going to call this other function.
So when we go back to our breakpoint here so let's see here, we have that breakpoint still set.
So we're going to go and click that button.
We're going to click on that other button, which is right here.
So when I say ad class vanilla now, you could see here what's happening is that we actually have that
breakpoint coming right back to our JavaScript.
So this is our code and it's it's stopped right at exactly our code.
So this is it's cutting right to where we're modifying the DOM.
So this is an example.
You're using Jorquera, you're using regular vanilla JavaScript.
This is a great thing for you to know.
OK, this is exactly what modified my Dom.
I've traced my code back to wherever that bug is or wherever that feature is doing, and that's great.
So this is kind of an older feature, but I wanted to mention it because you're going to you may need
to use this for those situations.
Now, moving along, like I said, with react, not as not as useful.
So moving along, I want to talk about some of the other break points.
Now, that was attribute modifications.
Right.
That will also get triggered for any of the other DOM attributes that could be set here.
So to remove that, we're just going to click on this and we're just going to.
So I actually if you go to the source panel, you go down here to breakpoints.
You could see Dom breakpoints.
You could just right.
Click and say remove all break points.
Now we're going to go back to elements and want to do that again are actually this time we're going
to go to a different type of breakpoint because we just talked about attribute modification, breakpoints.
Now we're going to talk about the second thing, which is you could talk about subtree modifications.
So if we go to the app, we're just going to put a breakpoint here that says break on subtree modifications.
To show you that again, because that window doesn't show the pop up.
OK, so here we go again, break on subtree modifications.
So this is going to break.
So let's say if we were still pause on that other break point.
So we're going to go ahead.
You know, here you can by the way, you could debug the element.
You could debug anything you want in the section prior to that.
So that's pretty cool.
So we're going to continue on here with that.
I wanted to mention that that class that was added, it turns the text read, right?
So I added a new class that's in the styles here that turns the class read new class.
But if you go and change the font size, you add that big class that is going to get overridden because
react is react.
Doesn't know about that new class.
We added because we added it with vanilla JavaScript and so that new class is going to go away.
So you really don't want to do this.
Don't don't modify the DOM if you're using react because react is going to get very confused.
You run into all kinds of issues.
So never, never do this unless you're not using react or using something or some other framework.
So.
All right, so now what we were doing again was the the subtree modifications, so have another function
here called remove title.
It's going to remove that title.
But first, I want to show you that when I change the font size, when I change that attribute, the
underlying HTML is that that breakpoints not being triggered.
So you could see that when I change that, the class names being changed, but the actual breakpoint
is not being fired.
But when we remove the title of a button here that just removes the title, when when the react hook
is set, click the button, removes the title, remove the title, sets this react hook to be true.
Then we know that there's no title boolean and that does not render the title.
So when we do that, click that button.
Now we get our breakpoint once again.
Not very useful because we're in react Dom, so we can, you know, we know where we are and react Dom,
which is cool, but we are not hitting our code.
So again, just something to be aware of.
The next thing is same thing, attribute removal.
Let me go over here.
So this was subtree modifications on our base app.
So we broke we put a break point whenever some node got removed.
So that's why that node got hit.
So we removed that.
So I think you can just click on this break on C, I don't think that you can actually remove the breakpoint
from this menu, which is not ideal.
So we're clicking on that.
Nothing's happening.
Go back to our source panel or remove the breakpoint here.
Continuing on next and final dam break, we're going to talk about is called the snow removal.
So just like we had that title, so the title is completely gone.
So we're going to go and refresh our app so that we could get that title back.
So we got title back there.
Go back to our break point again and what we're going to do here, we're just going to set a break point
for node removal.
So we lost our our our element are going to go ahead and.
Right.
Click on the title because we want to see where that's being removed.
Go here and we just say break on notable.
So this is useful.
You want to see when that actually got removed.
So do that.
And then we go and we remove the title again and there we go.
We get the same break point action happening.
So there you go.
That is Dom breakpoints.
I don't know if I really talked about.
Yeah, I think I covered pretty much everything that you could do.
You could do with this once again, more useful if you're doing jorquera document, vanilla javascript
stuff.
So if you were using react and you wanted to see well where did that get modified, you you would really
want to just trace the DOM.
And that's sort of useful for conditional breakpoints, which we'll talk about next.
So if I wanted to debug, how was that font being changed in React World?
What I would do is I would just go over here and I would just put a breakpoint right here at the top
of this render method right before the, you know, right.
Right before the actual code got rendered.
And I would just say, OK, well, what why is why is this big class true?
Because I would just look at this code and say, OK, when it's big class, it's big.
And when it's not, it's not there's no there's no class.
So that's why declarative versus imperative react is declarative.
It's declaring exactly what the code looks like versus imperative code that just kind of hacks at the
DOM altogether and and changes things without any concept of state.
So.
So I react is better, you don't really need these types of breakpoints anymore, you could just kind
of put a breakpoint here, which will do next with conditional breakpoints to see, well, when is this
big class true and what's what's what's going on in that situation.
So, all right.
This is this is Don Breakpoints.
And let's move on.