So last lecture, we kind of showed how to click on the stack trace inside of the app and show you how
you know, how we got that error.
This one, we're going to take a step further and we're going to do something that's going to get you
to that error even quicker.
So what this is going to do is we're going to open up the webcam inspector and we're going to click
on pause on exceptions.
So when we have this pause on exceptions enabled, what this is going to do is when we click on that
and we get that error, this is going to just highlight for us directly in our app.
So we are we've paused on.
It's almost like an error break point.
So if you're ever in a situation in your app where you have no idea where this error is, you've clicked
on all these different stack traces or you want to see certain data around that error.
This is a great opportunity to do that.
So in this example, let's say I didn't even know where this file was or I couldn't get to it or I was
clicking on parts of the stack trace and I couldn't get here.
If you do this, like if you're in another script, this is actually what you need to do because let's
say you have an error and a third party library or something and you're clicking on that third party
library.
But that's not going to that's not going to get you really closer.
It's going to be more difficult to do that.
Instead of doing that clicking and looking through, you could just click this top right here on the
webcam, Inspector, pause on uncaught exceptions.
And what you're going to do here is, ah, pause on exceptions.
That is going to enable you to break point on the air itself.
So then what you could do here is now we're paused on this error.
I can hover over it.
I could see that there is no X or there is no function called X, and if I hover over this I can just,
you know, I can once again see that error right here.
A lot of times you'll you won't know what error that is for some reason.
You know, just another way of just seeing, like, OK, this is where the line is that has that error.
And if I hover over it, I get that error.
So that is this over here.