All right, so for this challenge, you could see here we have GitHub card repos are not showing any
data.
Please see if you could fix.
So you could see here we have this GitHub repos display here and we're going to go and open up the sandbox
to get a full view.
OK, so as you can see here, this is a fairly involved example, we have a lot going on here in the
main app and then also we have some folders over here with an API components and some styles as well.
So the issue.
That we are experiencing is that the cards are not showing any data, so you can see here we have some
data, it looks like being shown.
But at the end of the day, when we type something in, you could see here we are getting some cards
back basically.
So when we do type this in, we really want to figure out first exactly what's going on.
Right.
We see we can experience the error here.
We could see that we don't have any names found here.
And we see we have some mystery data on the bottom.
So first thing we really want to understand is what is actually going wrong here and the intention here.
Now, I know it's kind of a complicated example, but the intention with this challenge specifically
was to understand why the names here were not being shown on the cards.
Right.
And as well as this section here now you can see there is part of this data being shown here, but other
parts of the data are missing.
It doesn't look like any of this functionality is broken.
It looks like this app works.
It's just that there's data missing.
So let's continue on our investigation with identifying what components are actually causing this issue.
Let's check our console.
Of course, as you can see, we are getting just some logs here, but no errors.
So what I want to do first, actually, is find the components that are actually being rendered in here,
so let's try to find that card first.
So if I go to my react dev tools, it's probably better to open this in a separate tab.
So let's just go ahead and click open in new window over here.
And so now you can see we have the whole app open up.
We're going to open up our dev tools.
And when we open up our dev tools.
We can go to our react component, explore here, and we could just find these components here so you
can see we find the card and then we could go out and find specific things.
So let's actually find the specific data point.
So here we go.
We have No-Name found.
Here we go.
And then we can go over here to view source for this component.
So we were brought into this with stuff which isn't very helpful.
This doesn't tell us really what's going on.
This is a library inside of material.
Why?
So this is kind of a problem with these styled component wrappers.
They don't really give you the direct component and these debuggers.
So we're going to do is we're going to actually go up.
A little bit to find one that doesn't have this with Styles thing here, right?
So if we go up one more, then we find this one and we are actually brought into what looks like our
code, right?
Well, it's actually materialize code.
So this doesn't help us either because we want to debug our code.
Right.
So let's go one step above.
We have paper.
We have card.
Simple card.
Let's go here, see if simple card can help us.
So here we go.
Simple card is a function inside of card.
Jass cards is minified here.
So we're going to go and find the actual thing here with control or command post.
And then we're going to find for card games and then we're going to actually pick the source, mapped
one and then we're going to clean up.
We're going to close our other tabs.
So now we found the card contents, so now we could start to debug well, what's going on in here?
Well, you could see No-Name found is just written here and cannot find language is written here as
well.
So you could see these are just things that are written in the code, it looks like just in completed
project.
Right.
So let's actually put a breakpoint here.
So when I search for someone.
And I go in here, I can now just start to explore some data, right, so you could see what are the
actual props passed into this component?
You could go up and try and read some Propp types, Propp types are classes, but no other type, so
we don't know what else is in here.
So we have here this is looks like some styles classes.
Right?
So we don't really have much else to go off of.
Right.
We could go here and we could look at this, which is the description.
We know that some data is coming in, which is the description.
So we look at that and we could actually look and see.
We do have another actual prop here.
So this is actually just this is not what you think.
This is actually the classes.
This is just some, you know, nuances with the debugger here not being correct.
Go over here.
And this is the actual real props.
So we have another thing in here called repo.
So this looks like the the repo, which is what we're intending to fetch.
Right.
Actually fetching GitHub repos by entering a username.
So it's important.
I understand the business use case.
So we have that repo here.
And what we want to do here is actually find that missing data.
Now, that's actually the easiest way to do this.
What I really wanted to show at this demo actually was the network tab.
So let's say I didn't know what was going on in here at all and I wanted to debug some network data.
So if I go here and I search again, you could see we have.
Our requests, if you go on to this exchange and fetch request to filter here, you could see here that
we are getting a fetch to GitHub API and here you could click on this and you could see that.
This is where we can get the data preview, right, so we can actually see all the data coming back
and you can then look and see the different data parameters here, which is really cool.
So if you were able to do this, this is a really great thing to learn and to understand how to look
at the preview, the response preview and the raw response data as well.
So that's great.
If we go here and fetch again, we look I think we just spelled his name wrong.
And there was no this is one of the maintainers of react, so.
We refresh.
Paige.
And once again, we go to repose, so at the end of the day, you have that previews here and what I
wanted you to understand was the name.
So where would the name be?
You could see there's a name object in this repo.
So let's go ahead and start filling in this data.
Right.
So we want to find the name.
We want to find the language.
So if we go back to our preview for that fetch, which is then, as you can see, we have the language
here as JavaScript and then also we're looking for stars or.
Or whatever this may be, it looks like shares or notifications or other data that we can look at,
so you could see here that this is really kind of a business issue, right.
Like you want to ask, well, what are the requirements for this component and look into that.
So clearly, the stars are here.
Stargazers count to see the correct example.
You could just look at the fork that I have here of this issue.
And this is where we have the original code here.
And so if you go into the card here, you can see the original fix for this, which is to add in the
name language and stargazers count and then Fork's.
So the point of this message was to learn to clarify some business requirements, look into exactly
what the components are supposed to do, look at your network tab to inspect network data, to understand
different attributes using the react dev tools to actually find components that are in your code base
and not part of an external UI library, and then resolving the issue by just filling in the data so
we could fill in this data in our app as well.
But it will end up looking just like that.
So that's the only thing that was wrong with this, was that certain attributes here were not like this
right here.
So that's the only thing and thank you.