All right, so in this example, Challenge 13, it says this should log keys pressed, so let's go ahead
in this input and start typing around.
And you could see here it's not logging the right characters, right.
So we open up this sandbox.
We could start editing this.
Now, if you were involved in any of the previous challenges, you know that this is a synthetic event
right here, right on key press.
So already we could see this is a pretty simple example that's very similar to ones we've been working
on.
You have an input here which you you could have found by just inspecting the code or looking through
this.
We were able to reproduce the issue here.
We have no errors in the console in this one.
So, again, this is not something that we could solve by fixing some error in the stack trace.
What we can do is read the code.
And you could see here on Key Press, we are calling this callback here.
And as I said, this is a synthetic event which isn't being used and key press is being set to a question
mark.
So we're going to want to edit this code.
So we've identified the root cause, right.
Or setting the key pressed to be a question mark character.
And if we type in here, you could see it adds more question marks.
So if we get rid of it, it still just keeps adding them on.
Right, because it's adding them on to the array.
So we don't need to mess with this at all.
We're just going to want to stick to this.
So the question that you are going to pose yourself now or you should have posed, if you're not familiar
with this, is how do I get the character from a synthetic event or how do I get the typed character
or the event's target character?
Right.
So this refers to the input right on Key Down is going to be an event handler for an HTML.
And what is the signature of that going to be in react world to synthetic event?
So what would be a good Google search here would be synthetic events, character types or key types.
Right.
But let's say character typed.
And then if we look at this first one, you could see it should alert when enter.
So as you can see here, they're questioning about this event code.
And as you can see here.
Event Dorcy works well, so this event Dorcy gives you enter, which looks like exactly what we want
to typewrite, we want to type the key so event.
And then as you can see here, we have the input with a similar event handler on key press.
And this is passing in the event just like we are, but it's using event Darcie.
So that would be our first thing would be to try E Docky.
You save this.
We clear this and we've seen how we get the key, so it's backspace, clear that up.
And we type Hello World, and it's being it's doing exactly what we expect, right?
It's adding in whatever key that we typed and this would work for shift enter.
So this is a really useful thing to know, which is event, if you're looking for the name of the key
types, you could just use Iraki.
You could also use EKI code, which is the number.
But I like using the string of the character better.
So that's this one.
If you want to use like single keys, only what you could do is just do you know if if idot key is greater
than or equal length is greater than one, you could return.
This was the original question and I was going to have you do this, but this is not really the best
solution for this, where you're filtering out the shifts and enters by checking if the key has a length
greater than one.
Right.
Because so if I type E or if I type backspace, it's not going to appear there.
So if you got that, that's a bonus point, but.
You know this I made this vague enough so that if you added in backspaces or enter or shift, they could
appear there and you would still technically pass the challenge in my book.
So if you did this, this is a bonus point.
This is just checking the key length.
So only single spaced.
Correct.
Are only single characters would be logged in this example.
So that's this challenge.