OK, in this one, we are going to talk about a very, very common error that you might get if you're
doing react apps and that is the is not a function error.
So as you can see here, if I refresh, let's just say you're in an app and a lot of times students
will be taking my courses and they'll post their code and just say, I'm getting this.
It's not a function error.
So this is actually really easy to debug.
And I want to help you to understand what's going on and how to fix this error.
So as you can see here, when you click on a mine, so I have this this app here that I've set up,
if I click on a mine, I get Griselda's X is not a function.
So most likely if you get this error, you weren't expecting to get the error.
So you might be thinking, you know, why is this here?
What does this mean?
And your first reaction is to kind of panic.
And that's not what you should do.
You should really what you should do is to actually read the error first.
So understand what's going on.
So basically what this is saying and then so after you understand what this is saying, you will go
down here and look at the stack trace.
So what you have what this is saying ultimately is the same Griselda's X is not a function.
It's exactly what it sounds like.
So this where we're being, we're attempting to call a function called X on this piece of data and this
function X is not on this object.
So we have this object here.
If this was another sister error to this would be cannot access property X of undefined, which means
that grid cells undefined.
But this one means that we're trying to call a function called X on this variable, whatever it is,
and this is not there.
So now you kind of know what that means.
So in your brain, you'll say, OK, I understand that this is here in my code somewhere.
And I tried to call this function and it's not there.
So you might think to yourself, why would I do that?
Why would I call this function that doesn't exist?
And that entirely depends on your appetite.
A lot of times you might assume a functions on an object, maybe this object has that functionality
like Griselle would have the X, another type of Griselle would have X, but this Griselle doesn't have
X.
So you might think, well, what what would I do in that situation to get the grid cell, to have that
function on it?
So that's kind of why that error would be there.
Now, let's talk about how you would debug this and fix it.
So if you go down here, you see right there, you know, this is a really awesome error that it actually
literally tells you like, hey, this is the line that your code of your code that has that error.
So we know that C we could see here that we're we're calling Griselle dot X and that's that's the source
of the error.
So so we know that X is not defined on Griselle and that might be a better description of this area
and might be better off saying something like Grit's, GRISELLE or X is not a function defined on grid.
So I think that might be a more descriptive error for you, for you to understand it.
So going down here, you could see that if we go down here where we're going under the stack trace.
So this is the the code that was called before this function.
So we have our handle left.
Click here.
Even Code Sandbox is going to do us a favor and highlight the error for us as well.
So, you know, with all of these tools and, you know, helping you, it should be very, very easy
for you to spot and fix this type of error.
So you just have to focus and look and see what's going on in the app, use the signs that are there,
and then try and figure out what's going on.
So like I said, I just pointed to how many clues that that point to this line.
There are a lot of clues.
So if you go down here, even in the console, if we go down here, this is really more stuff we go
to see.
I don't actually think that the.
If go this up.
So I'm pretty sure that let's see if we click this, so, yeah, yeah, you could see here that the
code sandbox shows you the arrows here as well.
So you have this error being defined for you in multiple spots.
But, you know, you may not have this simple to read menu.
You might just be going off this log here, in which case you should be able to click on it.
Normally in the let's open up the this is a code sandbox, Ed.
So if we inspect this and we and we open up, you know, if we actually go up and look at the real Web
inspector, this is probably more like what you're going to see.
You may not have a react app where you're actually looking at this error menu here.
You may not be in Code Sandbox, you're probably not in code sandbox, actually.
So you're probably going to look at something that looks like this.
And in this situation, what you would do is you would just click on one of these COL stacks so you'll
see this.
And like I said, you're going to have to come to that conclusion from this.
So all this you know, there's warnings.
There's there's all kinds of things going on.
You're going to have to be smart and highlight and look for an error that makes sense to you.
So this error, because I've seen this error a whole bunch in my in my days that I know what this error
means and only because I know what that error means, I can understand what's going on.
And so that this is a really protip right here.
This is this is something that you really won't understand as a beginner.
You because I like to beginner all this stuff might look the same to you.
Like, if I go up here and I read this, it says, cannot add node one because a node with that ID is
already in the store.
This is something that I have no real idea what is what's going on here.
Now, I'm pretty sure this might happen because I'm just guessing, but maybe this is happening as a
result of this error, right?
So sometimes the errors come in one after another and you have to scroll up to see the first error or
earliest error.
So this would be like a warning.
We know that this is a react warning, but if we go down here, we see as soon as you see this type
of error where it says some of your code has some some error that looks like this, that says it's not
a function, that's where you can make the assumption that, OK, this is my code and I know how to
fix this because the X is not defined on Griselle.
So my this is not a real example of, you know, a situation that I would have here.
So it's not the most realistic example.
So I don't have, like, a real fix other than to just delete this line.
So delete that line and know that fixes it.
But I just wanted to to make that aware, make you aware that the reason that you get that error is
once again, you know, so it compiles fine.
Right.
Like there's nothing wrong with the app right now, even though this code is there.
So this is an example of a runtime error.
And, you know, just just looking at grid cell that acts like if we logged grid Celldex, that wouldn't
cause an error because grid Celldex would just be undefined.
It's the calling of that function, the the the parentheses on that undefined variable.
That's what causes the runtime error, because JavaScript is like, well, what are we calling here?
I don't know what I'm calling and I'm just going to throw an error and break your app for you.
So I hope I did a good job of explaining that app and how you could look at various different ways of
debugging that I didn't actually go into the error again and here looking at the stack trace over here.
So once again, like if you click on this, the topmost place that you're calling that you could just
see, oh, I'm in handle left click and I'm in and I'm calling this function.
Sometimes you'd be in some kind of compiled code, like one compiled code.
Right now we're not in source map.
So using that, you can just click and it'll highlight that error for you.
So if I go back to the console, go back here and I once again, I click right here, I just click on
that.
It's going to highlight that exact line.
So then you're going to be smart and you're going to say, OK, what what is?
So, you know, based on what I said, it's calling X and you can come to that conclusion there and
you could say, OK, what do I got to do on Griselle to get X to be defined?
So that's a solution that you could work toward if this comes up in your app.
So sometimes I would be tracing up where this function is actually defined on GRISELLE or whatever data
structure.
So that would be this error.
Thanks.