All right, so four, challenge 14, this one is going to involve a little more research than past issues.
So as you can see here, we have an app that shows the height in pixels and it's open up this in the
sandbox over here.
You could see here we have basically some code here, not a whole lot of code, but the idea is that
the height here is not being shown.
And so the first thing is to say, well, what is this height?
And as you can see here in the description, we don't have a lot of details about this issue.
So as you could see here, the height that we're actually setting is set here and it looks like it's
intended to be setting here in this use effect here.
And what are we actually looking at as far as height?
We're looking at the ref and the ref is this container.
So the container is going to be the actual elements here inside of it.
So the objective of this whole code that we need to figure out is to how to actually get the height
of this element here.
Now, as you can see here, we're going to be using react refs.
So if you're not familiar with refs, then you would have Google that in terms of what is ref or what
is react ref.
And you would find this documentation here for refs and the dome.
So this is just a guide on react refs and they provide a way to access dom nodes or react elements created
in the render method.
Now, as they say here, typically and react, you don't want to use refs, you want to actually render
things, you know, just as they can be declaratively rendered.
Right.
So you don't want to actually use query selectors and remove elements or access elements and manipulate
them, you know, with the DOM node API.
Right.
So REACT is going to handle all the DOM node API under the hood, but occasionally you actually will
need to access the DOM nodes.
Right.
So REACT provides an escape hatch for that.
So let's say you want to manage focus, you want to call focus on an input element or doing things like
that.
Right.
Animation's things that actually require more visual type of manipulation.
So in our example, we're going to use a ref to get the height.
Right.
And as you can see here.
We we can get so the current is the current DOM node, right?
So a reference to the node is actually in current.
So that is what current is.
So we gave you that.
We gave you refought current as far as getting the current DOM node.
Now, we could put a breakpoint there and actually find that.
So if we open this up in a new window, we can then just confirm that we have some things being rendered
here.
So if we go here, I'll move this over a little bit.
And I open up my terminal and then I find the code, so it's going to be an apt James and I'm just going
to go and put a breakpoint there and then I'll refresh the page.
And as you can see, Reft Current is a d'Hiv, so this is the DOM node and you see there's a lot of
things on the domino, right?
So this is more or less a regular TML issue because we're bypassing react, we're getting right to the
source of the HTML and that is the reference to that HTML element.
Right.
So now you could try and figure this out by just scrolling down here and just looking at what you can
look at.
Right.
What you can access.
You could see there that right there we did see client height.
So that's one clue.
And then that's pretty much, you know, that's just a way of looking at that.
You could then but really what you would want to do, one thing that you could do is just continue researching,
Googling, right.
So you could say how to get the.
This is an issue I found by searching react ref's height.
And then I brought me to here.
And as you can see, they use client height.
They people, you know, are talking about that.
So you could read about this, which we'll talk about.
So this is just you're finding clues for things that you could try out.
So client height was something we pretty much confirmed might work.
But also, you see, you need to use get get bounding client rect so.
We have another code thing that we could try here, which might work so.
As you can see here, he links us to that so we could see get client get bounding client racked to returns
the size of the element and its position relative to the viewport.
So that's a good clue.
Now, maybe we could search for client Highton here and see if that's also defined, which is not on
this page.
But we can go to this related topic and see this provides zero read only property zero four elements
with no success.
Otherwise, it's the inner height of an element.
So it's slightly different.
It's the inner height of the element in pixels.
Now, to continue going, you might say, well, what's the difference between client height and the
get client bounding wrecked?
And for that I did another Google search client high versus get bounding client wrecked.
And we got this thread over here.
Which you can see that somebody commented on this, this person is basically asking the difference between
them and as you can see down here, this person explains it really well.
The client width is how much space do I have available?
And client and get bounden client rest is how much space does the element occupy on the screen.
So basically, as you can see here, you know, that's kind of the general idea of this.
They return different purposes.
The the get bound and client Recht considers transforms and returns the dimensions of the element as
it is actually rendered.
So this so basically you could use either one end of the end.
At the end of the day, they return different things.
Client height is sort of the inner elements.
And bounding client RACT is how much space as an occupy on the screen.
So in general, you would probably want to use client height.
So that is the answer that we're going to go with.
We're going to try it out by doing current client height.
We already know it's there.
So this should be as simple as that.
We could refresh the page because we're not going to get that update right away.
And so just like that, by changing it to client height, we were able to fix the issue.
Now, also, you could see here, you could then confirm that it works by increasing the height of that
element, by adding another element and you could see it does update.
So hope that was useful.
You can also type in get client bounding recht and then do height or get bounding client rect.
Dr. Height, and that will give you the not rounded version of that, which includes the actual rendered
screen, so actual rendered space on that screen.
So I recommend doing client height just because that's going to give you probably closer to what you
want.