All right, so in this lecture, we're going to talk about a super, super common error that you're
going to get all the time when you're working with react apps or any kind of JavaScript apps.
This is the way to show it right here.
This is the can I read Property Z of Undefined, where this is the object sort of property that you're
trying to access.
And this error is pretty simple to understand, but it's just occurs everywhere.
And you're you're going to get confused a lot of the times.
But basically what this means is you're trying to access something off of an undefined property.
And undefined is just a type in JavaScript.
It doesn't have properties or anything that you could access.
So if you try and do a dot on that undefined thing, that variable, you're going to get an error.
And that's just a fact of life.
It's unfortunate, but this is just something that you're going to have to deal with.
What you should be thinking about is, OK, the variable.
So this this really should say foo is undefined and it's kind of misleading.
And I just mentioned another way that the other variable, you know, is not a function.
Right.
This should say Foo is undefined.
Instead, it says cannot read property Z of undefined.
So it's kind of it makes you think like, OK, well, it makes you you have to actually think for yourself
on this one and think to yourself, OK, what is undefined that I'm calling Z.
And if you go down, you look right here, you see food and you knowing this information, you could
say, OK, Foo is undefined and sort of way.
The way that you continue debugging this as you would look, you would trace up and say, OK, well,
I just defined Foo here and I didn't set it to anything.
And then I said Food Z.
And and that's all I did, far undefined, so that's how you would fix this error as you'd figure out
why you're calling something on an undefined object, you trace that back.
Now, let's say I define FUX to just be a blank object.
OK, now you could probably guess what kind of error I'm going to get now, right?
So now I get food out.
Z is not a function.
So now let's say we define Z and we just put Z as a function.
And so now we don't get an error because we have food to find and we have very defined, so I hope that
makes sense.