OK, so for this example, you could see we have tax cut off on mobile, please see if you can fix.
So first you're going to go to the code sandbox here and you're going to actually try and reproduce
this on mobile.
So what we're going to do is we're in a copy this or you could just open a new window over here.
And now we could see we have this page here.
Now, if you remember our lecture on the dev tools, go to here and say toggle device.
So now we toggle the device, we put it on an iPhone or an iPhone X and then we refresh like this.
You could see now that's we've reproduced the issue, right.
We could see that we have text that is cut off so we could reproduce the issue.
Now it's time to actually go to our code.
So let's actually look and see what's going on in this app.
We have a simple opt out here.
And as you can see, we have some styles that are being imported.
And that is our first clue to see what's going on, because this looks like a styling issue, right?
This is an issue related to access and we're going to inspect these elements as well.
But just to kind of review, you could see we have styles that success over here.
And this, as you could see here, we have Apple.
We have our app class, which is defined right here.
And this has a bunch of styles on it.
We also have a media tag down here which has just a media query.
So this is your first clue that perhaps this is code that you may want to be able to modify.
So as you can see up here, this is going to really give it away right here.
We have 500 pixels, says the app width.
And if you go here to the react app here, you could see the iPhone is only 375 pixels.
So good to troubleshoot the root cause, right?
Why is this happening?
It's happening because the iPhone up most 375 pixels and we're telling it to render an element much
bigger than that.
Could also go ahead and inspect these elements on the page.
And you can see that if we hover over one of these, we could see we have that width right here.
Now, what happens if we just get rid of that width?
Well, that looks like it fixes it, right.
But what is the actual default property of that width and how do we set that on the mobile version?
Well, if we go here, we could look at width and we could see here that it set to 355 pixels.
So not an exact access property.
But what you could do here is we could look at this and we could just look at other properties.
We could set we could also set auto.
So let's try that.
That looks like it works.
Right.
And then also we could look at different types of things we could set here, Max, content and content.
Not all of these are available on all the browsers.
But another thing that I'd recommend you could do is also just 100 percent right.
So that's just going to set the width 100 percent, which is what usually you'd want to do that and
then you'd have maybe some margin or padding around that box.
So either 100 percent or auto would fix this.
I believe auto is the default property of width, but let's confirm that width CSFs.
We we just search that we can go here to three schools or Mozilla.
We're going to go to Mozilla and you're going to want to search for default by default.
That's the width of the content area.
As you can see here in three schools.
They say it more directly, default value is auto.
So what we're going to do here is go back to our app.
And in this media query you could see here, the background color is supposed to be blue at this point,
but this is not correct.
What this.
So what we meant to do is actually put a CSR selector in here.
Right.
So this is actually your second clue that if you just were to type CSR in here, it wouldn't work because
you didn't actually specify the DOT app access selector.
Right.
So that's another clue that if you got that far, maybe you figured out to put success in here, but
you didn't actually wrap this with the component.
So now if we save this, let's actually put that with auto in here as well.
Save that.
OK, now, if we go back here to this, we could see now it's actually working and if we get rid of
that, we change this to responsive.
You could then see as we go down, we get blue and then with changes.
So after, as you can see here, between the 400 and 300.
So, yeah, it does after 400 pixels, it will it will change that.
But between 400 and 500 pixels, it's still going to be a little cut off.
Right.
But it looks like it's still it's fine there, so.
Well, it's only fine because we're doing it live.
If you refresh on this width, it would still be cut off.
Right.
So the other thing that you could do is actually change this to be after 500 pixels, then we go and
we change this to the auto.
So let's try that again.
So we refresh now at 418, it does work.
So not always.
You can always rely on stretching it live.
You always are going to want to refresh the mobile version of that.
So that would be the solution to this issue.
You can also get rid of the blue if you want, but yeah, that's the solution.