All right, so for this example, challenge 16, you could see here, we can't select the option, and
that is all the information we get.
So if we go here to the code sandbox, you can see here that as we click, we are not being able to
select the option.
Right.
So if we go to the console, there's no errors here.
So it looks like we're going to have to debug how this component works.
So first thing we're going to do as as usual, you can search for this component that's causing the
issue.
And the way that we do that, as you know, is with the react dev tools.
So we could do that.
But just to keep this short, since we've done that a bunch of times and previous challenges, we can
just look at this example, which is pretty evident where these things are.
Right.
So if we go down here, we could see the best, the worst.
These are labels inside of this component.
So we can see the pop quiz up here.
So we're in this area right here.
And as you can see here, we have some components that are being rendered, we have radio group, we
have form control label, we have a button down here for the summit.
And that's all the clues we have about what type of elements were in release of this form control here.
So where are these elements coming from?
Right.
So if we go up, we see we have radio group.
So right here you could see Radio Group is a material UI component.
And as you go down here, you see we have some form control labels inside of that.
So form control labels, another clue that may have to do with this or may not.
So form control label is right here.
And so we have those can those components.
We also have what else?
So we have form control label and that's basically it.
So.
We also you could see here inside of the forum, controllable, there is a control option which passes
in the radio.
So the radio button is this right.
But let's pretend we didn't know about any of these components.
What would we do to figure out how to actually fix this issue?
Well, the first thing we're going to do is just kind of take a guess and take a stab at where this
is coming from.
My guess is because the radio change handler isn't working, it could be related to the radio group
element.
Now, how do I know where what library that's coming from?
Well, if you go up here, you see material, you iCore Radio Group.
Now, really, what you could do is you could Google this.
If you really don't know where this is coming from, you could just Google the path of that and you'll
get this radio group API for a material UI here, which brings you here to the material UI documentation
for Radio Group.
So.
You could see here, you could read about this, so this is an event to function when this happens so
you can pull out the new value by accessing event target value.
So we have change handler a value the value of the selected radio button.
This is a good clue right here about what this is.
So we're just kind of exploring the props that are documented here could also go down and see some demos.
So if you click down here at the demos, it brings you to the radio button demo page.
And as you could see here, we have a similar example, right?
So this is working, but our code is not working.
So we have a similar example.
So so one thing you could do if you remember our strategy guide is that we could return to normal so
we could actually just see if pasting this in actually works.
So we we see we can open up that code sandbox here, which is this example which is working.
We could go here and then we could actually just copy all of this in.
Right.
And so let's just maybe paste that below.
And you could see here handle change is not defined, so we may want to just stop that because it doesn't
really matter whether this one works or not, I guess it does matter.
So if we go back here to this, you could see handle changes this.
So we'll just copy that handler as well and we'll just see if we could paste that in.
So we have a value in a set value react hook that we also want to grab.
So let's just grab all of that.
And instead of placing that in there like this, we could do is leave that as handle change.
Save that leave, that is handle change, and then we go back up here and we see we have already asset
value and a another one, right.
So if we go here.
So if we pace that in, you could see now we already have that declared.
So let's call that example value and set example value.
So we're doing is we are just copying this example into our app.
So we have this.
So then we go down here to the example value down here where we have this, we say example value and
then set example value.
Right.
But handle change.
We can leave alone because that was the one that was pasted over.
So handle change is the one that we pasted in.
So we've got to make sure we also copy this.
I'm not expecting you guys to do all of this.
I'm just showing you what you could do if you wanted to just copy that example into your app.
So I pasted that example in.
I changed some things around because it was clashing with my example.
But at the end of the day, we did actually fix that or we put in a new example.
Now, if I compare that to what I'm doing in this app, you could see I have I'm checking the event
target value and I'm setting the true or false, but that's not what I'm doing up here.
Right.
So why is this the case?
First, let's just see if this works.
Spoiler alert, it does work.
So the reason it works is because what we're doing here is instead of setting true or false, we're
setting the actual value of the target.
And the value of the target is that radio button and the radio buttons, values controlled here and
the value.
So the value is a texturing.
Right.
So similarly in here, you could see that this example passes in the value.
So you could do this.
You can actually debug a working example.
Right.
So I could go and set a breakpoint here and check the actual value that's being set.
And then I could copy what I learned here that, hey, we actually need to set the event target value.
I could have made this more difficult by not even providing that for you guys.
But I provided that.
And except I just added a twist of, you know, converting to true or false.
So this is a string value.
You set the string of the radio button there and we learned that through this example.
But also we could just read the documentation of that a little bit.
We saw the value of the radio group was the value of the button.
But the other thing that we didn't really talk about is the form control label.
So you could research farm control label and you could see here a form control label is here.
It's let's see if it's talked about any more in this article.
So we're using control F or finding.
So these have labels, so.
So he could go to the API for foreign control label and if we go down here to value, you could see
the value of the component and things are passed in.
Right.
So.
Yeah, so the on change event, it's the source of the call back, so.
If we go down here, we could see this we use we don't have on control or on change in here, but we
do have the change up here.
So this is a basic introduction to how radio buttons work in material.
You are you have the value that you maintain in the opera.
So you are maintaining the value.
You're passing it in here with the radio group and the radio group is going to know which target that
you've selected.
So that's this example.
All you had to do was change this.
Event handler.