All right, so in this example, challenge 17, you could see here we have an objective that says can't
increment, please see if you can fix.
So going over to the code sandbox, you could see here as we click on increment or decrement, we get
an error.
And this says actions may not have an undefined type property.
Have you misspelled a constant?
So this is our error.
The intention with this obviously is to not have an error and to increment or decrement a number that
we could just assume.
That's what happens when we click these buttons.
Obviously, we're new to this app, so we're not entirely sure of that.
But we can continue looking at the app to see what the intended behavior is.
So as we increments, we get this error right.
And this is also evident here in the the problems section.
Now, if we go to if we open this up in a new window to see what happens in a regular console.
We should go out of responsive mode, OK, so we go over here and if we click, let's actually pin this
now to the bottom.
So as we increment get this, so here we go, code sandbox, not the best for getting actual stock traces,
right?
So you always want to in these challenges, you always want to open up in a new window.
So here you could see we have the error here.
So now in a real app or circumstance like this, you'd want to actually go into this.
So we're going to say we could see here we have the uncaught error actions, may not have an undefined
type property.
It seems to have been duplicated twice.
And as you could see here, we have a little bit of a stack trace.
Right.
So if we click on the either one of these so it's click on this is click the source, map one and then
create store is the minified version.
And here's our first clue.
First clue is that this is occurring inside of Redox.
So retargeted creates store.
You are getting this error and you can see here they throw that error in the library.
They say actions may not have an undefined type property.
And so then now you could actually debug Redox here, right?
You can actually look in here and say, oh, type of action is undefined.
So that should be your first clue.
Maybe you've never heard of Redox before.
You don't know what's going on in Redox.
You don't know what Redox is.
But as an experienced developer looking at Redhawks for the first time, this error, you'd still be
able to know.
Well, I know that the actions undefined because I'm literally, you know, this error when it's read
like this, that's the actual code that was run to trigger that source.
Right.
When you click, you get the read underlined error and you can also highlighted at the end.
So let's try again.
If I go here, create store, let's try again this one page that Jass Sonera in my code.
Right, because we have the source map with page that when you see a source map usually means it's your
code because usually other libraries aren't shiping with the source maps, so.
As you could see, we have this code here, so we have increment action and we have decrease action
and if we go back to the source code, we can get the exact so we have increment action on increment
action.
Right.
So we saw here at increment action.
So at this function call, this code was breaking and triggering this error.
So if we go here at the time of this, the increment action, which is here, import from actions.
So at this time it was causing that error.
Why why was this happening at this hour?
Well, this was our code.
We triggered this call to dispatch.
Right?
So our code was run here, increment action, which then was passed in to dispatch, which then triggered
the error.
Right.
Because if we go here, we see the error is in dispatch.
So just so happens, redux provide some commenting in their code here.
So dispatch is the action is the only way to trigger a state change.
So maybe you know a little bit about Redox that it's a state management library you could see here.
Well, this is the only way to trigger state changes by dispatch.
You just learned a little bit about Redox by reading into the source code.
The reducer function used to create the store will be called with the current state tree.
And given the action, the SOS return value will be considered the next state of the tree and the change
listeners will be notified.
So we don't even have to go to redox documentation.
We could just keep reading this awesome comment above this function, right?
The base implementation only supports plain object actions if you want to dispatch a promise.
OK, so plain object.
Right?
So that's giving us a clue that we need to check to make sure we're actually doing a plain object for
our dispatch.
Right.
This is the action.
So doing one argument is functions the action and here we go.
You see a plain object representing what changed.
It is a good idea to keep action serializable so you can record and display the actions.
Time traveling and action must have a tight property which may not be undefined.
It is a good idea to use string constants for action types.
OK.
So I think we figured out what's going on, Redox passes in in action to to dispatch, which determines
the next date.
The action type is undefined.
And we we know that because we're triggering this error and we have documentation telling us we need
to have the type property.
So let's go back into our code and check on how things are working in our app.
If we go here to the increment action, which is imported from the actions library, you can see here
we have two functions, one called increment and one called decrease.
And the increment is what we were trying to do.
And as you can see here, this is a function that we import in the where were we again?
Pages where we import that action and then we call that action.
We we actually call it now.
Why do we why do we need this?
If we are just going to return something, why can't we just use that here?
Well, this is best practice for redux so we can look at redux examples shortly to confirm that.
But basically, sometimes you want to put in like let's say you want to update a person or you want
to edit someone's name on the server or throughout your app you would pass in that name here.
So you pass in some options in here and then generate that action that way.
So we call this function and we return in action.
Right.
This value here, it must be in action.
So if we go back to our actions so like I said, normally or sometimes, you know, if we want dynamic
behavior, you could pass that in here.
But here you could see we don't have a type property.
Right.
So we're returning just basically the key as increment.
And that's basically an increment is from action types.
So increment is just a string.
So we're basically saying we're basically putting in a word that looks like this increment and then
the action types is actually this word.
So what we ended up doing was we ended up just saying this, increment this, and that's what Redock
saw.
And Redock said, hey, we don't have a type property in here.
So what the solution to do, we would need to just say, well, so you might be asking, like, what
is a type rate?
Why do I why do I need a type?
And that's your next question.
Right.
So if we go back into Redox now, we want to do some Googling, so say redox documentation, and we
can even say redox action documentation and we'll get redox actions here.
And as you can see here, the type is a constant which Redhawks recommends and then it's a string.
So with that, you could see here, here's our are expected action schema or a type of you know what?
This is what we would expect to see in action.
Right.
So really, the.
So let's see.
You might think, well, do I need Texte or do I need anything any other properties?
Well, it says they must have a Thai property, and that's basically it.
Right.
Other than type, the structure of the action is up to you.
So that is basically it.
So the structure is up to you.
So if we don't need any other thing here, which if you think about it, what do we need to increment?
We just need an action that says increment right.
We don't need to care about the current value or do we write?
So this is more diving in a more redox.
I'll just solve this for us right now.
We need to just put the type key in here and then now you could see we can correctly increment and decrement
or decrease, so.
As you can see, we use this to just tell Redox like this is the next state or this is the next, does
the action I want to do, we're not going to say this is the next state where we're just going to say
I triggered a user input action.
All I did was click increment.
And then in your reducer, this is where you actually handle that action type.
So you'd say action type.
And this is why we need action type, because we need to switch, you know, between the different action
types so we could do different things right here.
We spread over the state and then we use the value to increment or decrement that value.
We return that state to our app.
So previously, you know, it wouldn't work until you actually had that action type because you could
just you just be returning state, right.
So if Redox didn't throw that error, you would have to debug this and say, well, which action type
do I want to do?
I want to do this action type.
Therefore, my action type needs to be increment.
Now, if you want to use other things, like let's say you want to increment by five or something,
you could increment by a certain amount.
Right.
You could be like, you know, increment and then amount five.
Let's say you're passing through your app.
You could determine how much you want to increment by.
Right.
Be like amount.
And then, you know, you would pass that in here.
And then in your app, you would you would control that with like an input or something.
And then in here you could say state that value plus action dollar amount.
So you're just adding that onto that structure.
And then as you could see now I'm adding by five.
So you're adding on to that action.
It's just a generic object.
This is why people are confused about Redox, because it's using simple JavaScript, but it's very opinionated.
It's like a action type is a specific thing.
Now, you could do lowercase letters here.
You could you could not follow their best practices and just do this.
You could just, you know, do type increment in here to be the same thing.
But anyway, so that's just how this works.
This is just the example of just some basic redox, a very simple Redhawks example.
And you troubleshoot to learn all about redox actions.
And you learned how Redox works as a first time redux beginner.
You learn how Redox handles state transitions with actions.
Now, of course, you didn't learn all about Redox, right?
You didn't learn about the store or the reducers in depth, but you were able to troubleshoot that issue
without knowing anything about Redox.
You were able to go in there and fix that issue.
So that's this lecture.