All right, so challenge 18, as you can see here at breaks on button press, please see if you can
fix.
So as you could see here, this example is a class based component.
We're going to go over here to this example.
And I included this class based component here because there's probably other class in the other sections
in this course.
But I did include classes because REACT still is supporting class based components.
And if you're ever on the job or you're getting a job, you're going to be working with code.
Most likely that's class based components.
Honestly, it's you know, where we are right now.
Not everyone has converted their whole code base to Hooke's and most haven't, actually.
And so you're going to be dealing with these types of components.
And I included this in here because it's a really common example of an issue that you'll encounter with
class based components.
So if I go here and I click explode, we get this or this, that set state is not a function, so.
The issue here, and this is, you know, it's going to be happening in Europe, right?
We know where it's happening.
It's right here on the explode method.
The reason this is happening is because we are passing in this call back into this kallick handler.
But the problem is that this is not being defined here.
So this is super common scenario where you pass in a callback and then the callback is called in the
context of a new function that doesn't have this current this object, which is in classes.
You have the this parameter.
Right, to reference the current instance of this class.
And instead, what you need to do is you need a way to bind this function to the this parameter and
the way that you do that.
There's two ways to do it.
You could do it in a constructor where you say this dot set state or this, you know, you define this
to explode equals this dot explodes behind this.
But the easier way to do that is you can just add in an arrow function here like this, this syntax.
So it's that it's defining this method on this class and it's binding this function so that it's always
bound to this parameter.
So if I click this, we get the expected solution there.
So how would you have figured this out?
Well, you could just Google that error that we had before this thought.
This that set state is not a function.
And this will provide more than enough help to, as you could see, the just pages of this exact error.
So as you could see here, the callback is made in a different context.
Need to bind to this, just like I said.
And as you could see here, this is so what this person's doing here.
So as you can see here, this is a way different example.
But what they do is they bind to this like that, so.
This is an older example, as I say, when you're dealing with react, you're going to be encountering
all these old stack overflows.
And so, you know, this may not have helped you, but this might have this example.
So constructor superprofits.
So you always call a super on the props in in react.
You're going to want it because you're extending in and ethics classes.
You're going to want to always because you're extending a class you need to call super in the constructor.
And then this is where people would then say this dot on klick or this dot explode in our example equals
this dot explode up by this.
So if you'd never seen this before, you may have overcome you may have found this issue by or figured
out the solution by finding this stack overflow thread right here.
So my example is not going to.
Here we go.
So my example is this.
So Arrow functions are being so arrow functions are automatically bound.
And this is just an example of what I did there.
So they just take that function and they bind it.
So that's this is you.