All right, so in this example, we have similar example to the first challenge, which is the guess,
the password.
So we're calling this get the password 2.0.
So that's basically the same as the first challenge, which basically you have to use no code.
So we're not writing code here.
I didn't write that, but we're not writing code here.
So all you have to do is basically try and guess the password using just your chrome dev tools, basically.
So we're going to open up the sandbox in here and then we're going to go here to the new window, open
this up.
And so now, just as you remember from the first one, we're going to just see what's going on.
So if we try and enter in a password, you could see here we get an error that says invalid password.
So if we go and we look at that, we could see here it's happening in the app tags on submit.
Right.
So we're looking through we're saying, OK, well, this is happening here in this sandbox code where
where's our code react, Dom?
Developments, not really our code.
So we go up one more and we see this is our app.
So we click that.
Now, you could see here we have that error happening in this submit function here for try catch.
So if you're familiar with try catch blocks, you know that something went wrong here.
If we're in this section of the code, right.
And all this section does, it looks like it just sets an error, right.
That says we have an invalid password.
So that's how the error happens.
We broke something here, actually, believe it or not, because we we failed.
We threw an error in here and we actually ended up in here.
Now, the first thing now now you could try and just look through this right now and see what's going
on there.
But you could also set a breakpoint right here.
So once we set a breakpoint there, we had submit.
Then we get and we hover over that.
Usually that works, sometimes it doesn't.
So we hover over that can also just type that out in the console.
And as you could see here, this is the actual error that the code is returning to us.
So what we did, we just said invalid password.
We're not going to tell you the client site error that happened in here, but what happened?
So some error happened here, ended up in here.
The default JavaScript is going to tell you what that error is.
And it's a it's this error cannot be set properly.
Zero of undefined.
Now, where is that happening?
Well, as you could see here, the submit function, of course.
But then right in here, we could click on that.
And that brings us to this line, we're actually stuck on this line currently, but if we go here again
and we could still click on that, we could see it highlights briefly right here.
So it looks like we saw.
So this is the the line that's actually causing the issue.
And most likely, this is what we need to focus on, because if we do this and we don't throw an error,
then we see we could set the wind condition.
So we have diagnosed the issue.
We've determined the root cause is in the cement function.
We are causing an error that's breaking and creating the invalid password.
So let's debug exactly what's going on here.
Now, as you could see, we can't set property zero of undefined.
Now, if you remember, we did discuss this, right?
What does that mean?
It means that.
It can't set property zero of undefined, so undefined is what we need to look at, right?
What is undefined?
Ask yourself what is undefined here?
Well, clearly friends is undefined.
If friends is defined on person, it would say so.
Friends is not defined on person.
It would say zero of undefined right because of friends was defined and it was an array then it would
not throw an error here.
Right.
So if a person was undefined it would say, can I read property friends of Undefined.
So how would we solve this.
Right.
Well because we're in a loop.
We can't just put a breakpoint here.
Right.
Let's put a breakpoint in there.
We hit submit and you could see well, this friends is there.
This friends is defined.
Right.
So this is not where it's causing the issue.
So we hit Breakpoint again.
We see this this person also has friends, so.
What did what did we learn about conditional breakpoints?
Well, we learned that we can actually set a condition in here, so we edit this breakpoint and we say
no person friends.
So this means when this expression is true and when but that really means is when this is undefined.
Right.
Because if you invert or if you do this invert the undefined expression, you get true.
And we could confirm that by going in the console and you could say, look.
Like that we get true.
So that's just a little tip that you would be able to do here and say, OK, this so we want to put
a breakpoint here when this person has no friends.
All right.
So we're going to set that conditional breakpoint and we're just going to hit refresh.
So now when we enter in a person, so we enter in a password, we get we get this and we get this error
here, right.
We've officially paused when the person's friends are undefined.
And so we see this.
We say, OK, this is the person's name.
So it's it's.
So this is the person that has no friends, we found the person that's causing the error, and now you
might be wondering, well, how do I modify this code to not go here?
Well, you could see here we have an exclude person function.
So if the so when we submit, we can exclude a person.
Right.
And the person's name that we exclude is equal to the input inside of the password.
So that's kind of the secret of this, is that we need to type in something that we want to exclude
from this friend's array.
Now, if you read any of this, this is all just a red herring, basically, to trick you into thinking
it had anything to do with mystery person.
It doesn't.
This is just completely just nonsense that I added just to get this part of the code to break for a
certain person.
So mystery person is not what you needed to do here.
What you need to do is figure out which person has no friends, which is causing the error, which is
this person right here, which is if we go down her name is Pazzi Méndez.
So if I copy that.
Then let's get out of this break point.
If I copy that and I submit, I get the correct password.
So that's this issue, what we learned here was conditional breakpoints, basic JavaScript errors,
try catch blocks and tracing the stack.
So I hope this was a good lesson for you.