All right, so this is challenge number two solution, and the remaining of these challenges are a lot
of these challenges are going to be involved with changing code around or fixing code that's broken.
And you'll see the subjective up here, which is basically like, hey, this this is the issue and I
need you to fix this code by writing code in the sandbox.
So basically the concept here is that you're getting some vague issue.
So it's not going to be a specific thing you have to do because that would make it easy.
Right?
Like if I told you exactly what you needed to do, it wouldn't be very it wouldn't be much of a challenge.
So what this is doing is it's it's just giving you a simulation of somebody reporting an issue, which
is what you're going to encounter in the real world.
So here you could say it just says the app is crashing.
Fix the bug.
So as you can see here, the syntax error should be pretty obvious.
But if it isn't, then I'm going to show you how to debug this as if you had never seen this issue before.
So as you can see here now, we can open the sandbox like this.
So if we click that open the sandbox button, it's going to be loading here and then we are in here.
So this is just the the bigger sandbox, if you want to look at this.
And as you can see here, we have the larger area.
The area is more expanded.
And if I go down here to the console, this would be the dev tools console here.
Now, if I if I also just do control shift J, I will get the the real webcam inspector, which is what
you would see on a real app.
So I recommend just doing this.
It's not going to be exactly as if you were on a real app.
If you want to get the real app experience again, you could go up here and copy this you URL.
So if we do that, we go over here.
Paste that in, we get this here, so and then now we could open up the dev tools in here and this would
be more like a realistic app, right?
We're not in a code sandbox anymore.
We're sort of running their actual app.
So as you can see here, we are getting an error from Babille.
So you could see here we have this syntax error.
We trace it down into Babul.
So you very you know, it's not your code, right?
This is definitely not what is our code, but the error is being raised from Babille.
So Babul is going to interpret your syntax and it's going to basically throw this error.
Now, I'm not going to describe too much of this because if you don't know what this is, I don't want
to give it away.
But basically, let's just say that we we don't know what this is and we're just going to Google this.
So if I just copy this or if I just write click and I say search Google for that error.
So as you can see, I get some stack overflow here as the first Google result.
And you could see this person asks this error and basically they get this on terminated Jass contents.
And as you could see, they have to unclosed div tags, so.
So I'd get rid of those so and then try it again, so not really too much too helpful in this one,
but this person, I believe, shows what is wrong.
Give this closing, you know, backslash in the closing development and remove the semicolon.
So basically, he's just saying, hey, put put a closing div tag there.
As you could see here, we have a similar issue where we we are not closing the div tag and so it's
on terminated.
Right.
Terminating the div would be closing it off.
So we're just leaving something open ended.
And so that's the gist of this.
I know it was probably obvious for some of you, but if you if you weren't aware of this, this is a
syntax error.
And to just fix that errors, you could see all I'm doing is I'm just I'm just closing that div tag
off.
So I know this is probably an easy one, but I just wanted to include this in here as an example of
a syntax error.
So that is a challenge to now.
Another thing you could do is you could.
So let's go to our strategy guide here and how we debug that.
So again, we we read the error in the console and then we followed the stack trace that didn't really
help us that much because it was in an external library.
Right.
It was coming from Babul.
So we researched a little bit.
We did.
We Googled the error message and that was able to help us.
We found some some code, some comments that were able to help us find that bug.
Now, we could also try a clean example so we could try a clean react app.
Right.
We could we could basically, again, like return an actual, you know, div that was it was closed.
And then we'll figure out will match that up with our code and we'll figure it out from there.
But yeah, that's another way of doing it.
But again, this was pretty obvious one.
But if you had like a really complicated syntax error, you might want to backtrack and put some good
syntax in.
So that is the that's this one such challenge to.