This video, we're going to talk about the number one mistake, new beginners make writing code.
So most of the questions that I've gotten answering questions in my courses has been really traced down
to a single mistake that beginners make.
So what is the number one mistake?
New beginners make writing code so they don't check their spelling.
So checking your spelling is really important.
You're always going to want to do this twice or three times after you write code.
This is because if you're texting a friend and you spell a word wrong, it's not really a big deal.
Right?
But with code, it not only will cause your app to break sometimes, but also your app will not break
and you'll be forced to debug this issue later in a more difficult way.
So maybe you misspell an attribute or something so you can see case sensitivity matters.
So if you have the wrong case, you're going to have an error.
If you try and assume two variables are the same and matching up your brackets is really important as
well.
So it's really important to get the brackets around a loop and inside of your JSM correct and misdoing
the brackets could cause issues as well and compile time versus runtime.
So some issues will occur during compile time when you're writing the code, but also other issues will
come later when you're when your actual code executes on the browser.
Try it out.
Can you spot the spelling error?
So there isn't technically a runtime error here, but the console, that long statement will print undefined.
So this is an example of something that doesn't crash your app.
But it may be easy to miss this because it looks like person ID is defined there.
But actually, person ID is the local variable we used person person ID is undefined in this example,
so an improvement would be to name better variables.
So person name would probably make more sense than a person name.
And if you're going to use a local variable like person ID, you might as well just d structure const
id comma name off of that person and just use those if you're going to log them.
So just a way to clean up your code and to avoid spelling errors.