All right, so for this challenge, you could see here we have numbers are not appearing when clicking
on cells, please see if you could fix.
So this is a fork of a minesweeper game that I found and I tweaked it so that there is a bug in here.
So basically, as you click, there is just no numbers appearing, which makes this game impossible
to play.
So we're going to make this game fun again.
We're going to debug this and let's jump into it.
So we're going to go to open sandbox.
This is going to open up the sandbox, as you know, and.
Let's get started by opening up in a new window here so we can actually get the game here and we're
going to open up our dev tools.
So as you could see.
We have some errors already.
These are generally not something we're going to look at right now.
These are just warnings basically for the app.
So when we click, we are also not getting any errors.
So we can basically we can we have some more errors in here or we have some more logs as well right
here.
So as you could see, here we are.
We are getting some distracting information that's not helping us.
Right, because we click we're not getting anything about that, causing an error in the console.
So we could do then is actually just start researching how this component works.
So if you go to react components, you could see here, this is going to tell us basically where these
components are in the app.
You could also just inspect the element and read, you know, the class names and search for those in
your code base.
So let's go here.
And we want to look for a cell.
Right, because the cell is really what's giving us that data.
As you can see here, I know that it's a cell by hovering over it.
So I'm hovering over it.
I'm clicking here view source for this element.
And as you can see here we are in the cell component in our app.
So without knowing much else about this app, I was able to find the component that I want, if I go
here, I could see here more, you know, how they actually render it within the game and the cell.
So this is the game class.
This is the source map for the game.
So there's a constructor.
Looks like it looks like there's a lot of things going on.
It renders the board.
And then we could see there's a board over here.
You could trace that by where it's imported.
So dot dot means go up a little bit and then go back into board.
You could see we have index here.
The board is going in rendering all of this stuff.
So you might be thinking, how am I going to figure out how that cell gets its value?
Well, we're going to just stick to what we were doing.
I'm just kind of tracing it up for you.
But here where you could see the the grid finally renders the board.
Or the board finally renders the cells right, so just by researching, lightly scrolling and seeing
what's rendered in each file is always good practice.
But you can see here it renders the cell with a value.
So looking through the properties is really important.
But if I go back to the cell where I was originally, you could see also right here that there's a render
method and there's props.
That value is a mine.
So you're kind of getting some different types of class names that are being rendered.
So just figuring out the clues that are in this file.
And then finally, you could see here we have a div that means, you know, a divide HTML element,
and inside of that div is get value.
Now, if you saw we were rendering those bombs, right, let's see that bomb.
So what does that bomb actually is that is that part of the cells that another component.
Right.
So you going to want to go and let's just check what a bomb is.
So if we go over a bomb, you could see that I'm not getting any more real components in there.
So what does that tell you?
That means that it could be just the contents of that element.
Right.
So if I go here and I say value.
I could see this just some more react props for that sell, but let's go ahead and just confirm what
is actually needing to be rendered here.
So if I go back to the sources, it looks like get value is my main function.
So that's the that's going to be the root cause.
The source of my issue is it looks like a rendering issue.
Right.
There's no errors in the console.
So it's a rendering issue.
So get value is what determines the value.
Right.
So I could see here this if statements that say if it's not revealed, you can and it's flag, you can
show a flag.
So I could see if that works by right.
Clicking So if I restart and I right.
Click the flag still work.
So this works else.
If it's a mine it's going to show the bomb or else if it's empty we're going to show an empty string.
So what else am I missing here?
Well, I'm missing the part where it returns the number.
Right.
So where would it when would it return a number?
Under what circumstances would it return?
A number that's getting into a little bit more hairy situation of trying to understand all the business
logic of like, well, how does this app actually work and all of that?
And that's really important.
But for now, let's just debug see if there's any no no data on this value.
So if I click and this just happens to be a number, then perhaps there's a number on there.
And as you could see here, we have in being defined here, we don't know what that is yet.
But, you know, spoiler alert, that's that's actually it.
But how would we know that if we didn't, you know, know about this game?
Well, we had Propp types here.
So going back up, remember, we talked about the board earlier.
The board renders the grid cell.
The grid cell is the value.
So the value is actually grid cell.
So it's kind of confusing how they turn a grid cell into something else called value naming is really
important.
So grid cells are just inside of a row, right?
Because the row is mapping the grid cells and then.
What else is happening in here?
Well, the grid, so what is the grid cell?
So let's go up and see if there's anything about the grid cell in here.
And as you could see, there are some things about grid cells.
But what about the number?
What can I learn about the number?
You know, we're just trying to learn more about the data in here.
And it's possible that, you know, the the grid cell.
Would you be able to determine the number or just learn more about it?
So as you can see here, we used the DOT MN, so we use the end here to increment the the neighbor cells.
So if you know, you have a bomb that's detected, you know, you can the number is supposed to show
how many bombs are around it.
Right.
So that in the you you know, so you could see here the mine.
So it, it collects.
So does it get random mines is the name of this function, as you could see here.
This looks like this could be determining the number of mines as well with that end.
So we're we're just getting random mines.
We're getting that end and we are then returning those mines here.
I'm not sure of that.
Totally helped us to understand the number on that element.
So, again, this would just be something you keep researching.
So we say grid.
So we see create new board.
And you can see here, this is where we create the rose, not pop star width, which.
You know, this looks like it's creating the roads here we go through, we create that grid cell, so
we create the grid cell right here.
Now as grid cell defined in here, we're getting closer.
We're getting closer to understanding whether or not that's the number or not.
So we say.
Griselle here.
And you could see here we create a new grid cell and if we go to reveal bored.
So if you search for grid cell in this class, you will find this class down here, which is grid cell,
and then you could see here there is a constructor and not a whole lot of other information, actually.
Well, you could see mine's so around that.
So you do have mines in here.
So is mines.
You could see this.
That is mine equals is mine.
That equals zero is empty is an equal zero.
So we're kind of drilling into exactly the root cause of this issue, which is that OK, and is seems
to be the amount of number.
It seems to be the number of data that we that we want on this object.
Let's go ahead and return the number from the value.
So that's the solution to this.
Basically, you need to go back here and you need to find the grid cell and then in the get value,
we're going to end up returning value.
So this would return the number as a default case.
So default as we were turning the empty object, now we are returning the number.
So this was a kind of complicated thing that you needed to debug.
You had to learn about business logic of a specific domain that you've never seen before, researching
the different files and folders to understand the flow of data and rendering and then reverse engineer
how to render that data and then fix that rendering method to return the expected data that you've confirmed
is correct.
So.
You know, this was this this was an example of something that could have been infinitely more difficult,
right?
Like, I could have had you figure out how to calculate these and write a big function like that.
But this is a debugging course.
You want to debug what's wrong, not necessarily reimplement a bunch of features.
That'd be a different course would be like how to implement this feature using recursion or something
like that that they use here.
But this is just debugging you.
You know, you're being resourceful and you're you're kind of expecting that the app is already in a
functioning state.
You're just trying to understand the app and then return, you know, fix it, getting back to a fixable
state quickly so you could see most of my challenges or one line fixes.
And that's intentional is to get you to understand as much as you can about the app without doing a
big, you know, project on top of it.
So.
I hope this was helpful.