All right, so challenge 21, this example, as you could see here, it says it shows unauthorized and
we are unable to access the app.
So the intention here was to get you to debug this without writing any code.
Right.
So if we open up the code sandbox.
And we go to the OP in the new window, basically what we we can observe that we're not allowed to access
this app, pretty straightforward.
There's no errors in the console.
But as you can see here, there's a very simple app.
So we could debug this quickly.
As you can see here, it's locked when the react state is set to react to is locked.
Right.
While there actually is no react state, this is a function that we're just creating here.
And what this function does is it actually looks in local storage for an item called lock.
And when that lock is equal to unlocked, it returns false.
Elsah returns.
True.
So as you could see, it's true because if it's true, if we're locked, we return this.
So the objective here is to debug this without writing code.
So we open up our chrome dev tools here.
And because we are looking for the local storage, what you can do here is going to local storage and
actually add a key in here to.
Be locked, so how to do that is what we're going to do is we were just going to see if we could delete
selected so we could do is you could just double click in here and just add a new key.
So we're going to add a key equal to lock and then we're going to double click here and set the value
to be unlocked.
So then we refresh the page.
And you've unlocked the app, so that was the solution.
So what do we learn here?
You may not know that you can actually edit local storage values by double clicking.
This is useful if you're testing shared or settings functionality that you know is used in your app,
you can then modify that with the value, you know, here without having to use code to set local storage
values.
You can also clear all your local storage values right here.
And then you could see the app then goes back to the lock state.
So this is just an exercise in editing and adding local storage values.