All right, so four, challenge 22, you could see here we have when clicking on buttons, the theme
isn't set.
So we click on this and we get an error here.
So that's our first clue.
If we go to open sandbox, you can see here we have this issue here and we could start to debug this
issue.
So this issue is one that came up constantly in one of my courses.
And I wanted to include this here because I feel like it's pretty important.
And it happens because of, as you could see here, this is related to react context, and that's going
to be the topic of this specific challenge.
So let's go ahead and start debugging this.
So when I click this, you see, I clearly get an error here and we're going to go ahead and open this
up into a new window like we always do, just to go ahead and look at the console.
So you can see here, set theme is not a function on click.
So I click this and as you could see here.
We are inside of camp two, component two, so here we have two components that are being rendered,
one which shows the theme and then the other which shows this over here.
So camp one is first up here, which is just as light.
And then the other component here shows the current theme and then the a series of buttons.
Now it says set theme is not defined.
Right.
So this is something.
So you could see here, it's a set theme is not a function right on this line when I clicked the light
button.
So this is something that, like I said, happens constantly.
And I think people are confused by this because they are unfamiliar with react context.
So as you could see here, we have used context.
So where is set theme supposed to be coming from?
It's supposed to be coming from this function called use context right here and here.
We have a theme context.
So a theme context, as you could see here, was created up here with react, create context, dark.
So our question is, well, why isn't this returning what I want it to, which is these objects here?
So if we keep going, you could see here we actually use.
So now this is just an intro to context I'm going to go into now.
So basically you would need to research a little bit more about react, create context and use context.
So let's go ahead and research that now.
Now, I'm going to stick to use context because it's the most recent, you know, thing causing the
error here.
And I'm I just want to get refreshed on this specifically, which is looks like a react hook.
So let's go ahead and research that.
So if I say use context, it brings me to this Hooke's API reference where I click on Use Context and
you see here it accepts a context object and returns the current context value.
So the current context is determined by the value prop of the nearest provider.
So you could see here that the current context value is determined by the value prop of the nearest
provider.
So we'll first have to check if there's a provider.
Next, you'll see it will trigger a referendum with the latest context value passed in to the provider.
So as you could see here, it's correct to pass in the context in there.
So we pass that incorrectly, it seemed.
And we are then.
So here we go.
As you can see here, this looks very familiar to our example.
But as you can see here, we create a context.
And then we use that context here to get the theme and then we access properties off of that theme,
we say themed background themed foreground.
So you could see the object that we pass in here, the object that we get out of this is an object and
that we can access properties off of that.
So how do we get this passed in the app?
Well, through the value proper member of the nearest provider.
So the value prop passes in this theme object here, which is dark.
So we pass in this and then we could get the properties out of that easily by just accessing them.
All right.
So this is a documentation for use context.
Let's go back and check on our example so you could see we have the theme provider here.
And as you could see, we have a value object here.
As you know, as we just learned, the value is was returned here.
And it looks like we are getting the theme and then the set theme here.
So.
As you can see, what we have passed into value is just the theme, so all we have to do is then add
in a set, a set theme function.
Now, where do we do that?
Well, we have a react hook right here.
Right.
So if we add in theme and then set theme.
We could then pass in set theme here to the value prop of the provider, and then now if we click,
you could see we don't get the error anymore and we are correctly switching state, which goes into
the context provider and then gets structured here off of the value.
So this is a better example of how to use react context to create a dark and light theme.