All right, so in this example, you see chart colors are not correct, they should match our brand
color, this one.
So the objective here was basically imitating somebody saying that we want to change the chart colors.
So you have three charts here.
And the objective here is to basically make it look like this.
So this is the solution right here where all three of these charts have the same color, which is the
brand color that you were given.
So how do we do this?
Well, the first thing we want to do is look at our code here.
And here is the example opened up through Code Sandbox here.
And if we go to this example here, first thing we want to do is actually just identify the charts themselves.
So this is not, you know, syntax error or anything like that.
We need to look at the console for this is more or less a research problem that we have to look into.
And I included this because it's good to know how certain libraries work if you need to debug them.
So APACS charts, you could see here we have one library there.
We have another one called High Charts, and then we have another called Chartist.
So three different charting libraries that you would have to debug here in order to figure this out.
And all three of them might have different solutions.
It turns out that Apex charts and high charts have very similar ways to change the colors.
But Chartist has a much more different and inconvenient way to do that.
So the first thing we're going to go here to the Apex chart example here, and we're just going to look
at what's going on.
You could see this is the React Apex charts library up here.
And then we could go and see here.
We just have some options.
And yeah, that's passed into the chart right here.
And so just looking for opportunities to modify options basically.
And without the documentation, no, you're going to be hard pressed to actually figure this out on
your own.
So what you should do is actually look for apex charts, documentation or better yet, examples.
I found this example on their website.
So if you look for a react chart, demos column charts here in Apex charts, you will be able to find
this example where we go and we see we have the options here.
And then inside of the options we have a colours array and so the colours array, it's not defined here
fully.
Let's see if we go down.
So it's not actually even defined here very well.
So these these examples, like I've mentioned, are not usually going to be that helpful.
So what we could do is we could find more information on what that colours array is.
If you just go to if you just keep looking through the documentation, you will find or if you searched
for colours.
So if we search for Colores Apex charts, you'll just get this page here, which shows you how to set
a series of colours.
So for any of the charts, you could set this in the options.
So this is really just, you know, colors of series, right.
So if we go here in the example, we will as we saw in that other example, we define the colors inside
of this options object here.
So if we go back up.
We can see will define the colors to be an array, and we'll just put the one color that we want just
to see if that works.
So we go back here and we copy that brand color in.
Copy that in to an array just like this and then just like that, you could see the chart has changed
colors, hi charts does this very similarly.
If you go to the pie charts website, you can then look up ways of setting colors similarly.
And here you could just, you know, you could search there documentation.
You could look up here, you could go to charts.
So if we search their documentation like this, we just search for colors.
You'll get plenty of examples like this colors.
And then we could look at certain examples.
But this example doesn't seem to work for me.
So some of these examples seem to be broken unless we click run.
There we go.
So it does work.
So similarly here you could see here we have this global high chart set options, which is really cool.
So we could set them globally so that our brand color is always there.
And that's a good best practice.
Maybe the best solution for this would be to do that for each of these libraries.
So like hi charts, you could go over here.
And so high charts is the second chart, by the way.
We're done with the first one.
So we go here to high charts, set options, and let's go ahead and try to set that brand color.
So if we go up here and we go back to our.
Color and go back here to high charts that said options now.
If we refresh the page here.
We see that the the chart is correctly sent now to our brand color.
So now any charts that we create with hi charts will have that color that we have here.
So now, no matter what chart we create, we have our branding colors right here globally.
All right, so the next one, react chartist, you're going to do a little bit more research on this.
If you do, you might find this stack overflow thread which says, hey, I'm using Chartist, but I
can't change default line colors.
We have Barbar charts, but usually the way to do it is the same throughout your app.
So we have these bar charts here.
So anyway, what do they do?
Well, they actually will use Kath's to change the stroke to that color.
So what we can do here is we could do this similar example here.
We could try and find the excess properties that correspond to that.
So if we go here to our bar and we right.
Click and say inspect, you will then be able to check out the different elements that make up that
chart, which is pretty interesting if you're interested in this kind of thing of of learning how charting
libraries work, a lot of them are using these CGS.
And so CGS are basically animated, scalable vector graphics that apply, you know, inside of HTML.
So it's not a canvas where you're drawing on pixels, pixel based, rendering its vector based.
So you're using math basically to define certain things.
So here I'm looking at the lines here and as I drill in, I could see there's a series right here and
I click into that and then I, you could see I'm actually hovering over each bar.
So when I click on that, you'll see we have that.
Class here that we can then copy.
So this is the case that's applying that if I want to change that, I could just change it right here,
actually, so I could do this.
I could click on this square right here and I could change the color to whatever I want it to be.
But so that proves that that works.
So now we have to do is just overwrite this in our app.
So we go back to our app.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to paste in those exact classes that I found.
And then here you could see all I'm going to do is just set that show property to be our branded color.
So let's see what happens when I say there we go, that that looked like it worked.
So there we go.
So as you could see here, that worked.
And I've set the Smokler, so.
Once again, all of these charting libraries have different ways of nuances, of writing their documentation,
showing examples and some you have to you stack overflow to figure out what to do.
Now, it would be ideal if this you know, I'm sure that Chartist probably does have a way to set this,
but it doesn't really seem clear based on a Google search that I can actually do that.
Now, if I just search for Riak Chartist, I can try and dive in deeper into, you know, what's going
on with this library.
And I could, you know, end up here.
And then I could try and search for color on this documentation and nothing comes up.
So it's a very simple library here.
So once again, this example of something that you have to search for to figure out, unless I'm not
finding the right documentation, but that's how I would solve these issues here.
So be resourceful.
Look at your documentation, read the documentation, find example code and try and search for the proper
solutions.