All right, so here we are on challenge 24.
You could see here it says date is not formatting correctly.
I want the chip to display as the form same format as the date input.
Can you help?
So with this challenge, the objective here is to basically change this chip text to be the same format
as the date picker's format.
And this way you'll be able to change the date and you'll see that updated here.
But in this format, as you could see here, it currently does update to the same format or the same
date, it looks like.
But this format is not the same.
So this exercise is really useful when you are building an app with a lot of dates and you're going
to need to format the dates.
And this is not really a great format.
And so you wanted a clean format that looks kind of like, you know, a shorthand date format just like
this.
And so this exercise to get you to learn how date formatting works and by researching or reverse engineering,
how this data input works, you'll be able to understand how formatting works with that component and
apply that to this component over here.
And so what?
So let's open up the challenge here.
OK, so here we are in the challenge, and as you could see, we have some material UI components being
rendered and we have some, you know, a date picture being rendered, of course, as well.
And here's the date pick our keyboard date picker.
And so, as you could see, this is the material UI date picture.
And if you go and highlight that, you could see where it's imported here.
It's from material UI pictures.
So that's your first clue into what?
To research.
So our objective here, again, is to figure out how this date pictures, formatting so that we can
use the formatter over here.
So this is the chip.
So this is what we are and this is what we need to modify.
Right.
Currently, we're going to.
So currently it's using selected date.
So that's our first clue.
Let's go up here.
This is react use state.
Right.
So this is our state for this date.
So we're initializing it with a new date.
Now, this is going to be a native JavaScript date.
So you can research this by just searching for date JavaScript.
This is just the native JavaScript object.
So this this doesn't really give you a lot of formatting tools.
Right.
So this isn't a good.
So you could use the functions here and format the date manually.
But we have date formatting libraries to do this for us.
So that's kind of what you could look into, what material UI is using as a date formatting tool and
then kind of copy that.
And that's how we're going to do.
So if we go here, you could see that the date, the JavaScript date is the state.
So that's what we're we're actually storing the data.
And this is good.
You don't want to store the date has a string.
You want to store it as the actual date object.
And if we go down here, we could see that we are currently just calling to string.
So as you could see here, I think date should have to string here and it returns the string representing
the date object.
So that's what we're doing.
So we're using the date and we're just using a string here that's not formatted and we want to change
this.
So this is really the only line we're going to touch to finish this challenge.
But in order to get there, we have to do a little bit of research.
So it's good practice always to just research what you're dealing with when you see some code like this.
And so what we want to do here is now you could first you could search this library here, but it's
just easier to just search for material UI date picture like this.
So you search for this because we want to know, like, well, what is this using for format?
Right.
Like if I do this, you can then you'll end up here.
So if I do, this is another page that comes up.
Right.
So this is this is really the main page.
You want to go to the date time pictures page on material, UI, pictures, components, pictures.
So this is the actual component we're using in our app.
Right.
Material UI pictures.
And if we go expand this, you could see our exact component is here, right?
That's called keyboard date picture.
Right.
That's the one we're rendering here and that's the one we are rendering in this example as well.
Now that so we found an example that does this right.
But we didn't find we don't have an example of how they use the formatting outside of the date picture.
Right.
And that's what we need to keep researching.
So what is this?
So this is a separate package.
So this is actually a completely separate package that we can open up.
And again, this is not obvious from this, but, you know, going down here, this is the native date
picture.
So this is so this is not what we need.
This is different component all together.
So there isn't any more information here about dates.
Right.
So this is not obvious, but this opens up into this library over here.
This is called material UI pictures.
So this is the library, a special library built for material UI.
And we can learn a little bit about this now, just high level.
We could see it provides this.
And then, as you could see here, any date management library designed to be efficient or zero effort
compatible with moment date functions, luxon and deejay's.
Now, you don't know what all of these libraries are yet, but you are you have a clue into a date management
library.
And so what this is actually using is so go now.
Nothing else is as useful here on this homepage so we can go to get started.
But basically here you could see again material UI pictures was designed to use with the date management
library of your choice.
So here at this point, you should say, well, what is a date management library?
Which one?
Should we use what does that do?
Does that help me format, right.
And if we go, we could see moment James is one and here you could see the format with.
So they have formatting utilities.
Right.
You could see this is basically the main thing.
If you go to their website, this is like one of the main hallmarks of this is that it helps you format
dates.
And similarly, date functions is going to be another utility library that provides manipulating dates
in the browser.
So, again, formatting is like the main thing that you're going to use here.
And so, yeah, that that's basically it, you could read more about this, but so now we know what
date management library is and how it's being used sort of with this date picture library.
So the date picture library is using a date management library to format the date.
So this is a this is a library just for date pictures, right?
It's not a library for formatting dates, but it uses a date formatting library.
And so now we know that we could see that they tell you how to set it up in your app.
And this is your first clue here.
Another clue, which is date functions, utils here.
So they pass in that.
So as you could see, tell the peckers which date management library it should use with the provider.
So, you know, react provider's context.
They you you wrap your app with this and then you won't you know, this this date picker knows what
date management library to use.
OK, so we know that material UI material, UI pictures, utils provider uses this data manipulation
library here.
And then if we go to usage we could see that it says choose your library.
So as you can see again, it's the same same example.
Right, we have the utility library here.
All right.
So now we can go back to our example.
We know that this provider's here.
And so let's go ahead and see if we have that.
And we do.
We have this provider here and you could see we are using the same one.
And the examples date functions, utils.
So if we go up, we could see it's date date functions.
Now I want to get into date IO, but basically at Wrap's data is a wrapper around all these utilities
to make the same, to make the functions the same.
And but then you could see here we have date functions, utils and then you could see over here we're
using, we're importing from date functions so.
This is a clue that I left in, so we hover over format, you could see format is declared, but its
value is never read.
So I included this in here as a clue as like, hey, you should be using this format function here.
And that's what we could use.
Right.
So we can use this function from day functions.
Now, we can research date functions a little bit more to understand how they actually format.
And if you go here and to date functions, this is their home page.
But if you search date functions, format, search for that.
You can see here that this is right in their docks, there's a page all about formating, and if we
search for a format, you could see that they are importing format here.
And then if we see usage, you can see right here on their main getting started page.
So this, you know, isn't really that obscure of an example, right.
We're just formatting a date to accommodate format.
And this is the solution right here.
Basically, we need to use the format function from date functions to format the date, and that's basically
it.
Now, you could accomplish this challenge by using a different date, format and library.
But the completed state is to use this format function that's already imported here.
And you're going to import that right here and you're going to use that right down here.
So if we go here to, again, the format examples right here, you could see they use this and then
they pass in the formatting string right here.
And this is the string that we want to format.
This is the pattern that we're going to tell it to match.
And you could see all kinds of different patterns there.
Like if you go to format here, you could see all kinds of different examples.
So you could get any of these types of outputs if you wanted to.
So the solution is to use the format function here and get rid of this two string because we want the
raw JavaScript date, right, and then pass in the formatting string and then close the parentheses
like that.
And then there we go.
Now, the chip has the formatted date.
And if we change the date, you could see the chip correctly updates.
So that's it.
I hope you learned a little bit about formatting date and material, you idiot pictures.