All right, so for this challenge 25, you need to help this person with getting their vehicle entry
form to work properly, and so please see if you can fix the following issues.
So basically, our first kind of objective is to try and reproduce this issue set that we're given here.
So below here, this is the car entry form and we're just going to go and read through some of these
issues that this person pointed out with this form.
So first it says the form doesn't let me submit and always shows please enter a value.
Please make sure all fields are required except for condition which is not or which is optional.
So it says it doesn't.
Let me submit.
So clearly if I click this, so maybe let's try typing in a few things and I click this, and as you
could see, nothing is submitted.
And if we go up, it says it always shows please on our value.
So it always shows, please enter our value.
If I go here, you could see even even though I'm typing a value, the value is actually I'm still getting
this error that says please enter a value.
So it says, please make sure all fields are required except for condition which is optional.
So condition is should be the only field that's optional.
OK, and we can look at start looking at some clues here that tell us certain things.
For example, Condition has an asterisk here, which may indicate that it's currently in a state of
being required.
But that's just my hunch from looking at this.
But I can see clearly that the please enter a value is validation error that seems to be failing.
And so my objective here, high level, is to fix that validation error and then, of course, go ahead
and actually submit.
Right.
It doesn't look like it's confirming that submission at all.
So that's our step kind of after that, because if we are constantly getting validation errors, we'll
never get to our submit.
Right.
And so our validation errors are incorrect.
We have a value and we're being told that we need to enter a value.
And if we go up and type in on more of these, you can see that that is the case for all of them.
So please enter a value appears regardless of whether you have a value, that's the main issue.
So next, it says if a field has a validation error, please remove the error after I start typing.
So as you could see here a lot of times and forms like this, when you start typing, the error should
then go away indicating that you have fixed that that error.
Now, right after submitting, I want the vehicles to be listed in the table below.
So we have to get that submit to work first and then we're going to expect to see the vehicles appear
in this what looks like a table here below.
So that is the part three, part four.
It says after submitting, please clear the form.
So when you submit, you would expect these to go away.
The text entered to go away.
And when first loading the form or after submitting, I want to focus the first TextField.
So seems like they want some type of focused functionality that automatically happens.
Right.
So you could see here when I'm in it, it's focused.
There's a focused style around that.
That's what that means.
And you could research that if you weren't sure.
But the correct terminology here is focus.
This is what indicates that this input is currently being active.
And Tab's typically to, you know, change the focus of the elements.
But that's just a side note.
So that sounds like we have a good chunk of problems to work on now.
So let's go ahead and open up our sandbox to start looking at the code.
All right.
So as you can see here, I'm in the code sandbox now for a challenge.
Twenty five.
And if I scroll down here, I can just look at some of the code.
You could see here that we have a function here, validation text fields is the component.
We have some styling, we have a lot of material UI imports being added in here.
So that's a good clue to start looking into what we're going to be working with.
Your main component here is going to be the TextField.
Going down, we have a style here, this just looks like some boilerplate styles that we might not need
to adjust for this specific challenge going down here we have.
The initialization of react you state and some styles, we have a validate function, so that's a good
clue.
It has errors, a submit function, an update value function and then a bunch of markup.
So you could see we are looping over fields and we are rendering a textfield.
So that is the form, as you can see with the form here.
And then going down, we have a grid which represents our vehicle table and vehicle table.
Looks like it's imported up here from that vehicle table.
So that is a good clue that we have another file here that as the table and going up.
You may just want to glance at the other file in here.
Maybe you did.
That is the field options.
So the field options here is just looks like the fields, right?
The field configuration or the JSON object that has the parameters or options for rendering our form.
So.
That's a good clue.
So now let's go ahead and try and address that first issue.
If we go back, first issue is going to be the form doesn't let me submit and always shows please our
right.
So what?
So the first thing I want to think about is what's actually happening here.
Right when I'm clicking the submit button, that's that's really the first thing that happens.
Right.
So that is your first clue to try to research this component specifically.
Now, it's not that difficult, you know, in this size app to find where the submit button is.
So to do that, usually you can just control F and then search for submit and you'll see that button
shows up right here.
So and then you can also see that there's a function called simit.
So there's a button here and then there's a function on click and then that goes up to here.
So this is the callback for that.
And this, as you could see, this just was here.
I found this.
I didn't have to look very far to find out the problem code.
Right.
So validate.
So that's the first thing that gets called that.
If I scroll up is a function that's up here and this is a function which sets fields.
So sets fields is I highlight that.
I can see that it's used up here as the used state.
So it's setting the fields right.
So I can guess that the fields are what I'm actually that, you know, is the data for these UI elements.
And so I'm using a state of the field options.
And you can remember we just looked at the field options.
Those are being passed in as the initial state for fields.
So that's kind of a run through of fields.
Now, fields are then used here to reduce.
So reduce right here.
If you're not familiar with this, we can research that.
But basically it just basically crunches down the object or merges all of the loops into one object,
which is here.
So it starts out as an empty object.
And then you get the current field.
That's the.
So we're we're reducing all the fields down.
That's what appears to be happening.
Right.
So because we know that the default field object is this, which looks like just JSON object, right.
Or just a JavaScript, plain old JavaScript object.
Right.
This is the field.
So this is going to be our main data model here for this UI component.
So it's going to be just a string JSON object here with the keys being of the field keys.
Right.
So make the vehicle, make the model.
These are keys inside of this object.
So what is happening here is it's reducing down the fields into a new object that's setting on the app
with Satterfield's.
OK, so set fields' sets that new object.
So you always want to make sure that you're keeping the objects the same.
It's it's quite difficult to do this if you're not familiar.
So I didn't have to do that because it's it's kind of challenging to reduce this down.
It's not it's it's very difficult.
So because you have to know about how to use the the spread operators correctly and do that dynamically
as well.
So if you're if you found this name of this key, you would we're setting the remerging, the current
field object here with a new object or a new key override.
So let's say that there was a make or vehicle make.
Right this this would previously have a make up here, like the old make value.
So and then here we are overwriting even that.
So this is the current field.
Right.
And then we're just overriding that with a new key and value pairs, which are, well, just one key
and values here.
So.
Attributes is the current value attribute.
So this is another thing that's a bit confusing is object of entries creates a key value pair iterating
over a group of arrays.
So let me show you what that looks like in the console.
So if we go here in the console, I can just type in I'm going to just kind of set a variable, let
X equal A one, B to C three, OK?
And then we could do object entries.
Ex.
All right, so I'm getting a reference error here, and I'm not sure why, so I'm just going to jump
out into the actual app here, open up the Chrome console here, and then go to console here where I
am sure that this will work.
So const X equals A one B to C, three object entries X.
As you could see, it's three arrays, so entries is going to give you an array back an array of arrays
where each array is the key and the first element and the value in the second element.
Think about this as a for loop for an object.
Right.
An object has a key and a value for each of the key value pairs there.
And it's not easy to loop over the object.
Right.
You could do values, which gets the values of that object, object of values, and you could do object
keys to get the keys of that object in an array.
But what if you wanted to loop over both at the same time?
That's where entries comes into play.
Now, using those entries, we're going to destructor off of that.
So I'm structuring I'm saying give me your name, give me your attributes.
And this is just it could be anything I could put x y in here.
The structuring works by just assigning that similar to react you state.
Right.
You're d structuring off of this you state thing that's returned, which is an array.
You want just the first and second value.
So you're naming the key.
So that's the key name and then the attributes of that.
So by this loop, what we're doing here, this loop here is looping over and giving us the key and values
of the fields.
Where the key, the field name and the field values or the field pairs of attributes for that field,
so each field is going to be an object that looks like this, which has some information on it.
Right.
The label the for the form which gets set down there.
So if we go down here, we could see we actually loop over those fields down here and we structure off
of that.
So similarly, we're going to do that again.
We're going to do object entries down here and we're going to say, here's the key and here's the value.
And then we Destructoid off of those actual attributes.
So so that's that's sort of a very long winded way of explaining how this loop works, at the end of
the day, we're just going to merge a new object into our fields.
So what does that new object it's going to be for each key?
We're just basically setting that error.
Right.
And it looks like we're always setting this error correct.
Like we have an error and then we're always setting that and then we spread that over for that field.
So that's how we turn this object into another object that has errors everywhere.
OK, so if when I hit submit, you'll see errors go on every single field right now, what happens if
I comment out this error here?
So if I comment this out and I go ahead and go back and refresh.
You'll see now.
As I hit submit.
Nothing happens, so there's no errors.
Everything is the same.
So this is how we set the error every time.
So what the objective here was for you to do was to actually.
Only throw this error when appropriate, and what you could do is you could take those current attributes
for that field destruction structure, the value off which if you look and research about value, you
know that each field has a value on it.
And you wouldn't know that unless you read the on change handler and the change handler simply adds
the value.
So, you know, vet listeners, if you remember some of the other lectures, Iida, target value or
destruction off of that, setting it on the fields.
So each field.
We're setting that value of that current field that we selected or we entered in text, so that's how
we update the value.
So what you could do here is just check if that value is there, right?
Or if it's not there.
So if there's no value, we're going to want to throw that error.
So let's see if that worked.
I'm going to type some text in here and then I'm going to type some text in here and then I'm going
to submit and you could see attributes is not defined.
So we actually can't do this because we need the attributes.
We need the other attributes of that field.
And I think you can actually structure the rest of them.
Off of that, but we're going to keep it easy and we're just going to say.
But we're just going to keep it easy and.
We're going to change this back to attributes, but we're going to structure off of attributes here,
so we're going to say Konsta value equals attributes like that, and then we're going to use the value
the same way.
So let's go back and change this.
So now let's go ahead and look at this and see if this works.
Great.
So as you could see, it was that easy to just validate these fields by checking the value, so we checked
the value and we only throw that error if there is a value or if there's no value.
So.
There you go.
So that kind of fixes the first issue a bit, right?
So we have to now move on to this part, which says make sure that all fields are required except for
the condition which is optional.
So.
As you could see here, we have condition and this field should not be required.
So if I type in this, I want to basically I want this this current state to be I don't want there to
be an error here.
I want this to not throw an error when despite of there being a value or not.
Right.
So that means this code here would still throw if there was no value for condition.
And because condition is not required, I can bypass this error.
So we're going to just throw another attribute in here.
As you can see, we already have required being true set here on this configuration.
So we're going to go ahead and change required to be false on the condition we're still setting this
error, regardless of whether it's required or not.
And so all you have to do is just pull required off of the attributes and check that it is required.
Right.
And it's required.
So this is only happening if there is a required attribute.
OK.
So.
Now, let's see what happens when we try to type in some fields.
So as you could see, the condition no longer throws a validation here.
So moving on, I can just want to look at this area that that's happening here, and you could see it's
changing in uncontrolled input of type text to be controlled.
And we have a warning failed pop type.
So this is just some information here.
Looks like it's just warnings.
It's not actually affecting our app.
So we can address those at a later point going down.
All right.
So now it seems like we've completed this first thing except for the fact that it doesn't let me submit.
So, OK, so now I just want to submit an actual valid form.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to type in these here.
Remember, we didn't actually submit a valid form yet because we were always throwing errors.
But now we should be in a good state where we should pass.
This has error functionality here, right?
Because you can see here on Submit, we are checking if there's errors and we've always had errors as
of now.
So let's go ahead and submit.
And as you could see, we got rid of the errors.
So that's a new thing.
We got rid of errors.
And what else do we do?
We were no longer showing the errors and that's about it.
That's all we did.
We just got rid of the errors.
So what you could see here is how did we do that?
What did we do to get rid of the errors?
Well, we got rid of the errors because when you call validate, it actually will set the error back
to null.
So if there is if the value is suddenly required, this error will then or there actually is a value
in there.
But there was an error on it.
So let's clear this one out and I'll show you what I mean.
There's an error on this attribute right now.
Right.
But this error doesn't go away.
When I start typing, it goes away when I had submit because I went into this function and set the error
back to null.
That's really important to know.
So you're realizing that we're we're kind of secretly setting this.
We're in we're actually validating errors again and setting we're clearing the errors out effectively.
Right.
So when I hit submit, it's clearing the errors out.
So that's not really what you would think of as a submission, though, right?
We want to actually end up adding the records and clearing out these fields to add more records.
So.
That's sort of the state of where what this app is doing at this point in time.
All right, so we're going to move on to the next one, which is if a field has a validation error,
please remove the error after I start typing.
So we just went over how setting the error to null gets rid of the error.
We never actually talked about why that is, though.
So if we go down here, we could see the error is put on the TextField.
Now, what is the TextField?
The TextField is a material UI component, right.
So let's go ahead and search for that material UI TextField and we'll come to this page, which is the
material UI Web site.
And as you could see, we have, you know, all the components on the left and everything in the API
section is going to give you all the props that you could use.
So under the hood, what happens is this is composed of a bunch of other smaller elements.
So it's an abstraction that combines a bunch of elements together.
One of those elements just happens to be the form helper text.
The formal vertex is the error, basically.
So we go down here.
The error is right here, if true, the label will be displayed in an error state.
To go back, we could see that let's just set the air to true or whatever, we are actually setting
the error incorrectly here.
This is one of the validation errors that we get.
So this is just something that we can fix.
So it's it's being supplied.
It's an invalid prop.
So we're currently passing in that error, which in the case of a issue is a string.
So the errors should actually be a true statement.
So we can define the error as a string in our own app.
But when we pass that into the third party library, we want to make sure we're abiding by their rules.
So we're just going to say error, true or false, and now we're changing that to be a boolean now.
So now let's see when we have a validation error, we're no longer getting those warnings right.
So we just fixed that warning, which is cool.
We're getting another excellent thing over here, which is OK, that's fine.
We can we know that field isn't defined in this one part, and that's OK.
OK, so something else that we didn't mention was that condition actually has an asterisk next to it.
And the reason that is, is because we're actually setting every field and material uses TextField to
be true.
So instead of doing that, we're just going to actually d structure the required parameter here.
So if we go back to material uses TextField API, you'll see that if I go down here to required, if
true, this label will be displayed as required and the input element will be required.
So basically it's going to set this asterisk here.
So and I could show you that by putting this required here and then now the asterisk goes away.
So that really completes the the condition part.
But the part that we're trying to do right now is the Taiping.
Right.
So the typing needs to get rid of the validation errors.
So as I'm typing, I should be able to get those errors to go away as I'm typing.
Now we know that setting the error to null does that.
But if I go to the update value function, this is where we are updating that value, if you remember.
So we go up here and as you can see, this is the name of the field.
Right.
And then these are the attributes and this is where we set that value.
So what we can do is we can just always set the error to to be null.
So in that attribute, the error is going to be null when we update the value.
Now, let's see if that worked.
And it did so as I type, I'm getting rid of the error, setting the original, the errors going back
into here and being set as a boolean in material wise TextField and the error property, we didn't read
that yet.
The error property over here, if true, the label will be displayed in an error state.
So that's what that does.
So we're learning a little bit about the library and were correctly making sure we're tracing that state
down into our app and we're making sure that we set the proper things when we want to.
So when we update the value by typing or change of any kind, that callback is being run with the current
value.
We're updating the current value, but we're also clearing the error of that field out.
That completes part to.
All right, so we are on part three now where after submitting, we want the vehicles to be listed in
the table below.
So if we go back down here to the table, you could see that we are already passing in the this object
called vehicles.
This array called vehicles.
Right.
So vehicles up here, we're initializing it to be an empty array.
And then we have a setter called set vehicles, so.
We're just going to first look and see where set vehicles is being called, if it is called and it looks
like it is right.
But there's only one problem we're not adding any of our fields on here, so that's the main issue with
this.
As I set out to submit a form, even though the validation passes, nothing happens because we're setting
it to be the same thing as it already is, which is an empty array.
So this is actually pretty simple.
We're going to do is we're just going to create a new array around that with the spread operator around
the current vehicles and the new vehicle.
What's the new vehicle going to be?
It's going to be fields.
So fields exactly what we already have here, right here.
So you could make sure to set a new object if you want to like this.
So just to make sure if you want to only, you know, send certain data into the vehicles, you can
do this.
We're just going to spread this to make sure it's not the exact same object.
But we're going to do this.
And just like that, if we now submit, you could see we get a vehicle posted here.
So now, as you could see here, I'm submitting and I get to go down here.
We get this, which is two children with the same key.
So another clue, and that's pretty much it, just a bunch of warnings with that same thing.
So if we go up here.
We're getting children with the same key.
We'll look at that shortly if we go down here to this, you could see that.
If we go up.
We go up here.
We'll stay on target with our issue, which is that we want to actually clear out this form.
So I think at this point we've actually did do this part.
We've submitted the vehicle by adding it onto the array.
The next thing we need to do is clear the form.
So clearing a form.
So what does that mean?
Well, if you know about Satterfield's at this point, you should know that that would mean clearing
out those properties.
Right.
So clearing out that object would be one way of doing it.
But an even easier way of doing it is to just do the initial thing that we're doing here.
We're setting the state to be and spread.
So a copy of this.
Object here, which this is the default state, so we just want to reset to the default state, so I
have to do is just set fields and we're just going to set that fields to be the field options.
So to do that, we're simply just going to add a new line over here and we're going to say set fields
like this and then we're just going to paste in the fields or field options like that.
So now let's see if that works.
That works, so it looks like when I when I submit now, if I correctly validate the fields.
It clears them.
So what we're actually said on those fields, it was the value and it was the.
Right, so we set the value, we may have set the error at one point, but the point is we set the slate
clean when we set it to this object.
So with that, we are done with this one.
Now, let's go on to the final one.
When loading the form or after submitting, I want to focus the first TextField.
So what does that mean?
It means this.
We want this state to be the automatic state when we reload the page.
But how would you do that?
You might be wondering, right?
Do I have to force a click?
Do I have to force a tab?
Like what do I have to do to get this to happen?
Well, you probably could do that where you click on this element using a DOM hack.
But what's even easier is to just think about it in terms of what material you I have this functionality
already so you could do is like search for focus on here, for example.
That's one way of doing it.
But the point is, we wanted this to just be the default state.
So let's search for focus on here.
And you'll see the first thing that comes up is autofocus, if true, the input element will be focused
during the first mount.
So that sounds like it could be it.
So if we go here, that's all we have for focus.
So let's try that.
It's a boolean and it's default to be false.
So if we just set it on here.
So a focus is the last one, so you might be asking, well, what's happening there?
Well, if you go up, see.
So not that I have not that I know exactly what's going on in material wise library, but I can make
the hunch that it's setting autofocus on every single field and only one can be focused at once.
And so it ends up just focusing on the last one because it's saying, oh, focus me, focus me, focus
me all the way down to the last one.
So we want to only focus something here with the actual we only want to focus the vehicle make right.
So what we can do is we can go into our object and set auto focus to be true.
And then if we go here, all we have to do is d structure off of this.
And then once again, we can just say autofocus.
True, false.
So now let's see what happens when we refresh the page.
So there we go.
So when we refresh the page automatically focuses that and now let's see what happens when we start
typing and then we submit and it clears it and it focuses the first one again.
So this was just a cool example that I did to just kind of get you familiar with material UI forms,
tables, validation properties, researching APIs, tracking state.
Right, doing doing some resetting of state, getting a little bit hairy in terms of, you know, some
logical statements here and trying to understand this one.
And so I hope this is a good example to get you started on building apps with material UI.
So thanks and see you in the next one.