All right, so four, challenge three, it's very similar to challenge two in that the app is just crashing
and we have to fix the bug now.
Once again, this is made easy by the fact that we get that error right here.
And we could just read this error to understand what's going on.
And as you could see here, the error is pretty descriptive.
So it's telling us that the objects are not valid as react child's react children.
And it's it's given it says it's found this object with these with this keys, if you meant to render
a collection of children, use an array instead.
So I wouldn't say this.
This really tells you what is going wrong in our app.
It looks like what we're trying to do is render this name of this person in our app.
And we're failing at doing that, so the error is is not really telling us how to fix that, right.
It's just kind of telling us what's wrong.
So as you can see what you know, what we could do is we could read this error.
We could see, you know, we could we could read it.
We could try and understand it ourselves.
But first, let's just make sure that it's actually happening in our app.
Right.
So trace that stack, trace down and we see it's happening at Applegate's line six.
So and you could see here, it's also Happe is being rendered from this file here.
So you can you can understand that this is happening in our app.
So it's happening in Apgar's.
This is Apgar's.
Right.
So you can see here.
So this is our this is our code and it is happening on line six.
So that's how you would find this exact line that's causing that issue now to dive in deeper.
This is definitely a react error.
So if I go into the console, as you could see, we are getting the error coming from so tracing it
down well.
So the error is being caused by this, by our app, but it's being raised in from this app.
So it's it's actually throwing that error from react Dom.
So you can make that assumption.
If you've never seen react before, you've never used react apps before, you'd be able to understand
as an advanced user that this is coming from React Dobb.
So this is how you're an expert in Web development.
You still could figure this out just by understanding, OK, this is I'm tracing this into the react
on library.
Now, you could do you could so sort of debug this further.
You could you could search for this, throw on an invalid object type.
But what's going to really help you, it's going to be more obvious is if you just Google the this exact
error.
Right.
So if I Google objects are not valid as react child.
OK, so I've Googled that error message and I see here this first snippet.
Seeing an objects are not valid as Riak child might mean that a few different things are going on.
It could be because the items are being rendered in the JFK element are objects instead of primitives.
So we're understanding that it's an object and not a primitive.
So if you're not familiar with a primitive, you could also Google that.
But basically you probably know the solution at this point.
Primitive.
It should be either a string or a number.
Right, instead of an object.
So using this, we were able to Google this error and figure out that you shouldn't be passing objects
in your.
So at this point, you should know what JSF is.
If you don't, you should definitely look that up.
But basically the key thing here is that we know what we know what the issue is now.
We shouldn't be passing in objects in here.
And so we have to look for where is the primitive object, which is where where is the primitive variable
here?
And that's name text.
So if I open up that code sandbox here, I can just.
Better see this issue, so if I go here and I just say I could structure this instead, so I could say
you could structure text off of that object.
And put that here and then that way we can fix the issue, so another thing I could have done was if
I roll this back, I could have said name text to get that string.
So there we go.