All right, hello.
And this video, we are going to be talking about the Web kit inspector, so if you're a JavaScript
developer or react developer, you need to know about the webcam inspector, because it's going to help
you a lot when you're debugging your apps, not even just debugging issues, but kind of just seeing
how the app works, looking into various performance things, seeing the network tab, seeing your logs,
viewing source code, putting breakpoints in source code, pretty much anything to do with looking into
how your app works.
You're going to need the webcam inspector, and you need to and you're going to need to know pretty
much most of the things I'm going to show you today in order to be really productive.
So with that, we'll just kind of get started with this.
So you could see Hiraman, just a basic code sandbox here.
And I'm just pulling up the webcam inspector.
So to pull this guy up, you can use the hotkey.
John Mac, it's going to be command option J.
And if you're on Windows, I think it's control shift J.
So that's going to pop up this guy right here.
And this is going to be your Web kit, Inspector.
So we're just going to take a tour through of this.
But before we do that, I just want to point out something you could see here.
I have it in this popped out mode.
You might get it sort of put on the side of your app.
So that's a good thing to first kind of talk about is over on the top, right?
You can actually just see some of the options for this webcam, inspector.
So you could see here the thing that we're going to first talk about is this doc so you could control
where it actually docks on your page.
So you could see here I have it popped out onto a supper window.
You may find it more useful for one of these.
And actually, I at some point rotated between three of these, depending on what type of app you're
working on.
So let me show you what that looks like.
If I click Dock to Bottom, what that's going to do is just kind of put it on the bottom of my page
just like this.
Now, this might be useful if you need if you just want it there and you're just playing with your app
and you just want to go in and see some logs, this is where you're going to have it.
And I think this is pretty useful for that.
If you are looking to debug HTML, that's when you're going to want to go and then you're going to just
move this a little bit and you're going to want to go to this top.
Right.
And we're going to switch up here and then we're going to change it to dock to the right.
So and then we just can kind of move it around like this and then just have it over here on the right.
And what we're going to do, why we do, why we would do that is so that we could actually look at the
military here.
So this is a better view of seeing it, seeing more basically vertical space that you can look at various
HTML elements.
So that's why you would have it like that now if you were now, why?
Why would you have it popped out?
So let's say you had a lot of debugging that you wanted to do.
Maybe you wanted to look at like a full source of some JavaScript or something or some HTML.
And you you were doing some pretty serious debugging where a lot of times if you have to look at like
a lot of HTML, you would then just sort of maximized that like this.
And let's say you you wanted also to be able to look at all the CFS panel on the right here.
If you're doing like really serious debugging, that's when you would, you know, pop it out and then
just have that out here so that you could really take a big look at all of this.
So that's kind of the three scenarios that you would rotate between where this thing is going to go
in your app.
I just kind of explain that.
So for our sake, since we're talking about this Web inspector today, we're going to leave it in the
popped out scenario.
So with that, let's keep moving on.
So next thing is, let's just go right into the the elements tab here.
So the first tab.
OK, so now we're looking at the elements tab here.
And this is going to be you probably already know what this is.
This is basically just the HTML that's running on your page.
So this is the end result.
HTML this is not going to show you react elements.
For that, you would need to add in the react components extension, which we'll talk about in one of
the next lectures.
But in this video, we're just going to basically give you a brief overview of this tab here for the
elements.
So let's see if we can just sort of select one of those react elements in our scene.
So if we go over here, what typically the use cases, if you want to see what success is being applied
here.
Right.
So as you can see in this code sandbox, if we go to the styles that CSFs that's in this root or this
default create react, we could just add in special access class.
That's like my class.
And then in here, what we're going to do is we're just going to set the color to be blue.
So then we jump on over to say that I would jump on over to our app and then we could use that CSFs
class here and let's just say a div.
So we just put an.
Div with a class being the my class.
Actually, that's not a class, that's an I.D. So let's just change that to be a period here.
So that's a class.
And then we go back and we made that our class and then we do this and then we just say Hello Blue.
So then we have that blue text here.
OK, so now let's say you want to see how to actually or what styles are being applied on this element.
Right?
Do you maybe you have an issue where you need to change this color or whatever.
So how do you actually know?
How do you trace back that class?
This is a good use case for this element's top.
So as you could see, if we if we.
Right.
Click if we.
Click this element here.
And we click, inspect, it will pop, it will pop up that element right in our elements tab here.
So then going into this, if we click on that element, you could see then on the right we have a Styles
tab here.
So Styles tab, computed tab and then event listeners, are they like the sub tabs in this window here
for this elements tab?
So we click on that and then you could see all the cows that supply there.
So you could see here we have my class.
This is being applied and you have that color being applied there.
And if you go up here, this is just some one off styles that you can add in if you want.
This is sort of like an optional thing to add in or test new styles.
So if I you know, if I wanted to go up here and actually, you know, change this, if I wanted to
change this style up here, if I wanted to say color green and then I go down here and I could see that
that actually changes it, but it doesn't add in any code or anything.
I didn't modify any of the code here.
All I'm doing is just giving myself the ability to add in new styles on top of the existing ones.
Now, another thing that's really useful is the computed tab.
So with the computer tab, if I go up here, I can actually see all the CSFs that's applied to that
element and I can go and look and see where that came from.
So if I click on this, I can click on color and I could look and see, oh, the color comes from my
class.
So if you have something with like a ton of classes and you have no idea where that class is or it's
really confusing, you can just go right to this computer tab and just find the style property that
you want.
And then you can go and see where that class came from or where that.
Yeah, where the CSFs came from came from this class.
And then where did the class come from?
It came from this stylesheet over here.
So that's where you can go and click on that stylesheet and then go and actually see the actual file,
which is really useful too.
So that's going to save you some time into debugging this.
And we went from looking at a Web site to finding the CFS file that has that Silin.
It is not cool.
So very useful stuff that it's very important to know.
So moving on, if we go back over here, we can then look at some of the other tabs in this inspector,
so we just looked at where the sources tab.
Now we're going to move on over to the console tab.
So this is where you can see your logs in addition to actually running your own JavaScript and seeing
variables.
So if I go over here and I go back to the code sandbox, you could see I do have a log that I've added
in here.
Now, I can also just add in a variable that's like const X equals, you know, hello world.
And then I can put that in my app somewhere and just put like hello text.
And then I could go over here and I could just put that in here.
I could just say hello text.
OK, and now that who would say that worked, right?
So save this.
And yeah, that work, so now what I'm going to show you is, OK, well, we have this log here that's
logged in the console.
And another thing that we have that log there and then let's say I want to actually see the value of
hello text.
This is where we get into breakpoints.
So and I'm going to show you what this console tab can do when you're actually in a breakpoint.
You can type variables that are at the current scope of the breakpoint.
So actually, first thing that I'm going to show you in the console tab is actually to just running
arbitrary JavaScript so I can be like const.
Hello equals five three, and then I could just be like, hello, and then it's going to be that variable.
Another thing that I do all the time is if I want to just see an array function or something, I'll
be like const array equals one, two, three, just to get that array there.
And then I'm like, OK, what's the function for filter?
And I'm like a radar filter.
And then I know that that's a function.
And then I could just run a quick filter function on this and I'll say and is greater than two.
And then just like that I just did a little filter function just to show myself, OK, that's how filter
works.
And then I would go and put, you know, this code in my code base after, you know, I've debug that
a little bit, which is also really useful.
So few are actually in your code base and you're actually looking at some object or something.
You can really easily just know, you know, what what you can not only, you know, see what that variable
is, but you can, like, run JavaScript on it in the console, which is very useful.
So lot we could talk about with the console.
You know, this is where errors are.
This is where you can you could clear the console.
This you can you can just I don't do any of this stuff.
I don't do I don't really mess with this too much.
I don't like to change the, you know, change the type of errors or anything like that appear here.
That's not really something that I do that often.
So basically, what I just showed you is pretty much now moving on to the sources panel.
This is a panel that you're in all the time also.
And the most common thing that you would do here is actually find the file that you're operating in
and then put a breakpoint in.
So if we go back to our scene.
We we know that we have this app, Jacir, so there's an app.
And so what you would do is he can actually find that file in the webcam, inspector.
So if you go here in the webcam inspector and you go to control P, this is like something that completely
blew my mind the first time that I found it.
So if you do abduct Jaycee, you can then find that file.
So you're going to see two things here.
The source map one and the regular one.
You're going to want to click on the source map one, because this is going to be the the react code,
basically.
So it's easy to read.
It's just like in your text editor, it's not like compiled code or anything.
And then you can put a breakpoint in here.
And this is pretty finicky.
I mean, it does stuff that you don't expect, like it puts breakpoints everywhere sometimes.
And that's, you know, not not great.
I mean, I think it's is actually putting multiple break points in here at certain times.
So if we if we just get rid of some of these or we can just leave those in and you can actually go over
here and if you want to, you can go on the side.
And then you could see sort of the the function stack, the call stack, you could see the breakpoints
here.
So it should show you where the breakpoints are.
So let me refresh this thing.
Maybe if I refresh it, I'll show you.
So if I refresh that app, then.
OK, those went away, so if I do this and then I go back, put that breakpoint there, I go back to
my code sandbox, if I just hit refresh on this here.
That should trigger that breakpoint, so that breakpoint is now hit.
So.
We're in the code sandbox again, and now I want to show you, if we go back to the console tab, if
you type in actually see the scope of where you are, so you see hello text.
And just like that, I'm typing out something here.
So now if you want to, you know, write some JavaScript around this, you want to split it by characters
or something like that, you could do that.
And just a good way to just see some JavaScript, what that does, that not variable.
Now, I'm here in this breakpoint.
I'm in this scope.
So you're only going to be able to see variables that are defined here.
So if I had a variable defined after this, I wouldn't be able to hover over it.
But with this yellow text, I can hover over it and see what it is so I could see it's equal to Hello
World.
So this is extremely useful.
This is basically how you debug things 90 percent of the time you're going to be doing this.
I don't really recommend going into the code base and putting the word debugger.
I used to do that.
I think, you know, you can write like the word debugger in here and that's going to do the same thing
if you really can't find the file.
This is what we would do before you could just go in the webcam specter and find the file before like
source maps.
You know, you had no idea where this code was running and you could not there was no chance of you
finding it.
You would just put in a debugger like this.
But because you can easily find the file with the source maps, there's really it's just way easier
to just find this file rather than putting debugger statements in your code base, which you don't want
to even.
So anyway, we found the file and now we put a breakpoint there.
And what we're going to do now is, you know, you could step through, you could step over to the next
function call, you can step into it.
So if you're if you're about to run a function, you could do that.
You can, you know, step over.
You can continue the execution altogether.
You're no longer paused in the script.
Now, over here on the right, you could see we have the break point here.
You can right click over here and it doesn't show you.
Let me just get over here again.
So if I go over here and I right click it's going to show you you can actually you could remove the
breakpoint.
You could disable all break points.
So if you have a bunch of break points, you could just click remove all break points and there's dom
breakpoints.
There's a vent.
Listeners will get in all that later.
This is kind of high level overview of the usefulness of the sources tab.