Welcome to React Beginner Challenges, 25 debugging exercises from React School.
Welcome to the course.
Thank you for enrolling.
I'm so excited to welcome you to this course and I just want to say that I'm here to help you succeed.
So feel free to ask questions on any of these lectures.
First of all, I'd like to just go over the course structure so the course is divided into two sections,
the debugging strategy section and the React Challenges section.
The first section debugging strategy just goes over a lot of the tools and techniques that I've learned
over the years to help you understand how I debug in a professional environment.
And then the second section is the REACT challenges, which is 25 challenges that allow you to use those
skills that you learned in the first section.
So you don't have to follow this course in order.
It's not like my other courses where we have a big application that we build throughout the whole course.
Instead, this time around, we're just going to each lecture is really more its own thing.
So there's there's the first section where each each lecture is more or less a different tool or technique
that you could use to help yourself debugging.
And then the next section, the challenges section, each challenge is its own thing.
So you could really skip around if you want to.
But I advise you to just go in order just because they kind of build on each other.
But they also at the same time are their own standalone videos.
So first, to unlock the challenges, you're going to want to go to react at school, slash challenges,
slash, unlock, and this is really going to unlock the course content on the website.
So this content is private, so try not to share this link.
You can access the challenges here, react at school, slash challenges, slash one slash to all the
way up to 25.
And so the website, you can use that to see the code sandbox link as well.
And so, yeah.
So each challenge, it's kind of like a brief prompt about roughly a bug and then the code sandbox with
the app that you need to debug and your objective there is to really understand the complaint and to
return the application to a functioning state.
Always open the code sandbox in a new window, so I show you how to do that in every one of the challenge
videos, so don't really write a lot of code in the embedded sandbox because it can get kind of buggy
and sometimes you won't be writing code.
Most of the time you will be, but often a couple of times you will end up needing to debug the browser
instead of the actual code sandbox.
So we'll explain that as we get to those challenges.
And then please watch the next lecture to understand the philosophy behind these challenges and what
your true goal is within these course.
So this video is just kind of to set you up about what you need to know about the challenges.
Let's go into the next video now, where I'm going to share a little bit about the philosophy of debugging
and why you should feel good about taking this course.
Good luck and happy debugging.