OK, so in challenge for we could see we have this issue here.
Now you could see we have the objective, so basically saying, hey, the screens blank, please fix.
So now you can see here, unlike the previous challenges, we don't have a obvious error to debug.
So let's say if I refresh, so go over here and now if I open the sandbox.
Here we go.
So so now I'm in the sandbox, and if I go here to the console, so you see we don't have an error on
the screen, but if I go to the console, you could see I do see a warning that says functions are not
valid as a react child.
This may happen if you return a component instead of component from render or maybe you call this function
rather than return it.
So basically, that's that's my clue into this.
Now I'm looking at this app and it doesn't appear and anything is wrong.
Right.
But actually what we're doing is we are assessing here.
Functions are not valid as react child.
We are returning a function, whereas we should just be returning that X, right.
So just returning this just like this would fix that issue.
So kind of a sneaky type of error, you know, that you might run into if you think that you could return
a component like this.
So definitely a tricky issue.
So if you you know, we could Google this error and try and find, you know, solution.
See if, you know, if we Google this, we might get a similar.
You know, so if I go into this code, Kampia and.
So as you can see here.
This person is just returning that function inside of their JSM.
They're not they're not actually calling that function, right?
They're not invoking that function.
So, yeah, this was kind of a trick that I made just to to try and throw you off in terms of understanding
why this was happening.
Now, another thing you could do to get this to, you know, if you really were running out of options,
you could just return.
You know, go back to revert to a component that does work here, so that is challenge number four.
As you could see here, what we had to do in our strategy guide was we we did read the error here and
we we followed the stack trace.
There was no stack trace.
There was actually more of a warning than an error.
Right.
So we found that warning and then we Google that error message.
And we were able to understand through that error message what was going on.
And we were able to fix our code through that.