All right, so moving along to the second part of our Web, Inspector, Chrome debugger, chrome dev
tools tool, we have here the network panel.
So here basically you could just see the network activity for your site.
So here you can see the different files that have been loaded from the server.
So you have the method that you're getting that file.
So get request, you have the status code.
So the file fails.
You'll see the error here and then you have the type of that file.
So you can see here we're loading JavaScript, we're loading images, some styles and the initiator.
So where was that loaded from?
And you could see the size of that file and you could click on these to sort these by size so you could
see the biggest file that you're loading and then you could see the time.
So the time it takes for that to get to your website from the server, you could see that here as well.
And then on your right, you'll see just a time frame of this and you hover over that and you could
see just more details about that.
And you can see just a breakdown of that.
And then this up here is just across time.
So as you're loading assets, you could see here they some of the assets take longer and then you can
go and just click record.
And then you could see here you can refresh the page and then you could see all of your assets loading
after you stop recording.
So there you go.
So you can now just you can click on sections here if you want to, like, dive in deep.
And yes.
So this is pretty useful if you're debugging network activity.
I would say the most common thing that you're going to do here is you are going to check the response
from the server.
So let's say that you load some some packet of data.
So like let's say I load this file right here.
What you're going to do is you're going to read this information here.
A lot of the times that you can see, you know, the different headers that come back from the server.
You can see the response from the server.
So if you go here, you see a preview.
This is what the server returns.
You can see the exact content that your server is delivering to your website piece by piece.
So just like with images, you can go here and see different images for things that have been loaded.
And you could go here and see the response if there's a response from that.
So you could see a preview response and then the initiator where you load it, loading that from, and
then you could see more details about timing there.
So this is the network tab, very useful for checking out things coming from the server.
And up here, you could see you can actually filter out some of that data.
So if you go here and click X once you're in here, then you go back to this menu and you could go here
and filter out.
So if you only want to see JavaScript or X Chaffetz requests, you could do that and then looking like
that.
So you could see here JSON and if you go down here.
Yeah.
So a lot of times you could see the requests that are sometimes you'll want to debug like what am I
requesting.
So.
What am I requesting with right, so say your app is requesting with some query parameters.
This is where you'll see, well, what am I requesting right here?
And then you'll see that's exactly what you're getting back.
And JSON data, you can then go and actually browse through the JSON data that you're getting back from
the server self server, sending you some weird data.
You'll be able to debug that here, send a screenshot to your back end developer and tell them to fix
their code.
So here another thing.
This is another response.
And so there we go.
So this is pretty much the network tab.
You can also go up here and throttle the network.
So if you want to have slow 3G or fast 3G or disable Wi-Fi quickly, you could do that.
And over here, this is pretty much you can upload a network profile file.
If you want to see someone else's file, you could disable cache.
So if your network is caching, you could disable that.
And yes, you could filter, you could clear.
And that's basically, as is clear, the network tab.
It's going to clear all of that data.
So we have.
So there you go.
So cool.
So now we go back to Profile Tab.
This is for if you're debugging JavaScript specifically and also more and more information as well.
So you could see in addition to JavaScript, you can see your network here as well.
And then you could see more information.
So frames.
So as you load that page, you can see the exact frames that come in.
And if you go up here, you could see as we're loading in that profile, it's coming in or as reloading
in that page.
It's coming in just like this in this timeline.
So here we loaded that image.
And as you see here, we have green, purple and yellow and blue.
So sections out your site.
So you could see here across the the time frame that we're on right now, this should update.
So you have, you know, about a second of information here that you could look at.
You could see, OK, we spent 100 milliseconds rendering 30 seconds painting that to the screen scripting.
You have JavaScript running for most of it.
And then you go down here and you could actually scroll up to expand and then see the actual call stack
of that JavaScript it calls functions down.
So each function above is calling the function below.
And you can just zoom in and see different types of you could debug, basically see where your app is
spending most of its time if you have some kind of performance bottleneck.
So that's really cool and useful to do if you're doing some really intense profiling, if you're trying
to do some speed debugging, this in combination of the network tab are going to get you a lot more
information about what's going on in your app as far as performance goes.
So then down here, you see the bottom up.
You can actually see during that time what JavaScript functions were called.
So I think you need to.
Yeah.
So let's see if we click on one of these blocks, then you go down and you could see the exact time
that it's been in each one of those functions.
So we're not going to go too much more into this.
This is pretty intense.
We could do a lot more on this.
If you want to do more profiling, we could do another lecture on that.
Just let me know.
So moving along, we have memory so you could see how much memory your app is using across time.
So as you as your JavaScript gets more memory built up, it will show here and as well as DOM nodes.
So there's going to be nodes here.
These are actually your HTML nodes that are being rendered.
So you could see how many are actually rendering.
This is good.
If you have a ton of nodes that you're rendering and you want to just see what's going on as far as
your how your browser is handling that in terms of like what?
OK, we're taking up 11 megabytes of data and.
Cool.
So memory tab, same thing here, we're not going to do this, but same thing if you want to get a snapshot
of your memory distribution across time for different JavaScript and DOM nodes.
OK, moving along, we have the application tab.
So here is where you'll see the local data that your app is storing.
So when you have local storage, you have keys and values that are being stored there.
And that's pretty common in apps to have cookies as well.
So you could see a lot of cookies and that's pretty useful.
You have cash, so you could clear cache like this.
You could clear your cookies as well just by clicking on that.
So that's pretty useful.
And so that's the application tab.
This is basically just seeing your application storage and most of the time you're in here just looking
at local storage or clearing cookies.
Next tab is the security tab.
This is a tab I'm almost never in just to show you what it is.
Basically, we are showing whether this page is secure or not through https.
So whether you have an encrypted connection and it's going to tell you whether or not you have that
server certificate.
So if you want to see your origins that you're loading data from and to see whether they are secure
or not, this is the panel that you're going to do that and not much else going on in here, audits
here.
You could generate a report of your site so you could get a nice speed report.
And this is cool seeing your SEO for your site if you're interested in that.
So I need to properly size images.
This is the information that they're getting here.
I didn't minified it.
I didn't minifie any of my images here.
And that's probably why I'm getting that.
This is also the same.
This is also the same as page speed, Google page speed.
It's a website where you can go and enter in your website.
So if you want to just do that locally, you could do that here.
And I'm pretty sure there's mobile and there's desktop versions of this.
So this is, I believe, doing the mobile one here.
But there should be a way to see the desktop one.
So this is the speed on it.
And then next, you have your various chrome extensions of my ad blocker, my react dev tools here,
which we'll get into, and then a react profiler, and then up here you have some warnings and this
is just some warnings that are appearing in your console.
So you just have that little warning up here.
And then over here we have some more these things we kind of talked about already, which is the docs
side and the and other different shortcuts and other just settings for the developer developer tools
here.
So here is where you can actually enable dark mode if you want to.
That's pretty much the main thing that I've been going in here and doing that I can remember recently.
So the dark mode would be right here and theme, you could change that to dark mode.
And then I'll reload with the dark modin here, cool.
So that's basically it for Webcke, Inspector.
Next up, we're going to talk about the responsive button here that you could use to debug responsive
websites.