Right, so I'm here on challenge five, as you can see here, it says Set color button shows error.
Please fix if you can.
This is the description or the objective.
And first thing I want to do is actually confirm that setting that color button actually does show an
error.
So I go into my sandbox mode to open up this sandbox here.
So I'm opening here, I'm in the sandbox now, I click the color button and here we go, I get an error.
So I've reproduced the issue and I've confirmed that there is an issue here.
So the next steps that I'm going to take care of my strategy, guide her to get to gather some clues.
So I'm going to basically see that there are errors in the console.
There is an error.
And so can I trace that stack trace?
And as you can see here, I do get that line of code that's causing the issue.
And so that's that's a clue here.
The next thing.
So I've isolated basically where that code is happening.
Right.
And as you can see, I'm back in here.
I've isolated you know, it's been really obvious here.
It's telling you exactly where that line of code is and if you were in the console.
So if I refresh and just see if that bug also happens in the console and it does not look like it does,
let's see if I go into if I highlight this and I go into the actual app, I would like to go into the
actual app itself just to show you a realistic example.
Right.
So if I'm here in the app and I open up the chrome dev tools and then I go and I click on that button,
so now I could see I have the error being traced in here.
And once again, it's tracing back to that exact file.
So it says color is read only.
So it's tracing back to that same line that we had here.
So I go back here and as you could see, so colors read only.
So now I've isolated the line of code.
Right now it's time to understand what's going on in that's in that code itself.
So this this this exact app right here, if I refresh it, looks like what the intention here is.
If I go down and I just read some of this here, I could see we have a button and this button has a
click handler which says set color.
And there's a function called green, which I believe what's supposed to happen here is that it's supposed
to set the color to green.
Right.
It's trying to set that color equal to green.
But this is not working right.
It says color is read only.
So now I want to understand a couple things here.
First, I want to understand what's going on here and this line, because we're setting color equal
to green, right?
And as you could see, color is then used here in the style tag or the style property of the d'Hiv.
So now if we refresh the page, you'll see that the color of this div is blue.
So there's some clues here as to what's going on.
So it appears that the color is being initialized to blue and then we are trying to set it to green,
but we're breaking on that.
So that's my my quick analysis of what I think is going on in this app.
Now, how I would debug this further is to understand what's going on with this.
Now, I see this thing called use state here.
Now, if you know anything about react hooks, you know that this is the most common reactant you state.
And this is the this if you're not familiar with you state, you could research use state.
So if I Google use state, I could see we have using the state hook here.
And as you could see, we have a very simple example here.
So I could look at this and I could see, OK, I am clicking on this and I have I'm using so I have
this, which we'll call count.
So basically we are if you you know, I'm not going to so I can do a quick overview of react hooks,
but basically.
So if you go down here, you could see that we have a hook.
So we import that you state hook and then it's it's a special function.
And as you could see here, so this is the old way of doing it.
And then so here we go.
So now this is really the part.
So I'm basically I'm looking for where it defines what you state does.
So it's calling.
So our variable is called count.
And then as you can see here, there's a second argument.
So as you can see here, it says, what does you state return?
It returns a pair of values, the current state and the function that updates it.
This is why rewrite const count set count equals use state.
So you could research more of this.
But now, if you were totally unfamiliar with react, you state you would through Google, you were
able to understand what's going on with the U.S. state.
Now, that's just an example.
So you'd be researching that and then you would realize that, OK, color here is here and set colors
here now.
So if you know now you know about Riak state, you're wondering, OK, well, this doesn't look like
the right way to set react state.
Right.
So once again, though, what is this actual error happening here?
So if you Google this hour.
So if I say Read-Only.
You could see there's this error here.
So this is found I found this here, so this is the first result on Google, so occurs when a global
variable is assigned to a read-only property.
So those first two articles didn't really help, but then I found this one and it says this is read
only.
And then I go down here and I see you're defining this with the card statement.
CONSED creates a constant, that is to say, a value which cannot be changed after first being initialized.
So instead of consed use let or there.
So now this is kind of a distraction against the actual issue, which is that you should be using react
Hoke's.
You shouldn't be setting it like this.
Right.
So, but that's why we get this error because we're actually we're declaring this concept here and this
color is actually consed, so it's unable to be set.
So that's why we get this error.
But the real way to set react state is to use the set color.
So if I change this to say set color green like this passing in that value here, I could set the color
and then it turns green.
So this is how to solve that issue.
As you can see here, green is a function.
So I'm declaring this function here and dysfunction is being invoked when we click on that button.
So this was just an example of calling a reactive wrong, educating yourself about react hooks and about
const variable variable errors and read-only properties.
And we were able to debug that by researching reactance and properly using state functionality.