Hello, in this lecture, we're going to talk about the react developer tools, so this is a chrome
extension that you could download and then have access to look at your react elements similar to the
elements tab, except you'll actually see the react named elements in the panel.
And that's basically what the main thing this extension does.
And we're going to show you how to use it and install it.
So you're going to go to react developer tools on the Google Chrome Web store where you can just find
it and install it to your Chrome browser.
If you want to install it for another browser, you can search for it on GitHub and then it'll give
you instructions on how to install it for your browser.
So if you go on this page, this is going to give you a screenshot here and a brief overview.
There is not really an in-depth guide over here, but you can search for different guides online to
find out how to use it.
But I'll show you it.
There's not that many features in this.
So compared to the regular JavaScript debugger, this is pretty trivial.
And I would say not really that necessary.
So you can get by without using this.
But I think some of the features in here are really cool and I'm going to start using a lot more of
these.
So if we go here, we have a code sandbox.
So this is a place where you can actually test this out just because you may be using a react app that
doesn't support it yet.
So if you go here, you can see we have an app, just a regular react app rendering some components
here.
And then I have copied the link here and pasted that into a browser where I can see my app.
So Code Sandbox gives you that.
So if you go here and you just say, Hello, Sandbox, how are you?
And then you save this, you had control s and then you refresh your app, you'll see your changes on
your actual hosted app here.
So this is cool.
So now we're going to.
Right.
Click and inspect to get this webcam inspector up.
If you don't have that already.
And what you're going to notice here is that you can now basically see the actual elements that we have
in our app.
So we have an element called Hello World.
We have an element called other component.
And cool things about this are that this is the the react tree.
Right?
You're only seeing the react elements, which is useful if you want to see where the react elements
are in your app.
So clicking on these, you get a special panel over here where you can do special things for really
specific stuff.
So if you go up here next to that react component, you can suspend the selected component, you can
inspect the matching DOM element.
So if I click on this, it's going to bring me to the regular elements panel here, where you can see
that exact element here, which you could see is just a div, right?
So regular HTML here react components over here.
So this is the end result in HTML.
So go back over here.
The other thing I can do is I can actually I can log this component to the console here where you could
see more data about that.
So I don't really do that ever.
One thing that I think is really useful is you could see the source for that element.
So if I click on this, it's going to actually take me to exactly where that component is defined.
So I define that component here in Jass.
If I go over here to the components tab and I look at this other component, which is in a different
file, I can click on this view source and it's going to take me to that file.
And you could see here now I'm in the sources panel, right?
So here is where I have that other file.
So I knew exactly.
So if you're if you want to debug a react app and see where the files are for those components, there's
there's less efficient ways of doing that where you're putting breakpoints in those files or you're
you're searching for the names of those files in here like this.
So I could also just do this and type other file and find it like that.
But if you want to try something quicker, you might want to try this.
Next thing going down here, we have props.
So here in Hello World, I don't have any props hooked up.
But another component, if you go if I go over here and show you the other components source code,
I have basically some props here, a default prop that says Component Amesville, which is a default
prop here.
But let's see if we can modify that prop.
So if I go back to the webcam inspector, I can actually then change this prop here and I could actually
say title and I could just say Joe and I save that.
OK, OK, so there's a bit of a lag, so then there's that title there.
And so now you could see we have that component with the name Joe.
So that react dev tools here, components staff is actually able to change the react props for you on
any specific component, which is really cool.
So you could try different props out where you could see what props are actually rendered with, which
is really useful as well.
So we can copy that to the clipboard here using this.
And then I think we could paste those in here as a JSON expression.
So that's cool.
And then over here we can copy the source of that as well.
So if we copy that react source component there, we can go over here and we could paste that in.
And then that's the source of that app.
So you could maybe paste that into your file explorer to get to that file quicker.
So that's cool.
And so this also you could go up here and you could click you could just search for these components.
So if I want to search for other component, it'll highlight that for me and then also appear.
You can then you can you can then use the regular inspector here, just like the regular elements tab.
You can do this and you could see this component over here.
So I have another button in here, and it's not a react component, so this let's just actually make
that.
So I added this button in here, right here, so we can make this a button, which we can call function
or button.
So let's just call it button.
So do that.
And we go up here, we just create this.
And we return this button now, what this button is going to do, it's just going to set a style when
you click on it.
And the reason I'm doing this is so that we could enable the react profile or to see what's going on
with that.
So here we go.
We have this.
So now we're just debugging more debugging.
So we have this thing is not defined.
So I have this I have a hook.
So we'll just move that hook up here.
So I have a hook that you're using.
You state.
I'm just setting the color of that.
So as I click on this, it changes the color because I'm setting the state to be something and then
I'm inverting that.
So if it's true, it's then false and then false.
If it's true, it's undefined, it then becomes true.
So then if it's true, it's blue text and if not, it's green.
So why did I do that?
So I did that so that I could save this.
So it controls.
And then you're going to jump on over to your link, you're going to refresh and now we see our real
component.
So you go see if you're not seeing all your real components, maybe they're just regular HTML components
and you didn't know that.
And I have that react component there.
Now, another thing you'll notice is really cool.
You have that hook here.
So you could actually see the hook defined there.
And as I click on the button, it's now changing the state.
So you can see here that state of that hook is true or false.
So isn't that cool?
Really awesome.
Right?
Snakey debug state in addition to props.
So that's that's all going to share with components tab right now.
You can you could play with this, you could do previous searches and you can go up here, you can also
do the light theme.
So you could change some settings up here.
You could change it to a light theme if you want to do dark theme.
So let's go to the second extension that was installed, the profiler.
So this is going to do the same thing, the network profiler, performance profiler that we looked at.
If you write if you click on this and you click, start profiling and then you refresh the page.
That does nothing right, because what this is doing is only recording reactivity, so if you record
this and then you just click on this button a couple of times and then we go here and we undo that recording.
Now, you could see we have a timeline.
So not much of a timeline, but we have something here so we could see different states, I think,
that were rendered here, and that is where we could step through and see different times of those renders
or different.
Yes, a different time intervals for those runners.
Now, let's go to the interactions tab, let's see if we can see that here as well.
We're going to click on record again, click on a couple of things.
And it's going to say no interactions were recorded.
So we go here and we look at the API, you could see interaction tracing, and so you need to do is
you actually need to wrap your app in this special profile profiler.
So you're going to need to actually wrap your app in this specific component.
So if you're interested in trying this out, feel free to do that.
We're going to stop here, though, because, again, I don't do a whole lot of performance testing
these days.
So this is something if you're a power user and you really want to get a full, detailed information
on it, what's exactly happening with your Riak components?
I think we might do another video on this.
So that's it for now.
I just wanted to give you a little intro on what this is in case this was useful for you.
Thank you.