All right, hello.
And this one I wanted to talk about conditional breakpoints and watch expression's, so I wanted to
talk about these together for a specific reason.
I didn't want to just walk through what conditional breaks points are.
I wanted to kind of give you an example of exactly when you would use them and why you would use them
just so you're not constantly using them without a reason.
They're kind of a thing you use pretty rarely.
I think that normally you kind of know where to put a breakpoint in your app.
It's kind of obvious where the conditions are, right?
Like if I wanted to put a breakpoint on removed title, I'll just put a breakpoint here.
Or if there's an if statement under a certain situation, I'll just put the breakpoint inside of the
IF statement.
But in certain situations, for example, I added this new code here for looping over a long list.
Let's say you're looping over a group of people and you know that one of them is causing an issue.
Where you would do is you put a conditional breakpoint in there and then that would break only under
those certain certain situations.
So first, let's just go and just put a break point here just to show you just a normal breakpoint,
so.
So this is just a normal breakpoint, as you can see, we have our variables up here and I'm going to
just hit continue now if we do so now, you could see this is going again.
So what I'm going to do here is let's say we wanted to put a break point only when the remove or when
the no title boolean was set, which is only happens when we actually click on this remove title button
over here.
So when we click on this removed title button sets this no title to true.
So.
If we go back over to our weapons inspector, what we're going to do is we're going to right click on
our break point and say edit breakpoint sort of click.
We're going to say edit break point.
Now, in here, you could set a truthy expression so you don't have to just put something like equal
equals.
You can just put any expression that would evaluate to true.
So no title.
If I just write in the words no title, that would be a valid truthy expression.
So if I just put no title in there, my breakpoint turns yellow, which is an indication of it being
a conditional breakpoint.
Just so you know that this is not going to happen.
It's not going to break every time.
It's only going to break when that conditions there can.
Right.
Click and disable it if you don't want it to appear ever.
But you can also remove it as well from the right click menu.
So anyway, let's just go ahead and now click on that button.
So if I go back here to my scene and I click on that button.
Now, you could see that breakpoint has been triggered and what happens here when we hover over the
no title is true.
So now we're in that state.
We could see what other variables are in the state and it's very useful for that certain situation now.
Like I said, this is kind of something you wouldn't really do too often.
Something you'd really want to do is when you're looping over a long list or something that you really
can't use a regular breakpoint for.
And so in this example, I'm going to put a breakpoint here, you know, going to.
Right.
Click on that breakpoint.
And I'm going to just going to say I equals equals 40, so triple equals you're going to use that just
so it compares the the exact number is not going to be getting tripped up by a string, so.
I equals equals 40, it's only going to break during that loop when I is 40 and we're going to go and
we're going to now again refresh the page.
And so when we refresh the page, you can see that the eye is now 40, and if you go over here, you
could see this is the thread.
So we're just going to get rid of this.
Now, the idea over here, this is a watch expression.
So if I get rid of this, you should have this.
No watch expressions.
If you.
Right.
Click on that, you'll see that there's a thing called ad watch expression.
So this is just an expression that you could watch for that condition.
So if you wanted to save a certain expression, which we're just going to put in the word ID because
we want to just see what our ideas I didn't mention this, but we are generating this idea for this
eye.
So we're just creating this new variable here just to show you that when we we've conditionally stopped
here at this point where when I is 40 and we've created this ID, which is this string.
So just like that, we've we've put a conditional breakpoint in.
We've we've stopped our code at this point and now we can look at our watch expression and so forth.
So another so that that's great.
So if you wanted to put conditional breakpoints everywhere for a specific user ID or something that's
looping over a long thing, you could do that really easily with this.
And then you could watch a bunch of variables that you set to get like some nested attributes or something
out of there.
So that's very useful.
Now, what I'm going to show you here is actually another thing that you could see with watch expressions
is Chiasm continuing along.
It's showing me the watch expression for each one of those loops.
So that's really useful.
So that's pretty much all you're going to use conditional breakpoints for.
So thank you.