All right, so four, challenge six, we see this error that says drop down doesn't work, please see
if you can fix.
So this is a very short error, short description of what's going on.
And this one, we are going to try and reproduce.
So let's go ahead and open up the code sandbox.
So we open up this code sandbox and we see a dropdown here, I'm just going to tighten this up.
So we see we have this dropdown.
So as you can see, the first thing I'm going to try and do is reproduce this issue.
So if I click, I see a list of states and if I click on one of those states, nothing happens.
So if you're familiar with drop downs, you know that if you scroll and you click on one, it should
appear here.
Right.
So that's the reproducing of the issue.
So I've reproduced the issue.
My next step, if I go to my strategy guide, I want to gather clues.
So see if there are errors in the console.
So if I go back, I go here.
I look at the console.
And I don't see any errors.
I do see a warning, I see another warning as well.
I see these two warnings component will receive props has been renamed, and I also see Component Will
Mount has been renamed and it's not recommended for use.
Now at first glance, that doesn't really look related to this issue.
So I'm just going to ignore those two issues here.
Next, I can see we have a long statement that says selected.
I'm also just going to ignore that as well.
So I'm going to do here is I'm just going to, again, reproduce and I see that that log comes here.
Now, that's this looks like there's just a log statement in there that doesn't really help me troubleshoot
this.
So my next step, I'm going to open this actual app here.
I'm going to click on this.
I'm going to copy and then I'm going to paste that into a new.
Here, so I have this in a new browser window here so that I am not interfering with any code sandbox
code, so.
Next thing I'm going to do is I'm just going to go here, I'm going to open up the chrome dev tools,
always make sure you click and open up a new dev tools for that window.
I believe I had another window open and I have another one behind here.
So just make sure you close out of all your dev tools.
So as you could see here, I'm in my chrome dev tools.
Now, if you remember from the first challenge, what we're going to do is we want to find this code,
right.
So we want to find where this object or where this dropdown is being initialized.
Now, to be honest, if I was in a real app, I would probably go and familiarize myself with the actual
code itself.
So if I go here, I just want to get a little bit of context into what app I'm in.
Now, if you're in a real app, you have probably hundreds of files and it's going to be a lot more
difficult.
This one is, you know, a lot smaller.
So basically you could see here we have a couple of files.
We have this we have some data.
And, you know, this is the index and then this is calling example.
So I go over here into example.
And as you could see here, it's a very small component.
We are end up we end up rendering.
So I go down to my rendering function and I see a return.
This thing, which is select now that looks like that could be my dropdown.
Right, because we have some options here.
And as you could see, I go up and my next step is to trace exactly where this is coming from, where
is this select coming from?
So if I go up here, I see this is coming from this airport here, which is called React Select.
So that is not part of my code.
Right.
I don't see anything in here called React Select.
So I have to determine that this is a external library.
I can go and package that JSON here and I can confirm that React Select is a package and this is Riak
select version one point three point zero.
So this is a version of that.
So very important to note that because this might not be the latest version.
So that is basically I've you know, I found the.
Initialization of that component is the only component in this app, so very obvious, but.
And a real app, if I go back here, this might not be obvious where that is.
So, again, another thing I could do, a couple of things I could do, actually.
I could go in here components.
And as you could see here we have this is my react dev tools.
Here and I go here and I hover over these elements and I see here, I click on this select and then
I go here to view source for this element.
And it brings me here.
So it brings me select James, so as you could see here, this is happening in the node modules react,
select, libs select.
So that is telling me that, OK, this is coming from a library in my node modules.
So not exactly helping me in terms of where it's happening in the app, but it is showing me that it
is a node module.
Now if I go one layer up an example, I click on that and then I click on View Source for this element.
It brings me here to exampled Ijaz.
Now, this brings me to this example, dodgiest file and it says Source map detected.
So this looks like this is the minified code, right?
So it's a source map detected.
If I go to more click on that, it's going to tell me to access files via control.
So normally in this situation, if you're in a minified code, you do control P or command P and type
in the same file.
So Exampled Digests.
And then we'll find the source map version right here and we click enter.
And then now we have this.
So we were able to track that component down to this file and then we could find it through here.
And like I said, you could also you could also search for the strings so you could search for a state
and then you would probably get into the data digest where those states are to find, you know, if
I type in Arizona, you could see here Arizona will pop up no matches.
So if I type in Alabama.
You could see there we go, so that does pop up here in the source map, same thing.
If I click on that, it highlights this option here and that's showing me that this is the options that
are being.
Now, then.
OK, so I say, all right, well, I see Alabama and these options.
What's what's going on now where these options used.
So then I control F and I search for options and I see they're being passed into here.
OK, so at the end of the day now I have the react select.
I know that this is in React Select.
Right.
I know that this is a react select component.
The next thing I want to do is actually understand more about react select because let's say I don't
know anything about react select.
I don't know why this isn't working.
And now you could debug this by just guessing.
I could look at these props and say, OK, well I see there's an en change handler.
Maybe that has something to do with it because there's name, there's value and there's options.
So sometimes you could look at these components and you could just guess, OK, well, on change is
a pretty common callback and most of these really components are going to have that same on change handler
or the similar on change handler.
And so if you want to just go for it and just guess, you could just guess that that's the issue right
here.
And we see that this is traced down to this not handle change.
And as you could see here.
I can put a break point here and I can understand what's going on with that, so.
As you can see, here I am.
Setting the stage to be selected, so.
So let me let me actually put a break point here, so first thing I want to do is make sure that this
Handal change function is actually working correctly.
So if I go over here and I click this, I could see if I hover over this and I'm in here, I can hover
over selected option and I can see that this is right.
This is what I actually clicked on.
Right.
So this has a label and this has a value.
Now, my next question is, well, if that's correct, then why isn't it going back in to my select
as the value?
Right.
So I'm guessing once again that the value is the signature for the current value.
So now so that's that's an assumption I'm making.
And I can Google react to confirm that.
So let me go ahead and search for react select.
So search for react select now, as I said before, we were in version one, point three, so we want
to make sure that we're in the right version of this.
So you could see we we might be coming from react select version one.
So it's just something to keep in mind in this example.
We're not going to do that because it just so happens that it's the same signature.
But here we go.
And then we see we have this this dropdown here.
And we we want to just read a little bit about this.
Right.
So we're getting started.
We have options.
We have, you know, custom styles.
I'm going down.
I'm not really seeing a whole lot of information on the home page here.
So if I go to props, though, you'll see some props here.
And, you know, it's good to just read what's going on here just to familiarize yourself, but once
again, it's not really giving me an obvious it's not really telling.
It's only helping me in terms of what what this actually is doing.
Right.
So.
All right, so eventually, if we go keep looking at these examples will eventually come into this example,
fixed options, where if we go here and we expand the source code here, we are able to actually see
a similar code structure to what we have in our app.
We have it on change.
We have a name and we have a value.
And as you could see here.
We have similar we have an on change call back here, and we could just look at the function signature
here, we're taking in a value and we're setting the state of our app.
So we're in a react component, right.
With state.
We're setting the state to that value.
Now, you could just kind of ignore some of what's going on here.
Basically, they're taking, you know, certain actions, you know, certain actions that are being
applied.
I'm just guessing, you know, if we clear it, you know, you're going to want to set the value to
be something what it was.
Right.
So but at any rate, the value is being set here.
So we get so basically they they say order options.
And as you could see, we go up here, that order option.
So we're just tracing in what is this value and what are we setting on our app.
So values.
So it passes in that so it turns value into values appear and then it filters that array.
So you could see that it is an array, right?
Because you know, that values that filter filters an array.
You can only call filter on an array.
So value is an array.
We've determined that.
And then now we set that array on the app, so.
We we can kind of just guess, OK, well, this is a speech we also see here we see is multi.
So this is a multi select component.
Right.
And this is all kinds of different, you know, locked values, as you could see, were playing with
it.
And we could you know, we could try and find this component as well and debug it here as well to just
confirm what this is.
But we have a little bit more context of what our app is doing now that we have we see this example
now.
You could see here we do pass that value in this that state, that value.
And the value here is just this, that state value that we set here.
Right.
And just like up at the top, you could see here, state value here is order options as well.
So it's again, it's an array.
So we've got a lot of clues.
Now, you could see here that more more details about that.
So color options.
So if you go up here to color options, you'll see data.
So now let's OK, we have data here so we could even go into here and the this code sandbox and see
if this happened.
OK, so this is a 404.
So once again, the documentation on these things is not going to be always perfect.
And that's why I included this example, because it's just, you know, react select.
Do they upgrade things?
They break stuff.
The code sandboxes don't work.
You're not going to be in a perfect sunshine and rainbows environment always.
Right.
So we have a clue.
We have this clue about what's going on here, about what these do now.
And we see we have a working example we could play with over here.
So we go back to our app and once again we go and we check.
So still it's working.
It's not working.
So we go back here and we we're going to put a breakpoint here in this handle change function.
So we go back to our browser where we had that example open and we go and we once again, we find that
component and we do what we were about to do before.
Right.
We put a breakpoint here and then.
What we do is we will trigger this change event, so now that we know where we might be expecting an
array here, right.
So we go and we look at this and we say, OK, this is an array.
So now we notice that it's actually an array, it's on an object.
And we we know that we could pass that array into the value here.
So we say, OK, well, what's going on there?
We are setting in the state to selected and we're setting that.
So we should be expecting this that state that's selected.
Right.
So if we put a breakpoint here and we look at what selected option is, we see that it's nothing.
It's just an empty string.
So it didn't look like that.
We actually set that on our state.
So this is actually not a react select issue.
It looks like it looks like it's an issue with our app.
So what we need to do is figure out how to set the stage to be selected option.
So what we did.
So I'm going to reveal the solution now.
The solution here is that we that this not set out state selected here.
This was a mistake.
We only wanted to set selected option, not selected.
So we change that to be selected option like this, which means this is the key and the value.
Right.
This is the key.
Select that option, which should be set as the that state that selected option.
And then we go back to the dropdown and we could see that it's now working.
So what did we learn here?
We learned to debug the component, look at the examples for react select or the component that you
want to research.
Look at their examples.
Make sure you're on that right version.
We were actually looking at a more later version of that, but you could also, you know, search for
a react select version one.
And just so happens that they have documentation here for version one.
So and then once again, this is actually a simpler example.
But if we go here to source of that, we could see once again we would be able to figure out, you know,
we have value we have on change here.
And it's a similar example.
Now, you also might be wondering, why are you showing me this?
It's not react hooks, right?
This is a class based component.
So this I included this in here for a couple of reasons.
You're going to want to eventually you're going to run into legacy react code at some point.
And so it's important to know about legacy code and legacy components debugging.
These are going to really make you skilled because you're going to be able to troubleshoot older code
and that's going to really apply to newer code as well, because you're going be able to port older
code to another newer code and you're going to be able to understand what's going on in this example.
It didn't even have anything to do with this.
Actually, we were doing this right.
We didn't change anything with the initialization.
All we did was we just noticed that we were trying to set state to a state variable that we didn't use
anywhere else.
So we didn't use this that state that selected anywhere.
So basically, all I did was to create this example.
I just tried to throw you off by setting a state to a variable we weren't even using.
So I hope this was useful.
I'm sorry if that was confusing, but this hopefully allowed you to gain some insight into troubleshooting
more complicated dropdown components.