Hello, and this video, we're going to talk about a complete guide to console dialogue, so this is
the standard way to log text to the console in JavaScript.
Now, you can log a whole bunch more things from text numbers to any variable in JavaScript.
You could log errors warning's, you could style things.
And basically, there's a whole bunch of other things you could do with this.
You could profile, you could do console dot time.
You could.
So there's a lot of things you can do.
We're going to focus on console to log, console out, warn and console error in this video, which
are really the most commonly used console logs in general.
I think putting breakpoints is better than console log because you're inspecting data rather than,
you know, putting a log statement and typing out that text that you have to later delete.
I think log statements are a little bit more verbose.
But if you are in a really complicated code base and you just want to log something really quick rather
than finding that file, then console dialog is definitely going to be the way that you should go here.
So at first example here, this is just basic console to log in the arguments here.
We're putting a text string here.
And as you could see on the console, this is being logged over here, so.
Now, if we go down to their next example, you can so you might be thinking, you know, if you if
you want to do multiple console dialogues, you could copy and paste this throughout the next line.
But that's a little bit tedious.
But you could do instead is simply just add a comma here and then add another line of text or whatever
you want to add and could add a variable in here, a JavaScript variable.
As I show in the next example we are logging.
You can there's no limit to the number of arguments here, so you could add in as many arguments as
you want.
So here I'm logging in some strings, a number and array a an object and then an undefined here.
So all so that's what that looks like here.
If you go if we go to the console here, you could see the array and the object are things that we can
expand out and look at more data for those items.
So but it's nice to give you a nice preview here for the object in the array so you can, you know,
make some assumptions by just looking at it like that.
And it's cool.
So the most commonly used way to do this, if you're trying to log like an object or something, would
be in this example.
We have this board object here and here.
But what we're doing is rather than do you know, let's say you want to log a bunch of different things
in different spots.
What you can do here is that you're logging the text string first and then after that you have the object.
So here we have that object being logged and I can once again expand and view the data that I want.
But the key thing here is that you're labeling it ahead.
So it's nice.
So you're not just, you know, logging some random object that you don't know where it is now.
Something to know about logging objects is that this is actually it's by reference.
So you're not logging this actual value here.
You're logging it at the time of the you're opening it the end result value.
Right.
So this is a reference to this thing called initial state.
Now, if after I log it, I do something like this where I say initial state dot foo equals.
VA, what's going to happen is if we look at this.
We actually have that foobar in there, so if you're trying to log a bunch of objects, one after another
to try and see data changing what you would do instead as you would try to make a copy of that object
or, for example, what you could do in this example, I'm just going to make a quick, shallow copy
of this object.
So I made a copy of this object at this time, you know, so now I have this this copy here and now
this doesn't have that new object that I added here or that new property that I added on here.
But this isn't a deep copy.
So what that means is if I change the grid, then that grid will be whatever.
I changed it.
So it's going to be the current value.
So you just have to keep that in mind when you're logging it, you're logging the current value of that
object at the end of all of your code execution.
You're not logging the current value.
If you want to log the current value, you have to do a deep copy, which will do another tutorial on.
So next thing we're going to do is just log string substitutions.
So I'll be honest, this I pretty much never do.
I don't really ever need a really nice formatted logs like this.
But let me just comment about the other things here that I have.
So I coming out this so.
And you can see here it's substituting this string here.
And then at the end, it's going to substitute in the current value, ie, into that string statement.
Now, like I said, so and then also you have a number here, which is Pursat D, and if you go to the
console API from Mozilla, you could see the list of the substitutions so you can accept this.
So accept these substitution strings.
The you could put an object in your log, you could do a percent d an integer, so D an integer and
then you could also have a string and then an F as a floating point.
Now I would never do this because if I was doing this, I would probably just use a JavaScript template,
which is basically just a template in JavaScript which looks like this.
So I would basically, for example, just get rid of all this and I would just put this in here.
And then for whatever for whatever I wanted to log, I would just use the dollar here.
And then I would just say.
There you go.
So I would do something like that instead.
So.
And I would just yeah, so this is what I would do if I wanted to.
So as you could see, this is a string template.
So this is the way that I would prefer to do this, just because then you could put anything in here
and don't have to worry about the the formatting of that string substitution.
That's probably a pre JavaScript template thing that's just kind of left over.
So, again, if I put in, like, initial state, that's going to log that object object here, but
that doesn't work out.
So let me see what happens if we use the the percent O in here.
So let's go back to the thing here and we see percent.
Oh so we do this percent o and then we use the initial state here and let's just see what this would
log here.
OK, so if we use the string percent oh, in this example, we're logging this string statement here
and so that we could put like some text after this, for example, hello, object.
How are you so we do that and then you could see now if you wanted some kind of log like this where
you had an object in the middle of a bunch of text, you would use the string substitution.
But again, something I really would never do.
So just showing you that in comment that out and we can move on to the next thing, which is styling.
So, again, something that I don't do, but it's really cool and I think probably more people are going
to start doing this for if you wanted, maybe you had some kind of extension or you're putting some
code on someone's site and you want to style there a message for them.
You could do it like this where you have this stylish message here.
So basically that's just adding in a string of styles after.
And I took this example from the website Mozilla.
So this is just using the C to apply a CSA style to the output.
The text before the directive will not be affected, but the text after the directive will be styled.
So, I mean, this is really something that is pretty niche.
And I don't think there's ever a point to doing this, especially since logs are not shown in production
usually.
So you would never really need to do this.
So unless you wanted, you know, really you had a really intense log scenario and you needed a bunch
of different styles to come out.
You could you could do this if you wanted to.
So that's really cool.
I think it's cool, but again, not very useful.
All right.
So next thing we're going to talk about is console timeworn.
So console, I warn, is basically you've seen libraries like Riak do this.
They will put this warning in your app.
If you're doing if you're saying if you're using a deprecated function, for example, or you're doing
something that you want the user not to do, but to be aware of, but not necessarily to throw an error
or crash or app or anything, you would do this.
So this would show you the stack trace of that warning just so you can know where that came from.
So you could say it came from react or wherever it came from.
And so that's that's really cool.
So you could do console timeworn in your own apps, right.
So if you're writing an open source library or if you're writing some kind of even.
Yeah.
So if you're writing an open source library or tool or something that someone should use even an internal
library for people that you're using some kind of component or something, you could throw a warning
in that.
So we're going to comment that our next thing is concealed on log on a console, all log this area.
So this is a try catch block.
So I'm going to just throw an error here and just going to create some breaking functionality.
And I'm going to catch that error with the console log.
So what happens if we just consolidate, log that error, we get the stack trace.
So he could see here that, you know, it's pretty useful to have this stack trace in here.
And if you want to put something in front of that, you could do that as well.
So I think the normal the default is just going to be a console error e so if we just do that, then
we've caught the error.
So we're not going to break our app.
So this is console error.
So we do that and now you get the red text.
So it's the same thing except it's red and that's basically, you know, the whole point of console,
not error.
It just makes the text read.
It makes it it doesn't actually break your app.
So it could see, like, my app is still still functioning over here, but I caught that JavaScript
error, so my app is not crashed, so.
Let's continue on, so if I want to type something else so I could make my own error message in here,
if I want to say you did something bad and then I could log Stack Trace if I wanted to.
So take a look at that.
And so, you know, you could put a return statement, you could make one you could make one error that
does this.
So maybe you'd want to make an error like that and then you'd want to do the actual stack trace for
the user.
So.
See that?
See what that looks like?
So there you go.
So this is cool, this is like, hey, you want to make your own error logging.
You could do that with this pretty easily.
So, again, you can make it whatever.
Say you don't have to make it output the stack trace.
But that would be nice for you to do if you were making a library to include that stack trace there.
So there you go.
So this is just the console, that error and.
OK, so that's consultant error.
That's pretty much all I have for console, log and console Warren and console that error.
If you have any other questions on this, just let me know and I'll make another video on it.
Thank you.