All right, so in this challenge, challenge seven, we see ad user button doesn't work, please see
if you could fix as usual, I'm going to open up my sandbox.
And first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to confirm that issue, so I click on this button.
Nothing's happening.
So.
I've confirmed I've reproduced the issue and I'm not really sure what's going on with this, right,
it's a brand new app.
So what's my mindset here to understand what's going on in this app now?
I assume that ad user, Budden is supposed to actually add a user somewhere in here, and that's not
happening.
So very simple.
Looks like we have a very simple app here.
I'm looking through the code and I don't see many files.
I just see outguess.
So and nothing is even being rendered in here.
So we don't really need to go into how to search for this file.
I assume that you guys know how to do that already at this point.
If you don't, we'll just do that real quick.
You know, you can open up the dev tools, search for that app dogs, or you could also use the react
to dev tools here and understand this app is coming from this code.
Right.
Click view source for this element and the reactive tools.
And it's going to point you right over to this app, so.
That's step one, really, in our strategy guide, if you remember our strategy guide, we're going
to go and open that up.
She could see we want to reproduce that issue, we did that, there's no errors, right?
So that's the next thing we got to check.
We didn't check that yet.
We're clicking and we're not getting any errors in the console.
So once again, it looks like it could be a rendering issue.
So related to unexpected react state.
Right.
So that's our clue here.
If you read this this guide, it's going to it's going to help you.
So isolate what files.
So we know that it's pretty obvious we have Applegate's here and we have no error.
So we want to determine why this happened.
So once again, there isn't really exact instructions here in this guide on what to do next.
But we do have a clue that it's unexpected react state.
So as you could see here, I'm going to read the rendering method here.
So let's go and really dive into this rendering method.
As you could see, we have a div, we have a header that says ad users, we have a button here and then
we have another header that says there are users, users at length zero users.
So we could see here as we have users, that length is being added here.
So we could say, OK, users must be an array.
It's a JavaScript array.
Right, because that length is property of the array.
So we could see, OK, users is represents then the users array and let's go ahead and see what that
is.
Right.
A good strategy here would be to put a breakpoint, see what that actually is, to just confirm and
just examine data in the app.
And then we see up here we have that button that says add user.
And then we go up and we see this function here.
And you could see here we have users push and we're adding in an object that has the name of that user.
So that's my idea, so I this looks you know, it looks on the surface, looks good, right?
But we want to dig deeper.
We want to understand more.
So let's go ahead and put a breakpoint in.
So once again, I'm going to just you know, we could just open up the dev tools in here.
It's going to be the same thing.
I usually open up into another window, but we can also just keep it in here.
So we're in a search for APJ and the source map.
And we're going to do is we're going to put a breakpoint right in the render method.
So this is actually just the whole thing is a render method because it's a functional component.
Now, if you were just at the last challenge, you know, that was the Class-Based react component.
So we put a breakpoint here where it's returning the DOM and then here we could actually look at what's
going on.
So what we do is we click add user.
Or we can actually just refresh the apsos, refresh the app.
All right, we get a break point here, so we're stopped here now, we could do is we could hover over
certain attributes.
So we want to hover over users just to see what that is.
We hover over that and we see it's an array, it's zero, so the zeroth index andexanet array is undefined
and the first element or the one element is a function.
So this is odd.
This doesn't really look like user's right.
So something must be going on here.
Now, this isn't really the issue.
Right.
What is the issue is that users aren't being added.
So if I go here and I go in to add users.
I click add user.
I see we're pushing on to this kind of weird structure here, and we're pushing this user's name, and
then I go down here and I resume.
So if I if I click on here again, I notice it's not triggering this breakpoint, so that's a good clue.
They're saying, hey, wait, if I if I click on this, nothing is actually happening.
It's not returning to this breakpoint.
Right.
So with that, I'm going to say, OK, well, what's going on, let's keep going up.
Let's look at all of the code here.
Let's look at user.
So what is actually users saying use state?
So it's being initialized from your state.
Now, if, you know, if you looked at one of our previous challenges, you know that we also looked
at you state you should know that this is not the right way to initialize you state.
So what we what we know is you state is actually a Arae.
So it's an array, right, where the first value is the current value in the second argument in that
array or the second value in that array is the setar.
So if you remember when we put a breakpoint in there, we saw that the first value was nothing.
And that can be explained because we initialize that you state with nothing.
So basically what we were doing is we were not de structuring that array.
We were not doing this right.
So if I go back and code sandbox, first thing I would do is just say, well, this is not the right
way to call you state at all.
Right, so we need to be always using an array here so users set users would be the best way to do this.
Now, also, so you could see here now we click this and we get push of undefined.
So users is undefined here.
And so.
This is, you know, more more errors, but basically what we want to do here is, is this the right
way to set users on the app?
Right.
So how to set an array, how to set an array in the app is what we want to understand.
So if we Google how to set an array with react hooks or even better, Google search would be how to
add an item to an array, how to add how to add an item to an array with react hooks.
And as you could see here, we get Google right away, stack overflow, telling us you can update the
method for the state item.
So and then you can add a new element.
So basically.
As you could see.
We're getting we even have a code snippet here, so.
This is, as you can see here, by this large number, a lot of people thought this was a good answer
to this person's question, which is how to push an element inside you, state you array using react
huc so.
This is a similar problem to what we're trying to solve, right?
We're trying to add a user onto this array.
So if we go down here, we could see that when you use your state, you can get the update method.
So we have the array and then we have set the array.
And then we have an initial array, so.
You set the array, you have the old array using the spread function, spread functionality here, which
basically just flattens out that array for each value.
And then we have that new element here.
Now we go down here to this exact example we are using.
So we say you state we have to pass in that initial array here.
That's very important.
And that's why we were getting that push of undefined because users is an undefined object.
Right.
So we have to initialize that state with an empty array.
We do that, nothing happens here because we're not actually calling the set users.
So now we have to set users and we go back here to the stack overflow example and we see.
That we are setting the array with the old array being passed in.
And then we have the older I hear spread and then we have the Nuray here, so let's go ahead and do
that now.
So if we go here to add user, we want to set users to an array.
Right.
So it's going to be an array and then we're going to spread those existing users and then we're going
to put the new user.
So the new user was this this object here, it doesn't have to be anything important.
Right.
So it's just just an example.
So we do this, we save this, and then now we're initializing to an empty array.
So that's correct.
We add a user and then just like that, we are correctly incrementing that.
So what did we learn here?
We learned that.
You can't render without calling the set user's callback.
You can't just push objects onto the value.
You have to actually use the react hook to set that.
We also learn the right way to call you state.
You can't just put in a variable here.
You have to restructure with an array.
We learn to initialize you state with an empty array.
We also learned, most importantly, outargue is to Google or stack overflow what exactly you want to
do.
And if it's something common, turn your problem into a common Google query like how to add an item
on an array with react hooks.
And we found plenty of examples for how to do that.
So we learned how to be resourceful and we learned how to fix our issue.
So with that, we're going to go back to our strategy guide, see what we did here.
Again, we we reproduced the issue.
We saw an error at some point in our journey.
But really, we we followed, you know, we search for the elements, but we ended up having to research,
do a little bit of research and fix some syntax.
So.
With that, you know, we ended up having to revert to more or less a clean example from some documentation,
and we had to do some more research on use state.
So that's how we debug this.
I hope that this was helpful.
And I know reactance isn't as obvious as you might think, but if you Google, there's plenty of resources
out there to help you fix that.
So that's this challenge.