All right, so our next challenge, challenge eight, we can't type users in, please see if you can
fix once again another Vagg error into what's going on.
As you can see here, the app looks like it's already crashed when we started it up.
So once again, I'm going to go up and click open sandbox and that's going to give me this sandbox here
so where I can have a better workspace of what's going on.
So as you can see, we have cannot read property map of undefined.
So this is a pretty common error.
If you're not familiar with this, you can always Google this.
And as you could see in this first stack overflow, this person is quite confused.
They're getting the same error as us.
And as you can see, it's basically as a result of somebody needing to check whether or not they actually
have that data.
So basically what's happening here is that users is undefined and it cannot read property map of undefined,
so users is undefined.
So basically what we have to do, like our last challenge is initialize users to an empty array.
So we go up and we say, where is users defined?
So we search for our app and we see here users is defined here in a reactor, OK, so as you know,
we have to just put an empty array here.
So we do that and that fixes that initial error, right?
So that was our first clue.
I explain this in the previous challenge, but basically you have to look and research about you state
and react.
TOOKES And that'll give you a hint into why this variable here was undefined.
That's because we did not initialize that used state hook.
So we did that.
So that's easy, right?
So now we type in things here and we get this object object.
So now it's time to debug a little further.
So we go down here, we read some of the render method in here.
And as you could see, we have an endpoint where we type in that user and it looks like this this code
is trying to add users here.
So we have the input now we're typing into this input and we're getting this.
So that's bad, right?
This looks like an issue that we need to resolve.
So if we go and we look at what's happening on the input, we see we have a style, we have a placeholder,
which if we refresh, we get type name in.
So that's where that placeholder is.
Right.
We can make that assumption.
And then we have on change, name change and then we have value.
So name change looks like the function that's called when the input is changed.
So we go up here and we see this function called name change.
So we see that inside of this function we call a set name to value.
So what a set name.
We can research that we go up here and we see that set name is just another reactor.
OK, so we see you states being called here and we see that you state is being initialized with an empty
string and we see that that looks right.
OK, so we have a name here and we have a set name, Setar.
So this looks like good initialization of a reactor.
OK, so we've confirmed that.
So what's going on here?
Why isn't this working?
Well, let's put a breakpoint in here and see why it's not working.
Now, what else is supposed to happen here is that the value of that input is supposed to be set here
on that name.
So the value of that input as we type it looks like it's set to an object.
So that gives us a hint.
That's not correct.
Right.
When you initialize an input value, you want it to be a string so you could research HTML inputs,
but that's that's the gist of it.
And react.
You want to set that value to be a string for the input.
If you remember the react select example earlier, that was a completely different signature.
Right.
But similar in that it's a value and on change.
So what I'll do now is I'll open up the dev tools.
And I'm going to search for Abdul just once again and here I'm going to put a breakpoint on the name
change function.
So I go over here and I type in something.
And you see, I get a value and it's a synthetic event, so you could see here, I'm I'm quite confused.
I don't know what a synthetic event is.
But if you Google this, so I could Google now input change synthetic event.
And you see here we get some tutorials on synthetic event, so we see here we have this example, add
in on change handler to an input.
So.
We could see here, right in this example right here, a very simple example that we found on the Internet
on change handler.
Handle change, just like we have, but this time we see that it's easy, you don't target value.
So interesting right now we go down here, we say, and on change, event handler returns a synthetic
event which contains useful metadata such as the target's ID name and current value.
We can access the target's value inside of the handle change by accessing that target value.
Therefore, to log the name of the input field, we can log Iida target name.
So it sounds like we want to use the target value, right?
So we go back here, let's go ahead and change this signature to be an E to represent that event.
And then we say E target value.
So if we go into our breakpoint where we had put that breakpoint, we could see that if we go here value
this is actually the static event at Target and then we go to value inside of that target.
Go all the way down to LA.
There's a lot of properties in this, but eventually we get to value and we see we click on that.
We see we have s, which is what we typed in.
So.
We undo this break point and we go and change this to eat out target value, we had save and then we
refresh.
And we type in a name, so let's type in a name and then we click add user and it looks like it works
now, so we added more users.
Wait a minute.
This isn't working, so I would expect there to be more users in here, right.
So now it's time to debug what's going on here with this ad user button.
So if we go up to this ad user button, you could see here we're setting the users to be the name the
an array right here of just one variable, just one property of that.
Aura or one value inside of that Arae name, so that doesn't include the existing users, right.
So if you remember from a previous challenge, what we could do is spread those users here, Atacama,
and then add in the new name.
So now we save that.
And let's just see if that works.
So now, just like that, we don't even have to refresh.
We get the expected behavior now just to confirm we go down here, we didn't talk about this, but we
do see users that map, we are mapping over the users and we're just listing that user.
All right.
So let's summarize what's going on.
Users is an array.
We have to initialize that array with an empty array in the used state prop.
That's how we list the users and fix the initial error input when we type in and input the on change
event needs to select from the target value.
That's how we set with the reactor the current name value when we add user with the button on click
add user.
We need to spread the current users onto an array, a new array and add the current name onto the end.
Then we set users onto our an array onto our with the set users react hauk and that thus renders with
users being the new list of users.
So this is a basic to do list type of app, and I hope this is helpful and this is the end of the challenge.
Thanks.