All right, and this one, we're going to talk about console time, so let's see here, I have wrapped
this for loop here with console dot time.
And this is used if you want to basically profile or get a timed increment value in milliseconds of
how long that code took to execute.
So to do that and this is pretty rough, as in you're doing this in your browser.
So it's it's taking snapshots of the code at that certain time and then it's going to calculate the
total amount of time.
So that's not going to be the real time of execution because you're using this time the console.
That time, it's just going to be a rough approximation.
So and this will be different every time, which makes it not really a reliable thing to rely on.
But if you if you assess, you know, a different part of your code.
So if we add another one down here, you'll be able to get some relative complexity.
So you could say, you know, it may not be able to say that this will always be 100 milliseconds.
But what you will be able to do is if something else is consistently, consistently 10 times less than
that, then you could say, well, this is ten times faster than this or this is, you know, so you
can make those kind of assumptions.
But you shouldn't really think too hard about this number that ends up coming out, because there's
just so many factors.
Your browser, your CPU and all that kind of stuff is going to really make this number not totally accurate.
So anyway, how do you use it while you say console dot time and then you enter in a label?
So this is my label.
I'm calling it long runner.
And then at the end I just say console dot time end with long runner as the name of that label of the
profile that I want to time now, you could also, you know, add multiple ones.
So if I want to just do something like this where I just say console time test and then I can, you
know, go below that and just, you know, do a single variable or something.
Konsta X equals four and then say console dot time and test that will do a second profile after that.
So this is just to show you multiple times in the same thing.
So if you want to you know, if you have a really complicated function or process in your app, you
could sprinkle these cancelled time, you know, with numbers in front of them, be good.
And by doing that, you'll get a sense of which parts of this app are taking the longest.
So, you know, in this example.
So you could just see here at the bottom, right.
The long runner is one hundred and thirty six milliseconds and my little test is only two milliseconds.
So if you were if this was like really complicated bunch of functions, you know, you could have some
nested function calls in here.
You have nested function calls in here and you're wrapping the code.
So, you know, the code is going to get timed everything in between those two statements.
So by doing this, we just assumed, OK, well, this is going to be two milliseconds over here and
then this one is going to be one hundred and thirty milliseconds.
So we're we're making that assumption, OK, this one is two milliseconds.
That's really not a whole lot, but one hundred and thirty milliseconds, that's something we should
look into.
So that's just profiling in general with consultor time.