All right, guys.
So in this one, we're going to talk about console table and we're going to use it in a kind of clever
way to actually see the data inside of this minesweeper game over here.
And by using the console to table command, we're going to be able to cheat and just see all the bombs
in this and we're going to use the console table to actually see that graphed for us here in the console
to log here.
So normally, you know, you do console a log and output some text in here.
But if you want to actually see some, you know, spatial data, like a couple of nested arrays, that's
not really going to be helpful for you.
You're going to have to, you know, log those out in a series of numbers or something.
And it's going to be really hard to see the actual data.
Right, in terms of visuals.
So what we're going to do with this, when you use the console to table command now, we could use this
with objects or arrays.
So basically, I have my app in here on my left.
I have my initial state and we're just going to go ahead and start using this just console on a table.
And inside here, we're going to wrap we're going to use initial state and we're just going to do initial
state just so you could see what's going on here.
So right on over here on my right, you could see in the console we now have a table displayed, which
is really awesome.
We also get the actual object here.
Normally, if you just did console a log, you get this.
So you could see here we have a grid, which is an array of res.
And in here we have this table.
Now, you could see the grid.
It's being it's showing the the arrays inside of the grid.
So there's eight arrays inside of the grid for each row.
There's eight rows.
Right.
And then each one of those rows has eight columns or eight cells.
So that this is cool.
But this is not really giving us the grid.
Right.
So we're going to do is we're going to actually just do first.
We're going to show you what happens if we add another statement here.
We're going to do grid.
So now we're just doing the grid.
So this this cool, right.
We could see here we have the eight by eight grid here, but in each one we're getting the grid cell.
So you could see here we have eight by eight grid cells and that's cool.
But we're not really seeing any information in each in each cell.
Right.
So how would we actually see the information in that cell?
Well, what we could do is we could map over that data and just log a new type of data.
So log a map over that data with whatever we want to display.
So if we want it to display whether they had a bomb or not, we could do that or the number inside.
So if you go back here to components, you could see over here we have the cell and you could see here
we have the different properties of the cell.
We've got the is mine that we've got is empty.
So you could do whatever you want here.
You could see the value.
You could see the number.
So let's try the number first.
So what we're going to do here, we're going to go up and we're going to now just go over here where
we did this table.
And we're going to do instead is we're going to say initial state grid.
I'm going to do a map.
So we're going to map over this data.
And in the map function, what we're going to do is we're going to get a bunch of rows.
Right.
And we're going to do is we're going to return the rows, that map.
So we're going to map over the rows.
We're going to turn another map over those rows.
And inside of here, we're going to end up doing is we're going to say so each cell.
So cell, we're going to map over the cell.
And then finally, we're just going to say cell dot and.
OK, so now you could see something save this, so it makes it easier to see, OK, so it's going to
put it all on one line here.
So let me just collapse this so you could see that.
There you go.
So there we go.
That's returning the number of that value.
And as you can see now, we have access to all those numbers here.
So let's just see if that's correct.
So we know that if we click on one of those, we're going to get that number of how many minds are around
that number.
So if we go down here, let's just try and stretch this out a little bit.
OK, and we are going to see, OK, so we have zero, we have one over here and that the let me just
move this around really quick.
Let's move this up so you could see so you could see we have right in here, first row is going to be
zero zero.
And then we have the second row, we have a one.
So if I go up here and I click it, that's a one just to show you, I'm not making this up.
We go down over here.
This is should be a two.
Go so that that's the two right there.
Awesome.
So now we don't have any data about these bombs.
So if I start clicking on the zeros, the zero might be a bomb, I believe.
So if I just start clicking over here on these zeros, this so we've got one.
This is going to be a one.
And there you go.
That's a bomb.
Bomb a zero.
So this isn't really going to help me cheat.
So we're going to do is instead we're going to say cell that is mine.
And then if it's a mine, we're going to just put a B or else just nothing.
So there we go.
So now we could see we have the grid here, eight by eight of whether or not these are bombs.
So that should do it.
So now if we just start clicking.
So if I start clicking, OK, I know that's a bomb.
Right?
So if I go, these three should be not bombs.
Next one.
This one's here.
These should all not be bombs except for this one on the bottom.
So we know this column over here, this third one in should be all not bombs, this one up here.
And then we go down here.
This should be a bomb.
So I think if we right.
Click, we'll flag that flag these two.
And then we go up here, we flag this one.
This is a very fun way to play the game.
I think it's pretty fun there.
Go down here and that's a bomb.
This bomb is a bomb.
This is a bomb.
And.
This should be the last cell, so hopefully I'll win the game, so we go, I won.
So not very fun way to play, but this is how you use console that table to cheat or to see the better
view of that data.
So thanks.