All right, challenge nine, so in this example, as you can see, we have the objective up here that
says can't remove a child from parent and it says, please see if you can fix.
So we're going to go ahead and just open that sandbox down here and you should see this.
So as you could see here on the right, we look at this app.
We have our parent and then we have some children and these look like buttons.
So the objective here says we can't remove a child from parent.
So first thing we're going to try and do is follow the instructions on this button that says click to
remove.
We're clicking on the button and nothing is happening.
So if we head on over to our strategy guide, you will see we followed the first thing here.
We confirmed the bug.
And now we are just gathering some clues to see if there are errors in the console.
So if we go down here, we'll see.
OK, we have a warning that says each child should have a unique Kiprop.
So that's something we should definitely look into.
But that doesn't seem related or, you know, to our issue.
Right.
So we don't have an error in here.
This is just a warning.
So as far as errors go, if we click, we see no error.
So we can just kind of cross that out so we don't have errors.
So since we have no error over here, we're going to go and try and inspect some dumb elements and search
for suspected components.
So luckily, this is a very simple component.
As you could see here, we are not importing any other external components into this app.
And so that means that all of our codes are going to be right here.
And if we just browse this, we could see we have a child here.
And as you could see, we have a clip handler, so that's the next thing to do usually is when you're
trying to troubleshoot an issue that isn't really defined that well.
Right.
Like we don't have an arrow pointing us to a specific stack trace.
You're going to want to find the code that actually is related to that issue.
Right.
So we're clicking and that's an issue related to clicking.
So we're going to look for that component.
We've already found it.
You could also inspect with the react dev tools and try and find the component that way if it's more
difficult.
And so, OK, so what we're going to do now is we're just going to copy this link over here just so
we have a more direct way of interacting with this app as if it were a real app.
And if we were going to we were to go down here and open up the dev tools.
You could see here we have that warning, that same warning.
So this is the code sandbox console, not the same exact thing as the real Chrome Developer Tools console.
So we're just going to keep moving along now.
So first thing, as I said before, we're going to try and find that code.
So probably quickest way to do that is to just look at the react components tab here to find that child.
So just finding any child and looking for here the view source for that element.
So right here you could see this.
So it's going to click on that and that's going to show us where the child is.
Now, as you could see here, we have that click handler.
And so what we're going to do here is check the click function.
So this is removed, right?
So if we go and we find where a remove is and so we could just search for remove.
And as you could see, there is no remove here, so as you could see, the remove is a function passed
into the child.
So a prop here, right.
So the child is rendered up here and it's passed in a prop that is removed child.
And so this is the actual function that gets called.
So we're going to go ahead and put a break point there.
So this if this doesn't work, you can refresh breakpoints, aren't working for me right now.
So if I refresh now, it's working.
I can put the breakpoint here and now when I click, I can actually get into the scope of this function.
So as you can see here, we have just a function argument here that's removed I.D. So as you can see
here, this code.
So I'm not trying to analyze what's going on here.
First, as you could see, we have react hooks up here initializing with an array which looks right.
And then we have children, which is the array, and then we have set children.
So the code here is looping over the children.
Right.
And it's looping over the children here with this map function, rendering a child and the set children
function.
Here is what is supposed to set the new array.
Right.
And what we want to do is want to remove that child.
Trying to get rid of one of these.
So you would expect the array that's being passed in here to have one less element.
So this new array here is being created by this filter function.
And you could determine that is if, you know, function by Googling this filter function, which is
a regular array function.
So we won't do that, just a basic JavaScript array function on the array.
And so what that does is it passes in a callback and this callback is filtering based on this comparison,
which is returned from the callback, which is if true, the component remains in the array.
If false, it is removed from the array.
So this expression here must be false.
Right.
And what this is referring to is this ID and the removed ID.
The ID is the local ID in this callback.
So it it loops over the children.
As you could see here, the IDs of the children are the values.
Right.
So just matching up the variables now the ID is then compared to the removed ID.
So I would have to figure all of that out by myself before I even understand this bug.
Right.
Because I just did that investigation here for you.
And now we understand how the filtering is supposed to work, how the children are actually supposed
to be removed.
Now let's actually debug what's going wrong.
So if I hover over this, I see this is a class removed ID now.
I'm not expecting a class here.
I'm expecting a number.
Right.
So why is this a class?
Well, in the removed method here, you could see I just pass on this function, I just pass on the
function again.
So this is it looks like the native kallick handler.
This is the, you know, the standard click and learn, react.
We're not passing in any ID or we're not recreating any methods.
We're just passing in that same method.
So what does the unclick signature on Kallick method in react?
You would just kind of Google that.
This is probably simple.
You probably already are aware of this, but just sometimes it's good to refresh on pretty simple things.
Right?
So we so we just found this react class here, this react here for handling events.
So you can see here this is an event.
Right?
So it's it's an event that's being passed in.
So this class here, you could see it's a synthetic event.
So how did I figure that out?
Because this is the same callback I'm just passing in this function, a matching with the the you know,
the same the standard click handler for this.
It's always going to be this is you define this variable if you don't know.
So you define this prop here and it's a synthetic event.
So at the end of the day, what are we trying to do?
We're trying to get the ID of the child.
Right.
So how do you get the idea of a child from a synthetic event?
So if you go down here, we see our child is actually passing in that ID.
And so here is the idea of the child.
So if I want to do another complex Google search for how to get ID from synthetic events.
So.
This is the first kind of thing that comes up from that I'm looking here and so as you could see here.
This person is trying to do this, and you can see here, this person tries this event target get attribute
ID and so there's another person there.
So, you know, you can see people are just responding to this.
Let's keep going.
And as you can see here, so this is the type of thing where you're going to try to investigate this,
the the signature of that.
Right.
So so there's a couple solutions to this.
Like I said, you could just do that.
Let's so as we're in here, we're in this thing, this removed I.D. is actually the event handler.
So that would be so.
But we're just going to so we could do first is actually change this to be.
And then we'll just put this here now as E!
All right, so just renaming that variable to be easy and I put my break point back there and I just
refresh or I just click on one of these children again.
Now I have the E, so if I go into my console, I can now just test certain very I could just test certain
variables.
Right.
So I could say idot value or I could say idot target.
And I think that one person said idot target get attribute.
Right.
Supposedly if I'd say this and then I find the ID I get no.
So Iida target.
Let's look at that.
So that's a button.
So, so the Iida target.
This is the button that I clicked on.
Right.
But this is not the react child.
This is not the actual child ID.
Right.
So the button down here is where the ideas.
So it doesn't look like based on the target of the event that was clicked on, that I would be able
to actually even get the ID.
So that's your first clue that I can't resolve this without changing this callback, because with this
callback, I don't have access to this child.
Right.
I don't have access to this ID.
So what do I need to do?
I need to create a new callback.
And so I'm going to show you how to do that.
So what you would do here is so first thing is we're going to actually pass in the ID here.
We're going to leave this as it was.
And so how it was before or if I just undo my changes, the what this was here is the removed ID, right.
So we need to figure out how to pass a function in here.
So this is actually simple enough as going in here, creating a new arrow function and then just saying
remove child ID like this.
So what this is doing is I'm creating a new function in here to call the remove child function here
with the idea of the child or the idea of the children.
So I am overriding the buttons standard event here, which is E right.
So this is now the the new function passing in the event handler.
But instead I'm just saying I don't care about this.
I'm ignoring this.
I don't care about the synthetic event.
All I want to do is when you click on it, I want to remove this ID and this idea scoped to this map
callback.
And so this ID will always refer to that current child.
So now if I save this.
And I go back to my app or I just go over here, you could see I'm clicking and now they're being removed.
So I could go back to my app once again and refresh and just confirm that the ID is actually being selected
there.
And as you could see, the removed I.D. is nine, it's correctly passed in from the child that I clicked
on.
So that's this challenge.