[Autogenerated] Hello, everyone. My name
is Sam are bona I love coding and I love
teaching people to goat. I work at agile
labs dot com, where we create interactive
content to help people learn coding.
Welcome to this. No, Jess. Getting started
course from Pluralsight note is an amazing
run time. It's simply a game changer. Once
I got comfortable working with note, I
never looked back to anything else I used
before knows I'm excited to show you how
note is going to make your life as a back
end developer so much easier. I mostly
write code in this course, and you should
do to. Learning to code is mostly a
practical experience. Try to do and redo
the examples I'll present in this course
and try to expand their scope and
challenge yourself with every piece of
knowledge that you learn. Some of the
topics that we will cover in this course
include the what, Why and how of No Jazz.
A review of the modern JavaScript Concepts
notes Ruppel and Command Line interface
Notes Patterns. Global's and Utilities
Notes Package Manager and PM Working with
common Jess Modules, Notes, Concurrency
and Event Loop. Working with web servers
and working with the operating system. By
the end of this course, you should be
comfortable creating and executing code
for note, understand the big pictures of
the runtime and build simple back and
applications with IT. I hope you'll join
me on this journey to learn the basics of
the excellent no just run time in this getting started course at Pluralsight.