[Autogenerated] Hello. Thanks for tuning
in to this course. My name is Sam URL
Bouna. And this is the no just-as getting
started course at Pluralsight. This is a
beginner, of course, for the nauseous from
time. I won't be assuming that you know
anything about node. But I will be
assuming that, you know, the basics of
programming and a little bit of the
JavaScript language itself. This course
has a module about modern JavaScript. But
I do not cover the basic concepts of the
language there. If you've never worked
with JavaScript, IT for this course might
be a bit challenging for you. And if you
get yourself a bit more familiar with the
JavaScript language itself, this course
will be a lot easier to digest if you know
JavaScript. But you don't know the modern
JavaScript changes that happened in the
past few years. That's okay. This module
will get you covered. If you're expecting
this course to make you a professional. No
developer, I need to get your expectation
straight. This is a short course toe on
Lee. Get you started on your path to
learn. Note. It's just a first step. No,
it is a big framework, with many built in
modules and concepts, which you need to
learn. But they require much longer time
and bigger effort. This course is designed
to help you get ready for that. Here are
the main topics covered in this course,
and you can see them here in order. First,
we'll go over some of the core features in
note and how to execute scripts and work
with the command line. Then we'll do a
review of the modern features in
JavaScript that you can execute in your
note yesterday. After that, we'll talk
about notes. Package manager npm. Then
probably the most important part about
this course is when we start talking about
modules and note and how note handles slow
operations. Then we'll go over some
examples about working with web servers
and note both natively and with external
tools. And finally, we'll talk about how
to work with the operating system files on
commands. Ah, lot more features in the
note. A P I will not be covered by this
course. For example, this course will not
cover C plus plus add ons, buffers and
streams, modules like Crypto Z lip, DNA's
Net and di Gram and many others that I
classify as Mawr advanced concepts. The
good news is that I created an advanced
note course here at Pluralsight is well,
so after finishing this getting started
course, I think he'll be ready to take a
deeper dive and explore the other advanced
concepts that I cover in this advanced no
Jazz course. Here I am recording this
course on a Mac book. If you have a
Windows machine, things are going to be a
bit different for you. Note itself is a
bit different on Windows than it is on
Linux and Mac. You might run into problems
that I don't. If you do run into problems
that block your progress in this course,
please don't hesitate to ask for help in
the discussion section of this course. If
you have a modern Windows machine, one
option that might work a lot better for
you is to install the Windows subsystem
for Linux. This option will give you the
best of both worlds. You'll have your
Windows operating system running Linux
without needing to reboot so you can work
a Linux file system with your Windows
editor, for example, which I think is
great I've tested this option, and I can
confidently say that this will probably be
the future of writing code for node on
Windows. No, it is usually deployed on
Linux machines and production. So by using
a Linux environment on your Windows
machine, you'll be closer to the way
your-app ligations are running in
production. And that's always a good win.
I often get complains that my Pluralsight
courses are a bit fast, and it's hard for
people to keep up. This is true, and this
course will be no exception. It's not that
I am a fast talker. It's the fact that
these courses are tightly edited with no
breaks. Ah, lot of content is
intentionally jammed into a short course.
That, however, does not mean that you
can't manually give yourself breaks. The
most important button in the Pluralsight
video player is probably the pause button.
Use it often. For example, every time I
ask question, pause the video and think of
it every time I use something that you've
never seen before, pause the video and
Google IT. Rewind and watch things many
times if you need to. If you're used to
the pace and breaks of workshops, you'll
find the pace here much faster. The pause
and rewind _______ are your best friends.
Also, in some of the modules of this
course, I'll be presenting you with
challenges, positive video and do these
challenges. The best way to learn is
really to do. I'll be also asking a lot of
questions in this course, and I'll answer
these questions right after. But I want
you to imagine yourself in an interview
for a job about no just-as and treat these
questions as if they were your interview
questions. Try to answer them first before you listen to me answering them.