[Autogenerated] Okay, so you can probably
answer this question, but this is a first
step course in notes, so let me start at
the very beginning. What is no just-as
here is probably the simplest definition
of note. It's JavaScript on your back end
servers before note. That was not a common
or easy thing to do. JavaScript was mainly
a front end thing. This isn't really a
complete definition, because note offers a
lot more than executing JavaScript on the
server. In fact, the execution off
JavaScript on the server is not done by
note at all. It's done with a virtual
machine. PVM, like V eight or chakra note,
is just the coordinator. It's the one who
instructs the VM like V eight to execute
your JavaScript so note is better defined
as a wrapper around the VM like V eight.
I'm going to use the term V eight in this
course because that's the default VM in
note. But you can totally run note with
other VMS if you need to, so when you
write JavaScript or note, note will pass
your JavaScript to-be eight v eight will
execute that JavaScript and tell note what
the result is and note will make the
results available to you. That's the
simple story, but no, it is a bit more
useful than just that. Besides, the fact
that enables us to execute JavaScript on a
server, which is done through a seamless
integration with V eight Note comes with
some handy built in modules providing rich
features through easy to use asynchronous
APIs in the next module. We'll talk about
that and a few other reasons why
developers are picking know just-as over
many other options when it comes to creating servers on their back ends.