[Autogenerated] we learned that note
allows us to easily execute jobs shipped
good on servers, but this is not really
impressive. It was even possible to do
that before ____. So let me put the big
question out here. Why? Note since you're
watching this course now, you probably
know reason or two. Why? No, it is a great
thing to learn. Let me make sure everyone
knows all the reasons before we commit to
this journey. So besides being an easy way
to execute and work with JavaScript on the
server note comes with some feature rich,
built in modules. This makes it a great
platform for tools, not just a platform to
host back in servers. But here's the big
deal about the modules that are packaged
with load. All of them offer asynchronous
AP ice that you can just use and not worry
about threads. Yes, you can do a
synchronous programming in note. Do things
in parallel without needing to deal with
threads, which is probably the biggest
benefit of using or in time like note. And
if the built in packages were not enough
for you, you can build highly performing
packages using C plus plus note is
JavaScript, but it has first class support
for C plus plus add ons, creating
dynamically linked, shared objects that
you can use directly in note. Of course,
you can also write your add ons and
JavaScript, too, if you want. Note also
ships with a powerful do ______, which
I'll show you how to use in the last
module of discourse. No, it also has some
handy generic utilities that enhance the
JavaScript language and provide extra AP
ice to work with data types, for example,
and we're not done. In fact, these last
two points on this slide is, in my
opinion, the most important ones. And this
is why this course will have full modules
dedicated to these last two points. I
wrote an article about the exact topic of
Why note? With a lot more details around
the last two points in the slide. Let me
go over this article quick and summarize
it here for you. This article is about why
react Developers love note, but it really
applies to just note in general, why
JavaScript Front end developers in general
love note So note is a platform for tools.
So even if you don't want to host your
whole application in note. Note is a great
platform for tools and the reason It's
great because you have a lot of options.
You have so many tools out there because
no, it was the first major job script
execution engine that ships with a
reliable package manager, which is called
npm. We did not have a package manager for
a long time in the JavaScript world, so
npm is actually very revolutionary in here
because it changed the way we work and
share JavaScript. And no, it was the
enabler here. Because npm is part of note,
npm is basically the world's largest
collection of free and reusable code. You
can make a feature rich no delegation just
by using code that's freely available on
npm. Npm is a reliable package manager,
which comes with CLI that we're going to
explore and that CLI makes it really easy
to install third-party packages and in
general, share your own code and reuse
your own code. And the npm registry, where
the packages get hosted, has so many
options, and by so many I mean hundreds of
thousands of options off free tools that
you can just install and use in your
system. The other big thing about Node is
that it comes with a reliable module
dependency manager, which is different
than npm. This module dependency manager
is also another thing that we do not have
in the JavaScript world. More accurately,
we did not have for a long time because
job script today has what's known as app
JavaScript modules. But these modules,
despite being part of the language
officially, are still a work in progress.
They're still not completely supported by
all implementations nodes. Common jazz
dependency system has been available since
node was released, and it opened the door
to so much flexibility in how we could
JavaScript. IT is widely used even for
JavaScript that gets executed in the
browser because node has many tools to
bridge the gap between its common just
system on what browsers console work with
today, npm, along with common Js, make a
big difference when you work with any
JavaScript system, not just the JavaScript
that you execute on the server or in the
browser. If, for example, you have a fancy
fridge monitor that happens to run on
JavaScript, you can use note for the tools
to package toe organize to manage
dependencies and to bundle you code and
ship it to your fridge. Note also is not
just for hosting JavaScript servers, but
it's also a very good option to do so
because of its non blocking asynchronous
nature, which you can use without dealing
with threats. This is the main point that
made no different than any other system
that was popular before. Newt. Note comes
with first glass support and easy a piece
for many asynchronous operations, like
reading or writing files, consuming data
over the network and even compressing and
encrypting data. You can do all these
operations in node a synchronously without
blocking the main execution threat. This
works great with V eight because V eight
itself is single threaded, and this is
true for both note and browsers. You only
get a single precious thread toe work
with, and it's very important to not block
IT. For example, in your browser. If your
website blocks that single thread for,
say, two seconds, the user cannot scroll
up and down during these two seconds in
note. If an incoming SD to-be connection
to your Web server was handled
synchronously, rather than a synchronously
that will block the single thread. And
your whole web server cannot handle any
other connection while the synchronous
operation is active. And that's a big
deal. No, the asynchronous AP ICE also
work great for cloud applications in
general because a lot of these operations
are asynchronous by nature. And, of
course, by using note, you are committing
to the flexible JavaScript language, which
is used on every website. Today. It is the
most popular programming language, and
that statement will continue to be true
for decades to come. And despite its
problems, JavaScript is actually a good
language today. With note, you get to have
a single language across the full stack,
use jobs shipped in the browser and use it
for the back end as well, which means less
Centex to keep in your head and Les Mis
takes over. All This also means that you
can have a better integration between your
front and code and you're back in code.
You can actually share code between these
two sides, and using job script on the
back end also means that teams can share
responsibilities among different project
projects. Don't need a dedicated team for
the front end and a different team. For
the back end, you would eliminate some
dependencies between teams. The project
can be a single team, the JavaScript
people. They can develop a _ _. _. They
can develop weapon network servers and
they can develop rich interactive
websites. Note, of course, has a few cons,
which are, interestingly, the same pro
points if you just look at them with
different bias. For example, the non
blocking nature is just a completely
different model of thinking and reasoning
about code. And if you've never done it
before, it is going to feel weird. At
first. You need time to get your head
wrapped around this model and get used to
it. And the big npm registry with so many
options means that for every single thing
you need to do, you have many options to
pick from, and some people hate that. You
need to constantly research these options
and make mental effort to pick the better
options. These options usually have major
differences, and also npm enabled shipping
smaller and smaller code, which means you
need to use MAWR and more packages. It's
not unusual for a note application to use
300 or more packages. This is both a good
thing and a bad thing, depending on who
you ask. I think it's a good thing.
Smaller packages are easier to control and
maintain and scale, but you do have to
make peace with the fact that you'll be
using a lot of them. Smaller code is
actually why note is named node. In note,
UI build simple, small single process
building blocks, notes that could be
organized with good networking protocols
to have them communicate with each other
and scale up to build large distributed
programs. Scaling a node application is
not an afterthought. It's built right into the name.