[Autogenerated] I love thinking about real
life analogies that compare with the
coding world. One of my favorite analogies
about coding in general is how it can be
compared to writing cooking recipes. The
recipe in this analogy is the program, and
the cook is the computer. In some recipes,
you can use ready items and tools like the
cake mix that you can use to make
cupcakes, and that's specially shaped pan
that makes it easier to create cupcakes
when compared to coding. You can think of
these ready items and tools for recipes to
including and using a package of code
written by others in your own code note.
And it's powerful. Npm package manager has
their place In this analogy, npm is a
place where you can download code written
by others. Within this analogy, you can
think of npm as the store where you
purchase the ready items and tools. You
just bring them to your project with a
simple command, and you can think of no
jazz itself as your kitchen as it allows
you to execute lines in your coding
recipes by using built in modules like the
Oven and the sync. Imagine trying to cook.
Without these built in modules in your
kitchen, that would be a lot harder. And
just because you have these built in
modules in your kitchen, that doesn't mean
you have food ready to consume. Note is
your kitchen by itself. It's not enough,
but it does make your task to write useful
code much more easier throughout this
course. You'll hear me use the term call
back all the time, so let me quickly tell
you about it. Call Back is just a fancy
term for a function. In note. We call the
function a callback function if Node will
call it back for us at a later point in
the time of the program. This is done
through an asynchronous method. Here's the
simple callback function, which usually
received data as its argument, and we just
pass its reference here to some
asynchronous method, and that asynchronous
method will get the callback invoked when
the data is ready. I have another analogy
for you about call backs when you order a
drink from Starbucks in the store, not in
the drive thru. They'll take your order
and your name and tell you to wait to be
called when your order is ready. After a
while, they call your name and give you
what you asked for. That name you gave
them is the callback function here. They
called it with the object that you
requested the drink. So let me modify this
generic example of a callback to
demonstrate the Starbucks example. The
callback function is the name you give
during your Starbucks order. It's a
function that be called with some data,
which is you already drink when you place
your order. That's an asynchronous method,
because your order will take some time and
they don't want to block the order. And Q.
While your order is getting prepared,
that's why they'll call you back. And
that's the pattern of callback functions
in note. Now, modern JavaScript in Modern
Note started adopting another pattern for
asynchronous programming, which we call
promises, and the promise is a little bit
different than a callback To understand
promises. Imagine that you ask someone to
give you something, but they give you
something else. Call it a mystery object.
They promise you that this mystery object
might eventually turn into the thing that
you originally asked for this promise.
Mystery object can always turn into one of
two possible forms. One form is associated
with success and the other with failure.
This is like if we ask a chicken for a
chick and the chicken gives us an egg
instead, that egg might successfully
turned into a check or it might die and be
useless if you like analogies like these,
I have a lot more of them, and most of
these technologies are really related to
note. For example, see the reactive
programming one and the errors versus Exceptions one.