[Autogenerated] follow this video for
instructions on how to install. Note. If
you've successfully installed note, you
should see the following three commands
available globally in your system. First,
the note command itself, which, if you run
it without any argument, you'll get into
this interactive program where you can
type and execute JavaScript. Here's a
quick test of how modern your notice. I
typed the test for you right here under
this GitHub. Just go find this code and
then copy this line here the first line
and paste it into the nodes. Interactive
session. Don't worry. If you don't
understand this, it's just a test of your
note capabilities. If this line was
executed successfully without any errors
like it did for me here you have a good
version of note. If you get an error here,
you should upgrade your note for this
course. This course has a modern
JavaScript module where I'm going to
explain the modern concept this simple
line is using. You can also test if your
note has the new promises. AP Ice. Using
these two calls in here, you tell that
promise. If I should return a function
like this and require F s dot promises
should return an object of the full F s, a
p I just like this. Also, if you want to
use Eckman script modules with node, the
import statement should be available. And
it should give this exact specific error
in the rebel here because we can't use it
in a rebel, but it's available for
modules. So if these calls are giving you
errors or undefined objects, it will be a
good idea for you to upgrade your note
before starting this course. The other two
global commands that you should have our
npm and MPX. You get these as well. When
you install node, we'll talk about these
commands in the course module dedicated
for npm. If you see these commands working
successfully for you, you can skip the
rest of this installation instructions
video to install node on windows. You can
simply download the installer from the No,
just the order website and granite
Locally. This way you'll be installing
note natively on the Windows operating
system. But remember what I said about
node on windows in the overview video
note. Natively on Windows is not really
ideal, but if it's your only option don't
let that stop you. If you were able to get
a Linux subsystem working for you on
Windows great. All you need is to
commands. Let me show you how to find them
here real quick in this downloads page
scroll and find the article about
installing note via a package manager.
Click that you can also just Google this
exact title here. If the U I of the note
website has changed, the Linux
distribution that you used in your
subsystem is probably open to hear. So
click on that link and under the section
here, you'll find lines to install the
recent version of note. So these are the
two lines that you need in your subsystem
or Linux in general. You should also
invoke this other line here about build
essentials just in case you need to
install any Native Addams in the future.
On Mac, you can download and install no
directly. But if you're already using the
excellent Homebrew package manager, you
can just use that All you need is brew
install note, and this will give you the
latest note. If you don't have homebrew on
your Mac, you should really take a look at
it. It's pretty cool. If you have an older
version of note running through homebrew,
the command you need here is brew upgrade
Note. Just like that, there is another
option that works on both Mac and Linux,
and that is envy M node version manager. I
like this option because it allows you to
run multiple versions of note and switch
between them using a simple command. If
you find yourself in a situation where you
need to work on a project that use
different versions of node, N. V. M will
help you here. That's it for installing
note. Don't forget to make sure these
lines work for you on your new note you just installed.