[Autogenerated] on the course reviews
light. There are references two folders
associated with the modules of this
course. These folders can be found on get
hub or under the exercise files section.
Here is the good help repository that I'll
be using throughout this course. It will
give us starting points for code templates
and let us focus our time on concepts
rather than wasting time typing simple
scripts. This report is hosted under
GitHub dot com slash gs complete slash n
gs and GS here is not getting started. You
can see the different folders for the
different modules right here. The same
content of this ripa is also available
under the exercise files on the course
page. If you don't have access to get up,
your first step is to clone this repo
locally to your machine. To clone this
repo, copy the NGS repo. You're Ellen here
and type the following command in your
terminal Get clone the repo your URL. This
will create a directory named NGS under
your current working directory so seedy
into this new NGS And in here you can see
the list of numbered folders. Let me open
up An editor here on this repo. So within
the top level folders, which are
associated with modules in the course
you'll see folders and files representing
videos of the course module. In order.
However, some of the course videos will
not have folders, and some folders here
might have multiple files representing the
examples we are going to cover in its
associated video. The files are usually
numbered in the order off their example in
the video and all these files in the NGS
Repo is your starting point for each
exercise we're going to go through in this
course. One thing I'd like to point out
before we begin. This course has many
modules. We use the word module here to
describe a section in the course. The word
module is also heavily used, with note to
refer to a file or folder of code. To make
this a little bit less confusing, I will
say course module every time I refer to a
section of the course, So let's jump to
the next course module and get you
properly introduced to the wonderful nauseous Runtime