[Autogenerated] in this getting started
module will explore the node command and a
few global features like timers, and the
process objects. If you type in the note
command without a script for it to
execute. Note will start a rebel session
rappels stands for read evil print loop.
And it's a very convenient way to quickly
test simple JavaScript and no documents.
You can type in any job script here in the
rebel, for example, a math, random call
just like that. And then you press, enter
and note, will read your line evaluated,
print the result and then go back to
waiting for further lines. This is where
the rebel got its name. Read a line
evaluated, print its output and loop until
the user exits the rebel. Note how the
print step happened automatically. We
didn't need to add any instructions to
print the result. Node will just print the
result of each line you type. This is
cool, but keep in mind that some lines
will not have any results at all. The note
rappel will print undefined in this case.
For example, if you define a variable like
this, let answer equal 42 and you enter,
you'll see undefined. This is because this
is a statement in JavaScript. It's not an
expression, it does not have any output.
And this is why the ripple printed
undefined as the output of this statement.
Don't let that confuse you. On the other
hand, let's type out an expression. For
example. Three. The number equal equal
three. The character. This is a bullying
expression, by the way. Quick question. Do
you think this expression evaluates to
true or false? Well, this is one type of
question that can be easily answered
inside a node Rebel. You type it real
quick and enter, and there you go. This is
true. So this line was a JavaScript
expression, and the ripple printed its
result for us. Sometimes the expression
that you need to test might need multiple
lines. Let me clear this rebel session,
and I do that by pressing control and l.
This clears the session, and let's see an
example of multiple lines. Say that you
want to define a function that generates
today's date and test it out. You'll start
with the function name. Name IT today and
then begin with a curly brace, right. You
can hit Enter here. The notes. Rebel is
smart enough to detect that your line is
not done yet and it will go into this
multi line mode for you to type more so we
can type. Return New date Semi Colin hit.
Enter again, then the end Curly brace and
enter. And now note figured out that this
good can be executed and it did. Executed.
We can now use the Today function in the
rebel session. This rappel multi line mode
is limited. For example, if online three
you realize that you made a mistake on
line one, you cannot go back and edit line
one. In addition, you cannot type out
multiple expressions in the same multi
line session. Luckily, note has a more
featured editor right here. Inside
Durable. You type in adopt editor to open
it up, and when you do, you can type as
many lines as you need. For example, you
can define multiple functions or paste
code from the clipboard. When you're done
typing, you hit control D to have the
ripple evaluate your code. All the
functions that you defined in the editor
will now be available in your rebel
session. The dot editor Command is a rebel
command, and there are actually a few
other commands. You can see the list by
typing the dot help command the dot break
command, or it's not clear. Alias lets you
get out of some weird cases in the rebel
session. For example, when you paste some
code in notes, multi line mode and you are
not sure how maney curly braces you need
to get to and executable state, you can
completely discard your pace IT code by
using at dot break command. This saves you
from killing the whole session. To get
yourself out of simple situations like
this, the Docker exit command exits the
rebel, or you can simply press control de
the dot load and dot save commands can be
used to generate and use external note
scripts inside Europe. All this could be a
great time saver. Here is a fresh rebel
session. Let's say I started typing in
this rebel session. I defined one
function, and then I defined another
function, and then I define the third
function, and now I have some history in
this ripple session, and what I want to do
is I'd like to save all these functions to
an external file, to maybe review them
later or maybe commit them to get. All I
need to do is dot save and give it a file
name. I'm gonna call IT M seven Duchess.
And now, if I inspect the content of M
seven Dutch us, this file will have all
the lines that we previously typed in the
rebel session, which is really cool mawr.
Importantly, if later on we started a
brand new proposition and we wanted to
redefine the functions UI previously
defined in M seven judges, all we need to
do is use the dot load command with M
seven Digest as the argument. A node will
load all the lines in the file and
evaluate them. And now we have access to
the functions and variables defined in that file.