[Autogenerated] I need to emphasize the
importance of the tab key. If you're not
familiar with this powerful key, you're in
for a treat. The tap character itself is
not a very useful one, but the tap key is
the driver off a very powerful feature
called TAP Completion. You might be
familiar with that feature in your code
editor, but I'd like you to also be aware
that it works inside note rubble as well.
A single tap in the notes. Trouble can be
used for auto complete and a double tab,
which is pressing the tab key twice can be
used to see a list of possible things you
can type from whatever partially typed
string you have. For example, if you type
the characters see and then double tap on
that, you'll see all the possible keywords
and functions that start with C. You could
be defining constant or clearing a timer.
And if you single tap on something that
matches on Lee, a single option will be
out of completed. For example, crypto here
is the Onley cured that begins with C. R.
So if you single tap on cr crypto will be
auto completed, this is by the way, is not
about being lazy about typing the whole
thing. The usefulness of this tap
completion is about avoiding typing
mistakes and discovering what is
available. This latter point is important.
For example, say I want to know what a P I
functions and properties I can use on the
array class. I can type Ray. Note how I
used single tap for that. But then I can
type the dot character and double tap
after that. And there you go. These are
all the functions on properties that can
be used from the array class. This also
works on objects. If I have an array
object inside this rebel session, I can
use the same dot and then double tap trick
to get a list of all the methods available
on this object. If you can't remember the
name of the method you need, this list is
helpful. The tap completion discover
ability works anywhere. Do you remember
the special document? While you can see
them by double tapping on a single dot,
This discover ability also works on a
global level. If you double tap on an
empty line, everything that is globally
available appears This is a big list, but
it's a useful one. It has all the common
global's in the JavaScript language
itself, which you're probably familiar
with, like Ray number string and object
classes and built in libraries like math
and Jason on some top level functions. The
other Global's you'll see in this list are
the ones that are available in the know
Dreamtime itself. A few of these are truly
global in note, like the buffer class, the
process object and the various functions
to set and clear timers. The lower case
variables here, for example, DNA's Net
cluster and Ashley to-be. Those represent
the built in modules and note these our
notes powerful libraries that you get out
of the box, not how these are available
directly here in the ripple. But when
working with a regular note script, which
will do next, you'll need to require these
modules to be able to use them. One of the
useful rebels features that you can use
here is the underscore variable. This is
similar to the dollar sign question mark
feature In bash, IT stores the value of
the last evaluated expression. For
example, say that you executed a math,
random call. And after you did, you wanted
to put that same random value in a
constant. You can do that with the
underscore because it automatically stores
the last value you can use the underscore
variable in any place where you use a job
script expression. I could do something
like const random equal underscore to
place that same last random value in a constant