[Autogenerated] here is note. Hello World
Example. This simple script represents a
simple web server. You don't need to
install anything to run this script. This
is all nodes built in power. Don't worry
about figuring out what's going on in this
script just yet. We'll get there
eventually to execute this script with
note. You just specify the location of the
script as the argument for the node
command. You can actually see the location
of this script within the Projects folder
right here in the corner for my Adam
editor here. And I can also click this
region here to copy the full path for this
file. So now I'll go ahead and paste this
full path right here after the Note
Command, and this will execute the file.
As you can see, it reported back, that
server is running the script location that
you specify for a note. Command can also
be relative. So if I'm inside this one
getting started one Executing Scripts
directory and I specify node one Hello
world, just like that node will look for
the file in the current working directory
if the script that we're executing has a
running task like a Web server listening
for connections, for example, then Node
will continue running. Note that if the
script does not have a running task like
this other script here that just prints a
message node will execute this script and
exit immediately after that. And what
process exiting is a normal thing In a
note, Cluster node will not idle and use
resources unnecessarily okay, back to the
simple web server script and were executed
again. So now this simple web server
script is running and its task is active.
IT listens. For all the SD to-be
connections, however, this note process
will Onley use V eight when there are
actually to-be connections. Otherwise, V
eight will remain idle. Let's decipher
this simple web server. The first line
here is using the require function. This
is the first thing you need to learn about
nodes internal. The required function is
what you use to manage the dependencies
off your programs. You can use require to
depend on any library. Whether this
library is a built in one like Azure to-be
here or if it's ah third-party installed
library. This program here depends on the
built in HD to-be module. It's the module
that has the features of creating a Web
server. There are many other libraries
that you can use to create a Web server,
but this one is built in. You don't need
to install anything to use IT, but you do
need to require IT. Remember that when we
were in nodes rebel, this library was
available immediately without needing to
require IT. This is not the case with
executable scripts like this one. You
can't use any dependencies without
requiring them first. This line here
creates a server constant by invoking the
create server function on the HDTV module.
This function is one of the many that are
available under the http module AP. You
can use it to create a Web server, and IT
accept an argument that is known as the
request listener. This is a simple
function that node will invoke every time
there is a request to the created web
server. Remember this argument. As a
listener, this server will listen to
requests, and it will invoke the listener
function for each request. And this is why
this listener function receives the
request object as an argument. It's named
wreck here, but you can name it. Whatever
you need. The other argument this listener
function receives named raise here is a
response object. It is the other side of
the request connection. We can use this
object to write things back to the
requester. It's exactly what this simple
web server is doing its writing back using
the DOT end method and the Hello World
String. We'll learn about the dot end
method later in this course, but it can be
used as a shortcut to write data and then
end the connection. The create server
function on Lee creates the server. IT
does not activate IT. To activate this web
server, we need to invoke the dot listen,
function on the created server.
Dysfunction accepts many arguments like
what OS port to use for this server? The
last argument here is a function that will
be invoked once the server is successfully
running on that port. This example just
logs the message to indicate that the
server is now running. This listen
function is what actually keeps the note
process running. It's the task that will
keep the note runtime busy and not exit
while the server is running. If we go to a
browser and ask for initially to-be
connection on local host with the port
that was used in this script 40 to 42. In
this case, we will see the hello world
string that this example had in its
request. Listener, go ahead and try to
change this line and return something
else. You will need to restart the note
process to make the change work. Just kill
the process with control. See used the up
arrow to get the last executed command and
execute that again. If you refresh the Web
browser now, you should see the newly
returned strength. When we build a full
web search, for example, I'll show you how
to avoid needing to restart the server
every time you change something, because
this will be an annoying thing to keep
doing manually. This hello World script
uses the common GS module management
system. Every script that uses this
require key word here is classified by
note as a common JSON module. Note also
supports the JavaScript module management,
and you can use that in two ways, either
by naming the file with the dot M. J s
extension, which I'll show you right here
or by setting the whole project to use app
JavaScript modules. I'll show you that
option in the npm course module. So let me
copy this one. Hello world dot Js file
keeping the content as is and given IT at
dot m j s extension. This time, if you try
to run this script node will complain
about the require keyword because it
understood that this is an Acma script
module because of its extension. And with
Acma script modules, we don't use the
require keyword at all. We use the import
keyword Let's fix it. This is the problem
line To fix it, we use the following
import then the name of what you want to
import. In this case, it's HD to-be then
from the location of the module you're
importing or just the name for built in
modules like SDK to-be here. So import
something from module, path or name, and
this will now work. There's also another
Centex we-can use with import which is
called named imports. Let me show you that
you see, this creates server method that
we're using here through the SD to-be
object. Well, we can import that
particular method using this curly
brackets Centex and then use it directly
in the code. So instead of importing the
whole HD to-be object, we used a named
import and Onley imported what the script uses.