[Autogenerated] some of the popular global
functions in a browser environment are the
timer functions like Set time out and set
Interval? No, Jess has an A P I for these
functions as well and exactly matches the
browsers. A P I. These time or functions
can be used to delay or repeat the
execution off other functions, which they
receive as arguments. For example, this
code uses set time out to delay the
printing of this greeting message by four
seconds. The second argument to set time
out is the delay in milliseconds. This is
why we are multiplying for by 1000 here to
make it into four seconds. The first
argument to set time out is the function
whose execution will be delayed if we
execute this script, normally with the
note command note will pause for four
seconds, and then it'll print the greeting
and exit after that note that this first
argument to set time out is just a
function reference. It does not have to be
an in line function like this. For
example, this good here will do the same
job, but it uses a function defined before
said Time out. Note that if the function
that we pass to set time out receives
argument like this example here. Argument
123 and more. Then we can use the
remaining arguments in set time out to
pass these arguments to the delayed
function once it's executed with set time
out. Here's an example. Take a look at
this code and try to figure out what it
will do. The Rocks function, which is
delayed by two seconds except a WHO
argument and our set time out call, relays
the value Pluralsight as the WHO argument.
Executing the script will print out
Pluralsight rocks after two seconds. Time
for a challenge. Ready Using what you
learned so far about set time out. Print
the following two messages after their
corresponding delays. Print the message
Hello after four seconds after four
seconds, then print the message. Hello
after eight seconds after eight seconds.
This would be an easy challenge without
constraints, but we are not here to learn
just the easy stuff. I have a constraint
for you. You can Onley define a single
function in your script, which includes in
line functions. This means many set time
out calls will have to use the exact same
function. Okay, pause here and try it out.
I really hope that you will try to do
these course challenges because trust me
on this. It is the best way to get
comfortable with what you're learning. If
you just watch, you'll learn. But it will
be harder for you to retain and improve.
You do that when you start pushing your
limits and put yourself outside your
comfort zone. Here's how I'd solve this
challenge. I've made the one funk receive
DeLay argument and used that delay
argument in the printed out message. This
way, the function can print different
messages based on whatever delay UI pass
to IT. I then used the one funk in to set
time out calls, one that fires after four
seconds and another that fires after eight
seconds. Both of these set time out calls
also get a third argument to represent the
delay argument for the one funk. Executing
this script will print out the challenge
requirements. The first message after four
seconds and the second message after eight
seconds. But what if I ask you to print
the message every four seconds forever?
While you can put that time out in a loop
node offers the set interval is well,
which would accomplish exactly that. Just
use a set interval instead of set time
out. In this example, this code will print
its message every three seconds. Note will
print this message forever until you kill
the process with control C. Another cool
thing about these timers is that you can
cancel them with code. A call to set time
out returns a timer ID, and you can use it
with a clear time out call to cancel that
timer. Here's an example. This simple
timer here is supposed to fire after zero
milliseconds, making IT immediate, but it
won't because we are capturing the timer
ID and canceling IT right after with a
clear time out call. When we execute, the
script note will not print anything, and
the process will just exit. By the way,
there is another way to do set time out
with zero millisecond the time or a P. I
has another function. It's called set
immediate, and it's basically the same
thing as a set time out with a zero
millisecond. But we don't have to specify
a delay here. It's an immediate thing.
We'll see a practical case for this
function later in the course and just like
clear time out. There's also ah, clear
interval, which does the exact same thing
but for set interval calls. And there is
also a clear immediate which does the same
thing for set immediate calls. So as you
can hopefully see from this example,
executing something with set time out
after zero millisecond does not mean
executed right away, but rather it means
executed right away. After you're done
with everything else in this script, let
me make this point clear with an example.
Here's a simple set time out call that
should fire after half a second, but it
won't right after defining the timer UI
Block note synchronously with a big loop.
This is one with 10 zeroes in front of it,
So this is a 10 billion takes loop, which
basically simulate a busy CPU note can do
nothing while this loop is thinking. This
is, of course, a very bad thing to do in
practice, but I'll help you here to
understand that set time out DeLay is not
a guaranteed thing, but rather a minimum
thing. This 500 millisecond here means a
minimum delay of 500 milliseconds. In
reality, this script will take ah lot
longer to print its greeting line. It will
have to wait on the blocking loop to
finish first. Let's do one more challenge
on timers. Print the message. Hello World
Every second, but on Lee five times after
five times print the message done and let
the note process exit and you cannot use a
set time out call for this challenge.
Little hint. You need a counter here.
Okay, you can pause here. Hopefully, this
was an easy one. I initiated a counter
value as zero and then started as an
interval call, capturing its I. D. The
delayed function will print the message
and increment the counter each time inside
the delayed function. And if statement
will check if we're at five times by now.
If so, l Brent done and clear the interval
using the captured interval constant. The
interval delay is 1000 milliseconds. In
this file here, I've put a couple more
challenges for you to practice timers. I
will not solve these challenges here to
keep the course short, but I included the
solutions in this same folder in the course Rebo