[Autogenerated] so far. We used the note
command in two modes. To start a ripple
with no arguments and to execute the
script by using a single file path
argument. The Note command, which is often
called the CLI, also has options which
make it work differently. For example, the
desk V option makes it up with the version
of the note runtime and the DASH. P Option
makes IT execute a string and print out
its result, which I find super useful. For
example, if I want to see how Maney CP use
this machine has, I can use a call to the
built in OS module, which has a function
called CP Use and I can do dot lengthen
that to see the size of the returned
array. Similarly, here's another one liner
to see the version of the V eight used in
the current node installation. There are
many other options. You can see a full
list by using the dash H option. This
could be a big list so you can pipe IT on
the less command or its windows equivalent
to Pagine ate your way through this list.
Take a look at these options and
familiarize yourself with them. Don't
memorize anything except for the handy
dash p one. But just be aware of all the
things that you can do with this CLI. One
of these options also opens the door to
the options of V eight itself. Let's
explore that list using node dash Dash V
eight Dash options Pipe that on less as
well. Node will report all the V eight
options that it supports. These options
get past to-be eight, for example, to make
V eight. Always execute your job, script
and strict mode. You can pass the dash
dash. Use strict option. I wish this one
had a default value of true but
unfortunately, does not. The V eight
options are a really big list, and it's
mostly for advanced use. But let me tell
you a few more things about it. You'll see
some options that begin with the word
harmony. These flags usually control the
features that are still being tested. You
can use them by including their flags, but
just know that they are not final yet.
You'll see many options for tracing. If
you need V eight to give you more
debugging power, you can make it up, Put
more information. Some options control how
v eight behaves and also control its
limits. Other options will report
information or give you control over
what's usually not possible without them.
Do a quick scan on this list, but usually
if you think you might find helpful option
here, you can grip this list to search for
it. For example, you can grip for in
progress to see all the in progress
harmony flags for this particular note
version. In addition to all these flags,
the note CLI also supports some
environment variables that you can use to
change the process behavior. You can see
this list at the end of the dash H output.
For example, this node debug environment
variable instructs core modules to print
out any debug information they have. If we
execute the Hello World script with no
debug set to SD to-be, which is the core
module used there, then on each incoming
connection, that HDTV module will print
out some debugging messages. Most node
libraries, including the packages that
you'd install on use support a note debug
flag. You can give this environment
variable. A comma separated list of the
modules for which you want to enable
debugging another hand. The environment
variable is this note path. One by
default. Node has certain paths. IT used
to look up modules you require in your
code, and you can use this environment
variable to override that. These are the
built in environment variables, but you
can have your note process use any other
environment variables as well. Let's talk about that next.