[Autogenerated] you can use the note
command with custom environment variables.
For example, we could do something like
Val one equal 10 Val to equal 20. Note. No
commas here, then continue to execute a
note script like this in the notes script.
We can access the values in the
environment variables using the process
object, which has many properties. But the
one that you can use for this purpose is
the end property, which is an object that
has all the end of properties available
through the operating system. Like user
here. It also includes the one we just
customize, like Val one and Val to-be. You
can export environment variables prior to
executing a script, and note will read
those as well. For example, instead of
this one liner, UI conduce something like
Export Val, one equal 100 export Val to
equal 200. And then we can execute this
script normally, and it will pick up our
102 100 values. This is a handy bridge
between the operating system and the node
process. You can use it to communicate
dynamic configuration values. For example,
if you want your script to run on
development, port 40 to 42 but in
production you wanted to run on for 80.
Instead, you can use process the end to
make the port dynamic and control IT on
different machines. There is another way
to pass information for the execution
context of the note process, and that's
through the process. The Ark via Ray. This
array will have an item for every
positional argument you specify when
executing the node script in order. For
example, if we have a note command to
print process the RG using the handy dash
p CLI option All the arguments after this
command will be set in the resulting ray
as strings. Even if you pass numbers, this
ray will always assume strings. The first
item here in the resulting array is the
location of the Note Command. And if we're
executing a script, the second item in
this array would be the script name. But
in this case, we're not executing a
script. So the remaining items in this ray
are the arguments that we passed to the
Note command and they're all strings in
this array. This is a cool feature, but I
think I prefer the process. The end of
method because I get to name the past
values there with RG, we'd have to do more
tricks to accomplish this. Named values
feature Other properties you should be
aware of on this special process object
are the standard input output stream.
There are three of them STDM for input STD
out for output and STD air for error
messages. These control the communication
channel between the note process and its
operating system execution environment.
We've been actually using them under the
hood when you use a console dot log line
that line right to the STD out stream. In
fact, you can accomplish the same
functionality of console the log by using
a process The STD out the right line just
like this. S t d n can be used to read
information from users. Here's an example
to do that. The STD Io objects are all
streams, which is a topic that we are yet
to explore. But the gist of it is that we
use events and methods to use these
streams. In here we are listening for a
readable event and using the read method
to read a chunk of data and then we print
out the same chunk to STD out, making this
effectively an echo utility. IT will echo
everything you type two IT. There are
multiple ways to consume and benefit from
these Io streams and streams. In general,
for example, this same echo example can be
done using the excellent pipe function
that's available on readable streams like
process that s t d n UI pipe readable
stream into a rideable one like process
that STD out using the argument for the
pipe function. And this makes the exact
same echo utility. We'll have a bit more
to learn about streams later in this
course, but for now, just make a mental
note that streams are awesome and you
should utilize them in every possible way.
Notes. Process Object can also be used to
terminate the process or do something when
the process is terminated unexpectedly.
Here's an example of that. This code has a
timer that will fire after two seconds,
and it will call the exit function on the
process object. This will manually
terminate the process and make note. Exit
as note is exiting the process. It looks
for any listeners registered on the exit
event. We have done exactly that in here.
Which means right before note exits, IT
will execute this function to print out
this message. Because of the nature of
asynchronous code in node, this hello line
will be executed first. Then the timer
will go next and the exit listener will
fire. This simple example demonstrates the
power of note asynchronous nature and its
event with Adala. Gee, we will learn more
about that in the concurrency module of this course.