[Autogenerated] I hope you are now excited
about node. This module has been just a
teaser about the many powerful features
that come built into the note or in time.
This includes things like its powerful
rebel on CLI, and it's built in libraries
like etc. To-be, which we use to quickly
create a Web server. It also comes with
plenty of customizable options and a built
in bridge to the operating system. Through
the process object, however, UI Onley
scratched the surface in this module.
There are so many other things that I want
to show you. But before I do, let me make
sure that you are familiar with the modern
JavaScript features that I'm starting to
use and will continue to do throughout
this course. This next module will be
exactly that. A _____ course on all the
modern JavaScript features that were added
to the language since 2015 and are now
natively available in your node
environment. Features like template
strings, arrow functions, classes, block
scopes, de structuring promises with a
sync weight and more. If you're already
familiar with these features, you should skip this next module