[Autogenerated] JavaScript is a very
different language than it used to be just
a few years ago. IT JavaScript, which is
the official specification that JavaScript
confirms to has improved a lot in the past
few years after a rather long period of no
updates to the language at all. Today, the
JavaScript Technical Committee, which is
known as T C 39 makes yearly releases of
JavaScript and JavaScript engines like V
eight, shortly followed by implementing
the new features introduced in the EC
JavaScript releases. This has started with
JavaScript 2015 or its other commonly
known name s six. Since then, we've had
yearly releases named ES plus the current
year. Some of these releases were big and
others were very small. But the language
now has a continuous updates cycle that
drives mawr innovative features and phase
out the famous problems JavaScript had
over the years. Anybody can propose
features that they think should belong to
the jobs of language. The T C 39 committee
has a five stage process to filter and
finalize the features that are considered
for the language. A feature starts at
stage zero, which is when anyone proposes
anything to the committee. And if the
proposed feature has a clear problem and a
clear case for its need and someone is
willing to back it up through the process,
it gets labeled as Stage one. Once the
proposed feature has an initial spec
document, it gets labeled as Stage two
draft. At this point, there is a strong
chance the feature will be part of the
language when the spec of the feature is
finalized and the designated reviewers of
the future signed off on it. The proposal
is labeled Stage three candidate. At this
stage, the feature is queued for more
tests, and the committee will accept this
back text into its main specifications.
Repository, which gets the feature to
Stage four Finished and that feature will
be included in the next year. Lee Release
of Atma Script In No, Jess, you only have
access to features that are finished and
are already part of the language. However,
V eight often has harmony flags for you to
experiment with candidate and even draft
features. Sometimes you can also use the
babble compiler to write many of the in
progress features in JavaScript and have
babble compile it to the good old
supported JavaScript before you take your
code to production. Babel is popular on
the front end because many browsers air
usually slow to add support for all the
new features in the language, including
the finalized ones. And Babble offers an
escape hatch for developers to use the
latest and greatest without risking their
code not being compatible with older
browsers. In this course, I'll only use
features that are natively available in
Nadia's, including many of the modern
features that started becoming available
since 2015. In the next, few videos will
go over some of these features and learn the value they bring to the language.