[Autogenerated] first up, let's talk about
variables and block scoops. Here is one of
my favorite JavaScript trick questions. Is
this a valid JavaScript line of code?
Testing it in a no trouble seems to work
fine, which means it is valid. So the
question is, now, what did it do? These
are nested block scoops. UI could write
code in here for a equal 42 and then
access a right after and it would be
acceptable. JavaScript does not really
care about the spacing or new lines in
here. A block scope is created with a pair
of curly braces just like this example
here. This also apply to if statements and
four statements as well. These also get
their own block scoops. Block scopes are a
bit different than function scopes, which
are created for each function. You can see
one difference when using the var keyword
to define variables. Variables defined
with far inside a function scope are okay.
They don't leak out of that scope. If you
try to access them outside of the scope,
you can't. As you can see here, we could
not access the result variable that was
defined inside the some functions scope.
However, when we define variables with bar
in a block scope, we-can totally access
them outside that scope afterwards, which
is a bit problematic. And here's one
practical example of that. This four loop
has an index variable that takes from 1 to
10. You can access that variable inside
the loop normally, but you can also access
the same variable outside the loop. After
all iterations air done, the value of I
hear will be reported as 11 and that's a
bit weird. This is why the more
recommended way to declare variables in
modern JavaScript is by using the let
keyword instead of the var keyword.
Because when defining variables with let,
we won't have this weird out of scope
y-access problem. If we replace this far
here with let and do the same, test will
try to access let after loop. We need to
start new note session here, paste in the
code, try to access I. After that, it will
tell you that I is not defined, which
makes sense because we're outside of the
school where it was defined. So this is
much better. Block scopes like function
scopes can also be nested like the trick
question that we started with this is a
nested block scope within each level of
nesting. The scope will protect the
variables defined in it as long as we use
the let keyword or the Const keyword,
which behaves in the good way, like the
let keyword UI use. Const. When the
reference assigned is meant to be constant
because references assigned with CONST
cannot be changed, not how I'm saying
references and not values here because
Constant does not mean in mutability, it
just means constant reference. But if the
reference is foreign object, we-can still
change this object just like we can do
with functions that receive objects as
arguments. So if the variable defined with
Const. Is a scaler one like a string or
integer, you can think of it as an
immutable thing here. Because these scaler
values and JavaScript are immutable. We
can't mutate the value of a string or an
integer in JavaScript. And because we used
costs with these scaler values, we can't
change the reference either. However,
placing an array or object in a const is a
different story. The cost will guarantee
that the variable is pointing to the same
ray or object, but the content of the
array or object can still be mutated. So
be careful here and keep that in mind to
accomplish In mutability for objects,
JavaScript offers a freeze method, but IT
Onley freezes the first level of that
object. So if you have a nested object
within the first object, that nested
object would not freeze. If you want to
work with immutable object, I recommend
the immutable JSON Library, which has an A
P I that will guarantee objects in
mutability. Variables defined with CONST
are much better than those defined with
let for scaler values and for functions,
because you get a guarantee that the value
did not accidentally change. Looking at
this good example here and assuming that
between the first and last line, there is
a big program on the last line, we-can
still confidently say that the answer
variable still holds the 42 value because
the code ran without problems while for
the same example would let we would have
to parse through the code to figure out if
the answer variables still hold the 42
values. If you need a variable toe, hold a
changing scaler value like a counter, for
example. Then using let is okay. But for
the most cases, it's probably much better for you to stick with using Const.