[Autogenerated] There are many ways to
define a function in JavaScript on the
modern specifications introduced a new
way. Arrow functions away to define a
function without typing the keyword
function, but rather by using an arrow
simple like this, this shorter Centex is
preferable not only because it's shorter,
but also because it behaves more
predictably with closures. So let me tell
you about that. An error function does not
care. Who calls IT while a regular
function cares very much about that. A
regular function like X here always bind
the value for its this keyword for its
collar. And if it didn't have an explicit
collar, irregular function will use the
value of undefined for its vis keyword and
error function. On the other hand, like
why here, not caring about who called it
will close over the value for the this
keyword for its scope at the time it was
defined, making it great for delayed
execution cases like events and listeners
because it gives easy access to the
defining environment. This is important,
so let's take a look at an example in any
note module like this one. The top level
this keyword is associate it with the
special exports object which I'm going to
tell you more about soon. But in this
example, I'm just giving this exports
object a label toe. Identify it because
it's empty by default and here I am
printing the value for the exports. Object
for you to see testing this script with
note command. You should see an object
with I'd exports. Now I prepared this
tester object, which defines to similar
functions where in both I am printing the
value for the this keyword function. One
is defined with the regular Centex, while
function to is defined with the arrow
Centex. When function one is called, it's
this keyword will be associated with its
collar, which in this case is the test our
object itself. And this is why you see the
printed value for the this keyword in
function. One representing the tester
object itself. However, when function to
is called, it's This keyword will be
associated with the same this keyword that
was available in the functions scope when
it was defined, which was the modules,
exports object, the one I gave a label. As
you can see here, this is a big benefit
when working with listeners in no jazz,
and it's why you'll see me using error
functions all over the place. One other
cool thing about error functions is that
if the function on Lee has a single line
that returns something, you could make it
even more concise by removing the curly
braces and the return cured altogether.
You can also remove the parentheses around
the argument if the function receives a
single argument, making it really short.
This syntax is usually popular for
functions that get passed to array methods
like map reduce and filter and functional programming in general.