[Autogenerated] you can create an object
in JavaScript with a few different ways.
But the most common way is to use an
object literal. Here's an example of that.
This is a lot easier than doing something
like new object, which you can if you want
to. Literal initiation is very common in
JavaScript. We use it for objects, raise
strings, numbers and even things like
regular expressions. The object, literal
syntax, supports a few modern goodies.
Here's a simple example where this object
defined to regular properties if you need
to define a property that holds a
function, you can use this shorter Syntex
with object literal. Of course, if you
need an error function, you can still use
the regular property. Centex Modern Object
Liberals also support dynamic properties
using this Centex, which looks like an
array literal. But don't confuse it with
that. JavaScript will evaluate what's
within the square brackets and make the
result of that the new property name. So,
assuming we have a variable named mystery
defined before this object, and I'm gonna
go ahead and copy this code into a new
rebel session, and now here is your
JavaScript interview question. What is
object that mystery. It's undefined
because this mystery property was defined
with dynamic property. Centex, which means
JavaScript, will evaluate the mystery
expression first on whatever that
expression. Evaluated, too, will become
the object property. In this case, the
object will have a property answer with
the value of 42. Another widely popular
feature about object liberals is available
to you when you need to define an object
with property names to map values that
exist in the current scope with the exact
same names. If you have a variable named
pie and you would like O B G to have a
property named pious well holding the same
value as the variable pie instead of
typing the name twice like this, you can
use the shorter Centex by admitting the
second part in this shorter Centex is
equivalent to what I had before. Objects
are very popular in JavaScript. They are
used to manage and communicate data, and
using these features will make the code a bit shorter and easier to read.