[Autogenerated] the de structuring Centex
is really simple, but I've seen it
confused many people before. Let me make
sure that does not happen to you. The
structuring works for both arrays and
objects. Here's an example for objects
using the built in math object in
JavaScript when you have an object like
math and you want to extract values out of
this object into the enclosing scope, for
example, instead of using math up, I would
like to just have a constant named pi toe.
Hold the value of math up I, which is easy
because you can have a line like this.
Format that pie in another one for E. If
you need the same for E and so on with the
de structuring Centex, these three lines
are equivalent to this single line IT
these structures the three properties out
of its right hand object and into the
current scope. This is useful when you
need to use a few properties out of a
bigger object. For example, here is a line
to the structure, just the read file
method out of the nodes FS module. After
this line, I can use the read file method
directly like this. These structuring also
works inside function arguments. If the
argument passed to a function is an
object, instead of using the name of the
object every time you want to access its
properties, you can use the these
structuring Centex within the function
parentheses to these structure, just the
properties that you are interested in and
make them local to that function. This
generally improves the readability of
functions. So here we have a Circle Area
function, which expects an object as its
argument, and it expects that object to
have a radius property on. We're de
structuring the radius property out of
that object and using it locally in the
function. If we call this Circle area
function with an object like circle, it
will use its radius property inside for
its calculation. Let's go ahead and test
that you'll see the Circle Area
calculation working as expected. These
structured arguments can also be defined
with defaults like regular arguments. If,
say, I'd like to use the default value of
two for precision property here. Let's
define second IOPS shins argument for this
circle area function and the structure
precision out of that argument to use it
in the functions body. If I'd like to use
the default value of two for the precision
property, I can just use the equal sign
here after the structuring precision. And
that means default for precision, if not
specified, will be, too. I can also make
this whole second argument optional using
an equal sign after the de structuring
Centex. The same call here will use an
empty object for the second argument of
the function, and then it will use the
default value of two for the precision
property that is now used in the function.
Of course, if you called the circle area
function with the second argument that has
a precision property, that value will be
used inside the function. As you can see,
this de structuring feature offers a good
alternative to using named arguments in
functions, which is a much better thing
that relying on positional arguments de
structuring, whether you do it in function
arguments or directly with variables, also
works for a raise. If you have an array of
values and you want to extract these
values into local variables, you can use
the items positions to the structure,
their values into local variables just
like this. Not how I used double-click.
Mama's here to skip the structuring. The
third item injury, the D structured
variable fourth here will hold the value
of 40. This is useful when combined with
the rest operator, which has an example
here. By using these three dots, we are
asking JavaScript to the structure on Lee
one item out of this array and then create
a new array under the name Rest of items
toe. Hold the rest of the items after
removing the first-one. Let's test that so
first here will be 10 and rest of items
will be an array of 2030 and 40. This is
powerful for splitting the array, and it's
also even more powerful when working with
objects to filter out certain properties
from an object. Here's an example of that.
Say that we have this data object, which
has a few temp properties, and we'd like
to create a new object that has the same
data except for temp one and tempt to-be
we-can D structure temp one attempt to and
then use the rest operator to get the
remaining properties into a new object
called person. Just like the three dots of
rest. You can use the three dots to spread
one array or object into a new array or
object. This is useful for copying arrays
and objects. You can spread the items in
an array into a new array like this
example. New area here will be a copy of
the rest of items array that we d
structured above, and similarly, you can
also spread the key value pairs of an
object into a new object. Like this
example. The new object here will be a
copy of the person object. Note that these
copies air also shallow copies. Any nested
objects or arrays will be shared between these copies. Don't forget that.