[Autogenerated] template strings are one
of my favorite new features that were
introduced to the JavaScript language a
few years ago. Let me tell you about them.
You can define a string in JavaScript,
using either single quotes or double
quotes. Thes two ways to define string.
Liberals and JavaScript are equivalent.
Modern JavaScript has a third way to
define strings, and that's using the back
tick character on my keyboard. It's right
above the tab. Key strings defined with
the back tick character are called
template strings because they could be
used as a template with dynamic values as
they support what we call interpolation.
You can inject any dynamic expression in
JavaScript within these dollar sign curly
braces holders. So, for example, we can
use Matha random here, and the final
string will have the value of the
expression included exactly where it was
injected in the string. If you test this
string and note, you'll see a random value
every time you do it with template
strings. You can also have multi lines in
the strings, something that was not
possible with the regularly quoted
strings. Back text look very similar to
single quotes, so make sure to train your
eyes to spot template strings when they are used in examples