[Autogenerated] JavaScript offers many
programming paradigms and object oriented
programming is one of them. Everything in
JavaScript is an object, including
functions. Modern JavaScript also added
support for the class. Centex A class is a
template or blueprint for you to define
shared structure and behavior between
similar objects. You can define new
classes, make them extend other classes
and instantiate objects out of them. Using
the new keyword, you can customize the
construction of every object and define
shared functions between these objects.
Here is a standard class example that
demonstrate all these features. We have a
person class and the student class that
extends the person class. Every student is
also a person. Both classes define a
constructor function. The constructor
function is a special one that gets called
every time UI instantiate an object out of
the class which we do using the new
keyword. As you can see here we are
instantiate ing one object from the person
class and two other objects from the
student class. The arguments we pass here
when UI instantiate these objects are
accessible in the classes constructor
function. The person class expects a name
argument. IT stores the value on the
instance, using the whiskey word here and
the student class expects a name and the
level arguments. IT stores the level value
on its instance, and since it extends the
person class, it'll call the super method
with the name argument, which will invoke
the person class constructor function and
store. The name is well. Both classes
define a greet function that uses the
values they store on each instance on the
third object, which UI instantiate IT from
the student class here. We also defined
agreed function directly on the object.
When we test this script, 01 will use the
greet method from its class. The person
class 02 will use the great method from
the student class and 03 will use its own directly defined greet method.