[Autogenerated] note is event driven. Most
of the functions that you will be working
with in note return promises, and you'll
have to consume them using the promise
syntax. With that, then and catch, However
ah more preferable way to consume promises
is using the new A sync await Centex,
which makes your promise consuming code a
bit more readable and easier, especially
when you start dealing with loops and
other complexities. Here's an example code
that is consuming a promise object using
the regular promise. Centex. Here we have
a simple fetch function that reads and
https response for a URL. Don't worry
about the implementation of this function.
Just notice how IT returns a promise
object. This is the modern alternative to
using callbacks for the A sync nature of
dysfunction. To consume the fetch
function, we use the dot then Centex,
which will expose the data available after
the A sync action. Alternatively, we can
also consume any promise using the A sync
await feature as seen here. We use the
keyword await before the promise and that
will give us access to the data available
after the A sync action. We can use this
data directly after that wait line just
like this, which is a lot simpler than
callbacks and using dot then as well.
However, to make this away feature work,
you have to wrap your code with a function
labeled with the A sync keyword, and then
call the function to execute the A sync
action. Testing this good Now the same
fetch promise will be consumed twice, once
with the regular dot then Centex and
another time with the new A sync await
Centex the A sync awaits and taxes
definitely easier to read, and it will
make your life especially easier if you
need to work with promises that depend on
each other or promises that need to be within the loop.