[Autogenerated] this module was a quick
review of the modern JavaScript features
that were introduced to the language in
the past few years and are currently
available natively in note. We've talked
about block scoops and how they are a bit
different than function scopes and how
it's wise to use the let and Const.
Keyword within them. We've seen how error
functions are different than regular
functions. We've explored the modern ways
to work with object liberals and talked
about de structuring and the rest spread
properties. We saw how to work with
template strings and how to create and use
classes, and finally saw an example of
consuming promises with regular promise.
Centex on with the A sync Await us well.
In the next module, we'll explore the npm
tool. Npm is notes package manager, and it
has a website hosting hundreds of
thousands of note packages. We'll explore
the npm tool itself and talk about some of the most popular npm packages out there