[Autogenerated] Welcome back. Let's talk
about npm nodes. Package Manager npm
enables JavaScript developers to do three
main things, share their code with others,
reuse their own code across projects and
use code written by others in their
projects. So npm is basically all about
code sharing and reusability. If you have
a piece of JavaScript code that you'd like
to share with others or just reuse in
other projects, npm is the tool you need
to help with that. But npm is also about
compose ability off bigger applications
using smaller packages you can use. Others
work to complete yours so you don't have
to start from complete scratch. In
general, npm is an asset for any team that
is working on any job script project. It
makes it easy to separate and manage the
different versions off good. The npm
project runs at npm G s dot com. This is
the site that hosts the many useful npm
packages that you're going to love and
appreciate. It also hosts a lot of empty
and useless packages because there is no
quality control here. Anyone can publish
anything and we are about to publish
something in this module. But I'll try to
make it a bit useful. Npm is the official
note package manager. The npm project
started with a small set of notes scripts
to manage common tasks around folders that
contain code for node. And IT sense
evolved into a fully featured package
manager that it's super useful for all job
script code, not just note. If you browse
the registry of the npm packages that are
hosted on npm JSON dot com, you'll find
packages that are for node and packages
that are libraries and frameworks meant to
be used in a browser or a mobile
application. If you dig deep enough,
you'll even see examples of APS for
robots, routers and countless other places
where JavaScript can be executed. A
typical note project will have tens, if
not hundreds of npm packages. Some npm
packages represent big frameworks like
express or sales. Some provide utility
functions like load ash here. Some just
provide useful libraries. The request
package here is an example of that Many
npm packages are small and specialized
around one problem and focused on how to
solve that problem. Well, let's give
credit where credit is due. Npm simply
revolutionized the way JavaScript
developers work, the life of a JavaScript
developer was much harder before npm. Npm
is a very important part of note, and a
good understanding of how it works will
prove to be very valuable for you as a no
developer. So what exactly is a package
manager and why do we need IT? Let's
actually start with um, or basic question.
What is a package? The name package is
what npm uses toe label. The bits of
reusable good A note package is basically
a folder that contains scripts that can be
run by note, which is to say that any
folder that has some JavaScript code in it
is basically a node package. Another name
that is commonly used to describe a code
folder in note is module. Some modules are
built in note, so npm is not needed to
manage those but most other modules that
you'll be using our external to note and
npm is what we can use to manage them when
you have a project that has a lot of these
good folders that we are going to start
referring to as packages. From now on,
you'll need to manage them somehow,
especially when these packages start
depending on other packages. And when you
start working with multiple versions and
sources of these packages, that's where
npm can be helpful. When developers talk
about npm, they could be talking about one
of many things they could be talking
about. The npm GS website that hosts a
public registry of the many open source
npm packages. This website provides a few
graphical features, like searching for
packages. For example, every package page
has some meta information about the
package, like the number of downloads and
other information managed by the package.
If the package has a read me file, it'll
be displayed here is well. Developers
could also be talking about the npm
command line interface. The CLI tool that
we can use in our projects to manage the
package is this tool has many commands
that you can see here. We are going to
learn a few of them in this course module.
Npm is also the name of the company npm
Inc that hosts and maintains the npm
Registry and CLI Tool and is doing more
business around the npm Registry and tool.
They offer private repositories and mawr
enterprise level services. Let's now talk
about the npm CLI tool that gives us this global npm command