[Autogenerated] as a note developer, you
will be working with the npm command a
lot. This command comes installed with
node itself so you don't need to do
anything to install it. If you have not
installed, you should have the global npm
command installed as well. You can check
the version with dash V. Npm gets updated
more frequently than note. So sometimes
you might need to update npm itself
separately from note to get the latest
release. You do that using the command npm
install dash G for global npm. Yep. You
can use npm to update npm If you get an e
access air here, that means you most
likely installed node itself with some
admin privileges. You can use pseudo in
that case, or start a whole terminal with
admin privileges on Mac OS. If you install
node through homebrew or npm, you usually
don't need to sue do any note or npm
commands. If you are facing the access
error, you can also fix the npm
permissions so that you don't have to run.
Npm would suit you. Let's quickly explore
the first command of npm, the one that we
just used install to do that I'm going to
create a test directory test npm CD into
that and run npm install. By the way,
install has a shortcut. You can just do
npm my, which is cool. And we're going to
install one package called Express. So
this npm install command is our client
that just downloaded the package from its
source, which by default is the npm just
that calm registry itself. But you can
configure the command for other sources.
And after IT downloaded that package, npm
placed the package in a special folder
under the project named Node Modules. So
this is the process that's known as
installing a package. But there's nothing
magic about it, really. It just places the
package under this Node Modules folder.
Note itself is designed to use this note
modules folder by default toe. Look for
any packages IT needs to use. When note
needs to require a package like express
here, it does not communicate with npm at
all. It just uses the note modules, folder
and packages that were placed inside that
note modules folder. Did you notice how
when I installed the express package here,
npm warned me that this folder does not
have a package. Jason, file this package.
That Jason file is important. So let's
redo this example with a package that
Jason File. I have a folder in the three
npm folder here called one npm command.
And this folder has the package that Jason
file. So let's see d into this folder and
redo the npm install express command and
note what happens to the package that
Jason file. Did you see that? The package
that Jason file had a new section here.
This is the section where npm is
documenting this new dependency for this
project Express. Not only that, the npm
installed process will also take care of
installing any sub dependencies for the
main installed package. Take a look at
what you now should see under the Node
Modules folder. Although we asked npm to
install a single dependency express, npm
installed many other dependencies. What
exactly are these? These are the packages
that express itself depends on. And since
we made our project depend on express,
these other packages are now in the
projects. Sub dependencies. Okay, so let
me quickly review what happened when we
invoked the command npm install Express.
Npm first created a new Node Modules
folder because that folder did not exist
before the first npm install will do that.
Npm then downloaded express package from
npm just dot com and placed it under the
newly created Note Modules folder. IT then
modified the package that Jason file to
document this exact dependency and the
version used for this dependency. And it
also created a package dash lock Jason
File. So let's talk about these two files.
Package that Jason and package lock that Jason.