[Autogenerated] the package that Jason
File is the one file that you'll see in
every npm package. It's adjacent file that
can be used to provide information about a
package, and it's required by npm. This
file is mostly modified by the npm command
itself, but in a few cases you'll need to
manually edit this file as well. In the
previous example, we started with a simple
package that Jason file that only had the
required properties name and version. The
name often npm package is it's unique
identifier. If you need to publish this
package, that name has to be unique and
not used before across the whole registry.
The version Property is a semantic
versioning string. We'll talk about this
string in the next video. When we
installed the express dependency, npm
automatically modified our package that
Jason and added a dependency section
documenting the version of Express that it
used. Here is the package that Jason file
for the Popular Express package. As you
can see, this file includes meta
information about express things like
description, license and keywords. But the
most important information in this file is
the dependencies section. These are the
packages that express depends on. And this
is the same list of packages that we got
when we installed expressed locally in the
previous test. This is really the most
important benefit off the package that
Jason file. This file makes the building
off the project. Dependencies are
reproducible task. This means by sharing
this package that Jason file with other
developers or with build servers, the
process of building the project
dependencies on these other machines can
be automated through the dependencies
section off the file. Here, let me show
you how that works. With a local example,
let me add one more dependency in the one
npm folder example here. This time, let's
add the load ash package. The command that
we need here is npm Install load ash. Npm
is now downloading load ash and it just
placed it under the note modules folder
and updated the package that Jason file to
document this new dependency. Now, the one
npm folder right now has three things. The
package that Jason file the other package
lock Jason file and the Node Modules
folder. Now, Usually, when you share your
project with other developers, you don't
share your note modules folder This is a
big folder with code written by others. It
does not belong to your teams. Get Repo,
for example. So what your team will get
when you share this project is just the
Jason file. So let me remove this note
modules folder to simulate that. So a team
member just pulled this code. They now
have the package that Jason file and to
build their version of note modules. All
they have to do is run the npm install
command without any arguments. Just like
this, this command will install all the
dependencies listed in package that Jason
along with their sub dependencies. In
fact, thanks to the package lock Jason
file, they will get the exact same
versions. Even for the sub dependence
History, for example, expressed depends on
this bites package here that was installed
when we ran the npm install command. Let's
assume between the time that you added the
express dependency and the time a team
member pulled your code to use it, a new
version of this bites and PM package was
released. Your team member will not get
that new version. When they run npm
install, they are going to get the exact
same version that you used because of
package locked Jason. So the version of
bites that was used here is 300 If you
look at the content of this package, lock
that Jason file. You'll see information
not only about this project's direct
dependencies, but rather the whole
dependency. Three. For the project search
for Bites, for example, you'll see how the
exact version off the bites package is
included here, and you'll also understand
how bites was added to the project because
it's a dependency of body parts. Er, which
is a dependency of one of your top level
dependencies expressed in this case while
adding dependencies to package that Jason
when you install them, you can also tell
npm that a dependency is on lee a
development dependency, which means it is
not needed in a production environment. To
do that, you're in the same npm install
command, but with the Dash D argument D
for development. For example, let me
install the node mon package with the
Dashti argument Here. You'll notice how
npm added this node mont package under a
new section in package that Jason, this
time it's Dev dependencies. This is where
you should place things like you're
testing framework, your formatting tools
or anything else that you use on Lee while
developing your project. Now let's quickly
take a look at the help page for the npm
Install command, and you do that using
npm. Help install. In here, you'll see all
the usage patterns and the options that
you can use with the npm installment and
one of these options that you can see
right here is the dash dash production
flag. Or you can use the note environment
variable and said that to production on
what that will do is it will completely
ignore your death dependencies, because
these are development dependencies, so you
don't need them in production. This is
handy because this note Mont package is
not something that you need in production.
It's on Lee Use is in development. Do
automatically restart node whenever a file
is saved in the project. Notman is one
solution to the problem that you need to
manually restart node when you make
changes to a file and it's a good
compromise in development environment. But
it's totally not needed in a production
environment before we move on to the next
topic, which is this semantic versioning
string that we've been seeing in package
that. Jason, let me show you a command you
can use to automatically create a package
that Jason file for a brand new project.
So let me create another test folder here.
I can use the make Directory command here
on this machine on. I'm gonna call this my
project and C D into IT. So this is a
completely empty directory. Now, instead
of manually creating a package that Jason
file, you can run the npm in IT. Command.
This command will ask you a few questions
about your project and use your answers to
create an initial package that Jason file
for you. It tries to use defaults from
your folder. For example, if your project
is already a get rebo, we'll figure that
out and include the repo. You URL You can
also run this command with Dash dash. Yes,
to just use the defaults instead of
interactive lee answering questions. I'll
do that for this example. Check it out. It
created a package that Jason file with the
name of this directory and initial version
and this scripts section, which is an
important, one that we're going to talk
about in a few videos, and it's a very
good one. But first, let's talk about
these little version strings and understand the meanings of these elements.