[Autogenerated] npm uses semantic
versioning or some ver for short when it's
time to update packages. Every package has
a version. This is one of the required
information about a package. That version
in npm is written with the same ver
format. The somber string is basically a
simple contract between a package author
and the users of that package. When that
number gets pumped up to release a new
version of the package, December
communicates how big of a change to the
package itself. Will this new release be
The first number, which is called the
major number, is used to communicate that
breaking changes happened in the release.
Those are changes that will require users
to change their own code to make it work
with the new release. The second number,
which is called the Miner number, is used
to communicate that new features were
added to this release, but nothing major.
All the changes are still backward
compatible, and it's safe for users to
install these minor releases, and they
will not require the users to change their
code to make it work with these releases.
The last number, which is called the Patch
number, is used to communicate that the
release on Lee contained bug fixes and
security fixes, no new features and no
breaking changes. You often see a few
different special characters before the
versions. Strings in the package that
Jason file these special characters
represent a range of acceptable versions
on are put to use when you instruct npm to
update your dependency tree. For example,
the told a character means that an update
can install the most recent patch version.
Remember Patches, the third number for the
version of string on the screen here. It
means npm can install any version that
starts with 1.2 and is greater or equal to
1.2 point three. So a 1.2 point four
version would be okay, and so would 1.2
point five or anything in that class.
However, at 1.3 point zero version will
not be used. So basically, this version
range string is equivalent to one point to
point X, where X is greater or equal to
three. On the other hand, a caret-symbol
in front of the somber string is a more
relaxed constraint. It will get the
package updated to the most recent minor
version. Remember, Minor is the middle
number. For example, carry IT. 1.2 point
three here will match any one point x
point. Why, where X is greater than or
equal to two and why can be anything so
you might get a 1.30 or 1.4 point five,
for example. But npm will not update all
the way to 2.0. I'll admit this might be
confusing at first. Just remember that
Kelda is for safe patch level updates,
whereas caret-symbol more relaxed minor
level update. Npm has a site that may make
understanding this a bit easier. It's
hosted here at some vered npm jess dot
com. You can pick a package to see all of
its available versions, then enter Arrange
string to test for load ash, for example.
IT alga 4 16 3 matches all patch level
updates that start with 4 16 and has the
patch number greater than or equal to
three, while caret-symbol three will match
what the tell diversion matched. But it
will also include all the 4 17 versions.
You might find it easier to use the X
notation, for example, your version range
string can simply be 4 16 x or even for
the X, the tilde and carrot or helpful in
communicating the exact version arranged
started with I think some ver is great and
responsible. Npm developers should respect
IT when they release new versions of their
code. But it's good to treat what it
communicates as a promise rather than a
guarantee, because even a patch release
might leak breaking changes through its
own dependencies. A minor version, for
example, might introduce new elements that
conflicts with elements you previously
thought are okay to use testing. Your code
is the only way to provide some form of guarantee that it's not broken.