[Autogenerated] you have two options. When
it comes to installing an npm package, you
can install it either locally or globally.
When we worked under this one npm command
directory, all the three packages that we
installed under this folder here were
local. This is the default behavior of the
npm Install Command. It'll just installed
package locally under the project where
you run the command. If the package is to
be used within a node folder, basically,
if you need to use it just for one
project, you should probably install IT
locally. I'd say 99% of the packages that
you use should be installed locally. The
only exception is when you need to install
global tools. For example, create react
app is a package hosting a tool react.
Developers use that tool to well create a
fully configured react application. This
is an example of a package that's usually
installed globally. You don't need to be
in a specific directory to use this tool.
You can use it anywhere. Also, once you're
generated, react application is running.
You are not really depending on the create
react app tool itself anymore. You still
depend on other packages related to create
react app, but not on the package hosting
the command to install and update packages
globally, you add the Dash G flag, which
is short for global. Once a tool packages
installed globally, it's command will be
available for you to run from anywhere, so
for create react app. UI, npm install dash
G, create react app And once a tool
package is installed globally, it's
command will be available for you to run
from anywhere. The commands a package add
to your system are listed right here when
you install that package. So this create
react. App. Command is now a command that
I can run from anywhere, regardless of
whether the package is installed globally
or locally. Once it's installed, you can
require IT from any node script under this
to usage folder. Here we have a simple,
empty package that Jason File. Let's
install the load ash package locally.
Remember how to do that npm install load
ash and that's it that will install load
ash locally under the two Usage folder and
place that package under the Node Modules
folder. Let's take a look under the note
modules folder. Load ashes there and note
how this package has no sub dependencies
at all. The Onley package in our
dependency three right now is load ash now
within the current folder, we-can require
the load ash package from any file. Here's
a test that does exactly that. This test
DGS file requires the load ash library and
then uses its some function to some, the
integers in an array, and I'll app. Put
the result after that. Since load ash is
already installed under the noted Modules
folder, this file will run fine and
output. The result. Now try to run the
same file after deleting the note modules
folder. So RM dash R F note modules, all
of it. And now you'll find out that if you
try to run note test duchess, you'll find
out that you can't run this file load. Ash
is no longer available for node to use.
The Note Modules folder is simply the
connection between npm and ____. You can
actually place the load ash dependency
under the parent folders, Note modules
folders, so the note Modules folder
doesn't have to be in the exactly actually
where you are. Node will check all the
parents for their own Note Modules folder
so you can basically make a directory in
your home directory called note modules
just like that. And that directory would
satisfy all the dependencies for all your
projects. But really, this is not a
recommended approach. If your note script
requires load ash like this load, ash
should be a local dependency under the
project's main Note Modules folder. And
the version you install should be
documented in Package that Jason, so that
all members on the team have a similar
experience working the project dependencies.