[Autogenerated] I think we're ready to
bring out the big guns. Well, actually,
this is a lot easier than it sounds. Let's
create and then publish an npm package.
Try to do this exercise with me on your
own. Pause the video as needed and matter
what I do. I've included a test file under
the exercise files right here under the
three Create Package directory. The goal
is to make this file work and output
what's expected, As you see here in the
comment. So if we execute this file right
now, it will not work because the frame
print package does not exist. This is the
package that we will be creating in this
line. We're requiring this package and
capturing the top level a p i of this
package as the print variable. And then
we're using the print variable as a
function call. So the top level a p I in
the package that we need to create should
be a function. And here is the expected
output. IT just prints the message in the
argument in a frame of stars. All right,
so let's start from a make direct
recommend now. Usually you need to name
the package as the string that we are
using here to require so make directory
frame print. So under frame print, we need
to create new file. Let's call this file
index Duchess. Now the name index the jazz
is a bit special in note and npm by
default when you require a folder note
will look for an index the Js file under
that folder which will work in our case.
So just to test this index that yes, let's
place a console log statement here and
just say testing. So let me actually split
this file in the editor here. Okay, so
we've got this index suggests file under
the frame print directory on we have the
index dot Js file that is under the test
directory, which we're going to use to
test the frame print directory. Now to get
this line here to work, this frame print
package should exist under the note
modules folder inside the test folder. We
don't have that. We don't have a note
modules folder inside that folder for
testing purposes. Instead of using this
line, we-can require the adjacent frame
print directory using relative paths. So
instead of requiring this directly from
note modules. We-can say Let's go up one
level and then require frame print from
the same level as the parent of this test
folder where we're testing with that, we
can run this index dot Js file under the
test folder, and it will require the frame
print that we are testing right here. All
right, let's test that So node test index
Splunk-ES and you'll notice right away
that we are in business. The console
logline is now showing up in our test.
Very good. We're still seeing a problem
that says print is not a function because
we did not export any A p i yet. So
instead of console lock testing, let's go
ahead and export an A p I. Now in a note
module, you can change the A P I using the
exports special objects so I could do
something like a is 42 in here. However,
if you need to change the top level
export, you need to use the module. The
exports equal notation. So our top level
export here, which were capturing in the
print variable, is a function. So let's go
ahead and do a function here I'll name
dysfunction. Print dysfunction receives a
single argument, so we'll call this
argument message now, inside this
function, let's console log testing from
function and let me go ahead and run the
command again and make sure testing from
function appears and it does. And you'll
notice that the air about print not being
a function is gone now because our top
level A p I is now a function. So now all
we need to do is to make this function
output the message within F Star of
frames. For that, we can use a few console
log statements so we can do stars and
we'll do another one just like that. And
inside the frame, Well, just console log
the message just like that. Let's go ahead
and test no test the up, but now matches
what was expected here. Okay, so this is a
very simple package, and really, the logic
hair doesn't matter. What matters is we
now need to make this package work without
our modification to the test here,
Basically, by doing that and I'm going to
assume that we're done developing this
simple package, we need to publish this
package and use it through npm. So what I
want to do here? I'd like to go inside
test and do something like npm install
frame print. And once this command is
done, I should be able to run my test and
see the exact same output that's expected.
So to get this npm install command to
install our own frame print, we need to
publish that package now. Since the
package name is unique at npm j dot com
tow, avoid conflict as we're all doing
this exercise, I'm gonna add the prefects
to this package here and use my own
username at npm JSON com This way, when UI
npm install the package, you can use your
own username and you can publish your own
package as well. So you actually need to
create an account at npm JSON Com If you
don't have one to publish any package at
npm, you need to have credentials. So go
ahead and do that. So once you have an
account, you can use your user name and
password to publish the packages. So
here's what you need to do in npm. To
accomplish that, I'm going to clear this
command will come back to that in just a
little bit. And now, from anywhere here in
your shell, you need to do npm login. Npm
login is going to connect your npm just-as
com credentials with your local npm tool
here so that you can publish to your
account. So, npm Logan, we'll ask you for
username and password. Go ahead and put
these in and the email as well. This
should match the email that you used when
you created your account. And now I am
logged into npm GS. Very good. Now we can
publish the package. So this frame print
directory here is not yet a package
because it does not have a package that
Jason file. So we need to create a package
that Jason file Let me see d into IT frame
print and to create a package that Jason
we-can simply use npm in IT. The package
name is no longer frame print, so type in
your npm username. Dash frame print. The
version can be 100 This is the first
release you can add descriptions, entry
point, test command, git repository. And
I'm going to keep everything default here.
Okay, we have a package that, Jason. And
guess what? Once you have a package that
Jason, all you have to do is npm publish.
Just like that, This will publish your npm
package to npm j s dot com. So to test
that the published process was successful,
you need to go to this. You URL npm jess
dot com slash package slash the name of
the package that you used and you should
see your package published. This means
that npm can now install this package on
any machine. So if you haven't done the
first half of this exercise, you can just
install this package from npm and just use
IT. Now that we have a package published,
we can go back to the test directory here,
so I no longer need this index suggest
file. So focus on this index that Js file
under the test directory. Here it is using
the name of the package that I just
published. But remember that this package
is still in npm just dot com itself. We
need to bring it here locally, using npm
install for this file to access IT. So the
command that we need in this case is just
npm installed the name of the package and
this will download the package and place
it under the newly created Node Modules
directory right here. As you can see, this
is our package. And it is exactly the code
that we've written. But now this package
was downloaded from npm. And once we have
the package downloaded from npm we-can, go
ahead and test the script as is, and the
script will just work. So this is really
how simple it is to publish and use an npm package.