[Autogenerated] Let's talk about npm Ax
and the npm run scripts. Npm Ax is another
binary that you get when you install node.
It's part of the npm tool set, and the npm
Scripts feature is a useful and often
underrated feature of npm. IT enables you
to automate the way your team uses
your-app. You can use npm scripts to start
stop, restart or test your-app in a
standard way that encapsulates best
practices for this exercise. I prepared
this four script directory here under the
npm folder. In this folder, you should see
four files package that Jason and Package
Lock that Jason This is so that you can
install all the dependencies of this
exercise. Ah server that Js file, which
creates a simple express web server and
the test the Js file, which tests the math
square root function. Now you don't really
need to test the functions that are
available to you in JavaScript like these
thes functions are already tested. But
this is just an exercise To see examples
of how you can use npm scripts, take a
look at packaged adjacent. You'll see a
scripts section here with three entries,
start test and check You can add more
scripts in this section if you need to.
These scripts are defined with other CLI
tools like Node Justin es Linton. These
examples To run these scripts, we first
need to satisfy the dependencies listed
here in the files. UI do that using the
npm install command without any arguments
just like this. This will create a note
modules directory and place all the
dependencies we have here under that. So
let's test thes scripts one at a time. The
start script is going to run this command
node server digest. This is the same
command that you can just run here to
start Server did. Yes. In fact, go ahead
and test that it will say server is
running and the npm start script is going
to do the exact same action. So to run the
npm start script, you do npm run start
just like that. Now, for some of the
special scripts, Start is an example. Test
is another example. They actually have
shortcuts, so you don't need the run
command. You can just do npm start. So go
ahead and test that this is equivalent to
running note server Duchy s command and it
will run the server for you. And you can
go ahead and test the Web server on Port
8000 and it should be running. Let's try
the other script. Npm run test is going to
run the just command. Now, if you try the
just command here, it will not work. It
will say command not found, although just
was a dependency here and the binary for
just exist somewhere under the note
Modules folder. However, the just CLI tool
here is not a global one because we
installed IT locally under this folder.
The cool thing with npm scripts is you
don't need to worry about that as long as
just is installed locally under the note
modules, the npm script section is going
to find it. So if you run npm test another
one of the special npm commands that has a
shortcut for npm scripts, this will
actually fire up jest. IT will find just
under the new IT modules, and it will fire
it up and run the test. The test that Js
file, which is a special name that just is
gonna find now if you need to run just
right here outside of npm scripts, you
have a few options, but the easiest option
of all is to use the npm _________. So if
you do npm x-excess just MPX is short for
npm execute. MPX will also find the just
binary under the note modules folder and
it will just use IT so npm X just work as
well the es lint binary Here in the Czech
script is the same story. You can either
use it with MPX directly or if you use it
through the npm script, it'll work as
well. Now, the Czech script here is not a
special npm script, So to run it, you need
to do npm run check. So this will run the
command Eastland Server Digest and it will
check the server digest file for any ESL
and errors. Now, usually, when you do A s
lent, you need an s land configuration.
But I think I have a global one. Hears it
will just work and it's working and
checking that I have console statement and
server digest. Now, is lenses really
helpful? If this command does not work for
you, what you need to do is configure es
land and to configure es land. You need
access to the s land command itself. Now
we don't have it again. This is installed
locally under the note modules folder. So
to configure is land we can use MPX s lint
And what you need here is to initialize
eastland with a configuration file so you
can use the dash dash in IT argument here
and this will ask you a few questions
about how you like to configure es lint.
For example, I am using a popular style
guide so I can use the error functions
here to pick use a popular style guide and
I am using Airbnb. I like Airbnb because
they also support react and I use react.
So we'll go ahead and say no to react here
just Airbnb and the format can be
anything. I like to have it in JavaScript.
So what this command is going to do, it
will install some other dependencies. As
you can see here, those dependencies will
have the Airbnb configuration and it will
also create an S Linux R C file for your
project to work with the excellent. So
what's important to learn here is that we
use MPX here to access the local binary es
land that's included in this project, and
we were able to configure es land through
that. And if everything works for you, if
you run npm run check again, it should use
your ears lint and say that console log
statement is unexpected. It's a warning.
You're not supposed to leave console luck
statements around. So the npm Scripts
section here is really a good way for a
team of developers to have a standard way
of running things. This is how we run the
server. This is how we test the server.
This is how we check the server, and this
is really just the basic usage. But
there's more to the story. Certain names
in the npm run sections are special. You
can see the full list of these special
commands using npm help npm scripts. Also,
let's take a look at that so you'll see
them here with prefixes like pre and post.
So, for example, you have pre test and
post test. These commands will be run by
the npm Test Command before and after the
command, so let's go ahead and test that
I'm going to do a post test. And under
this command I'll do something like node
dashi to execute as script. And I'll just
console dot log in a string here console
log, done testing just like that. So guess
what Now? When we run the npm test script
itself, it will automatically run the post
Test npm test, and it will run the just
command. And when it's done, it will
execute the post test script and output
the council log message that we're done
testing. So these pre and post versions of
the npm run scripts give you an easy way
for some flexibility around major npm
events, like installing, publishing and
testing, and you can use them to customize
what's happening around these events. They
are very helpful when you need to
integrate your project with external
servers like a build or continuous
integration server, or if you need to do
custom actions before or after you release or deploy something new