[Autogenerated] in any note project. It's
usually a good idea to update your npm
dependencies before testing each release
to get the updates that have been made to
your dependencies. You want to at least
get any bug and security fixes in the
patch number of these dependencies. It's
also much easier to deal with these
updates if you do them frequently. The npm
update is the command you can use to do
that. It respects all the semantic
versioning strings that are in packaged
adjacent for this exercise. I have this
five update directory here under npm and
it has a package that Jason file with to
exact dependencies, load ash and request.
If you notice these version strings for
load ash and request do not have any
caret-symbol the prefixes. This makes them
exact their equivalent to doing equal sign
here. Which means I am interested in
exactly this version. So the first step is
to install these dependencies. So we do
that with npm install. This will download
the exact versions that we're interested
in and place them under the node Modules
directory. You can verify what versions
were installed using the npm ls command
now the npm ls command is going to l s the
whole dependency three. So basically all
your top level dependencies and all of
their dependencies on this request package
has some sub dependencies. But if you
scroll up a little bit here, you should
see the top level dependencies right here
at the beginning of the tree. And npm
installed the exact versions specified in
the package that Jason which means if I
issue the npm Update Command, nothing is
going to be updated because package that
Jason asks for exactly these versions now,
by default when you install any npm
package, let's, for example, installed the
express package. When npm installs that IT
rights IT with the carrot IT ation. So
this was added to package that Jason. But
it was added with the current notation,
which means that any update in the minor
section off the version is okay, We just
got the latest version off express. So npm
update will also not do anything. We don't
have anything that can be updated. We have
the exact versions that we're interested
in before playing with the version of
strings. Let me remove this express
dependency that I just installed you do
that with npm Uninstall Express and this
will remove it from under the note modules
directory. And it will also remove it from
package that Jason so we no longer depend
on this express package to explore the
update process. Let's add a prefix here to
the request package. I'm gonna add a
carrot to the request package. So this is
the default behavior. When you install
request on for load ash, I'm gonna add a
tilde. So the carrot in request means that
any minor update is okay So anything in
this section will be updated while the
tilde in load ash means Onley patch
updates are okay. You can see all the
versions that are available in an npm
package using the command npm show the
name of the package, for example request
and this will show everything about
request. If you're interested in just the
versions, you add the word versions, so
npm show request versions, and this will
give us an array of all the versions
available in request. Now they can't
version that we have is here, and the
latest version right now is to 87 0
because we've used the carrot in request.
The next update process is going to take
us from 2852287 Because this is a minor
update. And that's okay with the carrot
Asian. What about load Ash? Let's check
that out. So npm show load ash versions
and the latest version for load ash right
now is 4 17 10. And what I have here is
for 16 to with tell the annotation, which
means Onley patch updates are going to be
applied. So we're not going to go all the
way to 4 17. But we can get 4 16 6 because
that's a security and bug level fix. So
we'll go from 4 16 2 to 4 16 6 before
running the npm Update Command. Anyway, I
like to verify what packages are going to
be updated and to what exact versions are
they going to be updated? And instead of
doing this manual ing in your head and
checking the versions, there is an npm
command called npm outdated. This will
tell you what packages will be updated. It
will not update the packages, but it will
tell you that if you run the npm update
these wanted packages are where you're
going to get. So the current packages are
what you have. The wanted packages are
what you're going to get if you run the
npm update command and in here, it will
also show you the absolute latest
packages. If you're interested in those
because of semantic versioning in here,
we're not really getting the latest
package, but rather the latest bug fix
that we can have. And again, this is the
absolute minimum thing you should do when
you're planning to update your packages.
However, just be careful and test because
sometimes even patch level updates might
introduce new bugs in your system.
Alright. So to update UI, just run npm
update and this will update the packages
according to semantic versioning. And once
it's done, you can run npm ls I'm gonna
pipe that unless and this will give you
the latest dependency tree starting from
your top level dependencies here that were
updated to the latest. According to
semantic versioning, the package that
Jason file was also updated to reflect the
new versions that we're starting with
right now. And note how the npm Update
command used the carrot notation here.
Although I was using the tell the
invitation before, so be careful about
that. Now, what if I'm interested in a nup
date that is beyond the version string? I
can do that with npm. Install the name off
the package and I can actually place any
version here so I can say 4, 17 or just
four, and that will give me the latest on
the four. Or I could just say latest npm
installed load ash at Latest. And this
will give me the absolute latest load Ash
library, as you can see here for 17. 10.
And this match is the latest version for
load Ash right here with npm Show load ash
version. The singular version here is
going to give me the latest version
available. Load, ash. And it's the current
version that I have in package that Jason.
And this happened because I specified that
I am interested in the latest version of load ash