[Autogenerated] it's a wrap on this npm
course module. We covered a lot of topics
under npm, but they were really all
important and will be needed when working
with node projects. I'd like to remind
you, though, that npm is just one package
manager that you can use. There are a few
others, most notably the yawn project by
Facebook. The commands for these other
package managers might be slightly
different, but the concepts are similar.
Npm is what you get by default when you
install node, but you can easily switch to
other managers if you like them better. So
in this module we talked about what is npm
and why is it needed? UI explored the
basic commands for working with npm. UI
discussed the purpose of package that
Jason and package locked Jason. We learned
about semantic versioning and how the npm
commands work with them. We learned how to
locally and globally install npm packages
and how to use these installed packages.
In note, we created a simple npm package
and published that on npm Js dot com. We
learned about using npm X to execute
locally installed execute herbal npm
commands on. We saw how to use npm run
scripts to have a standard way to run and
test the tasks in a project. And finally
we learned how to check an update your
project dependency tree in the next
module. We'll talk about the most
important aspect about no jazz, which is
how it works with slow operations without blocking other operations.