[Autogenerated] Let's explore how to
define and use modules in note. But before
we do that, let me start with the basic
question. What exactly is a module in
note? The word module is basically a fancy
word that means a file or a folder that
contains code. That's IT. So this file
here with this simple console, the log
line is a module. I am currently under the
four Modules folder under the one define
use folder in the first file, right, there
is a module. However, the reason the word
module is a bit better to use than using
just the terms file or folder here is
because node actually does not just
execute the file as is. It wraps the file
with a function first. This is something
that you need to remember. So let me show
you what I mean. You know the keyword
arguments in JavaScript? If you access
that keyword inside the function like what
I'm doing in this file here, the cured
arguments will represent all the arguments
passed into dysfunction, regardless of how
many of them get past two IT. So if I
execute this file to arguments under this
folder, you'll notice How Right here This
is the representation off the arguments,
keyword. And it's representing all the
arguments that we passed here to the
dynamic arguments function. So this
arguments cured here is a handy way to
write functions that except a dynamic
number of arguments. Okay, here's a weird
question now, and this is one of the
questions I'd ask in a note interview.
What would know do if you console log the
keyword arguments on the top level of a
note file like this. If your answer is
arguments is not defined here because we
are not inside a function, you would not
be getting that No job. Your answer is
correct in a browser. But no, it has a
different story because not internally
wraps every file IT executes with a
function. This console logline here will
actually output something. Let's try IT.
Node three. Rapper digests IT outputs
exactly five arguments which noted, passed
to that hidden wrapping function when it
executes your file. You should remember
that every time you hear the word module,
this is not just a file. It's a function
that receives arguments, and it will also
return something. Let me write in comments
here. What node does internally to this
file? There is a function rapper here, So
basically, there's the function call, and
this function receives a set of arguments
and your could becomes the body of this
function, and then node will call this
function. The arguments that this wrapping
function receives are in order exports
module require underscore, underscore file
name and then underscore underscore dirt
name. Have you used any of these arguments
before? In your note file, you can use the
exports or module the exports to define
the A P I off the module. You can use
require to require other modules inside
this one and the underscore underscore
file name has the path of this file and
the underscore underscored Their name has
the path to the folder hosting this file.
All of these objects which she can use
inside this file, are not global objects.
They are just arguments to the wrapping
function. They are customized for each
file and they're different in each file.
So when inside a file, I do something like
exports dot a equal 42. I am just using
one of the arguments of the wrapping
function. The keyword exports here is not
some globally available keyword. It's just
the first argument to the hidden wrapping
function. This wrapping function is also
the reason why in node, when we define a
variable in any file on the top level,
like, for example, let G equal one. This G
variable will not be a global variable at
all. It's just a variable inside a
function. The scope of this variable is
the hidden wrapping function. This is
different than what a browser would do if
you define a variable top level like this.
Browsers do not have this hidden wrapping
function. So when you define a variable
like this in a browser in a script that
variable will be global. IT will be
available to all the scripts you include
after defining IT, because you're
basically putting it on the global scope.
But that's the browser, not note. Note has
the wrapping function, and this G here is
not global at all. It's just a local
variable inside the wrapping function. It
is really important that you remember that
this variable here is just scoped to the
built in wrapping function, all right. So
besides making five arguments available to
you inside any file The wrapping function
also internally return something and the
thing IT returns here is the module dot
exports property. This is what the built
in wrapping function return by default all
the time. For every file it will return
module the exports and module here is just
the module argument that gets passed to
the function as well. And it's the object
that note uses to manage the dependencies
and to manage the A _. _ _ of modules Note
that you don't need to use the return key
word here yourself. No, it will always
make this function return. The module
exports object, and this is the object we
can use to define the A P I of this
module. The exports object here is just an
alias for module the exports. When node
invokes the wrapping function, IT simply
passes module exports here as the value of
the first argument here. This is why we
can use the exports keyword itself to
export and new property on the A p I. But
what we're really modifying when we do
that is the module, the exports object,
which is the one being returned. So just
like I did exports the A equal 42. Here I
can do module the export and let's export
another property for this modules. AP I.
Let's do be equal 37 I could do that
because the module object itself is also
an argument that gets passed to the
wrapping function. So both A and B are
part of the A P I of this module because
exports is just an alias to module the
exports and were returning module the
exports to use this AP that we just
defined in these two lines here. There is
another file here in the same folder for
require, and this is invoking the require
function and passing it as a string the
path of the module. The result of this
require call is really the module the
exports object. That node returned from
our module. So the module AP I hear
becomes the module that exports that the
file returned and we can see the console
log in here. Let's go ahead and test that
real quick note for require. And as you
can see here, we're getting the properties
of the module that we defined here online.
Seven and eight This alias relation
between exports and module the exports is
the reason why if we reassign the exports
object directly. If we do exports equal
something, we're not really changing the
module. The experts object anymore. We're
just reassigning the alias. We're making
this variable point to a new local object
in here and no longer point to module the
exports. So if, for example, you want your
top level A p I to-be function instead of
an object, which is a valid case that we
use all the time. We want our top level a
p i to be a function not just an object.
You can't do it this way. This is not
okay. This will not work again because
you're not really modifying module the
export. You're just breaking the
assignment reference between experts and
module the experts. But you could totally
do module the exports equal ah function.
And that would be okay because module the
export is what being returned. And I can
change the value of module the exports
itself. So this line here is okay. And as
you can see, the top level a p I does not have to be an object