[Autogenerated] Here are some examples
that define and use multiple types of a P
I objects. I am now under the two examples
folder under the four Modules folder. And
in here we have eight files four different
AP I experts and how to use them. The
first file here is the simple case. When
you want your a p i to be a simple object,
you don't really need to use module the
exports. You could just use exports. So
you put exports and then you put
properties on your A p I. And to use this
module when you call the require function
on this module, you get back a simple AP.
I object so you can read the elements of
the A P i as properties on that object.
Note one use duchess. We are getting the
values that are exported through the AP
here because the FBI is just on object.
The second example here the top level a p
I is an array. So I needed to use module
the experts because I am reassigning the
default expert, which is usually an empty
object. And now I'm saying my top level a
p I is in the rate to use this kind of a p
I under to use here DJ s When you require
the module, you get back the value that
you need that value itself becomes your a
p I. And not how you can just in line the
require call inside some other function
because it's just a function call that
returns a value that value is your a p I.
And in this case, it's Henry. So note to
use the jazz and you get the array
directly here from the console log light
your-app I can also be just-as string.
Look at this file. This a p I is returning
at template String. Note that these
characters are the back deck characters,
not the single code characters because
this is a multi line template string and
the whole a p I is just returning this
string. So if I want to use this a p I
when I require the file, I get back an
object which is a string. So if I console
log this object, it will be a string. So
node three used gs. That is the string
that this a p I is using, but let's say
you do want an HTML template, but you want
it to be dynamic. You want to tell your
module that you'd like it to generate an
HTML template for a certain title. For
example, instead of a generic title, How
do you do that? You do it by exporting a
function. Check this one out. Four.
Function here. It's the exact same
template text, and it's being done through
a template string as well. But the
difference is that the top level a p I
here is now a function on. I used the
shorthand notation for the arrow function
here to have a narrow function that
receives the title as a single argument
and then return a template string that
injects the title value right here inside
the title tech. To use this, a p I. That
is basically a function when you require
this function here in four use, right, you
get back. Ah, function. I called IT your
template generator. It's a function, and
you can invoke this function with any
argument that you want, because the top
level a p I is itself a function. I
captured the result of the require call
into a variable. And I am now executing
that variable because it's just a
function. And the result of executing this
function is what the function returned
here, which is the template. So this
becomes my template and I can console log
that so note for you. Study s and you get
the exact same template. But now it is
being customized with a custom title that
I get to pass to the function that this a
p a is exploring. So this a p I is now a
lot more flexible than the previous one,
which just hard coded a value for me. So
these are just a few examples of how
flexible this module the exports object is
and how you can use it to return any kind of a p I in a node module.