[Autogenerated] if defining a variable on
the top level scope in a note module does
not make a global one. Is there a way to
define a global value in node? The answer
is yes, but you should really avoid doing
that. The Onley Global variables in note,
are the variables attached to this special
global object. This global object is the
equivalent to the window object in
browsers, and it's the only global concept
in note. If you inspect this global
object, I'm using a dirty trick here to
Onley. Show the top level properties on
this object rather than inspecting it as a
tree because it's a big one. If you
execute this file. No, the one there that
yes, you'll see a few things here on the
global object. There is the process
object, for example, and there are other
features like buffers and timers. All of
the's here are globally available in all
node modules because they're attached to
this special global object. So when you
use as a time out call set time out,
you're actually using global dot set time
out. But because it's part of the global
object, we can use it directly. We don't
need to do global dot because that's the
concept of the global object. In note,
things will just be available globally.
You can also attach new things to this
global object yourself in the to set the
Jets file here I have a simple example. I
am doing global The answer Equal 42 making
answer a new global value Now that you can
access in any node module, here's how he
contest that in the two tests suggest file
here I am requiring the file that added
the global value and then console logging.
Answer directly, not as part of a napi I.
And guess what? If we execute to test here
because answer was set on the global
object, you can access it from anywhere
directly. Pretty cool, right? Wrong. Don't
do that. Global values like this are bad.
This is true here, and it's also true in
the browser environment. You should not
make your code depend on any global state.
Just treat this global object as a built
in thing that node itself uses, and you shouldn't do not attach anything to IT.