[Autogenerated] Let's work under Folder
four. Event loop Here. The first file
here. One logged a jazz has a single
console. The log line. Execute this simple
file note. One logged the jest line. What
I want you to notice now is that note has
started an operating system process here,
and it's now done with that operating
system process. No, IT has finished the
process, and the operating system
terminated that process. A note processed
by default will not keep running in the
background unless it has a reason to. This
one liner script here did not really give
the note process a reason to continue
running. Let's now give the note process a
reason to continue running. We-can do so
by starting an interval timer. We've
learned about timers in a previous module.
Under this file to Interval. There is a
simple interval call here that executes a
console logline every five seconds. Go
ahead and execute this file now node to
interval and not how the note process now
did not exit. IT is running and it will
continue running forever until it gets
crashed by an unexpected error or the user
killed it manually with control. C the
real reason that process did not exit is
that notes. Event loop is itself busy now.
What is this event loop thing you ask? It
is your best friend and node. It's the
hidden magic that will take care off
anything asynchronous for you. And you
don't have to worry about working with
threads in other languages. If you need to
do a sync rinse work, you have to manage.
Threat yourself. You have to start them.
Do the a sync work inside of them, monitor
them, make sure they don't access shared
data or if they do, you want to make sure
that there are no race conditions. It is a
complicated task now. Some languages make
it easier than others, but I think the big
winner in this domain is note. Because you
just use notes. A P I and Mr Event Loop
here will do all the heavy lifting. The
event Lube is just a simple, infinite loop
that's built inside node, and its main
task is to monitor any asynchronous
operations that need to be run and figure
out when they're ready to be consumed. In
this example, the event Lubell Monitor
that set interval timer and every five
seconds will take the intervals callback,
which is the first argument to set
Interval the arrow function here. And it
will send this error function to V eight,
and V eight will execute what's inside
that function. Because this is in every
five second kind of thing. The note
process is going to continue to run
forever, and it will not exit. So while
this note processes running, if you go to
in another terminal and try the command PS
dash E F to list all the running processes
and pipe the output of this command on
grip note to just filter the list. Thio
any processes that are matching the word
node. This is a Linux command. But the
same list of processes can be seen and
filtered with the graphical program that
monitors process activities in your
operating system. So you should see the
process hosting our script right here. You
see that it is still running. Now I have a
few other processes that are matching
node. I think these are actually the Adam
editor itself here. Believe it or not,
this Adam editor here is a note
application. It is a complicated one. But
it's simply run with node, using an
application called Electron, which allows
you to use web and no technologies to
build cross platform desktop applications
for Mac Windows and Lennox. How cool is
that? Okay, so our process here is the
last one here because we started it last,
so it will have the highest process I'd.
You can kill our continuously running note
process, using the Linux skill Command
itself on giving it the process I d here.
But you can also kill any active note
process using Control C on its output
here. And that action will stop the event
loop and then remove the process from the
operating system. Run the same PS dash e f
Grab Note command now, and you'll see that
the process that was hosting the interval
file is gone. Notes. Event Loop works with
multiple phases and queues. At this point,
what I want you to remember is that every
note process starts this infinite loop
that we call event loop. But when the
process has no asynchronous operations to
perform, the event loop will exit and the
operating system will terminate that note process