[Autogenerated] What is the difference
between errors and exceptions and error is
simply a problem. Unknown problem
applications are usually not prepared to
deal with it, while an exception is a
condition that applications know about and
are prepared to deal with it. They catch
that condition and do something with it.
Let's talk about that in note. In The Five
Errors Directory here, I have three files.
The first file is one loop, and this file
is simply looping over an array of the
files, which uses files from the same
directory. I'm looping over this Falls
array using a four each call. And for each
file, we are basically reading the content
of the file using the read file sync
method, which is the first time we're
seeing this method. It's equivalent to
read file, but it will do the reading
synchronously, not a synchronously. We're
going to talk a little bit more about that
in the future, of course module. But for
now, let's focus on thinking about what's
gonna happen when this code encounters a
problem. So let's quickly run this code
and make sure it doesn't have any
problems. Right now it is running, and
it's reading to files data. Very good.
Now, what if I injected? Ah, file path
here. That does not exist. So this file
now in the middle does not exist in the
current directory. What do you think that
good is going to do? The code is going to
try and read a file that does not exist
and note will _____ and exit. So after
reading the first file successfully for
the second file note crashed on we're not
reading the third file in here. And this
is normal when note executes an error like
this one, which is basically not planned
for it will just _____. And this is
important to remember here because
although this process started the infinite
event lube to do any a sync actions, IT
immediately stop that lube when it
encountered this unexpected. There, I say
unexpected error here because the code did
not account for the possibility of that
error. We can make this code account for
the error by simply making an exception
for IT. UI right code to represent that
exception. So let's assume that trying to
read a file that does not exist is not
really a problem for this code. We're
gonna upgrade this case from a problem
which is an error into a condition which
is an exception. And the easiest way to do
that is through a try catch statement. So
if you look at the second example file
under this folder here to try this good is
using the same invalid file and the same
code. Except now I've put the file reading
part inside a dry catch statement. So try
this code and catch any errors. And inside
this catch block we-can, do whatever we
want with this error object. Once you
catch the error like this, the note
process will not _____ an exit when it
encounters any error within the catch
block when we run this code, because it's
going to generate an error. But that error
is wrapped inside a try catch statement.
The catch block will be executed. So not
how the note process did not _____. We
just got the file not found message for
the second file. And then the note process
continued to read third file because now
an invalid file path is no longer a
problem here. It's just an exception in
this code. It is okay to encounter files
that do not exist and just continue with
code. So this is a great feature, but it's
also a dangerous one. This code means that
we're okay with non existing files when we
attempt to read them. But it also means
that we're OK with any errors that
happened when we read a file. Not just the
error about a file that's not there. If,
for example, the file is there but has
corrupt data, this good will treat the
other error exactly the same. Making this
council logline here Not really inaccurate
one. Let me simulate that. The second
argument for read file sync here except an
encoding string So you can pass an utf
eight here to say I'd like to encode the
content of this file when I read it with
utf eight, let's pass an invalid,
including label. If you execute, that
could now because we did try, catch and
generically saying file not found. When
you encounter an error, we're going to see
the file not found message for all of
them. But really the error that happened
was not file not found. The error that's
happening here is that the second argument
to read File sync is an invalid, including
label, so this console log message is not
accurate. Amore Accurate message here
would be something went wrong, and we're
going to completely ignore it because this
is just a generic catching of the error
and that's not good. Here's the thing. If
you want your code to Onley, catch the
case for non existing files. You should
make this catch block here a bit more
specific in the third example file here.
You're going to see an example of that.
Take a look at three. Throw that jazz and
you'll notice the exact same code. Except
we're not generically catching the error
message. We have an if statement on this.
If statement is basically saying Onley,
ignore the error. If it's a file not found
error. Otherwise, throw the error object
again, and this throw line is what note
would have done with the error if we did
not have a try catch statement making this
code only ignore a specific case and
perform the default behavior. Otherwise,
in note, the default behavior oven error
is to have the process exit because the
state of that process is unknown and it is
not safe to continue running with an
unknown state. So let's try this one node
three. Throw that us. This is fine here
because this is an actual file, not found
error. And now let's simulate a bad,
including string again. Run the process
and the process will _____ and exit
because this is a problem. It's an unknown
error, unknown state of the process, and
the safest thing to do for that case is to have the process _____ and exit.