[Autogenerated] okay, You might be
wondering now if it's a normal thing for a
note process to _____ and exit, and we
should definitely let it do so. How is
this going to be an acceptable thing in
production? Remember when we talked about
why nodes is named node? Because you don't
run a single note process in production,
you run many. One working process exiting
should not mean the system is down. You
should be running a cluster of note
processes, and that cluster will have a
master process, which should be monitoring
your application worker processes. This is
true. Even if you're running a node
application on a single server, it's often
the case where production servers will
have many CBU course. You should be
running annoyed. Process for each core if
you're not running cluster. In that case,
you're not really utilizing the full power
of your machine. And even if you're
single, production server has a single
core. You should be running a cluster
anyway, because that cluster has the
simple job of monitoring the actual note
process and starting a new one. When the
process crashes and exits, you can run a
simple cluster in node using the built in
cluster module on, I go in depth about
that topic in the advanced Node.js course
here at Pluralsight. Alternatively, you
can use one of the many tools that wrap
the cluster module to run your note
application in production. PM two is one
example of these tools. If you run your
note application through a tool like PM to
that tool, can automatically use all the
available course in your server, and it
will automatically create a new process
every time an active process crashes and
exits. PM two can also reload your
application without any downtime. A tool
like PM to is really a must and production.