[Autogenerated] note originally used the
callback pattern for everything
asynchronous today. Notice changing, and
it's incrementally adopting other patterns
as they surface in the JavaScript language
itself. Let me show you some examples of
that under the A sync patterns. Here there
are six files. Let's start with one sync.
This is the pattern usually used in other
programming environments. Slow actions are
usually handled with threads directly, and
the code does not have any patterns to
consume. Data coming from these slow
actions. You can do that as well. In load.
We've seen this read File sync method in
previous videos. It's the synchronous
version that note makes available to read
files. You don't need any pattern to
consume its data. You get the data when
you call that method, and the whole
program here does not go through the event
loop were directly using the operating
system synchronous file reading a P I.
When you execute this code, you'll see the
file data console logline before the test
console logline because it's all
synchronous Now. Look at the to call back
pattern file here. This one is using the
read file method from the built NFS
module. This method is asynchronous. It
needs to go through the event loop. We
can't access the data directly after
calling this method. This is why Note came
up with this callback pattern, where the
last argument of any asynchronous function
like read file here is itself a function
which is known as the callback function.
This callback function is always the last
argument of the host function. The event
loop will make this call back executed
when the operating system is ready with
data for us. As I explained in the first
module of this course, one thing I want
you to notice about this callback pattern
is how the callback function always
receives an error object as it's first
argument. The data comes after that in the
second argument, and sometimes in many
arguments after that. This first error
argument is standard in the note idiomatic
callback pattern, which is why that
pattern is often referred to as the error
first callback pattern. If there is an
error in the code, this error first
argument will be an error object, and if
there is no error in the code, this first
argument will be passed as null when we
execute this file. You'll see the test
line first and then the file data line
here because of how read file is a sync.
Basically, this code was executed in two
IT orations of event Loop. The first
iteration executed read file itself and
the console log test lines. And that first
iteration, Onley, defined the callback
function. And also in that same IT oration
note will ask the operating system for
data later on once the operating system is
ready with data. And this could be a few
seconds later, the event Liu will go
through another iteration where it will
now invoke the callback function and
execute the console. Log online. Four.
Here This callback pattern is good but
limited, and it introduces some
complexities and inconveniences. One
famous inconvenience about call backs is
the fact that we need to nest them inside
each other if we're to make a synchronous
actions that depend on each other. Here's
an example under three callback nesting
that yes, we start with the same read file
method here to read the data of a file,
and then, once we have that data, will use
another FS method here, right file to
create a copy of this file. Note how I
needed to nest, the callback of the second
operation within the callback of the first
operation. And if I have yet another a
sync operation to be done after the right
file, I'll have to do more nesting here.
This problem is famously known as the
Pyramid of Doom in computer programming,
and it's not ideal. IT makes the good,
harder to write, read and maintain.
Luckily, since the JavaScript language
adopted the promise pattern which we
talked about in the modern JavaScript
course module, Note is doing that as well.
Look at four. Promise. If I digests no
today comes with a tool that you can use
to promise if I any built in asynchronous
AP I method, and this is a very good
start. In this example, I am using the
promise if I function to create a new
version of Read file, one that does not
need a callback but rather returns a
promise. And since it's returning a
promise, I am able to consume this
promise. Using the A sync await feature,
you can promise if I any asynchronous
action that's designed according to notes,
idiomatic callback pattern called back
last argument error. First argument within
that call back. Not only that note also
ships first level support for promises in
some modules as well. This FS module is
one of them. You don't really need to use
the promise. If I function here, you can
just use the native promises returned by
the F S module itself. Look at the five FS
promises that Js file and compare it with
the four. Promise If i the Js file we're d
structuring the read file method here from
a special object the promises object
that's attached to the top level a p I off
the FS module. By doing so, you get a
promise based read file out of the box and
you can consume it with the A sync a week
future as we did before. How cool is that?
This is the near future. Off all notes AP
ICE promises are better than callbacks.
The code is easier to read here, and
promises opened the door to so much
flexibility to nest operations and even
loop over them. Take a look at six
promised nesting dot Js file and compare
it with three callback nesting Dutch. Yes,
and see how I made the exact same copy
example, but with promises this time. And
look how much more readable this is. UI
just await on read file and then we await
on right file, and if we need to await
further, we just do it line by line. There
is no nesting going on here, and that
would make this code a lot easier to deal with.