[Autogenerated] There is a library in node
called Event Emitter, and it's an
important one. So let's talk about it here
in this video under the seven event
Emitters folder here, there is an example
digest for us to work, an example on event
emitting, and this is how we use the event
emitter. We require the events library,
which is built in. We don't need to npm
install anything here on UI. Usually name
the result of requiring the events library
the event in middle class. Just like this.
The Events library is one of the most
important built in libraries in note.
Because most of the other modules
implement the event Emitter module, for
example, streams in note. Our event
emitters. We've seen a few streams when we
talked about the process object. Remember,
the STD N and the STD out are both
streams, and that makes them event
emitters as well. And in the next module
will work with more streams. So let's
understand event emitters on their own
first. After requiring the event in middle
class like this, we create an event
emitter object. Let me put it in a
constant name IT my emitter and we use the
new keyword on the event emitter class. So
my emitter is now an object that can emit
events. An event emitting object has many
methods, but here are the two most
important ones. You can emit a string.
This string is a name that could be
anything, and you use it to identify a
certain event. So let's emit a test event
string here. Now, The other method on any
emitter object is how you can subscribe to
event emitted by this object. And you do
that using the dots on method. You say my
emitter dot on this test event string and
then you pass in a callback function in
here as the second argument. The my
emitter object will invoke this callback
function every time the event represented
by this string is fired. So let me put a
council logline here and log something
like test event waas fired. Here's how
this event emitting business is a lot more
flexible than single callbacks. You can do
this on operation multiple times. This
gives you the flexibility of defining
different behaviors in different functions
in response to a single event. Okay, here
is another one of them interview
questions. If we invoke this file now, how
many times will we see the test event was
fired? Message. Think about it and let me
execute this file note. Example that jazz
to test and that console logline was
invoked zero times. The reason here is
order. UI subscribed to the test event
three times, but that test event was not
fired after UI subscribed to IT. IT was
emitted once before we subscribe to it,
but no one was listening at that point. If
you limit the event after subscribing to
IT, you should now see the three callbacks
getting executed. Who is another interview
question if I don't emit this event after
the subscriptions that I just did, and I
just keep this line here, What can I do to
this line to make it trigger the
subscribers callbacks that happened after
IT without moving it to after the
subscribe calls, I can use the event loop.
I can delay the execution of this line to
the next tick of the event loop by using a
simple set immediate call. For example,
here is how to do that if we wrap this
emit line with a set immediate call. The
callback of set immediate will be placed
on the event lube, and it will be invoked
after the rest of this program is
executed. So these three subscribe calls
will happen before the emit call in that
case, and we see the test event was fired.
Message. This is event emitting very
simple, yet very powerful because it
allows for modules to work together without depending on any AP ice.