[Autogenerated] This was an important
module in this course. We talked about how
to define a news modules and note, and
we've seen some examples to define and use
multiple types off a P I. We talked about
the special global object and how you
should avoid using IT. We then talked
about notes event loop, the hidden magic
that allows you to easily do asynchronous
programming in node without using any
threads. UI briefly talked about air
handling and how to make exceptions for
problems. We talked about the concept of
clusters in note and how a master process
can restart other workers when they have
problems. We looked at notes, asynchronous
patterns and saw how the promised pattern
is a lot more flexible and readable than
the callback one. And finally we went
through a simple example for the event
emitter module, which is an important one
because most other modules and note used
the event emitter module one way or
another. In the next module of this
course, we'll talk about web servers and
how note provides some utilities to program these types of servers