[Autogenerated] note makes it very easy
for you to do network programming and
create a full and customizable Web server.
And it's all built in the run time. We've
seen this hello world example in the
second module of this course when we
talked about requiring scripts. I've
placed it here under the folder five web
to talk a little bit more about this S t
to-be module. As you know this, actually
to-be module is a built in one. It comes
with note. This is why we were able to run
this code without needing to npm install
anything. But if instead of SD to-be here,
we wanted to use another web framework Say
express, for example, we would need to npm
install the express package in this folder
before we can use it. But we don't need to
install anything for the built in,
actually, to-be module the require call
here returned something. It's just a
function call. And if you remember from
the previous module of this course, this
require call returns the a p I off the
module that we're requiring in here we're
capturing the A P I of the HDTV module
into a local variable which we also named
HD to-be. We don't have to, but that's
usually the convention. This local SD
to-be variable now has all the methods
defined on the public a P I of the HDTV
module, for example. One of these methods
is create server, which we're using here.
The create server is a function that
accepts an argument, and its argument is
also a function. This is why we have an in
line function reference here. This might
be a bit confusing if you heard the term
that functions are first class citizens in
JavaScript. This here is exactly what we
mean by that we can pass functions as
arguments to other functions. Another term
that you might have heard of here is the
term higher order functions. Those are
functions that receive other functions as
arguments or return other functions in our
code sample here that creates server
function is a higher order functions
because it receives another function as an
argument. So let me improve this code a
little bit by extracting this anonymous
function that we're passing to create
server and give it a name instead. So I'm
gonna capture it in a constant here on
Let's name IT. Request listener here and
I'm just gonna peace They could that I
just cut from create server. Now the
create server method can be passed The
request listener variable itself which
holds a reference to the function. This is
equivalent to what we had before.
Important side note. Here you pass in the
function reference here. You do not call
it like that. This is a big difference. By
calling the function the argument value
here becomes what the function returns,
not the function itself. What we want here
is to pass a reference to the function
itself which is basically a pointer toe
where the function is defined. Listener
functions received two objects the request
object and the response object. Now I name
them. Reckon rest here, but you can really
name them anything. These are positional
arguments. The first argument represent
the request side of a request event. And
the second argument represents the
response side of a request event. They're
famously named wreck and raise. So the
request listener here is a function that
will be invoked every time there is a
request event. This is important. Remember
when we talked about event emitters in the
previous module. Well, guess what This
server object that we get as a result of
calling the create server method is an
event emitter. And one of the events it
emits is named request. In fact, this same
code can be rewritten using the event
emitter ap I Instead of passing the
request listener function to create
server, we can use a call to server dot on
the event Name is request and pass the
request listener right here. Every time we
have a request, Event-Hubs into this
server were instructing the server object
to execute our request listener function.
Are you connecting the dots now? I
actually like this version Better than
using the shorthand notation of create
server. I think it's just more readable
inside the request handling function here
we can read information about the request
using the wreck object, for example, we
can read what you are all the user is
requesting. What parameters are they
sending along? What I p are they coming
from? And many other things we-can right
data back to the requester using the
response object here, which is what we're
doing using the end method this Docker end
method is equivalent to doing that right
and then doing response The end. It's just
a shorthand notation to writing a single
line and ending the connection. Since this
is an SD to-be communication thing, we
need to follow the SD to-be protocol. That
protocol, for example, requires an
explicit signal that the communication is
over. This is exactly why we need to use
the end method here. This dot and method
is not optional, because without it, the
SD to-be session will think that we're
still streaming data to IT. And of course,
we talked about how the create server
Onley creates the server method. It
doesn't make it actively listening to
requests to run the server and activated.
UI needed to call the dot listen method on
the server object this listen method
except many arguments. The first argument
is the operating system port, on which we
want the server to listen to incoming
requests and the last argument. If you
remember the idiomatic callback pattern,
this is our callback that will get invoked
if the server reserved the port and
started listening on it successfully. This
loss argument callback can be used as a
conformation here that the server is
ready. That's why we're console logging.
The confirmation message. The reason we
needed to use that callback fork
information here is because the listen
method itself is an asynchronous one. Note
also, that when we run this file, the note
process did not exit because the event
Lube is now also busy listening to
incoming connections on Port 40 to 42 it will do that forever.