[Autogenerated] no JSON development is a
bit different than many other run times
and frameworks. IT does not auto reload
any changes you're going to have to
remember to restart it. But let me show
you a better option. Remember, in this
same example, when we change things here
and saved UI needed to restart note to see
the new changes in the browser. This is
not ideal. The popular solution to this
problem in note is to monitor the
operating system files for saving events
and try to add a restart note. When you
get these events. There are many npm
packages that are designed for this exact
purpose. I usually use no _____. You just
npm install dash G node mon. It's probably
a good idea to have this package installed
globally, but it doesn't really have to
be. Once you have access to the note mon
command, you run your code with note mon
instead of note. So no _____ one. Hello
world Duchess, The note mon command is a
wrapper around the note command. So the
note mon command we just typed will run
our server as if we're running it with the
node command. But now it will monitor the
files for any save events and reload
itself when files are saved. So when we
change this to note and just hit the save
button, no _____ automatically restarted
itself and you'll be able to see the new
changes in effect. Of course, you don't
need this node mont package in production. This is just a development convenience.