[Autogenerated] the request Listener
function receives these two arguments.
Let's talk about them a bit more how to
use them. What information and
capabilities do they provide, how to know
what to do with them. The easiest way to
explore them is to log them. For example,
let's console log the request object here.
Now to get this line to execute. We don't
need to restart Note, thanks to no _____.
But we need to go make and actually to-be
request because this is the function that
gets executed. Perez de to-be request.
When we do a request, you'll see this big
object here in the logs. This is the
request object, and this is everything you
can do on it. It has a lot of properties,
and the printing here is also printing
everything nested under the main
properties of the request object, which is
a bit hard to read. To get a smaller
output about this request object, use dir
instead of log and pass in as the second
argument to it. The object with a property
depth equal to zero. This means do not
print any nested object on Leigh. Print
the first level of properties for this
request object? No, it has restarted
refreshed to see the new output. And now
we see on Lee the first level of
properties and any nested objects will not
be printed here. Not a couple of things
about this output here. The request object
is of type incoming message. It's the
class that was used to internally
instantiate a request object. This is good
to know, because if you want to find the
documentation about what you can do with
the request object, you need to go to the
incoming message class under the SD to-be
documentation. So this little request
object here belongs to the incoming
message class. All the properties and
events you find in this documentation
section applies to the request object.
Because the popular name of this incoming
message object is request one might
confuse it with this client Request class.
This client request class is used when you
want to use the SD to-be library as an
agent to fetch information from an http
server rather than as a server, which is
what our example is doing. So remember the
request object within an SD to-be server
listener function is of type incoming
message the other important thing to
notice here is that the console Docker
line was executed twice. We have to
request objects here, which means for a
single HDTV request coming from my chrome
browser, the listener function is executed
twice, not once. If you want to
investigate this a little bit further, and
you should drill down form or clues, for
example, look at the request property
values here, in particular the U R L
property. So instead of console Docker
request here, let's just log Request WRL
and see what that will output. So surgery
started. Refresh this guy and take a look
at the two girls were getting here. The
root request and the other is for the five
icon request. Micro is automatically
trying to ask the server if it has a five
icon. This girl is a property on the
request object, and it's actually the
property that web frameworks used to
implement their routing features. We'll
talk about web frameworks in the next
video. Let me now console there the
response object and take a look at that.
Refresh the browser and the response
object is of type server response. If you
need to look it up in the documentation
we-can use this response object to send a
few things over to the requester. IT can
control things like the status code and
the status message, the headers off the
response and any data we'd like to include
in the response body, which is what our
example is doing here. Both the request
and response objects are streams here. The
request object is a readable stream, while
the response object is a rideable one.
Because streams are all event emitters,
we-can subscribe to events emitted by
these objects too. We can also use them
with other streams, which is a really good
thing for you to learn right after this
course I cover in details in the advanced note course that Pluralsight.