[Autogenerated] while. No, it comes with
built in modules to work with S T to-be
SDK Bs and even actually to-be to these
modules or low level. And they offer
limited capabilities. For example, there
is no A P I to read body parameters from a
post request. You have to manually parse
the text, which you can do using other
note built in modules. But because of this
fact, a number of web frameworks have
surfaced in the note ecosystem to provide
a richer interface to create and work with
web servers. These frameworks usually rab
the underlying built in power in note and
give you a simpler AP to create more
complicated features in your Web servers.
The most popular of these options is the
Express GS framework. So let's create an
express based Web server example. Let's do
it here under the to express folder inside
the five web directory. I have an index
that he has already there, which is the
starting template often express server.
But the first thing that you need to do
really is to bring express here as a
dependency, and for that we need to use
npm installed and to use npm installed,
you should have packaged adjacent. So the
first step is to create a package that
Jason we can use the npm in IT command
here. And I'm just going to do Dash Dash.
She has to get the default of the npm unit
and this command will create a package
that Jason file for us. Here is package
that Jason here, Once we have packaged
adjacent like that, we bring in the
express dependency using npm Install
Express. This will download express, place
it under the note modules folder. And as
you can see, it documented that we started
depending on express for this project. If
you look under the note modules folder
now, you'll see a lot more dependencies
than Express Express is one of these guys.
But just keep in mind that all of these
packages are now part of your project.
Dependencies to use express UI require
express using the require function. The
express package exports its top level a p
i as a function. So when we captured the
returned AP, I into a local variable here
which is usually named expressed as well,
that express variable in our script is now
a function and This is why, to create an
express server, we just call this
function. The result of calling this
express function is an object that's
usually named server, or you'll see IT
named as app in some examples. Now, to
make the server object, listen to income
and requests from users off this web
server. We call the dot listened method on
it, which is very similar to the method we
use to create a Web server using the built
in HD to-be module. In note, it takes a
callback that gets invoked when the listen
operation is done. Now here's where
express is a bit different than the built
in module. We don't define a single
request. Listener UI define many
listeners. UI actually define a listener.
Per you are URL for every URL and actually
to-be operation that we want our server to
support UI. Define a listener, for
example. Usually the first URL that you
want to support is the route you URL UI is
the following sentence. To do that, we do
server dot get, specify the URL in the
first argument for this get function, so
slash here as a string, and the second
argument is the listener function that
receives both the request and response
object. So I just in lined IT here and
this guy receives request and response
inside the listener function. These
requesting response objects are also a bit
different. For example, instead of using
the dot right method on the response
object, we can use the dot send method.
You can use the dot send method to send
anything to the requester, not just a
string. You confer examples and then
object if you need to. And with that send,
you don't need to invoke the end method
Express will do that automatically. Let me
just send a string here. Hello, Express.
And let's run this code with no _____.
Remember, no _____ index suggests here
should run our express server. So with
this simple code, the server will start
accepting connections and requests. And if
the request matches one of the defined
Urals the listener for that, your URL will
be invoked. So when we go to the root in
point in the browser using the port UI
passed in the listen function, you'll get
the string UI defined in the dots and
method. However, if we go to a different
in point se slash about. For example,
Instead of slash, the server will not have
a listener. For that, you're just getting
a four or four here to define a listener.
For the slash about UI, just add one more
get method here and define it for slash
about instead of slash and let's respond
with a different message here. No _____
automatically restarted. Note. So let's
test both endpoint. This slash about is
going to respond with its message, and
this lash is going to continue to respond
with the original message. So, as you can
see, Express provides a more pleasant
Centex to implement more advanced features
in our Web servers. Without express, we
would have to do custom logic to implement
the same capabilities using just the
native SDK to-be module. And of course,
there are other frameworks that you can
use beside express. I'll mention three of
them. Here There is code Digest, which
focuses on more modern features of the
JavaScript language and the Neutering
time. There is sales judges, which is
inspired by rails, Really So, um or
featured web framework that provide
working with modules and auto generate AP
ice and many other cool features. And then
there is meteor, which offers UM, or
integrated way to build web applications
in general. And these are just some of the
popular options. There are actually
hundreds of other options that you can use
to build web servers with node Js, and you
get to pick the best one based on what you need.