[Autogenerated] one of the most popular
needs when working with web servers is to
work with a template language to deliver
static HTML that's generated based on some
data. Without a template in language, you
would need to do a lot of shrinking
combination to accomplish that task. There
are a few great options when it comes to
template languages with note, and most of
these options work with the big frameworks
like KOA and Express. The most popular
template in language in note is probably
pug, which used to be named Jade. This is
a simple language implementing the offside
rule, which means that the STM l nesting
is based on indentation. I'm not really a
fan of the offside rule, but if it's
something you like, check out pug. My
favorite template in language and no jazz
is handlebars. This is the same language
that the ember framework uses on. I find
it to be simple and feature rich, but the
simplest template ing language that you
can use is probably E. J s for embedded
JavaScript. You get a template language to
write HTML views, and you can imbed
JavaScript. While doing so. I prepared an
example for you to see how E. J s can be
used with the express here under the three
E. J s folder. Look at the package that
Jason, you'll see that we have the two
dependencies now express and E. J s. And
to bring these dependencies, you need to
run the npm installed command without any
arguments just like that. Now, look at
Index that Yes, this is the same example
that we've seen without E J s. And here
are the differences UI Instruct Express to
set the view engine to E. J s. This is the
only line really that's needed for
configuring express toe work with E. J s.
You set the view ancient to-be Js and then
inside of the request listeners instead of
sand here I am using render Index. This
means render one of the templates which
express finds by default under the views
directory inside this folder. So if you
look at the views directory, you'll notice
that I have an index that e. J s and then
about the E. J s and these air to
templates that are being used to render
html to the requester when they go to
slash and slash about. So the index that
E. J s has an hello e J s H two element
and the about the E. J s has an about H
two elements. And if you run the server
and after that, go to the port that we
just used. You'll see the index, the E. J
s template. And if you go to slash about,
you'll see the about E. J s template. And
this is all HTML that's coming from the
template in language. And because it's all
embedded JavaScript, you can embed
JavaScript. Let's put a div here and
inside the deal, I'm going to embed some
JavaScript. You use this kind of weird
Centex here, and inside of that, you can
put any JavaScript expression. So I'll do
math dot random, for example, and this
will give me a random value when I refresh
the template for E. J. S. There you go.
Embedded JavaScript, template ing
language. Very powerful. Now this syntax
here is specific to E. J s. Other
languages will have different syntax for
embedding JavaScript. If you follow my
online courses, you know that I am a big
fan off the react front end library and
the React Library uses the JSX Extension.
So react with JSX can be used as another
template ing option when it comes to
working with note on the back end. And
today, this is actually what I use when I
need template ing on the server. I use
react itself and GSX on the server, not
just on the front end. If you want to
check out the React y-access library, we
have the react just getting started course on Pluralsight.