[Autogenerated] node was originally
designed to help developers create web
servers, and then it was modified to be a
more generic runtime for JavaScript. When
it comes to working with web servers in
note, you have options. Lots of them.
We've seen how to work with the native
built in, actually to-be module itself
that comes with note. We learned how to
use tools like no _____ to automatically
reload node in development. We talked
about the request and response objects
within request listeners, and we explored
the express framework and saw how it
enables us to write more featured web
servers using shorter and easier to
maintain code. We've also looked at an
example that uses the E. J s TEM plating
language in the next module will explore
three other built in note modules that we can use to work with the operating system.