[Autogenerated] the OS module is a simple
one. IT provides a number of operating
system related utility methods. I wrote a
few examples of these methods here under
the six OS folder 10 SJs file. To use the
OS module you require first like this,
then the OS variable will have a few
methods you can call. For example, you can
read what the operating system platform as
set during the compiling of node. Using
this platform method, you can also read
the architecture of the US CPU. Is IT 30
to 64 arm or something else? You can read
information about each logical CPU core
with this CB used method. I'm just
counting them here. You can read
information about the environment like
where is the current user home directory?
And you can do operating system agnostic
operations like, for example, creating a
multi line string using the end of line
character. Although this is really less
important today because JavaScript itself
has template strings that can have
multiple lines, there are a few other
handy methods for this OS module that are
all well documented under the OS module documentation page