[Autogenerated] the FS module provides a
big AP for interacting with the file
system. We've seen a few of its methods
already. You've seen the basic read file
and write falling methods, but there are
so many other methods under this module.
This is probably the biggest AP I among
all the built in no jazz modules using
this FS module, not only you can read and
write files as buffers. You can also work
files as streams, which is a lot more
efficient when working with big files. You
can also work with directories and do many
operations on both directories and files.
Let me show you a few examples of things
you can do. Using the FS module. I'm using
the Promise based AP ICE. For these
examples, you can also use the original
call back a P I. For them and most of the
A. P I methods here have synchronous
versions that you can use as well. To use
all of these promise based methods, you
just a weight on them within a function
labeled a sync. Most of these methods are
based on a file path, and some of them
take an optional configuration object.
These square brackets here indicate that
this options object is optional. If you do
want to read and write files, I recommend
looking into the create read stream and
create right stream methods. These are so
much better than read, file and write
filed because the regular read file on
right file use buffers to work, and we'll
use a lot more memory than the streaming
based one. Using the F S module, you can
append data to a file. This will also
create the file. If it does not exist, you
can copy files, and if you attempt to copy
a file to a destination that already
exists, it'll be overridden. You can read
information about files using the stat
method. Using this method, you can get
data about the file like its size, for
example, without needing to read the whole
contents off the file, which is nice. This
method will also include time related data
about the file like, When was it created
and when was it last modified? You can
read users permissions for files and
directories using the access method, and
you can change the permissions and even
the owner of a file with the change mod
and change own methods. You can link and
unlinked files, and you can even truncate
a file's content if you need to. You can
make new directories, read the directories
list of files, remove the directory and
rename directories and files as well. This
is a very powerful module, even if you do
not use note as the host of your back and
servers. For example, I recently used the
F S module to generate test files for a
project that had hundreds of you I
components. It took me about 10 minutes to
do that, using the powerful methods you can see here for the FS module.