[Autogenerated] The child process module
provides four main methods that allow you
to execute any operating system command
from within a note process using a sub
process, and then get the result of
running that command in your main process.
The sky's the limit. Here, anything you
can do in your operating system shell can
be done from within note. The four main
methods are respond exact exact file, and
Fork Fork is a special one to create some
processes that run node itself again. This
is the concept that powers the cluster
concept In note. The other three can be
used to execute regular OS commands like L
S or P W D. For example. These have a few
pros and cons here. But I'm gonna save you
some research here and tell you that you
should use this pond method. It works with
streams, and it has very good defaults.
Here are a few examples of things you can
do with bond. You d structure this pond
method out of the require call to child
processes. Then you call this pond with a
string representing the command pwd here,
for example. Once you get the result of
that, you can use the pipe method to send
its output to the process. STD out, which
will print the spawned process output. In
the second example, I am reading the
content of a vial under my home directory
using the cat command. If you need to pass
the command arguments, you can use the
second argument of spawn, which is an
array of all the arguments you wish to
pass to the spawn process. Here's an
example. Sending two arguments. This will
list all the files in the current
directory. And finally, if you need to use
shell syntax in your spawned process, you
can pass in a configuration object with
shell set to true here, and with that, you
can get all the power of the shell I am
using, the told a here and the pipe
operator and passing arguments to commence
directly. This is a powerful option, but
it's also a dangerous one, especially if
you do not trust the source of where this
string is coming from. So I only use this
shell option if you need to, and if you
have control over or trust the source of the commands