[Autogenerated] Before we wrap up this
course, I'd like to show you one handy
trick about the bugging note applications
because I know you're going to run into
problems. No, it comes with a built in
debugging client, but that one is limited.
The cool thing about notes to ______ is
that it's beautifully integrated with
grown Dev tools. If you're familiar with
these, you know how powerful they are. All
that power is available to you when
working with note as well. To demonstrate
this, I've prepared a file with a bug
under the six OS folder here, File four
Bug has a simple function that is supposed
to take an array and convert it into an
object. So here is some test input. This
is an array, and you can see the output
that I'm expecting right here. It's
supposed to convert the rate into an
object. You can easily convert an array
into anything using the powerful reduce
function. However, when we run this file
node for bug, we don't get the expected
output, but rather a weird one. So what is
going on here? We can debug simply run
this file with dash dash, inspect B R K
brk. Here means break. So don't execute
anything at first, but rather stop in a
debugging state. When you run this, it
starts a debugging utility. It doesn't run
the file now in your chrome, go to this
special Ural Chrome Colin slash slash
Inspect. You'll see your note process
listed here inside targets, and it is
inspecting our file. Click on this inspect
link. And just like that, you have the
powerful Chrome Dev tools working for your
no descript. How cool is that? This is
really a big deal. Go ahead and try it out
and see how fast you can find bugs. Now
you can place and clear break points. You
can set watchers. You can step over step
into function calls. You can use the
console to see values and structures and
many other powerful features really on
before we debunk this code. Note how the
wrapping function showed up here because
every note module get this rapper. You
don't just execute your own code, you
execute your code within a function. So
this is a good reminder here, right? All
right, so let's debunk this good. Let's
place break point right here. Online.
Three which is inside the reduced
function. My expectation here is that the
line should be called five times and each
time it should have an accumulated version
of the desired object. And now click the
resume button here and it should stop on
the first call of this line. And it did.
Now you can hover over the variables here
to see their values, or you can just use
the console log to see their value as
well. So it looks like the current is
empty object and the accumulator is not an
empty object. So this right there is not
matching my expectation. The accumulator
should be an empty object at first, and
they can't should point to the current
element that we're entering over. So right
away you realize that current and
accumulators are swapped. The first
argument is the accumulator, and the
second argument is the current elements.
So to fix this bug, all we need to do is
make the accumulator first and the current
second and test to see if that works. And it did