[Autogenerated] in this last module, we
talked about a few built in note modules.
I went over a few of the capabilities of
the OS module, the FS module, the child
process module, and I showed you how you
can debug note applications using Chrome
Dev tools, which is my favorite feature in
modern note. It's a wrap on this course. I
hope you've enjoyed it and learned a thing
or two. Please don't hesitate to leave me
any feedback or ask any questions in the
discussions tab at the course page. If
this course wasn't helpful to you in any
way, it'll be nice to hear why and help us
here at Pluralsight toe Update. Discourse
for the better. If you're excited about
node and you're ready to learn more, check
out the advanced Node.js course here at
Pluralsight. After understanding
everything in this course, I think you're
definitely ready for this advanced one.
And if you like books, I wrote a book as
well about some of the advanced concepts
and note if you like smaller reads about
note, I actively block on medium com, and
a lot of what I write is about note in
JavaScript. Here's one other thing you can
do. Take that Pluralsight skill. I Q test
for note and see where your knowledge gaps
are. Don't get distracted by my awesome
score here. I can't brag about that
because yours truly wrote the questions
for this skill. I Q test After this
getting started. Course, I'm hoping you'll
be able to score at least 1 50 on this
test. And if you take the advanced course
and finish that, you should be able to
score at least 250. If you do take that
score, tweet about it and ping me on
Twitter. Putting these courses together is
long and hard work. It'll be nice to hear
if that effort helped you. Good luck, and thanks for watching.