- [Instructor] I've
downloaded the exercise files
and placed the folder on my desktop.
Let me show you what's inside.
Here we have the folders containing
the finished source for each project
that we'll be developing.
For example, 02_01 contains a source
for Chapter 02, Video One.
If you would like to load a project
from an exercise file
for the Angular project,
you'll have to take an extra step.
Let's begin by opening
up the exercise file
inside Visual Studio Code.
So I'll open up 05_01.
And if it has a package.json file,
that means it has dependencies.
So I'll use npm install to
install those dependencies.
And it's created a Node Modules folder
that contains all of the packages.
Once it's finished, you
can continue developing
or exploring the project.
Although these exercise files
are available, I suggest using them only
as a reference if you get stuck.
I highly suggest creating everything
from start to finish as you follow along
in the course, as practice makes perfect.