- [Instructor] Node is an open-source,
cross-platform runtime environment
for service-side and
networking applications.
It's built on top of Chrome's JavaScript
runtime, the V8 engine.
And so applications for Node
are written in JavaScript.
This is why many developers like Node,
because it's lightweight and you can write
your front-end and backend
in the same language.
But we'll cover more on that later.
If we head over to nodejs.org,
we can see the different
sections we have access to.
And one in particular
you might find useful.
In the top navigation, let's
go ahead and click on Docs.
And then let's click on
Docs for Version 8.6.0,
or the latest version.
Here, we'll be able to see all
the systems available to Node.
So if you ever run into any problems,
or would like to know
the parameters needed
for a function, such as the file system,
which we'll be using later in this course,
the API docs is a great
place to learn more
about the systems and
modules Node has to offer.