- In this course we'll be
creating a demo chat application.
It will feature HTTP requests
made from the front end
to the back end,
as well as web sockets through Socket.IO,
which will allow for
automatic push notifications
from the server to the client.
So let's take a look at that.
So I can post a new message
and it will automatically
show up in my client,
but in the second client as well,
and vice versa.
In fact, we can open up as
many clients as we like,
and it will scale.
We can even restart our clients,
and the data will still show.
And we'll be using MongoDB and
mLab to make our data persist
Most of the node concepts will be taught
by developing this app.
While a few of the more
fundamental concepts will be taught
through separate programming lessons.