- [Instructor] Let's
continue by installing node.
Head over to nodejs.org
and then in the top navigation
bar select downloads.
If you see an option
between LTS and current,
select current so that
we get the latest version
and at the time of this
production, it's version 8.6.
Then download the installer
for the operating system
which makes sense for you.
Afterwards, let's go ahead
and start the installer.
Once the installer initializes,
let's go through the different sections.
We'll accept the terms.
Leave the default installation directory.
And leave the default features enabled.
Then I'll hit install.
Since I'm updating node on my end,
the status might have
looked slightly different.
I'll hit finish.
And now let's test that node
has successfully installed
by opening up your
terminal or command prompt.
So I've launched the
command prompt on Windows
and I'll type in node dash v for version.
And as we can see, it's
the correct version 8.6.
If this is still not working for you,
you can go ahead and restart your computer
and give it another shot.