- [Instructor] Modern web
apps and websites all have
some front end components
or functionality.
Since the browser running these apps
all use JavaScript,
these components usually
are written in JavaScript.
It's nice to have both
your front end and back end
written in the same language
for multiple reasons.
First, there are no
syntactical differences
to worry about as with
two different languages.
For a long time, I was
programming with C# only
and switching to and
from JavaScript and C#
after long delays added some overhead
to my ability to focus.
This benefit is not as big
as being able to share code
and data structure between
your front end and back end.
Let's take a look at some examples
of where code sharing might be useful.
There are many great libraries
for encryption or utility
such as Underscore, that
can be used for both
the front end and the back end.
An example could be, if you are writing
a user authentication system with tokens,
you might want to use the
same token and encryption
library on both the front end and back end
to authorize your users.
Or, if you're writing a custom algorithm
or some sort of logic or function
that you could use both on
the front end and back end.
One example I can think of is
if you're writing a web game.
You will perform some
sort of attack algorithm
on the front end, or the game client,
and you'll verify it on
the back end in the server
to make sure nobody's cheating.
And to do that, you'll
need the same algorithm
on both the front end and back end.
Another example is a data model.
For example, the definition of your user
which can have many properties.
With all of these examples,
if they are not in the same language,
there will be maintenance overhead.
Let's imagine having to
change 20 data models
with multiple properties in each model
in two different languages.
It's much better to
have to do it only once.
This is a key principle of programming.
And one of the benefits
we get when we code share
and have our front end and back end
in the same language.