- [Instructor] Let's
summarize some of the benefits
and features of JavaScript.
With Node, we get access
to sharing the language
between the back end and the front end,
and as well, sharing the code
between the back end and the front end.
Another difference, and one that I like,
is that JavaScript is a dynamic language,
meaning the type is determined by value,
not when the variable is declared.
It is loosely typed versus strongly typed.
Another nice benefit is
that JSON comes naturally
to JavaScript, which makes
it ideal for web apps
both on the front end and back end.
JSON stands for JavaScript
Object Notation,
and it's based on a subset
of the JavaScript language.
A good example is passing
data from our back end
to our front end.
In other environments
with different languages,
you would have to do
some sort of conversion.
With JavaScript it's much easier.
Overall, JavaScript has many pros,
but these can be seen as cons
depending on the circumstance.
JavaScript is definitely
not the ultimate solution,
but sharing JavaScript
between your front end
and back end makes web app development
that much more fun.