- [Narrator] When you
execute a task synchronously,
you wait for it to finish before moving on
to another task which
is what causes blocking.
On the other hand, when you
execute tasks asynchronously,
you can move on to another task
without having to wait for
the previous task to finish.
For example, if you've
ever used an application
or a website where you
had to submit a form
and everything went
gray until the response
was received, that's
the background process
running synchronously and
blocking the responsiveness
of the user interface until it completes.
If we were to make a
list of all the things
you could do on a
computer and ordered them
based on their completion time,
there would be two that require
relatively long waiting times:
networking access and file system access.
And with a web app, these are some
of the most common functions.
This is why Node performs
so well for web apps.
The most common way to get started
with asynchronous code is to do callbacks.
So let's take a look at some code.
You could type this out in
the editor of your choice.
I'll be using Visual Studio code.
With this demo app, we're
loading the filesystem,
and then we're reading the
directories from drive C.
Once that completes, it then executes
the next line and so on.
And so, when I execute this,
we should see the
console log that displays
the directory list, and then we'll see
the next console log which
says "this comes after."
I'll be trying that now,
and you could follow along
if you like or just watch as I explain.
If you're following along, you could use
a terminal or a command
prompt to execute the code.
Or if you're using Visual Studio code,
you can use the integrated terminal
by going to View, Integrated Terminal.
And then I'll use Node and type out
the filename, sync-demo.js.
So the first thing we will
see is the console log
of the directory list.
And then as expected, we will then see
"this comes after."
So now, let's take a look
at a different version
of this code using asynchronous code.
I'll go ahead and run
this before I even explain
what it will do and how it works.
We can see that the
directory listing is shown.
And if we scroll up, we can see the text
"this comes after" before
our directory listing.
So let's take a look at why
this occurred in reverse.
Even though the console
log for "this comes after"
is on the last line, it
still executes first.
And the reason is because of this callback
which I have defined on
line three as a function.
And I pass it into the
filesystem for reading
the directory on line seven.
So instead of the execution waiting
for readdir to finish, it continues
and goes to the next line.
And then once readdir finishes,
it calls this function
which is our callback,
and then it executes the
console log on line nine.
You might be wondering why I called
our callback phoneNumber.
Well, a good analogy for callbacks is
calling technical support
for your Internet provider.
For most companies, you
have to wait on hold
and put your day on hold until an agent
is available to take your call.
But some companies have something
that's also called a callback
because it functions in the same way.
Once you register with your phone number
for a callback, you can hang up
and carry on with your day.
And then, the agent will call you back
when they are available
in much of the same way that readdir calls
our phoneNumber callback
which is described
on line seven or defined
as the function above.