- [Instructor] Now let's take a look
at how modules work inside node.js.
We'll dive right in and
start creating our own.
Let's create a new file.
So in Visual Studio code,
I'll hit the new file icon
and we'll call this my-module.js.
And now let's create another
file that we'll be using
our new module.
I'll call it module-demo.js.
The idea is to get the
code inside my module
to be accessible inside our module demo.
The power behind that, for example,
this could be a math
library that we've written
and we'd like to reuse
it inside different files
or maybe even inside different projects.
This leverages the concept of code reuse.
So to continue, let's go over to my module
and we'll use the exports object
and we can pass in any data
we'd like with exports.
We'll create a property called myText
and we'll set that to
some placeholder value.
I'll set it to hello from module.
(keys clicking on keyboard)
Node has a simple module loading system.
In Node, files and modules are
in a one to one correspondence
and in order to access my module,
I'll first set its
reference to a variable.
So let's go in our module demo
and I'll call this variable myModule.
And I'll use require to bring it in.
(keys clicking on keyboard)
And then I'll specify the path.
And now to test this, let's
do a simple console log
in the line below.
We'll test to see if we're
getting the same value
from our module.
So we'll access our module
reference with myModule
and then we'll get the value
from the property we created, .myText.
Now let's go over to
our console or terminal
and execute our module demo.
So I'll type in node and then
the file name module demo.
And as we can see, we're
getting our console log
with the hello from
module placeholder text.
And so we were able to access data
in our module demo from
another module or file.
We'll be able to do the same thing
with functionality later on.