- [Narrator] We covered creating
our own modules for Node,
but what about third party modules?
Node has something called
a Node Package Manager,
or NPM for short.
And packages are one or more
modules bundled together.
One of the more popular
packages is called Lodash.
Let's cover how we can install it,
and then how we can make use of it.
Let's go over to our console or terminal.
And we'll install it using NPM.
So let's type in "npm install lodash".
And if we take a look in our directory,
we can see a new folder was
created, called "node_modules"
and inside there, we'll see "lodash".
The folder "lodash" itself
has several JavaScript
files that provide us
with all of the functionality
and features of Lodash.
Now that we have it
installed, let's create a file
that we'll use to write our own code
which will utilize Lodash.
So I'll create the new
file called "demo.js".
Next, we'll use "require"
just like we did before
for our custom module, to bring in Lodash.
And I'll set it in a variable called "_".
And this is common practice with Lodash,
so that we can easily
access its functionality.
And then I'll use "require",
and specify "lodash".
Notice that I didn't have
to specify a location,
since Node already knows
the default location
for its modules.
Then let's use a "console.log",
and then I'll use the
"_.", and as we can see,
there are many functions
we have access to.
A simple one could be "random".
So let's select that, and let's try to get
a random number between
one and one hundred.
If we were to do this
with plain JavaScript,
it would take several function
calls to the math library.
But with Lodash, we get
that functionality built in.
So let's save this, and give it a try.
So I'll use "node", and specify "demo.js".
And we got a value of 53 in our console.
Let's try running it one more time.
And once again, as you can see,
we're getting a random
value, as we specified,
between one and one hundred.
There are several different
types of NPM packages,
and some will work as
command line interfaces.
Let's take a look at one of those now,
that's called Nodemon.
First let's install it.
But because it is a command
line interface package,
we'll need to install it
with the "global" flag.
That way, we get access to it
regardless of what project we're in.
So we'll append "-g"
inside the install command.
If we take a look at our
"node_modules" folder,
we can see that there was
no installation of Nodemon.
Once again, that is because
it is installed globally,
and not in our local
"node_modules" directory.
So to use it, we can type in
"nodemon" instead of "node".
What this allows us to do is
automatically execute our "demo.js"
anytime there's a change.
So we don't have to keep typing in "node"
to execute the new changes.
So for example, instead
of getting the range of
one to one hundred in our random call,
I'd like one to ten.
I'll save it by hitting Control-S,
and you can see Nodemon
detects those changes,
and automatically executes it.
Now, what if we end up installing
several third party packages, and we want
to keep track of what we have installed
and are dependent on in a list somewhere?
That's where the
"package.json" file comes in,
so let's take a look at that next.