- [Instructor] We have our own project
and our own custom files
and third party packages
from where we left off previously.
But what if wanted to
distribute our app or project
or put it into a git repository?
It wouldn't make sense to include
all of the packages we depend on
because they take up a lot of space
and since there are hundreds,
if not thousands, of files
each package depends on,
it takes a long time to transfer those.
But then the developer,
who just got our project,
will have to manually install
all of those packages.
And, if your depending on a few dozen,
it will take a lot of time
to execute all of those npm install calls
each time we download a new
project or take in an update.
To solve that,
we can create a package.json file.
Among other things,
it stores a list of the packages
you depend on in your project.
That way, when using
the npm command install,
it will go through that list
and install everything automatically.
So to create a package.json file,
let's go to our terminal
and type in npm init.
This will ask us several questions.
For now, I'll go ahead and
use all of the defaults.
But you can customize this
for your specific project
when it comes time to production.
Once its about to generate the file,
it'll ask you to confirm
and I'll submit y for yes.
At that point,
it should have generated
a package.json file.
Let's take a look at that.
As it is now,
it just contains all of those defaults
we were prompted to modify
when we used npm init.
It also was nice enough
to look in our node modules folder
and see what dependencies
we have in there,
automatically adding them
to the dependencies list.
Another shortcut you might want to know
is if you're trying to create
a package.json file quickly,
you can use the command npm init --yes,
to create one with all of the defaults.
Now that we have an understanding
of how to work with modules
and packages inside Node,
let's take a look at using
one of the more popular
built-in node modules
for reading and writing files.