(Male Narrator)
- There are two areas where
heavy input/output takes place.
Network and disc access.
So let's take a look at
disk access to begin with
by working with some files.
We'll start with reading files and then
move onto writing our own files.
In order to do that we're going to require
access to the file system
that's built with the node.
But first let's start
by creating a new file.
I'll call this demo.js.
Now let's require in the file system
and I'll call it fs for short.
And as you can see, the library itself
is also called fs.
The next command we'll perform will be
to read from the file
but we don't have a file to read yet
so let's create a temporary JSON file
and put some data into it.
I'll call it data.json
and in here we'll simply create
an object that has a property name.
And we need to wrap the
property in double quotes.
Then I'll use a colon and I'll use the
name Tim as a place holder.
Let's close that out.
The first thing we'll do
is access the file system
with a function called, read file.
(typing)
And now let's pass in the location of our
data JSON file.
The second parameter since this is
an asynchronous function
will be our call back.
So I could define a separate function
like we did in our asynchronous video
or I could provide an anonymous function
and place it in the
second parameter directly.
The callback will pass an error
and then the data that's read in.
And so that's another way
we can handle the call back.
Another way yet would be
to use an arrow function.
And it's slightly more compact
than the previous syntax.
So we'll use that going forward.
For now, let's go ahead
and console log the data
we get and see what happens.
(typing)
And then I'll use nodemon
to execute our demo.
As you can see we got some sort of output
with a buffer at the start.
That's not what we have inside our JSON.
So what's going on?
What's happening is we didn't
specify the file format.
And in order to read the JSON file and
other documents we need to
specify the UTF 8 format.
So instead of the callback
being the second parameter
we'll push it over to the third parameter.
And then we'll specify, as a string,
UTF-8 as a second parameter.
Let's save that and as you can see
we're able to read in the JSON just fine.
Another good to know
is that we can actually
access our JSON file
with a require directly
instead of using read file.
Let's try that out now.
So I'll go to line two
and create a data variable
set it to require and specify
the path to data.json.
Then let's console log data.
(typing)
I'll save that.
And now you can see we're getting
two objects in our console.
One from the require and
one from our read file.
They look a bit different so let's see
what those differences are.
The first thing I'm going to do is
try to access the property
name from our require
to see if it's a true
object or just a string.
So I'll go over to line
four and type in dot name.
If I save that we can see
it's outputting just the name.
And so we're able to
access the property and
therefore it is an object.
Let's try to do the
same for our read file.
As you can see, it's undefined.
Therefore it is just a string.
So let's create a new
variable inside our read file
callback called data and
set it to json.parse.
And then I'll pass in data.
So, essentially it's
taking our data parameter
converting it to JSON
and then overriding it.
And then we're able to access data.name.
And if we look in our console we can see
there are two names being displayed.