- [Instructor] Now that we have
a good grasp of reading
files from the file system,
let's move on to trying
to read directories
with the file system as well.
Let's create a new demo file.
And once again, we'll need
access to the file system.
And so I'll require an fs.
And we'll use a function from
the file system called readdir.
The first parameter we'll need
to pass in is the location we want
to read our directories from.
So let's use Drive C as an example.
Then once again, we'll create a callback
that takes in an error and data.
And then let's console-log the data.
Let's save that, and I'll
use nodemon to run demo.
And you can see we're getting all
of the directories inside our Drive C.
As you can see, reading directories
is very straightforward.
Next let's take a look at writing files.