- [Instructor] Since we
know how to read files
and read directories, next,
let's move onto writing our own files.
As usual, we'll begin
by creating a new file,
called demo.js and let's
bring in the file system.
And as you probably guessed,
in order to write a file,
we're going to access the file system
and use the function called writeFile.
The first parameter is
the name of the file
and we'll be writing a JSON file
and we'll simply call it data.json.
The second parameter, is the actual data
that will be written to the file.
We could add it inline, but I'm going
to create a variable for that.
So above our function, let's
add a variable called data
and set it to a JSON object.
Inside here, we'll add
a property called name
and we'll pass in Bob as the value.
And then, let's pass our new data object
as the second parameter
to our writeFile function.
Let's save that, so let's
go ahead and execute it.
I'll use node and specify demo.js.
And as you can see, a
data.json file is created.
But if we look inside, we're
not seeing what we expected.
And that's because the second
parameter expects a string,
yet we're passing in a JSON object.
So let's convert our
object over into a string.
So we could manually do
it by wrapping everything
in double quotes including
the property name,
but an easier way is to use JSON.stringify
so I'll modify that on line seven.
Let's save that and try running it again.
Let's open our data.json
and we can see that
our JSON file is now
in the correct format.
So everything's working, but
you might have noticed that
we're getting a deprecation
warning when we run our demo,
telling us that calling
an asynchronous function
without a callback is deprecated.
And if we hover over
writeFile, we can see that
the first parameter is the
path, the second is the data,
and the third is a callback,
so let's create that.
And this simply passes an error,
in case there was an error.
And I'll just use a
console.log and I'll write in
the console 'write finished'
and then I'll pass in
the error in case there was an error.
So let's save that and
try to run it again.
And you can see that
the write was finished
and we're no longer getting
a deprecation warning.
Now that we have a good idea of working
with the file system, let's take a look at
some of the popular web
frameworks for Node.