- [Instructor] Let's
take a look at some of
the available frameworks for Node.
But first, what is a framework?
It's sometimes interesting
when we look at a definition
in its generic form.
For example, a framework
is an essential supporting
structure of a building,
vehicle, or object.
And in software, it's
essentially the same thing.
It is a supporting structure
that allows you to build on top of it.
When it comes to web, and
we want to build large APIs,
or maybe HTTP servers,
we can leverage web frameworks,
and there are several
options we can look at.
Each of these provide
us with the structure
and components you need
to quickly make serving
static files, like
traditional websites, easy.
Or we can put together a web
API to interact in a web app.
A web API is a service that
allows us to get and save data
to our server or back end,
such as a web API that allows
us to maybe create users,
serve a list of users, et cetera.
Now let's take a look
at the different options
we have for web frameworks for Node.
We'll be looking at Express,
which is a very traditional framework.
It's tried and tested,
and it's simple to use.
The next framework we'll
look at is called Sails.
It has many sub-frameworks such as an ORM,
or object relational mapper,
which gives us database access
and many other rich features.
Then there is Koa, which is
the most modern framework.
So let's go ahead and take
a look at each of these
in more detail.