- [Instructor] Lets take a look
at the first web framework for Node.
We'll head over to expressjs.com.
If we scroll down a bit,
we can see it has support for
web applications and web APIs.
But first, what is a web application?
There might some confusion
around its definition.
Is is something for the front end
or something for the back end?
When I think of apps,
I think of things that run in your browser
or mobile devices.
But those apps often
need to talk to a server.
For example, to log users in
or get a list of data to display, etc.
One way to think of it
is that a web app has some functionality
on the front end and some on the back end.
The app, as a whole,
is distributed across
both front and back end.
Imagine Twitter without
being able to get any tweets
from its back end?
That being said,
Express.js runs within Node
and Node is something
just for the back end.
But it contributes to the app as a whole
which will talk to the back end.
As mentioned before,
there is a lot of community
support and online documentation
because Express.js has been
around for such a long time.