- [Instructor] Socket.io
enables real time,
bidirectional, event based communication.
Express on the other
hand allows the client
to send a request to the server,
but the server cannot
send request to the client
and so it does not have
bidirectional communication.
Socket.io solves this.
In other words, we can push notifications
from the server to the client
when an event happens,
as well as other data.
We will see how this works
eventually with our demo app.
Socket.io has two parts,
a client side library
that runs on the browser,
and a server side library for node.js.
Both components have an API
that's nearly identical.
And just like node.js, it is event driven.
Now that we've had a brief intro
into some of the most popular
web frameworks for node,
let's go ahead and create
the demo application
utilizing them.
Let's look at that next.