- [Instructor] When
creating a web application,
you can think of it as having a division
between two responsibilities.
You can either host static
content or dynamic content.
Static content can be things
like HTML files for web sites
or images, videos, etc.
Dynamic content, on the
other hand, is served through
a web API, or sometimes it's
used to serve dynamic webpages
where the content or the view is composed
on the server itself.
In our case, we'll look at
serving a simple HTML file
for static files, and then
we will create a web API
to show how we can serve dynamic content.
So let's begin by serving some
static files with Express.js.
The first thing we'll need to do
is create our project folder.
So please go ahead and do that,
since we will be working in this folder
over multiple videos,
and we won't be recreating a
new project for every video.
Then make sure you open up
that folder inside your editor.
Next, let's create our server file.
So I'll create a new file
and call it server.js.
One thing to keep in mind
is that Express does not come with Node,
and so we'll need to install it using npm
just like we did for all the
other third-party packages.
But if we want to save
all of our dependencies
that we install, we'll need to create
our package.json file first.
So just like we did before,
we'll use npm init to do that.
So I'll use npm init --yes.
And now we have our package.json file.
Next, let's install Express.
We'll use the command
npm install -s to save it
to our package.json file,
and then we'll type in express.
Let's check our package.json file
and you can see that under
the dependencies list,
we have express, and in
our node_modules folder,
if we scroll down, you can
see all of the dependencies
that Express came from as well
as the Express folder itself.
So now let's begin by
requiring it into a variable
we'll call express inside
our server.js file,
and then we'll set reference
to a variable called app
from an instance of express.
And then let's get the
Express server started
and listening for requests,
by typing in app.listen,
and it will take in a port
in the first parameter,
so I'll type in 3000.
So let's save that.
Then we'll use a nodemon
and run server.js.
Now if we start our browser,
and then go over to localhost 3000
and we open up the developer console,
and then go to Network tab,
and once again refresh,
we can see we're getting a response
but with a status of 404 not found
because nothing is being
hosted or served yet.
So now let's serve some
static content with Express.
We'll begin by using the function app.use,
and then we'll create an
HTML file called index.html
that will get served through app.use.
So above our app.listen,
I'll set up app.use
to get it prepped for our HTML file.
Since I'm using nodemon,
and I've saved this file,
we're getting an error,
since we're not actually
defining anything to use yet.
So let's create a new
filed called index.html.
And inside here, I'll type in hello.
I'll save that, and close out the HTML.
Now when ordered to tell Express
that we'll be serving a static file,
inside our app.use on line
4, we'll use express.static,
and we'll pass in our entire
directory with __dirname.
Let's save that, and then
try it again in our browser.
So I'll refresh, and you
can see that index page
or HTML file is automatically served now
and we're getting our
hello placeholder text.
One other change I'd like
to make is to set a callback
on our app.listen,
and then we'll pass in a callback
that takes in no parameters,
and we can type in console.log,
server is listening on port,
and then we could hard-code the port,
or we could get reference
to that actual port
in case it changes once we
deploy our app on a server,
and we can do that by creating
a variable called server
and setting it to our app.listen.
And then in our callback,
as a second parameter to our console log,
what we'll call server.address.port,
let's save that and give it a try.
And as we can see, we're
getting our message
in our console, server is
listening on port 3000.
Now that our back-end server is running
and hosting a static file,
let's take a quick look at setting up
a front end demo app that
will work with our back end.