- [Instructor] Since
this is a Node course,
we won't be spending too
much time on our front end,
but for now we'll dedicate
this lesson to setting
up our front end and
the rest of the videos
and chapters will be
focused on Node once again.
Let's continue in our index.html.
We will begin by specifying
our doc type as HTML,
so let's replace line one with an element
that starts off with an exclamation mark,
then doctype, and then we specify HTML.
Now in order to make our layout look good,
let's use a library called Bootstrap.
Head over to getbootstrap.com,
then select Get Started.
Here we can copy the style
sheet link from the CDN
the website provides and
paste it into our HTML.
So, let's scroll down and let's
copy the style sheet link.
And then back in our
editor, let's paste that in.
If we save this, then we go to our webpage
and we go to our network tab and refresh,
we can see that Bootstrap is being loaded.
Then back on the Bootstrap page,
we'll need to copy one other thing.
We'll copy over all of
the JavaScript links
from their CDN examples,
which will include jQuery
and two other JavaScript files
that Bootstrap can utilize.
So I'll copy that, and
once again paste it below.
Let's save those and give it a try.
Back in our webpage, we can see that
it's loaded the JavaScript files.
For our demo application, the
most important will be jQuery.
We'll be using jQuery in order to inject
our data into the HTML,
and bind to certain events
since we are not using a
framework like Angular or React.
Let's go back in our
editor, and we'll begin
by placing a Bootstrap container element.
A container element creates
a fixed width container
that centers our content inside.
So we'll start with a div,
and then we'll use a Bootstrap
class called container.
Then inside, we'll place
a Bootstrap jumbotron.
This will contain our
message-sending elements,
and the jumbotron is a Bootstrap
component that allows us
to focus or showcase specific
elements on our site.
So we'll place another div,
and add the jumbotron class.
Then inside, let's add a header with h1,
and we'll use class="display-4"
to set the style of the header.
And then the text will be Send Message.
Let's save that and take a look.
So we'll refresh, and we can see
our reactive container and jumbotron.
I'll also add some space
by adding a break above the jumbotron.
So I've created a new line
and added a br element.
Let's refresh, and now we
can see there's some space
in between the jumbotron
and the top of the browser.
Next, let's create an
input inside the jumbotron
after our title, Send Message,
and I'll use another br to separate them.
And I'll use the class
form-control from Bootstrap,
and I'll use a placeholder
and set it to Name.
Let's take a look at that.
Then finally, let's add a button.
So I'll use another break,
and then add a button.
The text will be Send, and
we'll use a Bootstrap class,
or several classes, the
first being btn for button,
and then btn so that we get
the success styling on the button.
Let's take a look at that.
The next thing we'll do is add a div
where the message history will be shown.
Let's add that below the jumbotron.
So I've added a new div on line 16
below our jumbotron on line nine.
We'll give the div an ID
property and set it to messages.
That way we can access
it by ID with jQuery.
So in the div tag on line 16,
I'll add an ID property
and set it to messages.
Now that we have our HTML set up,
let's add in some JavaScript.
We will put in some script
tags below our main div
and put in a callback function
for jQuery document ready.
So below our last div on line 19,
we'll add a script element.
We will use the shorthand version
of the document ready event function,
which is just a dollar sign
and then paranesthesia.
Inside here, we can add
our callback function
with an arrow function.
The document ready event will be called
when the document finishes loading.
That way we know all of our
elements are ready to be used.
And for now, we'll do a
quick console log test
to make sure everything's working so far.
Let's go back to our
webpage, select Console
from our developer
console, and then refresh.
And you can see we're
getting our loaded text.
The next thing we'll
do is create a function
that will allow us to add
messages to our message history.
So below our document ready function
that's located on line 21,
we'll create an add messages function.
And it will take in the message object.
Then let's access the
message div through its ID
and append some HTML to it.
So we'll use the jQuery shortcut,
and then pass in the ID with #messages,
and this will match the ID on line 16.
Then we'll use .append, and
then we'll add in some HTML.
We'll start with a header
four for the title,
which in this case will
be the message name.
And I'll use JavaScript template literals,
so instead of a single
quote, I'll use a backtick
to surround the header four,
and I'll use the dollar sign
and the curly braces
surrounding message.name.
Then another space, and
we'll close the header four.
Then we'll add a paragraph tag,
and we'll place message.message inside,
and let's close the paragraph tag.
If you're not familiar with
JavaScript template literals,
this allows us to inject variables,
for example, into strings.
We could use other formatting methods
but I find that this is one
of the cleanest methods.
To test this out, let's
call our new function
inside document ready.
So on line 22, instead of our console log,
we'll call addmessages, and
then let's pass in an object
that has a property name,
and then we'll set that to
a placeholder called Tim,
and then a property called message,
and we'll set that to Hello.
Let's save that and reload our page.
And we know our function's working
since we see the example object.
The next thing we need to do
is make our Send button do something.
So let's give the button
an ID and then create
a click callback for the
button's click event.
So on line 14, let's add
an ID to the button tag,
and I'll call it Send for now.
Then inside our document ready,
above our add messages test,
let's use jQuery to access the send button
with #send, and then we'll use .click
to bind to the click event
by passing in a callback.
Inside the callback,
let's just copy line 25,
and then paste it inside.
Let's save that and give it a try.
So I'll refresh, then I'll hit send.
Each time I hit it, it will
add a new message object.
And that's it for now
with our front-end app.
Next, let's focus on getting
some actual message data
to and from our back-end.