- [Instructor] Let's begin by creating
a getMessages service endpoint, and note,
this will allow us to get actual messages
from our backend to our front-end website.
Inside our server.js, let's
add a route for our endpoint.
We will be using app.get to specify that
we will be handling GET requests.
So between line four and
five, let's add a few lines,
so that we can make room for app.get.
Then for the first parameter,
we need to specify the route.
We'll use /messages, since we'll be
supplying a list of messages.
And then we'll need our
callback to handle the request.
That will take in request,
and then give us reference
to response, so that we can respond to it.
For now, let's respond with a
test string that says hello.
So we'll use response
dot send
and then a string that says hello.
We can try this out in
our browser by navigating
to the endpoint with a /messages.
And then we can see the string hello.
Next, let's create a
placeholder messages list
as an array at the top.
We will call it messages,
and then we'll create
two message objects,
with a name and message.
Then I'll copy this, add a comma,
and add the second message object.
Then change the name and the message.
Now we can update our
messages and point to send
that messages array instead
of the hello string.
Let's save that and refresh our browser.
And you can see that we're
getting the messages array.
Next, let's go back to our index html
and update our front
end, so that we actually
get those messages from the backend,
using an http ajax request.
Let's go down to our script element,
and add a new function below our last.
We'll call it
getMessages.
Inside here, let's make a
jQuery http GET request.
We'll use $.get.
And then we'll need the
URL from our browser.
So let's copy that.
And paste that in.
And of course, we'll need a callback
that provides us with our data.
So we'll supply that
as a second parameter.
Now, let's console log the data
to make sure that this step works.
And before we try this, let's call our
getMessages function and
our document ready function.
So we'll add that below our click binding.
Let's save that and give it a try.
Let's go back to our web
app, and then hit refresh.
If we give this a try, we can
see that it will not work.
It does not recognize
the jQuery GET function
as we can see in our console error.
That's because by default,
the jQuery CDN link
we copied earlier, is
using a slim version.
So let's remove that from the
URL in our script element.
So let's scroll to the top, and
in the first script element,
on line three, we can see
it contains a slim version.
So I'll take out the word slim.
Since we're now using a
different version of jQuery,
the integrity property
will no longer work,
so we can take that out.
Then let's save that and give it a try.
When we reload our app, we can see that
we have our messages list in our console.
Next, let's display these messages
in the message area we created earlier.
So let's scroll down and
get rid of the console log
on line 34 in our getMessages call.
And instead, we will
iterate through each message
in our data, and call addMessage.
We can do that with data.foreach.
And that auto-generates
a forEach function for us
with a callback, so we're
using just data.forEach.
Then inside, we'll call addMessages,
and supply the message
object as the argument.
Let's save that, and give it a try.
So now as I refresh, our list populates
our message history area.
We can do a quick optimization.
Since the signature of
our addMessages function
matches the signature of the
callback we're supplying,
we don't need a callback at all.
We can simply call forEach and then supply
the name of our function, addMessages.
And now our addMessages
function will be called directly
instead of going through
an in-line callback.
Let's save that and make
sure it still works.
So I've refreshed the page,
and both messages are still there.
Now that we're able to get messages,
next let's see how we
can post new messages.