- [Instructor] Let's begin by creating
a new message post and point in Node.
So let's open up our server.js.
Then, let's copy our app.get
on line 11 through line 13.
And we'll paste it below.
Next, let's change the get to a post.
Then, since we're not
responding with a message list,
instead of using res.send on line 16,
we use res.sendStatus
and we'll pass in 200 for 200 OK.
This will let the client know
that everything went well.
Finally as the test,
above our res.sendStatus
we'll use a console.log
to display the req.body
to see what data we get in our body.
In order to try this, we can't easily send
a post request with the browser,
so we'll use an app called Postman.
You can get Postman from
the Chrome app store
or as a standalone app for Windows or Mac.
Once Postman starts, let's update the URL
with our post endpoint of
localhost:3000/messages.
Then in the dropdown on the left,
instead of using the GET action,
we'll specify a POST action.
Then finally, we can go to
the body tab and select raw
and then in the dropdown, instead of Text,
we'll select JSON.
In here we can create our message object.
It will have our name property
and we'll also need the message property.
Notice that the properties end values
must both have double quotes
for it to be valid raw JSON
that we can send with Postman.
Now, let's hit Send
and we got back 200 OK.
So let's go to our terminal.
I'll go to View, then Integrated Terminal.
And the last message
we see in our terminal
should be the console.log from line 16.
But it's currently undefined.
That's because express
has no built-in support
to parse the body.
So let's install the
package that will do that
called body-parser.
So I'll open up a new terminal
and we'll use npm install -s body-parser.
Then let's require it in at the top.
So above our var app on line two,
I'll use var bodyParser =
require('body-parser')
then we will set it up as
middleware with app.use.
So below our existing app.use
we'll add another
and we'll pass in bodyParser.json.
This let's body parser know
that we expect JSON to be coming in
with our HTTP request.
So let's open up our terminal once again
and I'll close the new terminal
so we can see our nodemon.
Then let's go back to Postman
and before we hit Send,
I'll fix a quick typo
in the message property,
instead of comma we use a colon
to specify the value from
postman for our message property.
Now let's go ahead and hit Send again.
And if we get back a 200 OK,
let's check our terminal.
We can now see the message object
with the name and message property.
Now that we're getting our message,
let's add the new message we got
to our messages array.
We will be doing that
by using messages.push
and pass in the request body
which contains the message object.
So on line 18, instead of the console.log
we'll use messages.push with the req.body.
Let's save that and then let's give it
another try from Postman.
Yep, we get a 200 OK.
Let's go to our web app and refresh.
And you can see that we're
getting our Postman message.
The final thing that we need to do
is send the post request not from Postman
but from our browser app.
Let's go back to our HTML file.
Let's scroll down to our
getMessages function.
We'll copy it from line 32 to line 36
and post it below.
Then let's rename it to postMessage
and change it from a .get to .post.
Then we'll pass along the message object
as a second argument.
And we'll get that message
object as a parameter
so we'll add that to the
postMessages function
and then supply it as the second
parameter to our post call.
Then let's modify our click
event on our send button
so that it calls postMessages
instead of just adding
a placeholder message.
So I'll take out what we have on line 23
then I'll create the
variable called message
and set it to an empty object for now,
then let's call postMessages.
And actually, I'll rename this function
on line 39, to postMessage.
And then I'll pass in our message object,
it's currently empty so
we'll need to populate it.
That means we'll need access to the name
and message inputs in our HTML.
In order to have access to those inputs
we need to create IDs like we did before.
We'll begin with our inputs on line 12
and we'll set the ID of name.
Then we'll need another input for message.
So let's copy line 12 and
11 and paste it below.
We'll change the placeholder to Message
and we'll want it to
be a multi-line input,
so instead of using input
tags, we'll use textarea.
And then we'll add the
closing tag at the end.
Then let's change the ID to message.
Now we have IDs for both
our name and our message
that we can then set
in our message object.
So let's begin populating that object.
We'll start with the name property
and set it to the value of our input
which we'll access with Jquery with .val.
Then we'll do the same
for the message property.
Then finally, let's finish modifying
our postMessage function on line 41.
We won't need a callback,
so let's take that out.
Then let's save that.
Then let's give it a try in our webpage.
Put in a name and a message,
then let's hit Send and let's refresh.
We can see that both the name
and message are undefined,
not exactly what we expected.
Let's try to debug why this is happening.
Let's go back to our backend
and in our postMessages endpoint
let's add a console.log
again with req.body.
Let's save this and try posting again.
We can see that I've posted twice
and I have two empty objects twice.
That's because what
comes in from our browser
is URL encoded and so we
must set up body parser
to support that.
So let's go up to where
we set up body parser
and then we'll add
another line with app.use.
We'll use body-parser again .urlencoded
and then we'll specify
extended to be false.
Let's save that.
Then let's get rid of the
console.log on line 19
and give it a try after saving.
We'll go back to our app, we'll hit send,
then let's refresh.
Then we can see we're
getting the expected values.
So our message app works
both frontend and backend.
If we hosted this now, we would be able to
have a chat with a friend
and simulate a chat between two clients.
So I'll cop the URL, open up a new tab,
and then let's post a message
from our second client.
And then let's do the same from the first.
And then refresh on the second.
We can see it's working
but we've noticed somewhat of an issue
that we have no idea when
a new message comes in.
So we have to keep hitting refresh.
We could make this automatic
with a frontend JavaScript function,
which will keep doing
an HTTP get on a timer.
But there is a better way.
Let's take a look at socket.io next.