- [Instructor] We are
able to send requests
from the client or browser to Node,
but there is no way to do it in reverse.
There's no way for Node to
tell one or more clients,
hey, there's a new message,
so the only way to achieve this behavior
with HTTP requests is to do
something called polling.
With polling, every few seconds we send
an HTTP request asking the server,
hey, are there any updates?
Are there new messages I should display?
And we check over and over.
It would be much better
if the server could just tell the client
when a new message comes in
without the clients having
to constantly check.
You can think of it as a bunch
of kids in a van asking
the parents every minute,
hey, are we there yet?
The parents might plead with the kids
to stop asking at one point,
and that they will tell the kids
when they arrive instead of them asking.
This is how WebSockets work
and we will be using a WebSocket
library called Socket.IO
that works for both the
browser and for Node.
With Socket.IO, we will
be able to notify clients
or the app running in the browser
when another user has sent a chat message,
that way the app will update
their message list instantly.
You might have heard
of push notifications,
where a server pushes an update
or a message to a client
or multiple clients,
this works the same way.
The nice thing about
the Socket.IO library is
that if a browser is older
and does not support WebSockets,
it will default back to polling
and it has that functionality built in
so it will always work,
even if it's not as efficient
with older browsers.
So, let's begin by installing
Socket.IO with npm.
So, I've opened up a new Terminal,
and I'll use npm install -s
socket.io.
Setting up Socket.IO is
a bit tricker than most
of the other packages,
that's because it needs
to tie in with Express,
and the game plan is that we'll
create a regular HTTP server
with Node that will then share
with Express and Socket.IO.
So, let's open up our server.js,
and first let's set up that HTTP server.
So, below line three,
let's add var http require
then we'll use the HTTP library from Node
and we'll call .Server
on the require itself
and pass in our Express app,
then let's create io and set it to require
socket.io
and we'll pass in reference to http.
Now that Socket.IO is
set up on the backend,
let's set it up for the front end,
so let's open up our index.html
and at the bottom of the  tags,
after line five, we'll
add a new  tag,
and set src to
/socket.io/socket.io.js,
and now let's check out
webpage for any errors.
So, I'll refresh and we can see
that we are getting an error
and we're unable to find
the Socket.IO JavaScript
file we included.
The problem is that we can't
directly serve our backend
with just Express any longer.
We will use the Node HTTP server
so that way both Express and
Socket.IO will be running.
So, inside our server.js,
we can do that by replacing
our existing listen code
on line 25 with http.listen instead.
Let's save that and give it
another try in our browser,
so I'll refresh, we're no
longer getting an error,
and if we look at the Network tab,
we can see we're getting the
Socket.IO JavaScript file.
Next let's go down to the
script element in our HTTP file
and initialize Socket.IO.
So, at the top of our  tag,
we'll create a variable called socket
and we'll set it to io.
This initialization will
also try to make a connection
to the Socket.IO server at the same URL
that the current page is being hosted on.
Let's set up a callback for
the socket connection event
that will let us know
whenever a new user connects,
so let's save this and then
go into our server.js file,
and below our post
messages, we'll add io.on
and we'll check for the connection event,
and we'll supply a function
that takes in a socket.
And for now, let's console.log
a user connected,
let's save that.
Let's open up our Terminal
and go to our nodemon,
then let's refresh our page.
And now, back in nodemon,
we can see that a Socket.IO connection
has successfully been
made from the browser
since we're getting a message
in the connection event
and we can see a user
connected in our Console.
Next let's look at how to
create the message event
to update all of the clients at once.