- [Instructor] Let's submit an event
from the server to all clients
notifying them of a new message.
We can do this in our post
message endpoint function.
Let's scroll to that on line 20.
And below line 21, let's add io.emit,
and we'll call our event message.
And we'll pass the request.body,
which will contain the message.
Let's save that.
Then on our front end, then
let's open up our index.html.
And on our front end, we need
to add an event listener.
So let's scroll down
to our script section.
Then below our document
ready, we'll add socket.on,
and we'll check for the message event,
and we'll simply call add message.
And I'll rename this to add message
since we're only adding a single message.
And notice that I've
supplied just the name of
our add message function.
Since its signature matches
that exactly of the callback
that we'd need to supply
with our socket.on call.
Let's give it a try after saving.
So I'll refresh, and
let's post a new message.
It seems to work fine with one client.
Now let's try two.
So I'll duplicate this tab.
And I'll post a message
from the second client,
and let's check the first.
And you can see that
it instantly shows up.
It's fairly straightforward
with socket.io.
Notice though, every time
we restart our server,
we lose all of our message history.
Let's fix that.
We could do that with file
write and read functionality
that we learned in an earlier chapter,
but a much better solution
would be to store our messages
in a database.
Let's look at that next.