- [Instructor] There are many different
database technologies, such as
MongoDB, MySQL, Veras, and many more.
Node has packages to work
with most of these options.
And most of these options
fall into two categories:
Either SQL or NoSQL.
Let's take a quick look at SQL.
SQL stands for structured query language.
The key word here is structured,
meaning the data stored
inside is structured.
The database knows and
cares about the structure,
and the tables that store the data
must be designed with that in mind.
The object classes,
which represent the items
that will go into those structured tables,
must also be designed.
There is a lot of up-front
design work in doing so,
but also some performance and
query benefits in some cases.
But, in other cases,
there are also performance hits
from the overhead of this design.
NoSQL, on the other hand,
is the absence of that structure.
We just put data into collections
without paying much
attention to the structure.
As a result, there's less
up-front design work,
and possible performance
increases in some cases.
There's no good solution for all cases,
and each project has requirements
that might match SQL or
NoSQL better or worse.
A good analogy from stack overflow
is thinking of SQL like an automatic car,
where a lot of the manual
work is done for you,
and some performance
improvements, in other cases.
And NoSQL is like a
manual, or standard car.
Something to keep in mind
is that there are some databases
that share the features of SQL and NoSQL.
But for an introductory project
where you are learning
to work with a database,
a NoSQL database might be a
bit easier to get started with.
A good choice to start with is MongoDB,
as it is often used in the mean stack.
If you'd like to learn
more about the mean stack,
please check out my mean stack
and the MongoDB development
techniques course.
Now that we have a brief
overview of database solutions,
let's get started with MongoDB.