- [Instructor] Let's begin by setting up
the MongoDB environment.
We could download and run MongoDB locally,
but then when it comes
time to publishing the app,
we will need to host it separately
or find a third-party host for it.
Might as well do that now to save a step.
We will use a service that
offers free hosting called mLab.
Please head over to mlab.com,
then please create an account or log in.
Once you've logged in, if you
have any previous databases,
you can see them listed here.
Otherwise, let's select Create new.
I'll leave Amazon selected
and then select Sandbox.
But you can use any other
option that you like,
as most of them offer free services.
Then I'll select Continue.
In my case, I'll use US East
and I'll hit Continue again.
And I'll call my database learning-node,
but you can call yours whatever you like.
Let's confirm, make sure that it's free,
and then we can submit the order.
Within a few seconds,
the database is created.
Let's click on it.
The first thing we'll need
to do is create a new user
since that's what we'll use
to access the database from our app.
So let's select User.
Then let's click the Add
database user button.
Since this is just for learning
purposes and not production,
for the username and
password, I'll just use user.
And then I'll hit Create.
We can see our user is now listed.
At this point, we're ready
to get Node connected
to our new MongoDB.
To do that, we will need to
use a package called Mongoose.
Let's look at that next.