- [Instructor] Mongoose
allows us to elegantly work
with our MongoDB database
with object schemas.
Object schemas are
JavaScript objects we create
that will represent the type of data
we will be putting in our database.
Even though MongoDB is NoSQL,
and does not have structure,
with Mongoose, there is a bit of structure
we must design initially.
This gives us some benefits
of easily interacting
with our data through
objects, and other things,
such as validation.
Let's begin by installing
Mongoose with npm.
Then, inside our server.js,
let's require it in.
Next, let's connect to our mLab database.
We will first need the connection string,
so let's go back to our
mLab database website,
and copy that from the top.
So let's copy this URI.
Then, above our messages array,
let's create a dbURL variable,
and set it to what we copied.
Then, let's put in our user credentials.
Since I set my username
and password to both user,
I'll use that.
An important note is that,
in a production environment,
you would want to keep this
URL, especially the credentials,
hidden in a configuration
file that has a safe location.
Then, let's scroll down to
the bottom of our server.js,
and above our http.listen,
let's connect to Mongoose.
We'll use mongoose.connect.
We'll supply the dbURL
as the first parameter,
and then let's supply a callback
that will take an error, for the second.
Then, let's create a
console.log, and pass in
mongo db connection,
and supply the error
as a second parameter, in
case there is an error.
Then, let's save that, and let's look
at our integrated terminal.
And we can see MongoDB
connection is shown,
therefore we are connected,
and we're getting
an undefined for error.
If you're getting a deprecation warning,
you might need to specify a
setting in the second parameter
of our mongoose.connect instead.
So let's add an object
and make our callback
the third parameter,
and then we'll specify
useMongoClient, and set that to true.
Let's save this, and you
can see we're connecting,
and there are no longer
is a deprecation warning.
Now that we're connecting to
our mLab MongoDB database,
let's see how we can start
saving data with Mongoose.