- [Instructor] In order to
start saving data with Mongoose,
we need to setup that bit of
structure I mentioned earlier,
which is a model and a
schema for a message object.
At the top of our script,
let's create the message model.
So above our messages array on line 14,
let's add a few lines, we'll
create a message variable,
and we use a capital M to
indicate that it's a model
and we'll set it to mongoose.model
and for the first parameter,
we'll specify what we call it,
which is message and then we'll pass in
our schema definition,
which will be an object
with the properties, first being name,
which will be of type string.
Then our message property,
which will be of type string as well.
Let's save that.
Now that we have a model,
let's create an object
based on that model.
Let's go down to our post message function
and create that.
So on line 28, at the
top, let's add var message
equals new message and
we'll pass in request.body
since it contains our message definition.
Next let's save it to MongoDB.
We will use message.save and
we can pass in a call back
that takes an error in case it failed.
If there's an error, let's
send the status of 500,
which is a server error.
If there is no error, let's move the rest
of the functionality into
the save success block.
And so now, only if the
message was successfully
saved to the database, we will
then emit a socket IO event
and then we'll send a status of 200
and I'll leave our message.push for now
until we've completely replaced it
with our MongoDB.
Now let's send a message from our app
and then check mLab for
a new message collection.
So I've saved the changes,
let's go to our app
and then add a new message.
Now let's check mLab and
refresh our collections.
And we can see a new collection.
Let's click on that.
Inside we can see a new
record with the name Lisa
and the message Hi.
So we know it's working.
Finally, let's update our app
so that it no longer
uses the message array.
So let's take up line 35 in our app.post
and then on line 25, instead of sending
our messages array, we'll send
our messages from MongoDB.
So above our response.send,
we'll add message.find
and we want to select all of the messages
so we won't pass in any requirements
and so I'm passing in an empty object.
Then we'll create a call
back that takes an error
and all of the messages it finds.
Inside, let's copy our
response.send messages
and paste it.
Now let's get rid of our messages array.
If we save this and then
give it a try in our app,
we refresh and we can see,
the first message we added
to our MongoDB database.
Let's add another.
We can see it instantly shows up
because of socket IO and if we refresh,
it shows up again because of MongoDB.
Next let's take a look at some of
the newer features of JavaScript,
which Node now uses.