- [Instructor] In
asynchronous programming,
there is something many programmers
refer to as callback hell.
It can happen to nearly everyone
and it creates very difficult code.
Let's take a look at what it is exactly
and how we can avoid it.
Let's create a very basic bad word filter
for our post message function.
There are better ways to make this,
but we will purposefully
make the callbacks nested
so that you can understand
the teaching point.
So let's go down to our message
post function on line 25.
If a message was successfully
saved and there was no error,
let's check for bad words
inside the database.
So we'll use message.findOne
and we'll check for a message
that has the word badword in it,
and then let's pass a
callback with an error
and the censored word that it finds.
If there is a censored word,
let's console.log censored words found,
and we'll display censored.
And if we did find a censored
word, let's remove it.
We'll use message.remove
and then pass in the ID.
So we'll check for _id
and we'll use censored.id.
If you're not sure where
the id property came from,
since we don't have it as
part of our model on line 14,
it's actually Mongoose
that manages and creates
the ID for us anytime we save
an object to a collection.
So next, let's add a callback to
the second parameter
that takes in an error,
and then let's add a console.log
saying we've removed censored message.
And I'll save that.
I'll just fix the typo
first on badword on line 32.
Then let's open up our terminal
and let's go to our app
and type in badword in message.
Let's hit submit, then let's
take a look at our terminal
and we can see that a
censored word was found
with message badword and it
removed the censored message.
So if we go back to our app and refresh,
we can see it's no longer there.
So as mentioned before, that's not
the greatest implementation
of a bad word filter
since it posts it first
before it removes it,
but I did that on purpose
just to demonstrate
how complex nested callbacks can get.
And if you imagine this two or three
times deeper than it currently is,
trying to understand this
now can be confusing.
But imagine opening this
file up a year later
and then trying to
understand it at that point,
or for another programmer that hasn't
worked with your code trying to understand
your code and the amount of overhead
it creates in the development process.
Our goal then becomes quite
clear: we want clean code.
Something we can quickly
understand right now
or a year from now, and
there's several tools
to allow us to do this that avoid
nested callbacks, or callback hell.
So let's take a look at
those solutions next.