- [Instructor] Promises
give us another option of
how to work with asynchronous code.
Promises return an object
which promise to do some work.
This object has separate callbacks
for success and for failures.
This lets us work with asynchronous code
in a much more synchronous way.
A really nice feature is that
Promises can be combined
into dependency chains.
To demonstrate these features,
let's convert censor
example to use Promises
so that we can see how it
cleans up our code a bit.
Let's scroll down to our
message post function,
and on line 28, instead
of passing a callback
of the first parameter,
we'll pass nothing, and
then we'll add .then,
and this will execute
if there are no errors.
And then we can place our callback
inside the then function.
And so now, this function, as a callback,
is placed inside then.
Since we got rid of the error parameter,
we'll need to check for
errors using another method.
We can chain on a catch
function at the end.
And then we'll pass on a
callback to handle our errors
so that it will take in an error,
and then we can send the response of
sendStatus with 500.
In this case, we can get
rid of our error check
on line 29 and 30.
Then let's return console.error
with the error message.
Let's save this and give it a try.
So I posted the new message.
Let's go look at our Integrated Terminal.
Upon saving our message,
we notice we're getting
another deprecation warning.
It's suggesting that we plug
in our own Promise library
instead of the deprecated
version for Mongoose.
So we can use the built-in
ES6 Promise library.
Let's go up to the top of our file,
above our dburl,
and add mongoose.promise
equals Promise,
and we're letting Mongoose know that
the Promise library wants to use
is the default ES6 Promise library.
Let's save that and give it another try.
And now we're no longer getting
the deprecation warning.
Now that we've taken care of that warning,
let's move back to Promises
so we can see that saved message
still functions the same way.
But there isn't much improvement
in the look of our code.
We still have those nested callbacks.
To solve this, let's look
into dependency chains.
This is where Promises really shines
with respect to clean code.
I'll start by taking the body of
our message save then
function callback out,
and I'll simply add a console.log in here,
letting us know saved.
Then before I chain on the catch function,
I'll chain on another then,
and I'll add the catch to the bottom.
And then I'll start to stack
these chained functions.
Then, temporarily, I'll paste
the body below the function,
since I'll copying and pasting.
So I'll copy the
Message.findOne call we have
and paste it below our console log,
and then I'll return that.
Since we are returning the Promise,
instead of handling it with a callback
in the second parameter,
the next then that is chained on will take
the results of that first
Promise in a callback.
So, in this case, I can
get access to censored,
and, essentially, all the code
that I had in the callback,
I can move inside this new then callback.
And then I can get rid
of this temporary code.
Then, if there are no
censored words found,
I can move the rest of this code below it,
and we'll send the status 200
and emit the message.
Let's go ahead and give this a try as is
before we carry on.
So let's go back to our app
and send the new message.
We can see it's showing
up, and if we refresh,
it's still showing up, so our
functionality is maintained
as we continue to refactor.
Message.remove is the last Promise.
So we can go ahead and
chain that and its response.
So I'll take out a callback,
and then I'll return this as a Promise,
and I won't bother confirming
if the censored words were removed
in our console log, but
if there are any errors,
the catch at the bottom will catch them,
and it will send a sendStatus of 500.
And I'll move the first then down so that
we can maintain some vertical consistency,
and it's a bit easier to read.
Now, before we give this a try,
I would like to show you that
this is no longer refactor
since the behavior changed slightly
because, in our second then,
if it did find a censored word,
it will return a Message.remove
and will never actually emit the message.
So let's save that and
demonstrate how it works.
So, if I type in bad in the
message and then hit Send,
we go down, and we can see that
it's posted the new message bad.
But if I type in badword,
we can see that it doesn't even show up
the way it did before it was
removed from the database.
And if we refresh, we can see
it's not even in the database.
So that's a slight
improvement on functionality
as well as in the look of our code
because, here, we can clearly
see the steps our code takes.
It tries to do this save.
If it fails, it goes into the catch.
Then, it tries to find
a message with badword.
Then, if it finds it,
it tries to remove it,
and if it doesn't find it,
only then will it emit the message.
So Promises do offer an improvement
in creating clean code.
So, although this code still
might be difficult to read,
it should be a bit easier at a glance.
Since the code is now flowing
mostly downward and not inwards,
as they did with nested callbacks.
Next, let's look at improving our code
even more with Async 08.