- [Instructor] Asyncawait is
one of the latest features
to make it into Node.
Similar to promises,
it makes a synchronous code
look even more synchronous.
In order to work with await,
we will need to declare our
express function as async.
So on line 27,
in the second parameter where
we specify our callback,
let's add async.
At this point,
we can use await on message.save,
which will return a value once it finishes
and will save it into a
variable called savedMessage.
So on line 30,
I'll create savedMessage
and set it to await message.save.
Now I can get rid of this then call
and I can simply call our console log
to show that it'll save.
Next we'll do the same
for our censored words.
So I'll create a censored variable
and set it to message.findOne,
as we check for our bad word.
And, again, I can get rid of
this then in the callback.
Then we just check if
there was a censored word.
We'll display it in our console log
and we'll remove it.
And, again, we'll use await
and we'll replace return with await.
I'll also get rid of this console log
and simply remove the message
if a censored word was found.
If a censored word wasn't found,
then I'll omit the message
and regardless I'll send a status of 200.
And I won't cover how to
handle exceptions for now,
so let's just comment out the code
between line 43 and line 46 on my screen.
So I'll save that.
And then finally,
I'm going to add await
in front of message.fineOne on line 34.
Let's save that and give it a try.
So back in our app.
I've deleted all of the
messages in our collection
to clean it up.
And let's try new message.
And it seems to be working.
Now let's try one with our censored word.
And you can see its not showing up.
And if we refresh,
its not in the database either.
And so our functionality is maintained.
But if we look back at our code,
its significantly improved
and it's a lot easier to read.
Now since we commented
out the catch function,
yet we still new to handle exceptions,
let's look at how to
handle exceptions, errors,
and to debug in the next chapter.