- [Instructor] We got a
taste of handling errors
with callbacks and promises
in the previous chapter
with the error parameter
and the catch function.
We will now look at a more
generic form of handling errors
and exceptions with a try-catch block.
This works with async/await
as well which is nice since it
makes the code look a lot more
synchronous and easy to read.
So to do that, let's go to the top of our
app.post function above
line 28 and type in try
and then add in a trycatch
statement template.
If your editor does not have this,
you can just type it in manually.
Then let's copy all the
code that is not commented
between line 35 and line 48 on my screen
and let's paste it inside the try block.
Then let's copy the code that
we had in our original catch
and move it into the new catch
block and then uncomment it.
And then I'll get rid
of the commented code.
We can test out the catch functionality
by creating a throw at
the top of our block.
So let's go to the top of our try block
and add throw 'some error'.
Let's save that, and
then let's go to our app
and try to post a new message.
And as you can see, we're getting a
500 Internal Server Error,
which is the status we expected.
Then let's check our console for an error
but before we do, let's
match the error parameters
so that I fully spell out error.
Then let's save that and try again.
And I'll hit Send again, then
let's look at the terminal.
And you can see, we are getting
some error at the bottom.
Now that we know it's working,
let's remove the throw from line 30.
Next, let's look at finally.
This is another feature
the try-catch block
that will execute
regardless of whether your
try-catch block failed or succeeded.