- [Instructor] We have
our try and catch blocks,
and the third optional
part is the finally block.
This gets executed regardless if
the try catch block fails or passes.
For now let's add the finally
block to our app.post.
There are some cases in which
you would want to use a finally block,
but in most cases you're probably just
going to end up using try and catch.
An example could be if you're
submitting something to a log.
So, in our case, if we had a logger
we could add an entry that the
message post end point was called,
or if you're using a resource
that you need to shut down,
for example, in the case of a database
you might open a
connection, post something,
and then you might have to
close it in the finally.
For now, just so we can explore the
concept of the finally block,
I'll change this into a console.log.
Then let's open up our Terminal.
And now let's try posting a new message.
Let's go look at our Terminal,
and we can see that we're getting our
message post called console.log.
Next, let's add a throw
at the top of our try
to trigger our catch,
and make our try catch block fail.
And now let's try posting again.
We get our internal
server error 500 response,
and back in our Terminal we can see that
the finally block is still executed,
and we're getting our message
post called console.log.