- [Instructor] In this
video, we'll take a look
at some of the debugging features
that come with Visual Studio Code.
I do realize that some
of you might not be using
the same editor, but if your
editor does come with some
of the basic debug feature,
they should still be very similar,
and the concepts still should apply.
Up until now, we've been using
nodemon to run our server.
Let's stop it, so I'll go into terminal,
and terminate that job by
pressing ctrl + c in Windows.
Instead we'll be using the
Visual Studio Code Debug Runner.
I'll click on the little
bug icon on the left,
or you could hit ctrl + shift + d.
Now we can see a start debugging button.
If we hit Play, it will start
our server GS in debug mode.
This gives us several tools.
Let's go over to our app
post messages function
on line 27, and then let's
add a break point on the tri.
Let's go back to our web
app and post a new message.
You can see that a break
point has been triggered.
We can now do things like
see our local variables,
hover over any of the variables.
We can see our cull stack and trace it.
Then, we can just continue.
Next, let's post yet another message.
If we wanted to follow
along as the code continues,
instead of pressing continue
which will just give us the end result
as we saw earlier which
is our error exception,
we can step over.
This will take us line
by line through our code,
and we can see where we end up.
In this case, the next
line that gets executed
is the cache since the
exception was thrown.
At this point, we'll send a status of 500.
Then, we'll console log an error.
Then, finally, we get
to our finally block.
Let's try that one more time,
so we'll post yet another message.
This time we'll look at the debug console.
We have access to the
current scope of our code,
so if I type in req for the request,
we can see the request is
actually displayed here
as if we had console logged it.
We can do other things as
well including execute code.
I could type in response.send and type hi.
Let's try it one more time.
I've restarted our debugger.
I will post a new message.
Once again the same
break point will trigger.
This time let's look into stepping into.
The throw will cause us
to step into the cache,
so that's no different than stepping over,
but now if we step into
response.send status,
we'll actually end up in the
code and function responsible
for sending the status.
Anytime we end up in a
function and we step into it,
we'll go to that function in our code
whether it's code we
created or code we're using.
For now, I'll go back to the top,
and I'll take off the break point.
Then, I'll take out
the throw from line 30.
In the past as we've been
developing our demo app,
there's been several
occasions where we've used
a console log to test functionality
before we continue implementing
the full functionality.
In those cases, it would
have been good to use
the debug tools since we could
have added a break point.
Instead of adding a
console log, we can see
that we hit that break
point are we getting there.
What values are we getting
by hovering over them?
It gives us a lot more information
than the console log could ever give us.
There's also some nice add-ons
from Visual Studio Code
that allow it to connect with the browser.
In that case, we could
actually debug the java script
on our front end, and
then it would communicate
with Visual Studio Code to
allow us to step through
or over or use the other debug tools.
Now that we have a good
idea of exception handling
and debugging, next, let's
take a look at testing.