- [Instructor] You might
have heard of testing,
unit tests and test-driven development.
They are all related,
and we will take a look
at how to work with these using Node
and a test framework called Jasmine.
There are a few other options like Mocha,
but Jasmine comes with everything you need
to get started without much setup.
Let's consider a simple requirement.
Let's say we have a
product manager or owner
that will give a programmer
a simple requirement,
such as, "When I go to this endpoint,"
"localhost port 3000/messages,"
"I expect to get a list of messages."
That, by definition, is a
requirement of the application.
But, this can also be a test.
We could make a test that
automatically opens up
a connection, then checks
if it receives a list
with more than zero messages.
This is exactly what the tester
and possibly product owner
and product manager would do
once the programmer delivers the feature.
It would go through that test manually.
Jasmine, on the other hand,
can automate that testing for us.
All we need to do is
describe a specification,
and in fact, the test I mentioned earlier
will be one of the more complex tasks
we will write in the next video.
But for now, let's start very simple,
a test that only checks a single thing,
also referred to as unit test.
Let's begin by installing Jasmine first.
Inside our terminal, we
will use npm install,
and then --save -dev,
since this will only be a dev dependency
and we won't need it in production.
And then jasmine.
Then, just like we used npm init
to create the package.json file,
we'll need to use jasmine init
in order to create our testing folder
and a couple configuration files.
We could use the jasmine CLI
and install that with a global flag,
but another way to do it
is just access jasmine init
through Node modules.
So, we'll type in
./node_modules/.bin/jasmine init.
And we can see it created a spec folder
with a jasmine.json configuration file.
The next thing we need to do
is go into our package.json
and under scripts on line 6,
and then under test, we'll
change that to jasmine.
Now, to test this out,
we can type in npm test.
We can see that it ran
Jasmine, and it was started,
but there were no specs
found, in other words,
there were no test specifications found,
so let's create our first.
We'll go inside the spec
folder and create a file called
server.spec.js.
The first thing we'll create in this file
is a suite, or grouping, of tests.
We'll do that with describe.
And that's a function call
which takes the description
as the first parameter,
and I'll start with
a very simple calculator example,
so I'll just call it calc.
And then it takes a callback
for the second parameter,
so I'll create an arrow function.
Then, we can describe our
first specification, or test,
and it tries to be quite verbose,
so we could use something like
"It should multiply two and two,"
and the second parameter
will get a callback.
And inside the body, we'll describe
what we expect the
result to be with expect.
So we expect that two
multiplied by two should be,
or tobe, four.
Let's save that and try
to run it with npm test.
And we can see that it's started,
and one spec was executed,
and there were zero failures,
meaning it passed.
What if we change this to five?
We know that's going to be
wrong and it should fail.
And we're shown that we have a failure
at calc should multiply two and two,
expected four to be five.
So that's the general idea behind testing.
It's quite simple, Jasmine
makes it very verbose,
and even the failures
make it very easy to see
what we need to fix.
So now that we have an
idea of how testing works,
let's go ahead and apply
it to our application next.