- [Instructor] So back in our server spec
let's fix our calculator test
and change it's to be to four.
Now let's describe another set of tests.
This time it'll be
specific to get messages.
So all the test part of this group
will test various features
of our get messages endpoint.
So let's create our first
test or specification.
It should return
200 ok.
So we expect that the status code
of get messages will be 200 ok
not 500 if there is a server error
not 401 for not found, etc
and then let's add a call back.
So inside here we actually need to make an
HTTP get request.
Natively we can't do
that so we'll have to use
a library called request.
So let's install that with npm install
- - save - dev
request
and at the top let's require it in.
Then we'll use request.get
and we'll specify our URL
and then a call back.
The call back will contain an error
and the response.
For now we'll console log
the response to make sure we're
actually getting a response.
At this point we'll
have to start our server
so we use nodemon
and it started our server.
Now let's open up a new terminal
and we'll use npm test.
We can see that two specs passed,
but we didn't see our
response console logged.
That's because this test ends
before we even get a call back.
The reason for that is because
it's not set as asynchronous.
So to do that with Jasmine
inside the spec definition.
We need to pass back done
and then we need to call done
whenever our asynchronous code finishes.
Let's give that another try.
Now if we scroll up we
can see our response.
Let's try console logging
the response.body,
and we can see our messages.
So now let's create our first expect.
So we're checking that
response.status code
is equal
to 200,
and I'll take out the console log,
save that, and let's try running it.
We can see two tests passed.
Let's create another test spec.
So I'll copy the first it from line 10
to line 15 and paste it below.
In here we'll check that it returns a list
that's not empty.
It should return a list
Then let's change our expect.
So we'll check the response.body
.length
to be greater than zero.
That made the array inside the body
that needs to be greater
than zero or not empty
and since we know there are two messages
they should pass.
So I'll save this and let's run our test,
and it's passing, but
just to try something else
I'll check if it's greater than 40.
Let's try that.
And even though I set it to 40
yet we know we only have two
items inside our message array
somehow it's still passing.
In this case even though I
thought I was testing something
I was actually testing
something completely different
and if we remember our response.body
is a string by default.
So really I was testing the length
of the amount of
characters in that string,
which is roughly around 70 or 80.
So a good idea is to actually
get your tests to fail first
that way it further reinforces that
you're actually testing the right thing
and this is a concept we'll get into
in test driven development
in the next video,
but for now what we're going to do
is convert this over to JSON first
with JSPON parse we'll wrap the body
and we'll get the length of that JSON,
and since that JSON will be an array
this should work
and by work I mean it should fail.
So let's try it
and there we go expected
two to be greater than 40.
So now let's switch it back to zero
and it should pass.
Now that we have an idea
of how we can apply tests
to our existing application features
to verify that they are working
and will continue to work
as we develop new features
let's take a quick look
at how we can develop
new features in our app
using test first or
test driven development.