- [Narrator] In this video,
we'll add a new feature
using test-driven development.
So we'll add a test
first, we'll make it fail
and then we'll implement the feature
to make the test pass.
The new feature we'll add
is a new messages get call,
or endpoint that will allow
us to get the messages
from a specific owner,
by checking the name.
And we'll get that name
through a URL parameter.
So let's begin by creating a test.
We'll start running new describe.
And these tests will revolve around
getting messages from a specific user.
The first test will be the standard,
it should return a 200 okay,
so I'll just copy this from above
from line 10 through line 15
and paste it in our new describe.
Next, I'll need to supply a user name
at the end of the Url
and I'll just use Tim.
Let's save that and give it a try.
We'll use npm test.
We can see there were
four specs that were run
and one that failed.
Our get messages from user
should return 200 okay
and we got a 404, not found
that we expected, to equal 200.
And so that's good.
The route doesn't exist yet
and we should get 404's.
So it is failing just like we expect.
Now let's go ahead and make that pass.
So let's go to our server js
and copy our app.get messages function
and paste it below.
Then let's add a user parameter.
Now that I've added the user parameter,
that should be it.
Let's try and see if our test passed.
Now that we ran our test,
we can see it's passed.
It did find the route
and regardless of what
was sent to us back,
our test passed.
But we don't know if it
actually functions as expected
because our full
requirement is that it only
gives us messages of a specified user.
So let's create another
specification for that.
We'll check that the name should be Tim.
And we'll copy the request call
between line 26 and 29
and paste it inside.
Then let's check the response.body.
And as before, we'll need
to convert it to JSON.
Then we'll get the first
element in our array
and check the name,
and make sure that it's
equal to Tim.
We'll save that.
And before we run it, think
of whether it will work
or will fail, let's give it a try.
And it's failed.
That's because the
messages we currently have
in our database aren't
guaranteed to be posted by Tim.
Second of all, we don't
have the functionality yet
in our server, to support
that specification.
We're just returning all of the messages.
Let's go ahead and
implement the functionality
to make this pass.
First thing we'll need to do
is get access to that user parameter.
So we'll create a variable, called User,
set it to request.params.user.
And then we'll select all of our messages
if the name matches the user.
Now once again, if we run this,
think whether it will fail or pass.
And it failed.
And it cannot read
property name of undefined.
Why is that?
Since we're only getting back messages
that the user Tim owns,
we currently don't have
any messages by Tim
and so we're getting
back nothing in our array
and it's failing as a result.
So at this point, let's go back to our app
and post a new message by Tim.
And now let's try running our test again.
And it's passed.
It's not ideal that we have
to actually set the state
of our database in our server
in order for our test to pass.
The ideal thing would
be that our test suite
sets up the server and the database
just the way it should be
before the tests are run.
And in more advanced testing,
that's exactly what we would do.
We'd have a before function that executes
at the start of our test
or test suites, that sets up the database
with say, a message from Tim.
The test then executes
and then an after function
would execute and remove that message,
therefore returning the
database back to a normal state.
And those are some of the
important concepts of testing
and test-driven development.
At this point, we've developed a feature
in our application by
writing tests for it first.
Let's go to our browser and
try it out for ourselves.
And we can see, it's working.
And that's the basic process
of test-driven development.
Next, let's take a look
at some of the things
we've covered in this course
and where you can go from here.