- [Alex] We've covered many
of the basics with Node
and we looked at many more
advance features as well.
This resulted in creating
a basic but robust
chat application where
I'm able to post a message
and have it automatically
synchronize across
several different
browsers using Socket.IO.
With automatic notifications and updates,
we also looked at database
frameworks and providers
such as our mLab database
that's using MongoDb.
And I hope you have a good
understanding of the differences
between synchronous and
asynchronous code at this point
and how Node shines along with JavaScript
when it comes to working
with asynchronous code
and the various options we
have for working with it
such as callbacks, promises, async/await.
And finally we ended up with
a new way of development
called test-driven development.
If you enjoyed developing
this chat application
while working with both the
front end and the back end,
I suggest working with framework such as
React or Angular to develop that further.
And you can check out my course,
Building Angular Apps and
Node Apps with Authentication
to explore these concepts
further as well as
introducing authentication
into your application.
Good luck with your future
Node and web development
and thank you for watching.